Welcome to the project.
This project is cloud automation with Ansible.
Yes, we're going to automate cloud tasks by using Ansible.
Let's see the scenario and understand when this would be required.
Okay, So let's say you have a diverse cloud management team and their job is to deploy setup infrastructure
on the cloud.
So any new project comes in, this team is going to be in charge of setting up the infrastructure,
deploying the stack on the cloud, and making all the regular changes as and when required before we
implement any project on a cloud.
We ideally set a VPC.
All right.
So this team will be in charge of setting up a VPC on a cloud to provide the security and high availability
to the project.
And also, this team is getting a regular request for deployment.
So let's see how Project A where you need to set up some VPC.
Then you have project B there.
Also you need to set up some VPC your project C.
So like that, many such requests, regular requests they get.
Now, as you know, VPC consists of many moving parts.
There are so many things when we are setting up a VPC, you have a subnets, NAT gateways, internet
gateways, route table, any SEAL rules, security group instances in that elastic IP and so many more
things.
And not to mention the bastion host.
Which it's also called as a jump server.
Mostly these jump server or bastion hosts are provided.
Or used to have an SSH connection to your instances in private, VPC or even RDP connections.
So we can see it's a single point of entry from a public network into your private network.
Now if you're doing such thing, there is always a chance of making a human error, a typographical
error, or some configuration misfire.
Because of this or these human errors, you may have a non-functional or an exposed VPC, which is exposed
publicly on the Internet.
Also, not to mention managing all these things is a time consuming task.
First is the setup, then regular changes.
So if everything is happening through console or even CLI.
It's really difficult to track all the changes.
So in order to save our time and track all the changes, you need to have configuration management of
VPC.
We need to have a completely automated setup so we can avoid human errors.
And any changes we are going to do in the VPC will be managed centrally.
So there should be a centralized change management system.
Now if you are automating all this, we'll be doing it through probably some code.
In Ansible we have playbooks written in YAML format and it's text and we can version control it so we
can track who made the change when the change was made.
So we can use gate and do version controlling of our code.
So we'll have infrastructure as a code.
Now these are some quick benefits that I'm talking about, but this really gives many more benefits.
We know for sure CSC adds business value, but also anything that you automate, especially in cloud,
also adds a lot of business values.
So let's see some statistics now.
Now as per statistics, 70%, 71% of the organizations who are doing cloud automation have found they
have 10% more revenue growth.
84% of the company have said, yes, they have seen increased revenue and also they have lowered their
operations cost.
81% have become more innovative.
So when you have things automated, you don't need to be doing tasks manually.
You get more time to find more innovative solutions.
And 84% said they have become more agile.
And that's what we're looking in DevOps, really.
We need processes to be more agile, more quick.
So cloud automation sounds cool, but also it adds a lot of business value and that is as per the statistics.
And numbers don't lie.
Okay, so let's see what we're going to do, what tools we're going to use in this project.
So we're going to do we're going to use Ansible to automate a VPC setup and also Bastion host.
So you'll have bunch of Ansible playbooks that will set up VPC on a cloud.
And also we'll have a bastion host which will be used to log in.
After this, there will be another Ansible project where you will use this VPC setup and deploy the
entire web application, stack the V profile web application stack that we have been setting up manually
so far now will automatically automatically setup that entire stack by using Ansible.
That's in the next project.
In this project, we lay out the infrastructure for it automatically.
So let's make it happen.
So before I show you all the code that you're going to use and we're going to have really a lot of code
in that before I show you that, before we get into that, let's see the architectural design of what
exactly we're going to do.
So join me in the architectural design.
So starting in the architecture, we have the playbooks, we'll have some bunch of playbooks and these
playbooks will be using some variables which you are going to define in virus file and some Ansible
configuration.
This playbook will be powered with a lot of modules that we're going to use to set up the VPC.
These modules are going to use the world famous Python bottle, which will make an API call to our cloud
account.
First thing it will do is it is going to set up a VPC, a VPC that will have subnets in two zones.
We will be using two zones.
So zone one will have some subnet.
Zone two will have some other subnets.
Forced to start with in the zone.
We will have a public subnet in first zone.
Second zone will have one more public subnet.
This public subnet will route the request to Internet Gateway by using their route table, so they'll
have a route table every subnet and this town route table is going to route the request to Internet
Gateway and then the traffic can go on the internet or can be coming from the Internet.
We'll also have private subnet in both the zones.
One zone will have one private subnet, another zone will have another private subnet.
And again there will be a route table which is going to route all the requests.
Outgoing request to Nat Gateway.
Let's see again in the full view.
So a VPC distributed in two zones, Zone one and zone two.
One Public subnet in Zone one.
One public subnet in another zone.
Private subnet also will be distributed like that among two zones.
Every subnet will have a route table.
Public subnet will route.
The request to Internet gateway and private subnet will route the request to NAD Gateway, and the NAD
Gateway can throw the traffic to Internet gateway through the route table of public subnet.
Also, not to mention we'll have a bastion host a jump server which will be in a public subnet so we
can access it from the internet.
And then that Bastion host can have connection to private EC2 instances, instances which are in private
subnet.
And there will be, of course, a security group on the Bastion host.
So this entire setup we're going to do through our playbooks.
So we run the playbook.
Playbook is going to use some module, some variables, use Python bottle, connect to a cloud, set
up the VPC with four subnets each having route table.
Internet gateway and nat gateway for public subnet and private subnet respectively.
And also finally, a bastion host, which will be a single point of entry into our VPC from the Internet.
So this is what we are going to do.
We'll log into our account.
We'll create an easy instance to run our Ansible playbook.
And we're going to select a region which has three zones.
That's not mandatory.
You can do what are we doing in any region?
We can set up VPC in any region.
But just to follow along the project, you're going to select a region that has three zones.
We're going to install Ansible in that easy.
For instance, where we set up, we're going to install Boto.
That is the dependency to do the cloud automation.
We're going to set up an easy two role for Ansible.
So Ansible, easy to instance, can connect to all the services like VPC and all.
Authentication.
So we're not going to use Access key and secret here.
We're going to use roles which is much more safer option you if you are already on a US.
Then we'll create a project directory in our instance, for instance, and we're going to execute a
sample task to create a key pair.
Now, if you have never done cloud automation with Ansible, you're using Ansible to do system automation.
There is a little difference in doing cloud automation.
So while we're doing this task, a simple task or a sample task to create a key pair, you will see
the differences.
Once you get that, then you can follow along or all the tasks.
We will create two variables file.
One will have VPC information.
One will have Bastion host information.
So we're not really going to use static entries in our playbook.
Will fetch that from variable file.
Then we'll write our main playbook, which is to set up the VPC stack.
This playbook will set up VPC subnets, Internet, gateway, route table, everything.
And then we are going to write another playbook, which is going to set up a bastion host in the public
subnet of our VPC with write rules.
We're going to use a site YAML file then and we'll put entries of both the playbooks so we will finally
execute site ML, which will in turn execute VPC, set up Playbook and Bastion setup playbook.
Once we are done setting up our entire stack, we should have.
This entire VPC with four subnets routable Nat Gateway, an internet gateway.
And also the Bastion host.
So what are you waiting for?
Let's dive in.