Okay, I'm logged in to my management console.
Currently I'm in North Virginia region, but I will switch to Ohio region.
So as I told you, we need a region which has minimum three zones.
Or if you have only three zone, that is much better.
That's not really a mandatory requirement for this project.
But we need minimum three zones because we are in this project.
We're going to set up a VPC stack distributed in three zones.
So you can select any region of your choice really, but should have minimum three zones.
So I'll be on a higher region.
So we'll launch easy, for instance, where we're going to install Ansible.
And let's go to S.E. to.
Instances.
Or forced easy to dashboard.
You see, it has three zones.
Yeah.
So we can go ahead with this.
Here we have launch instance button.
So let's say launch instance.
We'll go with Ubuntu 1 to 20.
Should be fine.
1 to 18 is also good.
We'll go with RT to Micro.
We don't need any great compute power for to run our ansible because ansible really does not run anything.
It's going to be mostly working like a client only so it doesn't run any service.
We don't call it as a server, we call it a control machine.
So T2 Micro should be fine.
Let's go next.
One instance.
And while it's coming up we'll also provision it with ansible.
So we'll run apt update sudo.
Zero apt install ansible.
This is fine.
Now in ubuntu 20 they should give you latest version of ansible, but if you are on a 1 to 18, check
the installation document of ansible.
You need to add even the repository details.
So you add the repository detail.
It's going to install ansible from the ansible repository, but in 1 to 20 you can just say install
ansible and that should be fine.
Oh, of course.
We need to also add our interpreter part exclamation slash bin slash bash.
And then let's go next.
So you're going to take all default and just give it a name control machine.
Or you can just call it as control.
They should be good.
Create security group.
So we'll just create a security group.
It's pretty simple.
We just need to do a search to this.
So we'll just name Ansible security group and we'll say 22 from my IP.
Let's go.
Next lunch.
Okay, Let's create a key pair.
So create a keeper.
Let's name it as Ansible hyphen Ohio.
Python key.
Download.
And, let's say, launch instance.
We'll wait for a minute or so.
Our instance is up.
Let's log in to it.
Let's copy the public IP.
Let's see.
It's a search for nine keys in the downloads directory.
Principal Ohio is certainly open to.
And we're in.
Okay, let's check the Ansible version.
We should already have no ansible.
2.9.6.
That's latest version.
If you're using ubuntu 18 as I told you, use the ansible repository to install ansible from.
You can find the steps in the ansible documentation installation section talking about ansible documentation.
If you already have used ansible to do some cloud automation, you know there is a setup.
If you have not done cloud automation ever with Ansible.
So it's better you go through the documentation and find out what all you need to write a playbook and
make it working or get it working for cloud automation.
Okay, so Ansible is documentation.
That's what I Google and click on it.
So we specifically using it as.
So you can read about it.
You see, it's going to talk about board two three module.
The installation happens on local host.
And for authentication your account details you need to export these keys, access key and secret key.
So you need to have an IAM user.
With Access Key and Secret key, and you need to give the right policy so it can perform the task.
Now, ideally, it's an exporting variable should be fine.
Or if you want to store it into variable, you can use Ansible vault to encrypt your access key and
secret key.
But whatever the case, do not mention your access key and secret key in your playbooks.
Do not mention it.
You need to mention it outside.
Either you export the variable on the system or you first encrypt it.
And then you can access it.
Can.
Or better if you're already on it.
Like I'm using easy to instance, and from there I'm going to run Ansible playbook.
The better practice over here should be using roles, easy to roles.
I am roles which you're going to attach to, easy to.
So that's what we'll do.
So we'll go to I am service and we'll create role.
So this rolls will save you from the trouble of access Key and secret key managing access.
Secret key?
Because there's always chance of exposing those keys, especially when you're using it with version
control by mistake.
You put it on GitHub public repository and the hackers bots are going to pick that up automatically
and do bitcoin mining on your account or even hijack your account.
So be careful with the access key and secret key.
So it's better easy to instance, you just create a role, let's say easy to next permission.
And I'm going to give you full admin access to this because I'm going to do a lot of things with Ansible
Playbook.
I'm going to launch VPC UCC two.
So you can specifically find your policies and enter it to be more secure.
I'm going with Administrator access.
Let's give this a name.
We'll name it as Ansible admin.
Yeah, I'll sleep with that.
Okay, so I have a roll created ansible admin and I'm going to assign it to my ec2 instance, my control
machine.
We go to instance settings modify iam role.
Will select our role and civil admin.
If you don't find it yet after creating, just do a refresh and you should find it or you can use it.
Created from here.
Also.
That's new thing.
That's nice.
Let's deceive.
Now let's test it.
So to make a test, I can use this command.
Eight plus six.
Get caller I.D..
I get caller identity.
So if this works, your authentication is working.
You can see the road name there.
What role is being used?
Oh, and by the way, to run this command, you need to have a SQL.
So if you're on Ubuntu, you can just say sudo apt install a cli, install a cli first a c ally.
And then you can run that command or you can run you run any other CLI command to test your authentication.
So our authentication is really working with the roles.
Now we can move ahead.
Once again, this is important.
So I'm telling this once again, do not put your access key and secret key in your playbooks just to
sample this.
I will show you.
Let's go to a module in module.
So this is easy to module of Ansible.
And you can do all this, right?
You can launch an instance with this.
You're going to see that.
But it will also have options for access key and secret key.
I see that it is access can a secret key.
So you can mention that, right.
So that module, that task is going to use this access key to authenticate to your account.
But if you're practicing, you may put it on a public repository like GitHub.
Public repository, and this can be seen by everyone.
Okay, So this turns out to be very dangerous.
So avoid mentioning access key in secret kind of playbook just to be safe.
Either export them or if you're already on us, just use the rules as I did.