Okay, Now we are going to do a sample.
Begin to write a simple task to create an easy to keep pair.
And we'll see what all we need to do when we need to automate or we need to access services from Ansible.
If you're used and if you're not used Ansible for cloud automation, then this will be very helpful
for you.
Once we get over this, then we'll start writing Playbook to set up our VPC stack.
So let's create a project directory and I'm going to name it as VPC.
Hyphen stack hyphen v profile.
So let's get into the directory.
Okay, let's go to the module index and sample module index documentation.
We can go to the cloud modules.
And you'll see all the cloud models, especially in the Amazon section, you see all the models.
So we'll go with very simple one, easy to key first.
So let's see how to use this module and what are the problems that we'll get and how to get over.
With those problems.
Again, so easy to underscore.
Key module.
This depends on python greater than 2.6 and boto.
So check the requirement of the module.
Based on the requirement you have to install the dependencies.
You'll see that now again, access key and secret key is there, but do not use it.
So a simple task.
This is going to create a key peer.
Yeah.
So name.
Easy to underscore.
Key.
Name of the key.
So let's get in.
Let's write our test playbook.
We'll see a test x dot y mil.
So the horse.
So the execution will be on local host.
And connection also we can specify we can say connection local.
Gather facts.
I don't want to gather any facts because it's going to be gathering facts of my control machine locally,
which is waste of time.
So I'm going to say gather fact false.
Tasks.
So we are going to mention our task.
Or, you know, we can just simply copy paste from there.
I like that.
All right, Let's take care of the indentation.
Okay, sort of example.
I will give them a sample.
How about that?
Okay, just a sample.
Okay.
Just to test.
You can see this a.
Warm up before we actually write our playbook.
So this is going to create a key pair.
So let's see.
Ansible hyphen playbook dest.
Let's run our playbook.
And let's face errors.
Yes, as I told you.
So this.
This module that we're using.
Easy to key depends on bottle.
So you need to install bottle.
So it is telling you you need to have bottle core or bottle three.
Because you're using Python three.
So there are two ways of installing boto.
You can use PIP or you can use directly app commands.
I prefer app commands rather than using PIP because pip will give you a very latest version, but it
could be very buggy.
So we can just make a search pseudo app search bottle.
Through people.
Also, you can install and you can install any version also with PIP.
But this is much easier and convenient if you're only using Linux.
So python three, hyphen porto you have python three hyphen portal three.
Python three hyphen two core.
Okay, I'll just Python three have one.
Yeah.
So this is Python interface.
So let's try that first.
So it's a sudo apt install.
Install that run app update if you have not executed it.
Okay.
Um.
Okay, now let's try the execution again.
And as I told you, this is this is a trial run.
So we're going to try with few things.
Okay.
It still feels okay.
It's still telling me that there is a problem.
So let's install now to core.
Yeah, but to core because it is also telling us about the core.
Motoko is already installed installs as a dependency with the same module.
Sorry, same package Python.
Python three hyphen bottle.
So.
Well, let's try Other one is a python three.
Let's run a search or bottle.
Python three hyphen mortar three is also there.
Let's try that.
I'll just say python three ball three install.
And let's try the execution now.
Okay.
I think it work, but we have a different error now, right?
Etc..
Key module requires a region and none was found.
So now you know for sure that easy to underscore key module needs this package.
Python three hyphen border three.
So there are various cloud modules and based on the requirement will install the dependency.
If you want, you can keep all of them.
Nothing is going to harm you, but initially you can find out like this.
Now it is telling us to find the region or mention the region.
Let's mention the region.
So there is a.
Argument region and you can mention the region.
So let's go to our region.
Okay.
We have US East too.
Let's create it in this region.
You can check in the documentation.
There will be option region.
If you don't want to mention it, you can set global variables also like this region or easy to underscore
region, and so you don't need to mention it in every module that also you can do.
But for now, let's keep it like this and let's see one quit.
And let's try now.
All right.
That worked, right?
But we had created key payer.
It was the private key.
Generally, if you do it through console, it will download.
Right.
But now it's not showing.
Well, it returns the value, but then we are not using that value.
Every Ansible task returns and JSON output and in that output there should be definitely key.
But we are not using that.
We are not saving that.
So anyways, let's, let's go and check our key first.
So let's go to key players in this region and we should see the sample key.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm going to delete this key.
Because.
It's going to send you the private key.
Then later you can't like, redownload the private key, right?
It's not again.
So I'm going to edit this playbook and very important thing with cloud task or any API based task is
you should store the output into a variable.
So I'm going to give the variable name as key out.
Right?
And then you can print it when you're initially, if you have first time using a module, then you store
the output and see the content.
Okay, that's a key out.
Let's print it with debug module so you'll see the content.
And then based on that, we can decide where if we have the private key and then we can store it into
a file also.
So I deleted the key.
So it's going to recreate the key again.
And you get the output back.
Yeah.
And there's the private key.
So that Jason content has a key called key out in that you have a key called Sprite underscore key and
the output is really the value is really the private key.
This we can copy paste in a file and then we can start using it.
But that's manual work.
So what we're going to do is.
We should be storing it into a file so we can use copy module.
Let's give a name store.
Log in key.
And we can say copy module.
And we'll see content.
All right.
So we have content.
So Coppi also has the option of content instead of sauce.
If you'll never use the content option, check checking the documentation.
You can just mention the content, right?
Whatever you want.
You can put it into double quotes and you can store it in a destination file.
In our case, we are going to store the private key, so we have already stored the output into the
variable we need to access.
Key out.
Key out is our variable in that you have a key called a key that has another key close, private, underscore
key, and that has the content of our.
Private key file.
So we're going to use this key out dot, ky, dot private, underscore key and access it and store it
into a file.
Okay, let's open the playbook again.
So the content will be double quotes and the variable name in curly braces to calibrations.
So key out, that's our variable name, dot key we have inside that private underscore key.
So that should return us the private key content and destination.
We'll say store it in the current working directory with the name sample hyphen key dot pem.
Okay, now let's execute that.
Kiyosaki dot private underscore key this is good key out.
Dot ki dot right underscore key.
Yeah.
Okay.
But now you'll see a new problem.
It is undefined variable.
It is it says that no private key because if you check now the key already exist.
So now it's not going to return back the private key.
So you see under inside key you don't have private underscore key value.
But we can test it very well if you don't have a key.
Delete the key.
Let's delete the key once again.
And let's go back.
If we execute it now, it should work.
It should store the private key into a file.
You see, we have the private key and has saved it into a file.
Let's see.
Unless you have the sample key.
See that it worked.
But then we have multiple tasks in our playbook.
We keep adding the task and we execute.
Then it's going to throw us error.
If we add another task, we execute the playbook.
It's going to throw us error and the execution will stop.
So now we have to handle this error, right?
So in the output we see change as false, right?
So when the query is created only then we will save it.
Else will not save it.
So we need to put a condition.
So we'll put a condition there.
When.
Key out.
Not changed.
Now you don't even need to say equal to true or anything because its value is anyways true or false.
You don't need to compare it.
You can just a key out dot change if its value is true.
If the key gets created and the value is going to be true, then only it's going to save the key or
else it's going to be skip it.
Okay, So let's see this.
Okay, now let's execute it once again.
You see it skipped it.
Right.
And then, you know, we really handling the error.
We can add multiple tasks and we can execute this many times you want.
All right.
If so, you used Ansible for system task, right?
And you've seen always it's important.
But in cloud there are some issues when you're using cloud models.
So I wanted to highlight that.
And also it's a little warm up before we begin our cloud automation.
Important points to note over here is when you execute a task API based task, like a cloud task easy
to key here.
This uses bottle connects to your account and it's going to return output in JSON format, so you better
save it.
So every time you use a module, you better save that output into a variable, so you are going to use
it in the next task.
Most of the time we use it, we refer it into next task.
Like, for example, we create a security group and after that we're going to create easy.
For instance, so we create security group, we store the ID.
Then while we're launching you to instance in the next task, we'll refer that way.
We'll refer the security group ID from that variable.
So store the output and then use it.
And if your tasks are not important, then you have to add some intelligence and make them important.
So these are like little differences that you will find when you use API based tasks from system task
easy to easy to instances.
Security Group.
VPC.
We're going to do all use all those models.
These are all API.
It will make API calls.
Okay, So I hope this was clear.
And a very good warm up before we begin our actual project.
So now let's save this.
If you want, you can delete this.
We are not going to need this.
So I'm going to just delete this one.