So one more completed.
Let's move now to our main workout.
Right?
So main project work, we are going to set up VPC stack by using Ansible playbook.
We're going to write a long, long PE playbook starting in this project and also in the next project.
We'll be having long, long playbooks.
And if you're already interested in using any ID like Intel J or Sublime or anything, you can go with
that.
But then make sure you create a git repository and push the code from there.
And here we're going to pull that code.
So let's do that setup first and it's optional if you like, do it or else you can just write your playbook
by using VIM editor.
That is also fine.
So for this, I'm going to create an account.
Sorry, I already have an account on GitHub.
I'm going to create a repository on GitHub.
So.
So log in to your GitHub account and create a repository.
We'll name it as Ansible.
Answer.
Bill hyphen eight s hyphen vpc.
Okay, Let's give that name to be safe.
Put it private.
I'm going to keep it public because anyways, I am not going to put anything over there, any access
in secret.
This is where things go wrong.
You put access key and secret key, and you put your playbooks or your code in the public repository.
You're exposed.
So be careful over here.
Select private if you're not so sure.
Or skip this altogether.
GitHub work itself and read me.
Dot md file Create repository.
So I'm going to store all my playbooks over here.
I'm going to push my playbooks.
I'll write it on my system by using intelligent, push it on GitHub, and then from my system, from
my control machine, I'm going to pull the code.
I'll do it both ways.
Again, this is optional.
If you don't want, you can just directly start using through Vim editor.
Okay.
Now I'm an intelligent ID.
If you've gone through prerequisite video, we have already.
I already shown you how to set this up with GitHub.
So we're going to put everything on our GitHub repository that we just created.
So we're going to say VCs.
Get from version control or first, let's create a new project.
Project from version control that is also good.
And we can mention the repository URL.
So copy your repository url.
Mention it over there.
Mention a part where you want to save it.
I'll keep it in my drive.
I'll say clone.
I would like to open it in a new window.
And I'll close this old window.
So we have a redeemed file.
Nothing else we can add our content.
I guess the first thing in our Playbook stack, we're going to create variables, file first variable
file for VPC and then variable file for bastion setup.
So I'll create two files.
It's going to be just a text file.
So it's a new file.
And we'll name it as VPC underscore setup.
If you're doing this first time, just use the same names from the next execution.
You can start changing this name.
And because we're going to refer the same name in our playbook.
So we pick underscore, setup.
It's just a text file.
Yes.
So I would also like to add it in my git repository.
Add.
And let's mention the variables, starting with first VPC name.
And let's give a name.
I will say we profile hyphen VPC.
Okay.
Give me capital.
No, this is fine.
Let's give capital here.
We profile VPC.
That's one variable I've defined.
Then VPC range.
Let's give VPC range.
Range is not just range.
So let's keep the variable in VPC.
Sider the seed capital there for sider and let's decide a range 172 170 2.23.0.0 slash 60 and we're
going to subnet that with.
You're going to take six subnets from that or slash 24.
So let's mention the subnet ranges also.
Subnet.
French.
So six subnets, three public subnets, and three private subnets.
Get carved out from the main VPC network.
So 20.1, 20.2, 23, then 20.4, 20.5, 26.
All of slash 24.
So you're going to get to 56.
But.
It will also resolve some IP.
So you'll have like 251 IP per subnet.
Okay, So these are variables just we're going to access this variable in our playbook.
That's where the main fun happens.
Region will set a region name.
Now you can set a global value also if you want, but I just wanted to use more variables in this project,
so I'm going to mention region also.
So I'm really using US East to make sure it's in tribal codes.
It's not mandated to put this in double code, but since there is a hyphen, I try to use double codes.
And now these subnets will be created in three zones, as I already told you.
So we'll mention the zone names.
Okay.
These are three zones I'm using.
If you are not sure about those zone names, just go to your EC two dashboard.
Scroll down and you should see the zone names over here.
US is to a us is to be us is to see.
That's compared to that.
Nope, sorry.
One and a half given.
So I made a mistake.
Good.
I confirmed.
But anyways, it's going to alert you when you execute the playbook.
No such zone found something like that.
We'll also set one more variable state.
We'll give it a present.
This is the variable file for the VPC setup.
All right, let's control.
Let's save that.
We'll also added into our git repository, but also we'll create one more file first, one more variable
file.
This will be for Bastion host.
So let's name this file as Bastion underscore setup.
Text file.
So we have here.
Bastion underscore ami this variable will mention the EMI.
So let's get the my ID.
So let's go to s.
Easy to.
Launch instance.
So you can use Amazon Linux, you can use RedHat, you can use Ubuntu, you know, you can just copy
the.
But my suggestion is for bastion host.
You really go with some secure EMI like from one from CIS.
They're not free.
There are charges for it.
But if you're investing money on project, you'll definitely can spend that much for secure EMI.
So this will be a single point of entry to our VPC from public networks.
So we have to make sure this is rock solid, robust, safe, secure.
So you can use hard images at one from SES, which is very popular and there are a few other if you
have your own choice, you can use some hardened amis.
Because normally mice will definitely have no bugs or vulnerabilities that can be exploited by the hackers.
So I recommend such amis.
But this is not free.
And for our project exercise, we want to keep things free as much as we can.
So we'll go with Amazon Linux to.
Can't copy the ID.
And let's face it, based on your region, it will be different.
So check that.
If I see the same image in a different region, it will have a different ID.
Region will also mention region here.
So.
US is to.
Double code not required.
We are also going to create security group for this bastion host and in the security group we are allowed
traffic 22 as such only from my IP, only from where we like in your case to be your IP, of course,
but we'll create a variable.
Call us my IP and find out your IP.
What is my IP?
Just Google it and just put it over here with slash 32.
So assuming your IP is that you can change that, now I'm going to cheat.
That's not my actual IP.
I'm going to change it with the real IP.
Okay, I'm done setting up both the variables file.
I can write playbook.
But first, you know, let's save it and let's commit it.
We'll pull this from our system, from our Ansible control machine.
So control K to commit.
You can give a commit message variables file and get.
And that's the message they commit.
Okay control shift key to push it to your repository is push so you can select the branch.
Say push.
Yes, it's pushing there.
Now, let's go to GitHub.
And let's refresh this.
So we should see two new files and the Kermit message.
Now we are going to clone this.
It's a git clone.
Ansible is VPC and we'll keep that as our project name now.
All right.
So I did that.
So you can very conveniently write ansible playbooks the yaml file in your ID.
You get all the help from ID, all the features, and then you can just pull it and run it from here.
I also recommend you can install a YAML plugin for IntelliJ or whatever id you're using.
Just install a YAML plugin so it can highlight all our syntax that will be easier for us.
So for intelligent, let's install the plugin.
Intelligent Ansible.
So.
So plugin support.
Let's check that.
There is not really a ansible plugin.
It's yaml plugin.
So we can say get and select a version.
Oh, wait.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
You can directly click it from their intelligent ID.
So it's going to radically install it in your intelligence.
You'll get an option like this.
Just say, okay, so now your intelligence will have YAML support.
So if you write yaml code it will highlight.
It will highlight the indentation, the columns, everything.