Okay, so now let's get started and started with our VPC playbook.
So I'm going to say new.
And I'll just see file, just give an extension, that's all.
So the playbook, I'm going to name it as VPC setup dot yaml.
Yeah.
You see, it's just see reading it there as why am I look.
So it's going to understand now yaml.
So for host on local host.
Connection and all this from our warmup exercises, Right.
Connection local.
Gather facts.
False.
I don't want to get together any facts.
Tasks.
For Starsk, We're going to import our variables files because we're going to use that.
So let's name that task and say import VPC variables.
Okay.
You see, I hit enter.
It automatically goes in the same line, Right?
So that's the benefit of it is.
So we're going to use include underscore versus module and we'll mention the path of our variables or
better.
I was thinking to put variables into a vast directory.
So you know what?
Let's create a directory here.
New directory, I will create a directory named as VARs.
In this directory.
We'll put our variables file.
Okay, let's move it.
Three factor.
Yeah.
This is much better, actually.
So do that.
Or it doesn't matter if you keep it in the same level, but just convenience.
And also good practice.
And whether you have mentioned just mentioned the path.
So I'm going to say I have put it into verse VPC, underscore a set up.
That's my variable file name.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's first thing.
And I'm going to mention first task to create the VPC range.
Let's create the profile.
VPC.
The model we have is easy to underscore.
Underscore net.
That's the module name.
And you have several options with that.
First, the name of the VPC.
And if you're going to access our variable, we have the variable, right?
VPC underscore name that will mention, yes, this is much better.
CIDR underscore block.
So let's access the variable name VPC CIDR.
Right.
Now, if you're not so much fan of using variables and you just mentioned that static value and you're
wondering why not directly give the names instead of giving the variables and then having it in extra
variable files?
Well, it's because so you can reuse when I'm going to give you the same code.
You'll understand the difference.
You don't need to edit the playbook.
You just need to change the variable value.
And that's it.
You're done.
You can execute your playbook.
So it makes the code reusable.
So you try to use variable as much as you can.
Region will mention.
So we have defined the variable as just region.
A few few other options that I learned which will need DNS support.
Yes.
DNS hostname.
Tenancy default, state and present.
Anyways, the state is by default as present.
So this will create our VPC, but as from the warmup exercise, remember we have to store the output.
Right.
We're going to use let's say variable called VPC out.
It's going to store the output of the execution.
If you have doubt in these options and the name of the playbook, just go to Ansible documentation.
Yeah.
Let's go back here.
Go back.
VPC underscore net configure a virtual private cloud.
So check in the documentation.
You have the dependencies, mentioned all the options, mentioned DNS support, DNS host name camp.
And you'll have an example as well.
So very conveniently you can access the information and as per your requirement, you can change the
options if you want.
So keep that in mind.
All the modules that I'm going to use, you can check in the documentation, see all the options, and
that's how we're going to execute this entire project.
If you want, you can simultaneously take notes or screenshots of modules, or then you can make a list
of modules that you've used.
Making the list of modules should be more than enough.
You don't need to really do anything because documentation is online available.
You can just search for the module and you can see everything with examples.
Let's do this first here.
We'll do an execution, then we'll come back.
So I'm going to save it.
Control this control key.
And I'll see VPC set up.
That's the commit message.
And I'm going to push it.
Control.
Shift key.
Push it to GitHub.
Okay.
And let's do it.
Pull.
Things are going to change now.
You'll have a variable directory and a VPC setup playbook.
Yes.
Okay.
Let's do an execution now.
Ansible hyphen playbook.
VPC set up.
If everything is good, this will work.
And that worked.
So it should have created a VPC.
Let's go and check in our console.
So you go to.
VPC.
Okay, so your VPC is.
So we have our VPC created.
We profile, underscore VPC.
Yeah.
And now we can we can create subnets and route tables and all those things in that.
That's the default VPC.
I recommend you just give a name.
Clearly default because you know, when you're doing this exercise you will tend to delete VPC.
Be careful, don't delete your default VPC or else you'll you'll be in a big mess.
Be careful with that.
Don't delete your default VPC.
So only play with your own VPC that you have created.