Okay, so that's done.
Let's go next let's create now subnets in those VPC.
First, I will create a public subnet.
That's the name of the task I'm giving the model Is this easy to underscore, VPC, underscore subnet,
and you can mention all the options.
The first option we're interested in mentioning is the VPC ID, in which VPC do you have to create your
dimension that right.
So.
How do we know?
Well, we have stored the output VPC out.
Yes.
And that should have the ID so you can print it.
You can debug this.
I will add, you know, like a debug option there.
So debug task so you can see the output.
The that.
VPC out.
So the entire execution is going to be like that.
We execute a task, we store the output, and then we use it.
So if you're not sure about the key inside that, then just print that and you can see.
The keys and the sub keys inside there and the values inside that.
Other options region have specified again Region variable a z zone variable Zone one.
But we have their zone one.
So first public subnet will be in zone one.
That's zone one.
State present.
So again, that is also mentioned cider.
Bob.
Sub one cider pops up.
Nice name.
Okay.
Yeah.
So pub sub one cider.
So that's going to be the value for it.
A few more.
Option map underscore public.
So we're going to launch easy to instance under this public subnet and they should automatically get
a public IP.
So map public.
Yes that option also tags resource underscore tags.
So name.
Otherwise it will not show the name in the tags and limit us v profile hyphen pub.
Sub one.
Yeah.
And again, store the output into a variable register.
Pub sub pub sub one underscore out.
Okay, that should create one public subnet with all these details.
Let's test it.
Save it.
Control K.
Comet sub one.
Control.
Shift k.
Push it.
And let's first pull it.
Yeah.
So let's check it.
All right, let's test it.
What is not a new line character there?
I have not given any one character that give it.
That looks really ugly.
Okay.
I would once again, same commitment.
I'll give.
Control shift key.
Now this is much better.
Okay, let's do the execution now.
And Sybil hyphen Playbook, VPC setup.
We already have a VPC, so it's not going to do anything.
And we got an indentation error.
And let's fix it also.
Yeah, I was just showing you.
So you know, you will get such kind of errors, indentation errors, which are very common and it's
very easy to see it in the ID.
That's what I wanted to point out, actually.
See, that's an error I made.
Right.
So this should be the same line as the name, right?
And I've given here four spaces.
This is fine.
If you want, you can just reduce it to two space or one space.
But I have not given this space.
It has given it automatically.
And so even by using ID, there is chances of making mistakes like this.
So just check your code once again.
You should be fine.
All right.
It's in the same line as everything you can see there.
That line dropping right register is in the same line as easy to write.
All these options are in the same line.
Then you have indentation for the resource tag names option.
So verify that this is a very common error and very simple actually to find out.
So let me save this.
Control shift.
Key push.
Get pull.
That's executed once again.
And that is good.
Yeah.
Sorry.
No, it's good.
So it created a one single public subnet in our VPC.
I just wanted to show you this.
And we stored the output in our printing it VPC output.
All right, so you get VPC there, you get the ID.
Night we had.
So variable name dot VPC, dot ID gives you the VPC ID like that.
All the task.
We're going to store the output and we're going to use it if you want.
You can just use a debug module and print it.
I'm going to comment the debug module after this.
Because that's going to be too much of output.
Commanded.
Okay.
Now, since you understood how to do that, let's Right.
Let's put all the other subnets.
We have total six subnets to create one we have already given.
Now give five other subnet information and it's going to be as similar as this.
Just the names will change.
Okay.
Next task.
Similar.
As I said, names are going to change because we're using all variables.
Second public subnet rpc ID region zone two.
Second VPC sorry.
Second subnet in second zone State Prison CIDR.
Again, we're picking up from the variable file.
Yeah, that one.
My my public.
Yes.
Resource tag.
And let me change the name.
We profile and we store the output into variable pops sub underscore out.
Third public subnet.
Again, similar.
This is going to be in zone three.
CIDR is different.
And the name, of course, and storing it the output into a variable.
So three public subnet there.
And let's test at least this much first.
Save it.
Not run.
Commit.
Some one, two three Bob some commit message.
You should give a proper correct message when you're working in a project.
Oh, yeah.
Control shift key.
Bush.
It will.
Ansible hyphen.
Playbook.
VPC.
Setup.
So VPC is already there.
First public subnet is already there.
So it's going to create the second and third public subnet.
Okay, let's check that.
Let's go to subnets.
We should see three public subnet.
Yeah, three subnet.
Actually, there's nothing public about this subnets yet, but we got it right.
20.1.
20.2 23.
Yes.
Yeah.
This is better.
20.1, 20.2 23.
And they are scattered across three zones to A, to B, to C.
Yeah, and they're definitely part of our own VPC.
Right.
That's our VPC.
So we did good.
Let's now create other three subnets.
We're going to name them as private subnet.
Three private subnet.
So let's go to intelligent and almost similar, but these are going to be private subnet.
So after these three public subnet, three private subnet.
So you see nothing much changes.
You can really copy paste your task and just change the names and the variables of course.
So creating one private subnet in zone one.
So first private subnet in zone one, that's the CIDR range.
Yeah, that 140 and we'll have 4.05.0 and 6.0.
So this is 4.0 in zone one.
This is five zero in zone two.
And this is 6.0 in zone three.
And we are naming them as private subnet.
And also remember, we are storing its output.
Yeah, which will be useful later.
I'm going to see if this comet.
Yeah, it was new code.
So three new subnets.
Private one.
Private two.
Private three.
To execute.
Okay, let's check that.
Let's refresh.
And you should have know three private subnet.
One, two, three.
And so.
Now.
That's public.
Sorry.
All right.
You know what?
I should do it like this.
4.05.06 or three zero.
Private subnet one private subnet two private subnet three in our VPC and they should be into three
different zones as same as public subnet two A to B to C.
That's nice.