So that did it.
Okay.
Now we need an Internet gateway for our public subnet.
So we'll create an Internet gateway.
Let's say.
Internet gateway set up.
Easy to underscore, but there's no hyphen.
What's taking hyphen automatically?
AC to underscore VPC underscore GW.
That's the name of the module.
Okay, first thing VPC ID, I can really copy it from there itself.
See that?
Because I'm already using it in the other module.
So in this VPC, I'm going to create this Internet gateway.
Again, check the documentation.
You have this option VPC ID in this module region also.
That's convenient.
State also see.
You know, you just need to put hands on few cloud models and then things will become very easy.
Resource tags.
But see, these two are very different module.
It was check again.
I know for sure that this option is available in this module, but don't copy paste options from different
different modules.
There is a chance that this option may not be available in this module.
These are two different models.
But I know for sure it's available, so I'm putting that.
And of course, I want to register the output.
I have to change this name.
Name it.
As we profile GW Internet gateway like that.
Register the output.
Registering to GW underscore out.
That should create an Internet gateway.
Let's see if this.
GW.
Control shift.
Key push.
Ansible hyphen playbook.
VPC setup.
So now this should create a new internet gateway for us.
By checking all our subnets.
Well, there is a problem.
Oops.
Oh, that's a genuine mistake.
Register is saying that it's not a supported parameter.
Okay, then I can quickly understand that Why?
Why it's happening.
It's thinking register is is an option.
Because I made indentation mistakes.
Register should be in line with the module.
Yeah, like that.
Okay, let's fix that.
Let's pull the changes.
And let's execute.
And there you go.
Internet Gateway got created.
Let's check it.
Okay.
That's up there.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Internet gateway there.
And you should see the Internet gateway.
Again, there is an existing internet gateway of default VPC.
Just name it as default, something that it's easily recognizable for you.
So you don't accidentally delete your Internet gateway.
And then you'll have no internet to your CD instances which are in default.
VPC can.
Okay, so we have created Internet Gateway.
This is for the public subnet to route traffic, but the route table will tell the public subnet to
go and access this internet gateway and vice versa.
So we need to create a route table now and map it to our public subnet.
Again, like the drought tables here.
Existing drought table.
And if you see it's map to it's not map to any subnet this drought table.
Okay.
Wait a second.
No, I'm looking at a right wrong place.
Yeah, There.
That's that table.
As these three subnets, or he can say this three public subnet of default VPC has this route table.
And it's routing the traffic, all the traffic to Internet gateway like that.
We need a route table for our public subnet as well so it can route the traffic to the Internet gateway.
So next we're going to create.
Roundtable.
Okay.
That's the module.
Easy to underscore.
VPC.
Underscore root table.
Again mentioning VPC, ID mentioning the region.
And let's also give it a tag.
Tags.
Name.
We profile hyphen pub arty.
Okay, This is just a tag.
You can give anything if you want.
Now this is for which subnets.
So you have to mention the subnets is an option here subnets and you have to mention the list of subnets.
So three public subnets.
So we have to give the variables here which we have only stored.
So Pop's about right.
If you want, you can print it.
Using debug module.
But there is a key in that called a subnet, which has the key caller's ID that is going to return you
the subnet idea of that.
Okay.
Like that.
Similarly for all the others.
The variables I'm giving in a proper format.
You see, it's very easy for me to use and change them.
Like pops up, one pops up, two pops of three.
I don't even need to go there and see the variable name, right?
Because if it's a proper format, it's easy to follow.
Okay.
So those are the subnets for the in this row, for this route, table and routes now where the traffic
should be rounded routes.
So destination.
So this is list of routes.
So it's going to be hyphen and the destination.
Right.
0.0.0.0/0.
So all the traffic is routed to.
Gateway.
So option Gateway underscore ID.
So the internet gateway guide so ICW dot underscore out.
Dot gateway.
Underscore ID and store its output.
Make sure registers in the proper indentation.
Register.
Bob.
Artie!
Underscore out.
I'll just see small out if that's looking a little complicated.
You're not sure about the option?
Just checking the documentation.
VPC.
Easy to underscore VPC underscore table.
Kemp, You can see all the options that I have used.
Routes.
State subnets.
Right.
You can see state an array of subnets to add to this route table.
Write the list array.
And you can see the example very easily.
Now, documentation is the king.
And you follow the king generally.
Okay.
Let's go back.
That's going to create a round table.
Let's see if this committed.
Routing table for public subnet.
Commit and let's push.
Let's just check the indentation once again.
Yeah.
Okay.
Seems good.
Let's go get pull.
Let's execute the playbook.
So everything is done.
We have it is now going to create a route table map all our public subnet with it.
And we'll make sure the traffic is forwarded to Internet Gateway.
Now that's a success.
Let's see that.
Okay, let's refresh this.
Yeah.
So there you go.
October.
So Route 0.00/0.
Forwarding the traffic to our Internet Gateway Subnet Association three public subnets are mapped out.
You can go to the subnets and from there you can see this round table, right?
And this existing, this is default.
So we name it as default underscore.
And so I don't accidentally make any change to it.