Okay.
Next thing in the game, not Gateway.
So we have now we should have now a fully functional public subnet.
You can start launching instance to that and you should be able to access them also.
But then now we have to focus on the private subnet.
We have created three private subnet and we need to create a net gateway for it and again, route table
for the net gateway.
Okay, so that's the module.
Easy to underscore, VPC, underscore Nat Gateway.
It's going to create a new NAT Gateway and also allocate new elastic IP to it.
State subnet sorry, state present subnet ID so we have to mention this navigate will be created in
which subnet.
Obviously we're going to give the public subnet.
The Nat Gateway lives in the public subnet, so we give public subnet ID.
Now we have three private subnet.
So for high availability we will need three NAT Gateway by the way, but that will turn out to be very
expensive for the project, for the exercises.
So you can just create one single nat gateway in one single public subnet to save some cost.
So Nat Gateway is not free.
So once you're done with this exercise, make sure you delete your NAT gateway first.
Even if you keep your VPC, that is fine, but make sure you delete the NAT gateway and release the
elastic IP.
So we're creating it in this subnet.
First public subnet.
Wait, yes.
So we're going to wait until this is up and running.
Not gateway takes time to come up region you specified and an option if exist do not create.
This is very important option.
If you forget to put this option and you keep executing your playbook as many as time you execute the
playbook, that many times not gateway will get created.
And then imagine the charges.
So make sure you don't miss this option.
Act if it already exists, do not create.
So this is going to make it important.
I told you not every module will, by default be important in cloud.
Some of them There are some tricks.
You have to use them.
And of course, then you register the output into a variable will next create the root table for it.
So a roundtable almost similar as we created for the public subnet.
But this is going to route the traffic to Gateway into the Nat Gateway, which we are storing over here.
Navigate to underscore out that has the key nat underscore gateway underscore ID and you will get the
NAT gateway ID feel free to use debug module.
After your task and print the output that you have stored.
Print the variable that your stored so you will know the key name are correct or not.
As the name of the model is debug.
It's very good and very helpful in debugging things.
Printing is the first part or the main part in debugging printing the values of variables.
Right.
Okay.
So again, this is the module it's creating in our VPC in the region that we specify the name subnets.
So private subnet IDs three private subnet.
This route table is 43 private subnet and all the traffic is going to go to the net gateway for this
and we store the output.
Let's see if this commit this.
See that gateway and multiple.
Commit.
Yeah.
Let's pull it.
Well, you not verify the indentation, but let's execute and find out.
So creation of that gateway takes time and I'm going to pause my screen and come back one when this
is completed.
Okay, So after a few minutes, that gateway got created.
Also, the route table for private subnets are created.
Let's check that.
Let's go to not gateways.
And then we go.
Then we have an add gateway.
Also, it has an elastic IP.
You can find elastic IP there itself, or you can check the elastic IP here.
So once if once you delete the nat gateway after a few minutes, you should also release the elastic
IP.
So it does not charge you for the elastic IP as well.
We should also have a round table now another out table, public round table.
It's attached to sorry, private root table.
It's attached to three private subnets.
And the route says all the traffic goes to Nat Gateway.