Now you should have a fully functional VPC with public and private subnets distributed among three zones.
And while we are doing all this, we also collected a lot of important information.
The IDs of VPC, public subnet ID, private subnet ID, Gateway ID, Route Table ID, which will be
very useful in our next project.
And also in general, it is very useful information.
So we better store this information into a file in a form of variable so we can reuse it later.
But for that, let's just print access all those IDs.
So I'm going to print all these variables and ID specifically from that variables.
And then we'll see.
Once we print it, then we're going to store all that information into a file, into a text file, which
will be a variables file for us.
So we'll use the debug module to print, of course.
And we'll say var and we'll run it in a loop.
So I'll give the variable of the loop item.
And the loop loop.
And then I'll give a list of all the variables.
Okay, so VPC out variable that we stored.
Dot vpc dot ID that's written as the VPC ID public subnet ID three public subnet ID three Private subnet
IP ID Internet Gateway ID, Public Route Table ID, NAT Gateway ID and Private Route Table ID.
So I'll just print it first.
We save it.
Print.
IDs.
IDs commit.
Let's push it.
I guess it should go through all the task, get the variables, and then finally print IDs from that.
So you should see all that valuable information, all the IDs.
VPC ID all the subnets ID.
Now we should have a plan to store these IDs into a file in a variable format.
But if you want to use it like instantly without storing into a variable, you can also set facts fact
variables.
So you can set all these ideas into some variable, and we can use a module which can set facts for
us.
So in the runtime if you want to use it.
In fact, variables are very handy and there is a module which can set facts for you.
And the module name is set underscore fact and then you can set fact variable.
It's a dictionary format, not a list format.
So let's say I will search VPC ID, that's the fact name and its value.
So when I run this in the run time, it will set that as a fact variable and then I can use it in an
exit playbook in the same playbook if I want.
So this is for the runtime and let's set like that all the IDs.
So all the other ideas like that, you can set as fact variable.
Also, there's one option that you can use if you wanted across the execution.
You can see cache able.
Yes.
So when you do that, then this variable will be added to the fact cache.
You can find detailed information about this catchable option in variables documentation of Ansible.
So I'm showing you just to show a very good feature in Ansible so you can use it during the live execution
during runtime.
You want to use these variables as fact variable.
You can use that.
But for our particular use case, we want it to be stored into a file, as I already told you, so we
can use it later as well.
So for that, I'm going to use a copy module.
And store all that information into a file.
So I'm going to see name.
Let's name this copy.
Or should I say create variables file for VPC output.
Okay.
And the copy module.
Content.
So all this we are going to give really horizontally instead of vertically.
So this could be very long horizontally.
So in double code, you can give all the variables separated by a new line character.
Like we said this.
Will ignore the double quotes there.
We don't need that double code.
And a new line character.
And then the next variable.
Again.
Ditch that double coat.
Otherwise it will create a problem.
So I've set all those variables in a horizontal format.
Separate by newline character.
And destination will give it in the vast directory will give output underscore vars.
And let's see if this committed.
Store output
variables.
Okay.
Yeah, I think the idea did very quick, so.
So.
Should have pulled all the changes.
Alright, let's execute it.
Ansible playbook.
Okay.
There's an indentation.
It's right here.
But I think it's talking about set fact.
And yeah, I think that's a mistake.
So let's fix it.
Yes.
It should be here.
Right.
And saying we have to do it for this also.
Control a safe commit.
Fixed indentation.
Okay, let's try that now.
Okay.
So it is it created a file in the vast directory.
So we should see inverse.
Output?
Yes.
Great.
So we have all the all this valuable information saved in a variable file which can be reused later.
And we are going to actually use it because our next task is to set up Bastion host in the public subnet.
So we will need the VPC ID, we need the public subnet ID.