So now let's move to our next task.
Which is setting up Bastion host and we're going to write a new playbook for that.
So we'll say new file will limit us.
Bastion.
Hyphen instance.
Dot wireman.
Okay, There's a mistake in this file.
Let's delete this file.
Wrong name.
Yeah.
This is good.
Okay, so the global settings and then tasks.
First we have to include the variables.
So bastion host setup, I should give it here.
So Bastian set up this variable file, which is having the image of the Bastion host region and my IP
for the security group.
The other variable file also will include that we have just created.
Well, this file does not exist in our machine.
We created in the Ansible control machine, and we have to either commit it from there or we have to
create that file over here.
So we will come at it from there.
Okay, so in our repository.
They did not get it right.
So whatever changes we make, we can push it back.
To GitHub.
So we've created a new file over here, so we're going to commit that.
So I need to set a global name.
And the global email.
And then we'll commit.
And we'll push it.
Get push.
We have pushed the change now from our intelligence.
Let's pull that change.
Okay.
So I pulled it and we have.
The output file.
Now if you're using GitHub public repository, which ideally you'll not use in projects.
But keep in mind, this is very valuable information.
It can turn very valuable to people who want to exploit also.
So be careful and don't put it in public repository in your real projects.
Okay, let's fall back.
So before creating the Bastion host before launching the instance, we'll have a key pair and we'll
create a security group.
It's the same thing from our warmup exercise.
We create a key.
We store the output and we save the private key into this file.
Only if the file is created.
Next, we'll create a security group for our Bastion host.
So let's name our task Cricket Security group for Bastion Host.
And the model is easy to underscore.
Group.
So name of the security group, some description over it and the region which it is taking it from this
file.
Sorry, Bastion setup file.
That's where the region is mentioned.
That variable.
But the other information we have to mention, the VPC ID, where we want to create the security group.
So we definitely don't want it to be in a default VPC.
We want it to be in a VPC that we have created and we have all that information in output VARs file.
So we can say VPC underscore ID.
And let's get that variable, the ID.
So as I told you, this information all will turn very, very useful.
Now, let's give rules to the security group so you can just set rules and you can give a list of rules.
We have just only one rule in this 22.
From my IP, again, my IP variable is in.
Here.
So you better get your IP.
Put it over there.
And don't forget to use slash 32.
So this should create the security group, but you want to store the output into a variable again.
So in the next task where we launch easy to instance, we'll refer this.
As the security group.
Okay.
Now let's create the instance creating Bastion host.
You can see like that.
Module is easy to.
Default key underscore name.
That's the option.
So you can use the same name as you create it for the key.
You can either access it from the variable also, or you can just give the name as you have given in
your playbook.
Other options.
Instance type data.
Micro image.
Bastion underscore AMI again, it's already mentioned over here.
Wait.
Yes.
We'll wait until this becomes up and running.
This becomes healthy and maximum we're going to wait for 300 seconds.
Okay.
Now, the important part over here, if you're going to give tags.
Okay, so we're using three tags and here it's instance underscore tags.
That's the option, not resource tags.
Name, project and owner.
Now, if I execute this playbook, it will create easy.
For instance, if I execute it again, again, it will create a pseudo instance.
So this is not important by default.
So you have to make it item potent.
And the way we do it first, you give the tag and you give the number of instance that you want.
Like I want.
Exactly.
Exact count one, only one instance.
And then we're going to give an option count, underscore, tag.
So you give the same tags over their count tag.
Now, what this will do is.
When you execute force, it will check whether this count.
Of tax exist or not.
If it does not exist, it will create the instance next time.
When you run the playbook, it will c count the tag.
It already exists, so it will not create the instance.
So that should make it important.
Also exact count one.
So this tag is going to count once.
If you have this tag one time, then it will not launch the instance.
So you have to be careful at this know such kind of places.
Group underscore ID so security group ID.
So you already stored that into a variable bastion underscore out.
And it has a key close group underscore ID.
Again, when you use any task, don't assume it will be ID or group ID.
Print it by using debug module and see whether whether it exists or not.
Finally, let's register all this information into a variable.
If you want to use, you can use it later.
All right.
So that should be done.
Let's just verify indentation once again.
Now, at a glance, it seems good.
Let's try executed.
Not forced.
We have to commit it.
Okay.
Let's pushed.
Let's go to our instance and let's pull it.
All right.
So a few tasks, including few variables creating key pair, storing the private key, creating security
group, and then finally creating the instance.
Except there is one problem in this.
I hope you notice that.
We discussed.
We are going to create our bastion host in a public subnet we just mentioned here the group id we have
not mentioned here.
The CBC subnet it in which subnet do you want to create it?
So let's go back.
VPC.
Underscore subnet.
Underscore ID.
Okay, so let's find out the variable.
It's an output verse and let's say you want to create it in this subnet.
First public subnet.
So copy the name.
So you see that output vase file really turned out very helpful.
We got VPC ID from it.
You got region from it.
We got public subnet ID from it.
Let's see it.
It's committed.
Okay.
I think I need to wait for a second or so.
Slow down.
So once again.
Yeah.
Let's test it.
And simple hyphen playbook.
Okay.
There's the mistake.
Name?
Colon.
I'll keep the same comment.
Started the execution.
Okay.
That's because of the register.
So that is a very easy mistake to make.
Right.
But there are actually two levels of indentation here, right.
So rules this already indentation.
All right.
So fix that.
Let's see what committed.
Okay, let's pull it.
Okay, So the execution completed and I was also waiting for a few minutes for it to become stable.
The instance will be stable.
Let's go to our management console.
Let's go to e.
C to.
Okay, so we have the Bastion host.
Let's see.
In the networking section.
That's a VPC ID, that's our subnet.
Now, we did not mention VPC ID, but we do mention subnet ID and that of course belongs to that VPC.
So it's got created.
It should have a public IP.
Yes, and we can log into it, but the login key is in the control machine.
So.
Let's just do a cat.
Some key.
Come out and I'm going to create a file.
Been downloaded directly with the same name.
You can use different name also and will copy all this content.
Private Key content.
Let's see.
Gender.
Or if you want, you can just do an SEP.
But this is an easier option.
Now I have my key.
Log into my bastion host and the user is easy to hyphen user because it's an Amazon Linux.
Oh, let's get the public IP again.
So if you're able to log in, if you are able to log in, then the public subnets are verified.
Yes, we're able to log in.
So public subnets are verified.
Now, from this bastion host, I can log into instances which are in private subnet.
If I launch an instance in a private subnet, so I should be able to log in to those private instances
which are in private subnet from this bastion host.
And we'll see that in the next project where we're going to set up our entire stack in this secure and
highly available VPC.