So that should be all in this project.
But wait, we have to do a little cleanup.
We have Nat Gateway Elastic IP and those things should be removed.
So let's go to our VPC section.
Nat Gateway.
If you'd like to keep this VPC, you can except delete the navigate and release the elastic IP.
So that will take some time to delete the net gateway.
Once the Nat Gateway is deleted, you make sure you go to elastic IP section.
And you have to say release elastic IP address.
But that's going to not be you know, that's not going to be working right now because it's already
attached to Nat Gateway and you'll get an error.
By the time you can delete your bastion.
Host.
If you also wish to terminate your instance, you can.
If you have the source code in our repository.
So in our repository you can really access it from GitHub also.
So we have the branch Ansible hyphen VPC.
Check out this branch and you should see all the code that we have used in this project.
Use it as a reference.
It's better you write the code by yourself, step by step.
Everything.
But still all the information is available.
The VPC setup playbook is there.
The Bastion instance.
Variables.
And feel free to change the value of variables as per your wish.
As per your region, you want to use as per the zone that you want to use.
Okay.
So as we're talking, this Nat Gateway is also deleted.
And now I should be able to release the elastic IP or it takes still some time.
Yeah, it's done.
If you're getting an error.
Elastic grip is already attached, so wait for a few minutes.
It will release the elastic IP from the nat Gateway and then you can release the elastic IP back to
the pool if you wish to keep other things like VPC subnets routable, you can keep that.
And anyways, you have the code, you can launch NAT gateways and all the things whenever you want.
All right then.
Then let's wrap up this project video with the architectural design that we have seen.
So we created the playbook which access the variables, and we have specified the list of modules.
It used Python bottle.
If you remember, we installed the bottle library.
We make API connection to a cloud or account by using the IM roles.
We created the VPC.
In three zones we created.
In the diagram, you have just two zones.
Public subnet.
With internet gateway and round table connection.
We created private subnets with Nat Gateway and out table connection.
And of course, the Bastion host we also created Keep It and Security Group for the Bastion host And
then we launch the instance in the security group.
So that will be all in this project.
I hope you have learned a lot.
Thank you very much for watching this.
I will see you in the next one.