Welcome to the Project Cloud State with TerraForm is the name of this project.
And yes, state, not automation.
Yes, of course we automate cloud setup with TerraForm, but it's more about maintaining the state of
your cloud infrastructure.
All right.
So let's say you have a cloud management team and they are in charge of deploying setup and managing
the infrastructure on the cloud and also very heavy usage of cloud services.
Now, of course, then there will be regular provisioning requests and regular changes, regular deployments.
So if you have the heavy usage of cloud services and a very regular usage, then you should also get
into some problems.
When we talk about infrastructure, there are so many things and setting up an entire infrastructure
is a complex process.
This network does security, there's operating systems, the storage load balancers, etc., etc..
One time infrastructure setup is fine, but if you want to do it multiple times, doing the same thing
is not repeatable.
Or maybe similar infrastructure for dev staging productions and also multiple projects.
So manually, if you're doing that, it's not repeatable.
Also, it will be very difficult to track like who made the change when the change was made.
You try to make documents of the infrastructure like inventory, but that's time consuming process and
that should happen because if the infrastructure state is not centralized.
Also, there'll be huge chance of making human errors and these things can lead to non-functional infrastructure
or bugs errors or even exposed infrastructure in such a huge environment.
Doing all those things will take a lot of time.
All right.
So these are some problems, common problems.
There could be more.
Let's look at the solution.
You need to have configuration management of the infrastructure.
Like at a centralized place.
And you need to have everything automated, of course, so there's less chance of making human error.
And always you should be maintaining a centralized state of the infrastructure.
So all the configuration of your infrastructure is maintained at a centralized place and we can automatically
deploy the changes.
Any change management can be triggered very easily and we can avoid the human errors.
Your infrastructure should be in files or in code so you can version control it.
You have infrastructure as a code and you should have a repeatable infrastructure as a code.
So you should not hard code values also, then it should be reusable across different environments like
def queue, staging production or even across different projects should also have a reusable code.
Cloud automation adds lots of business value.
And here are some statistics.
71% of the company says they have seen 10% of revenue growth.
84% have lowered their operations cost.
81% have become more innovative.
When you automate infrastructure, you save a lot of time.
You can invest that time in learning and adapting new technologies in your projects, which can add
more business value.
And of course, you become more agile.
So 84% have become more agile quickly.
They can deploy changes as per the requirements, and I think infrastructure was never so easy.
Infrastructure has really become a code now, and we'll see how we're going to do that.
So we are going to use TerraForm and enable a cloud computing platform so we can set up a complete infrastructure
on a cloud by using TerraForm.
Not only set up, you're going to see how we're going to maintain its status.
So any change, how we can very easily deploy to our infrastructure.
Okay, so here are the things.
Four steps that we're going to do.
We're going to set up TerraForm with back and forth.
So we have a centralized state of terraform or of a cloud infrastructure.
Then we are going to set up VPC.
With that gateway Internet gateway subnet so we can have a secure and highly available VPC set up with
TerraForm.
Will also provision beans, tech, environment with TerraForm and also the backend services that we're
going to use.
Ideas elastic cash and active MQ.
And also along with that, we have security groups, Key Bastion hosts and few other things that you're
going to automate and maintain with TerraForm.
Okay, so let's do this.
But one thing keep in mind, it's not about just automation.
It's not about just the speed now.
It's also about maintaining the state, having the state of your infrastructure in a file.
That's pretty awesome.
And obviously then when you have state, you can very easily make changes, the differential changes.
So let's see the architecture of the project.
Okay, so this is the architecture.
We're going to have TerraForm on our local machine and we're going to store the state, the information
about our infrastructure in an S3 bucket, which will be obviously in our cloud account.
We'll also configure TerraForm with the proper authentication.
We're going to use then TerraForm to access our cloud services and create a VPC, a VPC that is distributed
among multiple zones.
Or should I say its subnets distributed among multiple zones.
So we'll have public subnet distributed among multiple zones connected to an Internet gateway with our
route table.
So we're going to set up route table and route the traffic to the Internet gateway.
We'll also have private subnet again distributed among multiple zones.
In our private subnet, we're going to set up services like ESI, two instances, my SQL database or
elastic cache.
Of course, this private subnet will be connected to a NAT gateway through a route table.
And to access this entire VPC.
Or should I say, to access a private systems in your private subnet?
We are also going to have a bastion host, so we'll even provision bastion host from our TerraForm Scripts.
So once we have our VPC created, then we're going to create our infrastructure on that.
Or should I say layout or stack?
Which we'll see in the next architectural diagram.
Once we have our VPC set up, we are going to create our stack the services that we need to set up our
stack.
We're using TerraForm again and obviously we are going to maintain the state in the S3 bucket as you
have seen the previous design as well.
So TerraForm is going to set up IDs instance in private subnet, elastic cache in private subnet, again
Amazon MQ again in private subnet in the VPC and bean stack, where the load balancer of the bean stack
will be in the public subnet and the instances will be in the private subnets to access our infrastructure
will also take care of the security group and the rules and also log in key if we need to log into our
ec2 instances which are part of our bean stack.
But we don't need to create it in multiple steps as we did it in Ansible project.
We did first thing, then we did second thing.
Yes, we could have done all the things together in Ansible as well, but the complexity is too much
there.
So we divide it into multiple phases.
But in TerraForm it's going to be much easier to automate these things.
Also, it's not just about automation, it's also about maintaining the state of the infrastructure,
as I keep repeating that.
So there are no varieties of tools in the market to automate cloud computing tasks, but I think in
today's market, TerraForm is one of the best cloud automation tool.
Also, if you have used cloud formation, you know it will be similar.
But cloud formation is very specific for us.
But you can use TerraForm to do other things as well.
You can use other cloud providers and there are other kinds of automation that it supports.
So let's get started now.