First, we'll create a repository on GitHub and will make sure every code change that we make, we are
committing it and we are keeping track of every change.
So I will create a repository in my GitHub account.
I will name the repository as TerraForm.
Hyphen.
E.
W s hyphen v profile.
In order to keep it safe.
You can make it private, but I'm keeping it public.
But remember, you have to make it private, because if you accidentally put the access key and secret
key, then you will not be exposed.
I'm going to keep it public because I am not going to store any access key over there.
Will later create the get ignored file as well.
Not now.
So the first let's create the repository.
Okay, let's get.
The other and we'll open our intelligence and we'll code by using intelligence.
If you wish to use your own ID or VIM ed, your choice.
I'm going to use intelligence and I'm going to create a new project from a vision control.
So we'll give our what'll.
And select a location where you want to store your repository.
I'm good with that.
After five.
You wanted in this window itself.
Let's make little change in the RMD file.
Called us to form code for V Profile project.
This should be fine.
Let's save and commit this.
To control key to commit control shift key to push it to our version control remote repository.
Install and set up terraform on your machine.
If you have not done it, then go to the TerraForm.
Introductory video where I have explained how to set up TerraForm and also likely do not store your
credentials in the source code.
Do use, configure and set your access key and secret key.
I already have TerraForm installed or Fusion TerraForm.
Zero dot 13.2.
Anything older than this.
I do not recommend any older version of TerraForm will not have the right syntax for the variables what
we are showing in the project video.
So I installed TerraForm with Jocko installed TerraForm Command.
You can also do that in Windows Machine.
In macOS you use Blue kiosk, install TerraForm and set up your credentials.
If we have this, we can do our next thing.