We'll create a file.
Call us back and.
S 3.2.
Added to the gate?
Yes.
In this file, we mention the S3 bucket where we're going to store the state of our terraform of our
cloud infrastructure.
So as we're going to maintain our state back and state in three buckets, so let's create a three bucket.
Let's go to a three.
And I'm going to create a bucket named as Terra form.
Or I'll just say Terra.
For the wi fi hyphen state and I'll give some number just to make it unique.
Okay.
I'm going to use the region.
Ohio.
US East.
You can wish any Univision choose any region, but make sure it has minimum three zones, because we're
going to create VPC zones into three three zones, three subnets into three different zones.
So I'll select Ohio.
There.
Let's get into our pocket and let's create a directory of folder.
We'll name it as just terraform.
We'll put this information.
In their back end.
State files a form.
Backend is a three.
Now TerraForm supports multiple backend services like you can also use console if you want.
So we're going with SX three, that's our bucket name.
So mention your bucket name, water bucket.
You created key the directory that you created in that S3 bucket and a file name which will maintain
the state region.
I'm using us east to Ohio.
Feel free to use any other region if you want.
With that, we'll first initialize.
To reform.
So we have to just say terraform it.
Let's open our git bash, which is pretty easy to use.
Okay, so I'm in the directory where we are creating our TerraForm scripts.
I'm going to say TerraForm in it.
I had deleted the user.
So I have set the access key once again and I'm doing TerraForm in it.
OC successfully configured the back end SX three.