Next, we'll create the providers file.
Remember.
And don't ask me.
Okay, so provider obviously has a region.
Var dot.
Underscore region, which is a variable.
I'll just keep it as just region.
So variable and we are going to create a variables file where we'll declare all our variables.
So let's create var start tf.
First, let's put the region variable US east to region.
We're using a underscore region will name it as a US underscore region in the providers file.
Make sure you're referring to the same name of the variable I have used underscore region and the same
variable I have defined.
Next, we'll define variable for our AMIS.
So based on the region, it will pick up the right AMIS map variable.
And this army is going to be for the Bastion host.
We're going to launch also bastion host in our public subnet of our VPC.
So based on what region we define, we have given three region you can give all the regions that you
use.
So we're going with Ubuntu.
Let's update that Amis.
Let's go to launch instance.
That's fine.
Ubuntu 21 to 20 should be good.
So let's pick up that.
Okay.
Other images.
I'm not updating.
I'm just keeping it for dummy because anyways, I'm going to use the same region.
This region, if I change to other region, I'll give it us East one.
Yeah.
Or about one or whatever region I'm using, then my code will fail because these are just dummy values.
But you find the right ID and put it into your variable.
Okay, we'll define other variable we're going to create of keys.
So we'll create variable names for them.
Private key part, Public key part.
And also the username.
So we'll create variable private underscore key underscore part its value we profile key.
So now we we're going to create key.
After this, we'll make sure we create the key with this name, the current directory and user we're
using open to because this is open to.
So when the Bastion host gets created, we are going to provision it with few commands.
For that, we're going to use this key to log in private key file to login.
Public key file will be used when we're launching the instance or creating the key pair and also username
it will use.
And this key to login, we'll be also creating security group for our Bastion host.
So we'll give a variable for my IP.
So my IP variable there, which we'll be using in our security group Ingress rule.
We are also going to set up.
Amazon active MQ, which will be a replacement for a rabbit MQ.
So when we create a last or active MQ, we need to provide the username and password and these will
define it as variable.
So our MQ user and our MQ pass.
You can wish and change a different password.
But make sure it's it's longer, more than 12 characters.
I'm going to make it much more bigger.
This is fine.
So we also create ideas.
And we'll have database username and password, which we're also going to use to log into our instance
and provision it with our schemas.
So we need the database username and password.
And again, we'll put them as variables so db pos variable and DB name variable.
And of course also we need to give the DB user variable.
So DB user variable, DB pass and DB name.
So account's going to be our database name for our V profile project.
One more variable instance count.
So if you want to launch any number of instances, we can just update this number and we can have many
instances.
We don't need to make change in our code.
VPC we are going to create.
So VPC, name and VPC name will name it as we profile hyphen VPC.
We're going to create six subnets in three different zones, three public subnet and three private subnets.
So we're going to give the zone name.
So zone want us east to a zone two us is to be zone three US east to sea.
So three zones there.
Idea.
We'll keep it as one 72.20 1.0.0 last 16.
And in this, we're going to create we're going to slice it with three public and three private subnets
or total six subnets.
So we'll give their range as well.
Okay, so public subnet one CIDR.
Public subnet two CIDR Public subnet three CIDR public subnet sorry Private subnet one CIDR And it's
just in a same order.
1.02.03.04.0.
Then private subnet 35.0 sorry two.
Private subnet 25.0.
Private subnet 36.022.
So total six subnet in the VPC and we are not going to mention the CIDR in the script.
We are going to put everything as variable.
It may take initially a lot of time to declare variables for you and could be cumbersome, but it's
going to save you a lot of time later.
Most importantly, it will make your code reusable so you can just you can use the same code for a different
project.
You just change the value of the variables based on the requirement, like name of the VPC, CIDR range,
key login key zones, regions, database usernames and password.
You can change them, tweak them and use it for the other project.
Okay.
Intel AG is saying that it supports plugins for dot file.
Let's say install plugin.
Let's try that.
Okay.
And we getting nice logos also there right in that TerraForm logo and it's going to read our code properly
now.
Proper formatting.
This is good.