Okay.
Once we have variable declared, let's set things in the same order.
Key.
Let's generate the key.
As such hyphen kitchen.
And I have to make sure I'm going to give it with this name or else I'm going to change the name in
the variable section.
Oops.
Just as he Jen I can give hyphen f just I'll just hit enter and now I will paste the name u profile
key.
And so I should have a private key and a public key with that name.
Let's match it.
Now we prove that the private can that's the public key, can see the keys over there.
But you really don't need to see the key.
It's fine.
Now, this is to create the key pair.
So let's first create the key pair.
How about that?
So let's create a new file to create a key pair.
I like distributing my resources into different, different file.
It makes it more readable, more accessible.
Right.
We can put everything in one file, all our code in one file, but it becomes difficult, cumbersome
to manage also.
So key.
Maybe just one single resource, but.
Distributing into different files makes more manageable because it keeps peers active.
So we have the TerraForm plugin install entirely.
And let's see its benefits now.
You see, I just type out s and I can hit tab and will complete the rest then.
What resource do you want to use?
It's already highlighting as s underscore key underscore pair.
Yeah.
And name of your resource V Profile key.
That was pretty convenient, right?
Also, key name.
And we can give you a key name.
We profile key.
So key will get created with this name on the plus account.
Public key.
We are not giving the content.
We are giving the function file.
And we're going to give that dot see that it's even highlighting or showing us our variable.
Public key part.
Yeah, in seconds.
I have written that.
So it's.
It's very easy, very convenient.
Okay, let's commit this.
And will give it a key.
Pierce.
Commit.
Message, commit.
Okay.
It's saying there's no error, but there is a warning.
Would you like to review that?
Let's see.
Court analysis.
It's giving some warning in voir dire for let's check it by number six and ten II number six.
That warning is, I think, for the backward compatibility.
We can pass any argument or we can pass a string or list that should not be any problem.
Let's save this anyways and let's format it to see if it can fix.
Commit.
Let's push it.
Okay, let's try and execute that.
Faust will run TerraForm.
In it.
So install plugins, then we'll set TerraForm validate.
It's a success.
Let's try now.
TerraForm.
Format if that fixed that code analysis.
And didn't do anything in the vase, but it make changes in back end and keep SDF.
Basically it aligned everything properly.
Okay, that is good.
Let's also apply our state first, let's say plan.
You can check if you have any conflicting things we don't have.
We profile hyphen keys.
There were keys there, but still deleted because we don't need it anyways.
And now let's apply it.
Yes.
So that you'd have created the key.
Everything is validated.
Now let's begin writing code for VPC.