Now we can write VPC code as normally fetching the resource from the documentation, mentioning VPC
details, subnet details, route tables, NAT Gateway, Internet Gateway.
We can write all the resources one by one and plug in, connect all them together.
Also, there's one very easy way you can use TerraForm Registry and you can find modules.
Modules are readymade packages if you want to set up VPC, complete VPC with Internet Gateway, routable
subnets, Internet Gateway, all of that, it can be done very easily.
So you can come to the TerraForm Registry and you can search for a module like we want to set up VPC
so we can search VPC.
That's search.
So it's in this house and this is official that is called as official.
It's official module repository.
You have their VPC and you have for security group, also X ideas and many more.
So let's select this VPC.
So how to use this?
There'll be some information about what all you can do with this module.
But the easiest way is to check the examples.
Example Complete VPC.
Okay, let's check that.
And there will be a GitHub link with example.
So let's click on that.
So here you have complete VPC and this main dot of output.
Dot.
Let's see.
Main dot.
Okay, so you have to mention provider, which we already have mentioned.
Security group.
You can create like this by giving an VPC ID.
The BBC that we're going to create from module but.
Then we have the actual module thing.
So module.
VPC.
And then in this you can mention name of VPC CIDR availability zones in a list format.
So all the availability zones, private subnets, public subnets, or you can create other subnets,
for example, like this.
If you want to enable DNS hostname if you want to have a nat gateway.
Our VP in Gateway DSP Options set.
And evil is three end point.
And so all those options are there.
You just have to give the values and your VPC will be created.
All right.
And we're going to use this way to create VPC.
And this is these are through modules.
So when you do when you mention this and when you run TerraForm in it, it will download these modules.
So let's go to our ID and let's create a new file.
We'll say VPC, dot, d, F.
So I'm going to say module.
In double quotes.
I'll give the model name.
VPC.
The important part is this.
Source.
Equal to.
Okay.
So that's the part we are saying, you know, download it from here.
There's a VPC section.
So that's going to be the source, but it's not yet available locally.
So ID is also Intel is also giving us, you know, the error.
I can't locate this module locally.
But when we say terraform in it, all these modules will be downloaded.
So let's give other details.
Name and CIDR that we are taking from the variables file, which we have already defined.
BBC name.
And the basic idea.
Availability zones is.
Private subnet list.
Public service list.
We also need an ad gateway so you will not get with true.
But if you have multiple subnets so it will create multiple NAD gateway, that could be very expensive
for our exercise.
So we'll just say single net gateway.
Also enabling DNS host names and DNS support.
And also, let's give some tag.
So that's those tags are really very general properties or attribute, but we can also have VPC tags.
Right.
Okay.
So that simple code that is like, what, 22 lines of code that will create our entire VPC stack with
three public subnets, three private subnet, three public subnet distributed in three different zones.
Also having the NAT gateway.
An internet gateway will anyways get created because we have the public subnet.
We have not.
We are not mentioning the drought tables.
It will also create route tables automatically and link our subnets as well.
Let's commit this.
We can ignore that.
Let's commit.
Control shift key.
Let's push.
And let's test it.
So we have included a new module, so we have to set TerraForm in it.
So you see it's downloading.
And it's keeping it in this location.
Okay, so we have the modules.
Let's check in our ID.
You see that that warning is gone now?
Yeah.
You know, let's now test something, right?
Let's say enable.
I would like to enable the three end point if you want.
Okay.
It's just showing you an option.
You see now it's clearly showing you right now if you want to already highlight all the things, you
know, just type there, you know, initially model VPC, give the curly braces and run terraform in
it.
So, you know, you can easily find all the options.
You don't need to go through the documentation also.
Time to test.
TerraForm validate.
That's a success TerraForm format.
TerraForm Plan.
Okay, So with that 22 line of code, it's going to add 20 resources.
That's amazing.
Fine.
I'm going to set TerraForm apply to set up my entire VPC now.
Right.
So it's creating elastic IP, VPC, elastic IP attaching to the nat Gateway.
Roundtable subnets associating roundtable with the subnets.
Okay.
Now, Gateway, that's going to take some time.
Okay, that is done.
We can check it in our account plus account.
Let's go to VPC.
We should see the VPC.
There we profile VPC subnets.
We see all our subnets, public and private subnets round table, of course.
My private round table.
You have the routing, tree routing to the Internet gateway.
Now, that's default.
Wait.
Yeah, that one.
Yeah.
And that's private.
Can see the subnet association.
Right.
All that we just 22 line of code.
All right.
That's brilliant.
Okay, now we have the VP running.
Now we can set up our stack, but we also need to have security group.
So we need we're going to set up backend services as we discussed in architectural design ideas, active
queue, elastic cache.
Front end.
We're going to use beans tax.
We need security group for beans stack and back in services security group.
We'll have load balancer we need load balancer security group also the bastion host not to mention we
are going going to create bastion Host so we are going to need security group for the bastion host as
well.