So let's create.
Resources for the security group.
So name it as crap.
Dot tx f.
Okay, so resource.
Underscore security group.
And the name forced the security group for being stack load balancer.
I'll keep that name.
Okay.
Name will be this description.
Some description you can give.
Now security group has to be part of a VPC, so we have to give the VPC ID, VPC ID.
Our VPC is created by module.
And so its path is module dot VPC.
And we need the ID of the VPC, but we don't know as long as it doesn't return the value.
So what could be the attribute or the data source?
We can find the output from the module documentation itself.
You can see output.
So these are the things that it returns like aces and so many other things, so we can just search for
it.
It would be a lot of IDs.
I think we with VPC underscore ID.
So this description, the idea of the VPC are default VPC ID.
So we have two things VPC underscore ID or default, underscore VP, underscore ID.
We can use both.
But we just need to use any one.
So we'll just go with VPC underscore ID.
So I'll say module dart, vpc, dart VPC, underscore ID.
Okay, so we have a grace rule.
Right.
So I'm just, you know, just typing and hitting tab.
That's it.
It's just completing.
Yeah.
So outbound rule.
I'm going to say protocol.
When you say minus one, it means all the protocol and.
I'm going to give the CIDR block.
0.0.0.
0.0.0.0.
Slash zero.
So I'm saying all the outbound traffic is allowed to go anywhere in Greece.
This is the load balancer security group.
So and we're going to allow the connection on 80.
80.
And the protocol.
I'm going to use a TCP CIDR block.
So inbound traffic, 80 allowed from anywhere.
Okay.
That should be two rules.
Inbound and outbound.
Now security group for the Bastion host We are also going to launch a bastion host.
So the resource.
Head of the security group.
Let's give a name.
That is the name I'm giving the profile.
Hyphen Bastion hyphen Security Group.
Name of the security group.
Some description.
And it belongs to this particular VPC ID.
Okay.
This is a new is going to return a string.
I need to remove these double codes.
Of course.
Yeah, that is right.
Yeah.
So it was not highlighting because there was double quotes.
Right.
So we can just say module dot the VPC dot and you can list all the attributes, all the output here
itself.
You don't even need to go the documentation VPC, ID.
Okay.
So the ingress and ingress rule.
Outbound again, traffic allow for all protocol to go anywhere.
Ingress.
So this security group for Bastion hosts, we have to be very careful in ingress.
Right.
I'm only going to allow 22.
PCP.
Only from my IP, and I have already declared variable for my IP and I'm going to use that var dot my
IP.
So to security group down there.
Load balancer security group Bastion host security group now security group for our EC2 instance, which
will be part of our bienstock environment.
We'll create security group for that.
Now, yes, I know if you're thinking that when we create bienstock, it will create its own security
group.
Yes, that's true.
But you know, it allows 22 from anywhere.
Plus we have to check then all the information from the output.
Right.
How about like we have a complete control over it?
Yes.
And I think you should have as much as control on the security as you have on the infrastructure.
Okay, let's create then security group, for instance, in our bienstock environment.
Okay, Again, I'm saying egress, outbound rule.
All traffic can go anywhere.
I'm going to give now in grace rule.
And I would like to do a search to this beanstalk instance, but this will be part of private subnet,
so we cannot access it from the public network.
We can access it from the Bastion.
Host.
Bastion host will be the part of the security group that we just created over here, this and this resource
block.
So 22 allowed from my IP, we can do access to the Bastion host and from there we'll do a search to.
Instance, which is in the beanstalk.
So I have I'm going to give the rule in ingress.
Put 22.
And I want the access from the beans from from the Bastion host security group.
So I'm going to say security groups.
So I need to give ID from here.
A underscore Security group dot v Profile hyphen chain hyphen g.
Group dot E profile.
Hyphen.
Bastion hyphen 6.1..
Dot ID?
Yes.
So only the private connection gets it done.
Only the private connection from the Bastion host security group is allowed to the security group on
Port 22.
So we're keeping tight control on the security groups.
Okay.
One last security group for back end services ideas Elastic cash active MQ.
New security group.
It should be good.
That name we profile happened back in hyphen SG.
That's name.
I'll give some description.
There's a security group for IDS, active MQ and elastic cache.
And it belongs to the VPC.
ID just copy it from here.
You know, it's really, really sometimes faster to type by using this TerraForm plugins than copy pasting.
Outbound rule.
Should be fine.
Inbound rule, though.
So I'm going to see all the port, all the protocol allowed from the security group.
So the beanstalk instance is going to access these backend services.
So we are going to see a security group dot.
V profile Prot sg.
That one.
Dot ID.
That is the security group of our being stag instance.
Okay, so we're done creating all the security groups resources, but these instances, ideas, active
and elastic, they'll be interacting with each other.
So I want to allow all traffic from its own security group ID, but if it's not created, we can't give
the security group ID, but we have another resource to do that.
And the resources security group underscore rule so we can update.
The security group rule with this resource.
So a type ingress I'm updating the ingress rule of.
The security group, Baghdad Security group from two all poured some 0 to 65005 35.
All the ports TCP ports security group ID the security.
The idea of the security group that you want to update that you want to add the rules.
Source security group ID from which security group ID you want to allow the connection.
So again, same security group ID So I want to allow all connection to its own security group ID and
that's it.
I think that should be the toughest part in this entire stack because this, like so many port numbers,
protocol, ingress, egress.
Right.
But if you have experience setting up this stack manually, as we did in the project ID plus refactoring,
so you should be able to follow it very well.
It's the same thing, what are doing.
But we are automating and we are maintaining everything through a file state file.
Let's commit it.
And if you're going to see a security group, I'm trying to keep the commit messages very small just
to save some time.
But now you should have better commit messages.
Okay.
Let's test it.
First we're going to say TerraForm Validate, or did we include a new module?
We did not, but let's just see TerraForm in it.
Okay, this is good.
It's just using existing things.
So terraform a validate, which will validate our syntax.
So that X is coming because I'm just using the tab.
Right.
But it's not required that a form format.
Yes, all the security group should be formatted very well now.
All the rules, equal tools, everything.
Please, properly.
This is good.
Okay.
When that happens, I would like to also committed.
Yeah.
Good.
TerraForm Plan.
So we already have the VPC, so it's just refreshing.
It's checking.
Is the VPC in the same state as defined in our resources file?
If it's same, it's not going to do anything to the VPC or any resources to it.
Refreshing.
Seems everything nice.
But five things to be added, and those five things are of security group.
For security group and one update on the security group.
Yeah, we are good with this TerraForm apply.
I'm going to say yes.
That is done.