All right.
So we have security group ready now.
It's time to set up our back end services ideas.
Elastic cache Active MQ.
So let's create a new file.
Mm.
Back and hyphen services.
Dr..
Okay ideas.
We also need to create ideas.
DB Subnet Group.
DB Subnet group is simply collection of the subnets.
So we'll use the resource.
So the underscore db underscore subnet group that is the resource.
And let's give a name of proof.
We proof.
We profile hyphen, rdx, hyphen, subgroup.
Subnets are subnet, i.e. the list of subnet ID.
Let's give a name also to it.
I'll give a name as.
I just simply mean.
List of subnet IDs.
So.
Subnet is created through the VPC.
So we have module dot, VPC, dot.
This should be private.
Let's see this list.
Private subnet ID.
There is no ID, but this private subnet there.
Private subnets subnet.
So that is supposed to be a list.
So the first element in the list will get the first private subnet ID from there.
Comma.
Module.
Dot VPC.
Dr. Private subnets.
One.
Module.
Okay, so three private subnet IDs.
Our ideas will be in this subnet group, which is part of three subnet ID or collection of three subnet
ID.
That should be it.
Let's give some tags.
This is fine.
Okay, before we write the results for the ideas, we have also elastic cash and elastic cash.
Also, there is a subnet group.
Resource.
E w.
S underscore elastic.
Cash is elastic.
Cash.
Elastic cash.
Subnet group.
In the resources we profile have an e cache fund subgroup.
Name.
Seem subnet IDs will take the same ones we did over here.
Okay, so tag, that should be fine.
So our subnet glue for ideas and a subnet group for elastic cache.
Now let's create our ideas.
So resource e.
W.
S.
Underscore d.
B.
Underscore instance.
And you limit us.
We profile hyphen radius.
Now these are the options attributes I'm going to use allocated storage 20 GB storage type GB two engine.
My SQL engine version 5.6.34.
Instance class DB2 micro.
Be careful at this part.
Name.
That dot db name.
This variable we have defined in the variables file.
And their variables file.
That DB name, DB user and DB pass.
Yeah.
So user name and password.
Parameter group name have taken the default parameter group multi.
I'm saying false, but if you want high availability then make sure you do.
True.
So you'll have one primary, one secondary public accessibility.
No, we don't want public accessibility.
So false because Beanstalk instance is going to access this IDs so we don't need to make it publicly
accessible.
This option will save you some money when you're practicing.
Skip Final snapshot.
True.
When you practice rides.
Now, I learned that hard way when I was doing TerraForm.
I was learning TerraForm and I was experimenting with ideas.
So I end up having a lot of snapshots because when it was deleting the snare ideas, it was keeping
the snapshot.
And I did it like many times.
So I had like many, many snapshots.
So keep this option true.
So it will also delete the snapshot.
It will not take the snapshot when the IDs is getting deleted.
This is good for learning purpose when you're experimenting, but really not good for production use
case.
You should have a snapshot if you're deleting any idea.
So in case you want to recover, you can recover from that.
The DB subnet group.
So the DB subnet group that we created previously.
There.
So you have to give a dot name, not the ID db subnet group name, that's the attribute.
So to give the name of the DB subnet group, not its ID VPC, it's part of our VPC VPC security group.
And so we already have created VPC Security Group.
They're right.
Security Group V Profile hyphen Backend hyphen s G.
Okay, so that was about ideas.
Now, elastic cache.
So the resource name is E.
S underscore Elastic cash.
Elastic cash.
Underscore cluster, but really will not have really a cluster, just one single node.
We're going to do name it as V profile hyphen cache.
Let's give the same name for the cluster.
Right.
We profile hyphen cache.
Engine, so it supports mem cache and will have mem cache.
And.
Okay.
No type casualty to micro number of caching node one.
Make sure you give this one, otherwise you'll have multiples.
Parameter group name is the default parameter group.
You can find that from a plus documentation.
Port number 11211.
Security Group ID.
The security group that you already created, you profile back end g same we have given for the IDS
subnet group name again name not the ID.
So the subnet group that we created for elastic cache.
That's pretty long path, right?
But now at least you don't have to type it.
You can just type and, you know, it's just going to complete the rest of it.
Okay.
Now.
Active mq so the resource is.
Underscore m q underscore broker.
Wow.
That has given like all the options.
Nice.
You know, Yes.
I sometimes say it's easier than, you know, copy paste.
Okay, so the broker name, That's the broker name I'm giving.
Same as the resource name.
Engine type active MQ.
Engine version 5.15 point zero.
Host instance type mkt TX two dot Micro Security Group again the back end security group Subnet ID.
Now we don't have the subnet group concept over here.
We just have to give the subnet IDs.
So subnet IDs, it's a list so you can give we just creating one single instance, not a cluster.
So one subnet id should be fine and private subnet ID of course.
Username and password.
The user that you want to create value rabbit MQ user that is again coming from.
The variables Rabbit, MQ, user rabbit, rabbit and queue password.
This is the password.
All right.
So when you're building your application, you know you have access to the variables file, right?
Application properties, file for a V profile.
You can update with all these details.
I think we are good with the back end.
Let's commit it back end services.
And I would also like to push it now.