Okay.
The final thing, Bienstock.
So we'll create a file, actually.
We're going to create two files.
One is for the application, and then inside that, we create the environment.
Creating application means is just.
Just give the name the name of the project.
Right?
So I will just see Bean hyphen app dot TX.
Just click the application.
So resource underscore.
Elastic.
Underscore.
Beanstalk application.
Yes.
And that's all.
We will just give the name.
And that should be fine.
Save it committed.
Being app.
Okay.
Let's create another file for the environment.
Details.
Name.
It has been hyphen e and v.
Dot t.
F.
Okay.
So for this particular resource, we're going to use a plus underscore elastic beans tag, not application.
Environment.
Name we profile being proud and I'm going to use a similar name for the resource also.
Application.
It's going to be part of the application that we are creating from here.
So let's say elastic beans, Tag application.
Yes.
Dot V profile.
That's fine.
Okay.
Now, there's really lots of options in beans, Jack.
And for this, I want you to take you to the tour of the documentation.
So let's go to the farm registry and we will search for being stuck.
Bienstock environment.
Yes, at one.
And so you have some quick examples.
Name application.
That's the application you already given that solution Stack Name the platform which you want to go
with.
So we really want to go with the Tomcat platform.
You can check that from the documentation as well.
But few other things.
Let's see on a name we can give application we have even seen in prefix, right?
We want to give a particular URL for our load balancer.
We can use that description tier, but do you see there not many.
Actually, most of the settings will be coming from this one setting option setting to configure the
new environment.
Like we want to give application load, balancer, security group or number of instances in our auto
scaling, our sticky sessions and all those a lot of settings right in the stack that is going to be
coming part of this settings option setting so we can see in detail.
So we are to see like setting and we calibrate and inside that we can give these things namespace.
Name value namespace is going to be the urn.
Like for example you can see here setting namespace.
So being stack should be part of our VPC, right?
So namespace plus e to vpc, vpc id hide name.
And the value.
Like that.
You can keep giving all the settings.
You can have like a number of setting blocks like this as per the settings that you need.
So these are just the sample, two samples of the settings, but there are so many settings in the beans
stack, they are not listed over here.
The namespace and what should we give the name and the value?
It's not listed over here that you have to check from the docs.
Okay.
So you can call for all those settings like we're talking about VPC, right?
So namespace equal to a colon ec2 two colon vpc.
Night like that.
And the name.
Which name you want.
VPC ID value.
Value of the VPC ID, right.
Similar to that like name subnets or what?
All you can specify in a VPC subnets LP subnets you have you'll be scheme TB subnets.
A lot of options you have there and you can give it value.
Right.
So you can check all the namespace you want to modify.
You want to provide values to cloud watch logs.
You'll be load balancer which load balancer you want.
Load balancer details.
Right.
Load balancer, port port number, Right load balancer.
If you see load balancer.
Right.
So do you on cross zone you what security group we have.
We already created security group for load balancer.
So we're going to use that at setting namespace load balancer and then security group and then the value
of this security group that we created, what else we have.
These are deprecated things load balancer, port numbers and all listener.
So let's see if we have sticky session here.
Policy name.
You should find four sticky session sticky.
Stickiness enable This is this belongs to its setting process elastic beanstalk environment process
default.
Yeah.
So I can give that namespace equal to this.
And then name stickiness enabled.
It is value by default is false.
We can change it to true.
Yeah.
Okay, coming back to this registry again.
So we need to provide a few more details.
Let's go to our code.
The solution stack name.
That is one important thing.
And so here the example is given 64 bit.
What's this for?
Go platform.
We need Tomcat platform.
How do we find out what name to give?
And let's check the arguments Solution Stack name Amazon API documentations.
It's listed here.
Supported platform and we have Tomcat.
Tomcat.
Okay.
So these are the values that we can use with use.
We can just copy it.
All right.
So we'll go with.
Tomcat 8.5 should be fine.
So most of them are 8.5.
So if we have to use this name 64 bit Amazon Linux for blah blah, blah.
Yeah, like that.
So you can copy whatever you need and you can put it there in the solution stack name.
Let's go to our ID C solution Stack solution stack name.
And I need that one.
Yeah.
Nothing so special about this.
Just the default one.
Okay.
See name prefix the URL.
So I'll see that we profile haven't been hyphen praat hyphen domain.
If that's not available, we'll get error also while we're creating it.
Now let's start giving the settings.
Settings.
That's awesome.
It gives everything right?
Name namespace value.
So name I want eaw s colon e c to colon VPC.
I want to put this into my VPC that I created.
Oh, that should go in the namespace.
It should put that first.
Really?
This goes in the namespace name.
So I need the vpc.
I t all this you can find from the documentation again.
Write a list called an Easy to Colon VPC, VPC ID, and then the value of VPC ID.
So knocking double codes, we have the module dot VPC.
Dot City.
Okay.
Like that.
I'll put all the settings that I need for my bean stack environment.
Okay.
One setting is to create the instance role elastic beanstalk role.
Associate public IP address that is also in the VPC.
Next setting is for the subnets.
I want to put all the instances in the private subnet, so again, I can use the VPC namespace subnets
from that.
And here I'm using a joint function from TerraForm.
TerraForm has some nice functions.
Join is one function that can join a list into a string.
So I have list of subnets over here and which is going to return actually.
The name of the subnets and I want to have that comma separated.
Get in in the form of strings.
So I'm joining all that.
Subnet one subnet to subnet three with a join function.
Separated by comma.
So you can check the TerraForm Function's documentation.
There's so many functions that TerraForm provides like string, function, chomp, join.
We're using, join, join, simply joins.
A list separate by comma.
So in this case, I wanted the subnet names separated by a comma.
So that's why I'm using the join function, because this is going to return me the list.
And here the value is a string, not a list subnets here.
Value is a string, not a list.
So but we have the list.
So we're going to convert that list to a string with join function.
So you want to do add some programming intelligence like that.
You can check the functions of terraform.
There's so many functions replace split if you have done ever python programming, you know this almost
similar or even Ruby scripting, then you have almost similar functions there as well.
Okay.
Elastic load balancers or instances will be in private subnet but are load balancer will be in public
subnet.
Can load balancer of a pin stack which should be in public subnet.
So similar thing name you'll be subnet for this the value should be list of public subnet not sorry
not list string separated by comma.
And so this returns me a list.
Again, I'm using join function to separate that by comma.
And so this entire list will be converted to a string.
Auto scaling launch configuration.
I want to select instance type as TX two Micro key pair.
I want to attach the key pair, the key pair that we created over here.
Right.
Eight plus key pair V profile key.
Keypad.
Dot v Profile Key.
Dot Key Name.
That's it's going to use this key that is created for our Beanstalk instance auto scaling group.
I want it to be launching in any available I will say any three if we have three subnets.
Right.
So launch it in three subnets.
Minimum size.
I'm going with first one single instance, but I'm saying like, you know, maximum you can go probably
eight instances auto scaling group settings.
That's that's just the name of the environment.
Fraud.
I'm giving the environment name.
Name is fraud.
And lost setting for the logs.
Settings for health monitoring enhanced can be expensive, so you can turn it to basic if you want.
Again, you can check that from a B+ documentation.
Upgrade.
If you make any upgrade, it should be rolling upgrade.
I'm saying with this namespace rolling update enable true.
Rolling update policy based on the health right.
If the incidence is healthy, then go to the other batch rolling update size.
We can give a size like one instance at a time or you can give the percentage also.
Okay.
Load balancer.
Cross zone load balancer.
And I also wanted stickiness, so I'm going to add stickiness as well.
So I'll add setting.
Namespace.
Let's search again for stickiness.
Stickiness.
Enable.
True.
Copy that.
And that's the namespace.
Name.
Stickiness enabled.
Hopes.
It's copying the new Klein character value.
So what are the values default is to false?
You have true and false.
So we'll go with true.
True.
This should be good.
Let me separate it a little bit.
Yeah.
Batch size you want given percent or you want to give it an.
So fixed size, that size is going to be one instance at a time.
Again, you can give the percent and you can give the person number of percent at 30%, 50% of the size.
Get deployment policy rolling.
Although Skilling launch configuration names security group so which security group we want our instance
to be and so we already have created the security group.
So DOT we profile product security group.
Right.
And this is going to be an ID format, So dot ID?
Yes, that's right.
Load balancer.
Load balancer should be in which security group?
Right.
So we have the bins tag security.
It'll be security group dot ID.
Yes.
Okay.
I think we're done with all the settings.
Yeah.
Now we can go ahead and execute this, but there could be a bug in this.
The bug could be this.
We're creating security group and then we're creating beanstalk environment, right?
First, our security group should get created and then the beanstalk environment should get created
because it's referring most of the time.
It will be intelligent to find that out, but sometimes there are some misfires that are happening and
for that I want to base and I want to create a dependency like for the security group, get created
and then the beanstalk environment so we can put an option depends on.
So in which resource do you want it to depend.
I'm going to say at a.
S underscore security group.
Security group you'll be.
Yes.
And also, this is a list so you can give multiples.
One more.
A.
S underscore security group.
Dot.
No, not back.
End her.
P security group dot the broad security group That is the security group for Beanstalk.
Easy, for instance.
Yes, Dot.
No, I don't need to give any dirt.
This is a depends on you.
Just give.
You need to give the name of the resource, that's all.
Can the resource type dot the resource name.
Now, TerraForm now will make sure that these resource gets created first and then your beanstalk resource.
This resource gets created.
Okay.
Now time to test it.
Really, a lot of things that we did and there's definitely there will be chances of misfires, bugs,
configuration errors, syntax errors, Reference errors.
But.
We are using the TerraForm plugin from intelligence, so it made very easy.
You also refer to the documentation.
Can you follow these basic things?
Right.
Go through the documentation you can use ID so you know you can save a lot of pain.
Okay.
Anyways, we have to test it.
Let's go and test.
So first terraform.
You know we have.
Anyways, let's run it.
If you include any new module or anything because we're using directly beanstalk resource that is part
of a plugin, so you don't need to do anything.
But yes, there's been stack module also there.
But that beanstalk model now, it's just almost similar to what we did.
TerraForm.
Validate.
Let's check the syntax.
So this ID is really helping us with the syntax.
But yes, we had some problem.
Subnet group.
Okay.
Dag is not expected here.
Let's go and check back in services.
Yeah.
So the tag is not supported for this resource, it seems.
Let's see.
Tags.
No, it's not there.
Okay, this is fine.
Let's make the change.
Let's commit it being environment.
Okay?
Let's commit everything.
Okay, let's try again.
TerraForm Validate.
Okay, that's a success and the tax is not supported and should support it.
Tag is a very common thing, but anyways, it's not supported, so we removed it.
TerraForm format.
Yeah, it's back and services been in.
We did a lot of things.
Okay.
This format is very necessary to make the code more readable.
Finally, let's see if plan.
Their chances of success are getting better and better, right?
Validating syntax is good.
Now let's say plan.
If this also gives us good result, then we can apply it.
Okay if he got into an error.
Lie number three in our B environment file and resource application.
Sexually inappropriate value for attribute application string required.
Okay, let's check that.
So be environment file, line number three.
People for application.
We profile proart OC dot name so it needs a string.
Right?
So name should be found there, I think.
I think that should take it.
Save it.
Okay.
Let's check once again.
TerraForm Plan.
Okay, that's a success of seven Things will be added.
All right.
That's awesome.
I'm getting excited.
Let me say terraform, apply now.
Okay.
Now we have very close.
To have a complete application stack means stack backend services.
VPC is there security groups?
Load balancers?
Right.
So we're automating all that.
Plus we're maintaining a state.
We're maintaining the state in the remote state.
S3 Yes, yes.
S3 Bucket We're maintaining a state.
We are also version controlling our code and so we are very much apt compatible to work in a DevOps
team now if following all the right standards.
Version controlling IT infrastructure as a code.
We are maintaining the state in a centralized place.
We are using nice ID to help with our infrastructure as a code.
And moreover, we are testing it.
We are formatting it properly and all the right standards are in right places.
And it cannot get any better than this.
You set up a CCD with this through Jenkins next.
So now we can use that.
Or you can use CCD from a.
You can use code, commit code, build code, pipeline code, deploy all the services.
Okay.
While this is happening, let's also check from the console.
Being stuck.
In Ohio.
He profile being brought?
That's the one.
It's in a pending state.
It's getting created.
That's pretty awesome.
We should have all our backend services as well.
Elastic Cache.
Active queue.
And.
Ah, yes.
So there's a cluster that's getting created.
This we profile Rabbit.
That takes a very long time to come up.
And then there is ideas.
Ideas also take some time to come up.
CDB identifiers.
We can actually use one more property to be identified and we can give a proper name instead of like
TerraForm and that ID, right?
Okay, So we'll wait for a few minutes until this becomes stable.
So I'll pause my screen and come back one when this is completed.
So after some time it completed successfully.
Exactly 11 minutes, 6 seconds.
Yeah.
So everything is getting tracked.
If you're good with your code, you can make sure you commit it.
And you push it.
Okay, So stocks should be completely up and running.
Environment.
It's an orchestrated.
And that's the endpoint as a default application.