Now we have two simple things pending.
One is Initializing our Ideas database.
So we have the SQL queries, the SQL file.
We have to run it against this, my SQL IDs instance, but it is in the private subnet, so it cannot
be accessed from the outside world.
The only way to access it is to run through an instance which is in public subnet.
So.
The Bastion host.
We anyway need Bastion host and we'll also use this bastion host to provision how to say initialize
our ideas instance with SQL queries.
So next we'll write the code to create a bastion host and execute database commands from there so it
can access the ideas instance and initialize our database.
So let's do that.
So I'm going to create a new file over here.
Named Bastion host.
Dr..
In this will mention the resource to provision to create a bastion host and easy to instance.
Resources.
E w.
S underscore instance.
Logical id.
V profile hyphen bastion.
For the army it will be coming from.
The variables file.
So we have to use a lookup function and look for the region name in the map variable Amis.
So for that we will say look up function.
We're going to pass the dot amis.
And that dot underscore region.
So this function will access the map variable EMI.
And in that it will look for a key with the region name.
So variable eight plus underscore region.
Is going to return the region name us East to and it will find the army.
So this image is of Ubuntu server 20 in our region.
Which will be automatically fetched by this resource based on our region.
Name instance type will keep it as tx to micro.
And let me fill in a few other details.
Key name.
Which is coming from our key payers resource plus underscore key payer or we profile key dot key underscore
name.
So if you have to put this under the public subnet of our VPC.
So subnet id module dot vpc dot public underscore subnets zero which is going to return.
Model dot VPC public subnet zero.
That is the first public subnet.
So our bastion host will be created in the first public subnet of our VPC.
Count will only keep it one.
And we have a variable for that.
Why, don't instance, count?
Next is the security group VPC.
Security Group ID.
E w centers core security group dot v profile hyphen bastion hyphen sg dot ID should return the idea
of this security group.
Let's give a few tags.
Okay.
So that should really provision our bastion host in our security group.
Oh, our VPC Public subnet VPC.
And that should be fine.
But we have one more thing to do.
We have to provision our ideas instance with the schema.
So we'll use a shell script, will push a Shell script to this Bastion host and we'll execute that Shell
script.
Now, that Shell script should have the IDs instance endpoint, the username and password.
And that will be dynamic when we launch our ideas instance, we'll have an endpoint.
We have to store it.
So we can access our IDs instance endpoint.
But TerraForm already maintains the state of the infrastructure.
Its state should have information about the IDs endpoint.
But to extract it in a file, we need to create a template.
Set up a form template file documentation.
So there is a template file.
Function in TerraForm where we can pass.
A part of a template file.
So we can create a text file, we can put template information over there and we can mention the variables,
like we can mention the IDS endpoint, which will be used in our template.
A template file will be just any other file.
But we can put a variable in the template file.
TerraForm is going to interpolate the variables with the value.
So this is an example of a template file.
It's any other text except you have the variables, loops, all those things, conditions you can maintain
and terraform is going to interpolate all that and create a text file from that, which then can be
pushed with the template file function.
So first I'm going to create a template file with the Shell commands, Linux Shell Command, which is
going to initialize our ideas instance.
So.
Let's create a file.
Mm db.
Hyphen deploy dot dm.
Bill.
That should be the extension temple.
Here.
We'll put the shell commands that we want to execute.
So first an update.
Then I want to install Git and my SQL client.
So planning to execute all these commands in our Bastion hosts our Bastion host is an open machine,
so I'm putting Ubuntu commands installing get my SQL.
And then I will clone the source code over here.
Source code.
Earl Branch VP hyphen rim.
And we have the file in our source code, which we are going to execute with our MySQL command.
So I'll give the MySQL command hyphen edge and the IDs endpoint.
Now that has to be coming dynamically.
So I'm giving a variable over here.
Ideas have an endpoint, which we have not yet defined.
We are going to pass it through our template function and hyphen u user dollar.
DBE user.
And the password.
Hyphen.
Hyphen password.
Equal to dollar.
DB boss.
On database named accounts.
So we created a database named Accounts.
Input redirection and part of our SQL file, which has the SQL queries, which is in our source code.
So when we clone, we should have a directory v profile hyphen project and this is happening in the
home directory of a one to user.
And I'm going to give the complete path, absolute path slash home slash open to slash V profile.
Hyphen project.
So in this directory, our source code will be cloned.
And then inside that we have a source directory in that we have main in that we have three sources.
And inside that we have the SQL file DB underscore backup dot SQL.
If you are not so sure about this part, check in our repository GitHub repository.
In VP branch you should see file in this part.
So this will be our shell script that will get executed.
First, we're going to push this Shell script to Bastion host and execute it.
But this needs a few variables that will pass.
So let's go to Bastian Host resource.
So we'll use provisional file Provisional to push this file first.
Provisional.
We provisionally file.
Content.
It's not just any other text file.
You have to pass it through this function template file function.
And let's give part of the template db hyphen deploy dot tx.
Simple.
We have to put this into the double quotes.
Goma.
And we have to give the variable the variable that we have we are accessing in this template, this
endpoint DB user DB path.
We have to parse those variables after this.
If you're using template or many, many templates, a good idea that you create a different directory
and put your templates inside that so it becomes more manageable.
So like I can create a directory.
I will name it as templates.
And let's move over template to this templates directory.
We factor.
Okay.
And then I'm going to give the path templates slash.
The template file name.
That's not mandatory, but makes your code a little more manageable.
Now, about passing the variables, so we are going to pass it this way.
This is the way in curly braces.
Give the variable name IDs, hyphen endpoint point.
That's the variable we're using.
Or do you have an end point?
Equal to the value.
So let's go to our backend services.
So e underscore db underscore instance start v profile hyphen IDs and there is an attribute called US
address which is going to get us the endpoint.
So that's the value of.
One variable like that.
We have two other variables.
So comma separated DB user, that's another variable.
And its value is in the variables file.
DB user and DB pass.
So we're going to use these variables.
Var dot db user.
Comma db pos equal to var dot db pos.
Let's just check the syntax.
So it's going to take that template and push it.
And we need to mention the destination where we want to push it.
So destination.
Let's put it in a temp directory.
Damp slash.
We profile hyphen db deploy dot as such, so we'll store it with the extension dots because this will
be a shell script that we are going to execute.
And next is, once we have the Shell script over there, we just have to execute that Shell script.
So another provision for.
Not provider provision and remote exec which will execute our script on this bastion host.
So we're going to give inline commands.
So you say inline equal to and in the list format, you give the list of the commands that you want
to execute.
First, you want to make it executable.
So C each mod plus X.
And the part of our script.
Coma separated.
You can give multiple commands or the next command is obviously executing the script.
So we'll say pseudo.
And execute the script.
So part of the script, which will execute the Shell script.
All right.
So this script will get executed, which will access our ideas endpoint and run our SQL queries on it,
which will initialize our database.
Let me see these two things.
Of course, we need to give also the connection information, how a TerraForm is going to access this
bastion host to push the file and execute Shell script.
So you need to give the connection information.
Connection information user forgot username which is in available file private key.
I'm going to be using a file function, which is going to open up our private key.
That's the variable.
Private key part.
And the name of the file is V Profile Key.
So that's the file.
And the private key file is going to open up and use that file.
And IP.
So since we are executing it from our local machine, we are going to access it over the internet.
So we have to use the public IP.
Of the Bastion hosts so host self dot public IP which is going to return the public IP of this bastion
host.
So it will use these credentials.
Log into the Bastion host.
Push the script and execute the script.
All right.
So in this, we're not only just provisioning the Bastion host.
We are also executing script, which is going to initialize our ideas instance.
So two things in one.
But then you have to make sure this runs only after this instance is provisioned.
If you're running all the scripts at once, then there may be a chance that it will launch Bastion Host
first and then it will create the backend services, backend service.
If the database is not ready, if this instance is not ready, will not get this endpoint.
All right.
So it provisions it trying to deploy this template file it will throw you error so this.
Bastion host setup should happen only after your backend services are up and running.
So if you're going to put depends on over here and we'll mention the ideas.
Resource ideas underscore db underscore instance dot v profile hyphen radius.
So then TerraForm will make sure first it is going to provision the DB instance and then only it will
access our provision.
The bastion host So you're creating a dependency there, which is very, very important.
Okay.
Now it's time to test.
TerraForm in it.
If I have anything, it will download any modules.
But I don't think I have mentioned anything new.
So this is fine.
TerraForm validate.
Okay, That's a success.
That's surprising.
I thought I will get some errors that are from format.
So Bastion host everything gets formatted properly and this is good.
Let's see if this.
And finally, TerraForm Plan.
Now get all the validation completed successfully.
It's time to now apply the changes.
So it is one to add.
It's going to add one instance, which is our bastion host, actually.
And I say, I am good with this.
Let's say yes.
Okay, so there is an error.
My SQL command.
It says not found.
So it pushed our script, but it was not able to execute it or execute it, but it did not complete
it successfully.
Script execution failed.
So let's check our template.
This is our script.
So the script looks perfectly fine.
It is failing at this command where it is running my SQL hyphen edge ideas endpoint.
For some reason it seems it's not able to access our IDs instance from the Bastion host.
And we can test this ourself.
Let's go to the Bastion instance.
Let's get it.
IP address.
As a such hyphen i v profile.
That's the key.
Or one too.
And the IP address.
So we're in the Bastion host.
And if you go to the temp directory, we should find our script V profile deployed dot script.
And you see it has got the endpoint, the username, the password, everything correct.
Let's try to log in with this command.
And it's not able to log in.
So this instance is not allowing the connection, and most probably it will be the security group.
Let's check the security group of IDs, instance.
So that's what this instance.
That's the security group.
Let's click on that.
Now, this instant security group rule says allow all traffic from the profile security group.
In which we have our bins attack instances.
But our bastion host security group value should be also over here.
So it should allow 3306 from Bastion host security group.
Bastion host security group.
We profile hyphen bastion hyphen SG and will not do that manually.
We'll put that in our code.
So let's go to security group.
People fall back backgrounds security group in this we have this instance so it has connection allowed
all IP from protected group that's right we have seen that we have to make one more rule over here.
Ingress.
From Port 3306.
DCP 3306.
Allowed from the security group.
It does underscore security group DOT the Bastion security group.
Dot it.
Okay, let's see this.
There is one more update in this project video.
If you're getting this error cell connection error.
This is because of new 1 to 20 security settings.
And as a temporary fix.
As of now, you can give one option while you're executing the MySQL command.
That's hyphen hyphen SQL hyphen more equal to disabled.
See this file.
And then you can continue.
But if you're using open to 18 ami for Bastion host, you should not get this error and you don't need
to put this setting.
This option is only for new ubuntu 20.
So see the file and then you can continue the execution.
And let's do this once again.
TerraForm.
Validate.
There are farm.
Format.
The reform plan.
Things looks good.
Let's say TerraForm apply.
It sees one to destroy, it's going to delete our Bastion host and recreate it once again.
And that is what we want when it creates new Bastion hosts going to execute the script.
This time it should be able to access the ideas instance.
Let's see.
Yes.
So this time it completed successfully.
Sebastian Host Created and executed our script.
Initialized ideas DB instance.
And yes, now we have a complete stack and we can upload our artifact to being stack.