So clone your source code.
Get clone.
If you already have this clone, get into the Vpro file Project Repository directory.
And you should be in this branch.
VP hyphen them.
Which we are already in.
Will update our application properties file.
We'll update the file with all the back end details.
Let's open this file.
Starting with this endpoint.
Username and password, Admin and admin.
One, two, three.
That's the same username and password we have used.
When will provisioning this instance mem cache?
Bought one.
One, two, one.
That's fine.
Rabbit MQ.
MQ for that endpoint, just copy it.
What is five, six, seven one?
But we have to change.
Five, six, seven, one rabbit.
Q Username and password V hash.
We should already have this in the variables file.
Rabbit is the username, and that's the password.
So we have given all the details verified.
Once again, ideas, end point ideas, username, password, mem cache endpoint, port number rabbit
MQ Endpoint Port number Rabbit.
MQ User and password.
What's even quit.
Let's go back to the project directory.
Where we have the bombed out XML file and we're going to run an install which should generate our artifact.
We're really doing it from our command line.
But if you already have the CD pipeline, you can also generate artifact from Jenkins and deploy it
also over there from there automatically to bienstock stack environment.
But for now we'll just do it manually.
Upload target.
So Artifact is ready.
Let's upload this artifact to bin Stack.
Application versions.
Here, upload and deploy.
So let's upload the artifact from here.
Get into your project directory where we clone the source code and build the artifact and let's upload
the artifact v profile v two dot var.
And let's see.
Deploy.
Now wasn't label let's say we have this portion as.
V profile hyphen version five dot for anything.
I'm just giving for a sample.
Deploy and wait.
It will upload the artifact.
Okay.
After uploading, it looks good.
Let's click on the link.