So we get our artifact uploaded and application is running.
Fine.
Let's make a test admin, underscore VPI password admin.
Underscore VPI.
If you're able to log in, the database is verified the database connection.
So we're able to login ideas, connection is verified and let's check rabbit MQ.
Who initiated this is also good.
Let's check Mom, cash all users.
Let's pick up a user.
Data is inserted in cash.
This is good.
Go back.
Let's click the user once again.
Data is from cash, so cash is also verified.
So that completes our test and also our project.
So really intense work there.
If you have come this far, you have done a great job and you have gained a real and rich experience
in automating a cloud infrastructure with TerraForm.
Complete VPC stack we have set up with TerraForm and we have created our application stack on that VPC.
So all the score and you say, just terraform apply and everything gets created automatically.
One final thing before I close this.
If you are doing it in parts this project, if you're taking few days to complete it, then your public
IP may change.
So you would like to update your public IP in the variables file.
Or if you just want to keep it simple, you can just say 0.0.0 slash.
Zero.
So for the Bastion host is going to use this as your public IP.
That means it will allow a search connection from anywhere.
Or you can keep updating it on daily basis while you're doing your project.
So yes, we have created the entire V profile stack VPC stack by using TerraForm.
We set up the entire PC.
With Bastion host.
And then we have created our V profile stack in that VPC.
So that should be all in this project video.
Thank you very much for doing it.
Completing it.
I will see you in the next one.