Hello and welcome to the Seeds of DevOps Project.
The name of this project is continuous integration with Jenkins and Tools.
So this is the scenario.
Let's say you have a product development and agile SDLC is in motion, so a bunch of smart developers
in an Agile team will regularly make code changes.
So there'll be multiple code changes every day.
And all this code needs to be tested because this is what actually is building your product.
So this code needs to be regularly built and tested.
So usually in an enterprise there will be a separate build and release team who will be doing this job
of building testing and releasing the code.
Or if it's a small industry, then they'll be it will be developer's responsibility to merge and integrate
this code.
So yes, there are regular code changes.
Also called as commits or pull requests.
Developers will be dependent on build and release team, usually to test the code and move it to the
next level in the release cycle.
But not so frequently the code will be tested.
If there are any bugs or error, it will be known late due to these bugs and errors in the code keep
accumulating and let's say these got accumulated.
A problem goes more deeper.
Now.
Developers need to rework to fix these bugs and errors, which is time consuming process and the teams
would be already approaching the deadline.
So product owners really need to test the code as fast as it's building.
But that's not possible because the build and release team is doing a manual process and also there
are approvals and ticketing system in place which delays the process more further.
So solution to this problem is regular build and test for every comet.
So as soon as there is a code change, the code needs to be built and tested at the same time.
But if the process is manual, this will not be possible.
So you need to have an automated build and release process.
And whenever there is a build and test of the code, the developer should get notified automatically.
So if there is a build failure, if the code is not passing your quality gates, or if there is any
bug, any kind of error, the developers will be stopped doing whatever they're doing and force.
They'll fix the code.
So if you have such kind of automation framework in place which will regularly build and test the code
for every commit, then you're also removing dependency of developers from build and release team.
Ta da.
This process itself is called a continuous integration process.
So input to this process is any code commit and output will be a well tested artifact and all this will
happen automatically.
Now this very tested artifact then can be deployed to servers for further software testing or performance
testing or load testing.
And then if everything is good, it can be promoted to production.
So may sound simple, but there will be actually so many tools connected together to complete this automated
process.
But this is a well worth investment because today's time is very demanding.
There are regular feedbacks and demands for that developer really need to work regularly and make regular
code changes to improve the product.
So in today's time you should definitely have a continuous integration process.
Let's talk about benefits of continuous integration pipeline.
First benefit that you obviously get is shorter mean time to repair.
Because here you are not accumulating the bugs or errors.
As soon as they are found, they are fixed.
So it very well works with the Agile team and there will be no human intervention.
So we're not dependent.
The developers are not dependent on build and release or operations team to do this, which saves a
lot of time.
And obviously, not to mention if there is any fault, any bug, any error, it can be found out very
quickly and can be isolated very quickly.
So in this project, obviously, we're going to set up a continuous integration pipeline.
So now let's talk about the tools that we are going to use in this project.
Starting with Jenkins.
Jenkins will be a continuous integration server and main hero in this project and as hero needs sidekick.
Our Jenkins hero will also need some assistance tool.
Obviously we are going to use a version control system.
We're going to use Git and Git hub as the remote repository and we'll have a Java code in that.
And to build that Java code, we will need build tool maven.
We're also going to do some code analysis.
So we are going to use forced check style, which is a very simple code analysis tool.
But there are more sidekicks.
There are more tools.
We'll use Slack for notification.
You can also have an email integration.
So we get email notifications.
We'll use Nexis as Monotype to store our artifact and also to download dependency for Maven.
So OSX sonar type Nexis will be our software repository.
We're going to get more deeper into code analysis.
So we'll be using so on the cube server.
So we're going to scan our code with the cube scanner and check style, and then we're going to publish
our result into Sonar Cube Server Dashboard.
And to set up these servers.
Jenkins Server next server owner Kube server.
We are going to use a fabulous platform.
We'll use eight AC two instances on two instances we'll set up Jenkins server next to server and so
on the cube server.
Okay.
So let's reiterate our objective.
There'll be quick fault isolation, shorter npdr.
Faster turnaround time.
So any new request, a new feature change needs to be done.
It can be done quickly without disrupting too many things.
So these are our objectives to set up a continuous integration pipeline.
All right, let's achieve our goals now.
Before we get started, we'll see continuous integration, pipeline architecture.
So you'll have a very clear understanding of what we are trying to achieve.
Okay, let's see the workflow first.
So the developer makes a code change.
Commit to version control system or source code manager.
An automation tool will automatically fetch that code, build it, run a unit test and return the outcome
on Slack channel.
So we'll be using Slack anyways.
The next.
Phase will be.
It will run core analysis and core analysis.
There will be gates, quality gates.
If the threshold if it is not passing the threshold cap, then it's good.
If it's passing the threshold, then a notification will be sent on Slack channel.
If this is good, it goes to the next level.
Then the software will be built, it will be packaged and the artifact will be uploaded and its outcome
notification will be also sent.
The artifact or the software will be stored into artifact repository.
If all these stages are successful, then the software can be promoted to the next level.
If there is any failure, the notification will be anyways sent.
Once the notification is received by the developer for any failure, they will make the code change,
they'll make the fix and the process repeats again.
So there will be a regular code commits, continuous code commits, and this process will run continuously.
So that's why the name came to continuous, continuous integration.
So this process will be automated.
So this can be done multiple times in a day.
If you want.
Okay.
Now, let's see.
Architectural design by using all the tools.
So a developer will make code change by using his or her ID like Visual Studio.
Our intelligence and that tool that ID will be connected to a good repository.
So developer makes a code change and commits.
This comet will be synced with a remote repository will be using GitHub.
So as soon as GitHub receives a comet.
Our continuous integration server.
Jenkins will detect that and fetch the changes.
Fetch the latest code so it will have an integration with GitHub.
Then Jenkins know Jenkins will be running some code test.
Unit test, basically, which is part of your build process.
If there is any failure, the notification will be sent.
If it passes.
Core analysis will be done on the code by using textile and a sonar scanner.
So in this project, we'll have multiple code analysis tool.
So it will generate some report and this report we are going to publish on so on the Q server.
So on our cube server will display the result and we'll also have quality gates, a quality criteria.
If you're passing the quality criteria, we can move to the next level or a failure notification will
be sent and the process really stops.
So you see, we are putting brakes at every level.
If there is any failure, it automatically breaks.
If not, the process continues automatically anyways.
So once the code analysis is done.
Then we'll build the artifact and we have Java code.
So we're going to use Maven Build Tool.
If there is any build failures, any build errors, notification will be sent.
While the source code is getting built, it will need some dependency over Maven.
We need some maven dependencies.
Those dependencies we will be storing in Nexus repository.
So Maven will automatically download all the dependency from Maven repository, which is in Nexis.
Is this Chronotype Nexis.
Once the artifact is packaged, once the software is really created, then the software we are going
to upload it back to Nexus sonar type repository.
So really using Nexus Monotype repository for two cases.
One is to download dependencies from and the second is uploading our artifact or storing our artifact.
So we're going to version and store the artifact.
So every time this continuous integration process runs, we'll have a new version of software.
And based on requirements and choices.
Any version then can be selected from Nexis repository and can be deployed to servers.
Okay.
So now we can really pause the video and watch the architectural design once again.
All right, now let's see the flow of execution, all the steps that we are going to take in order to
complete this project.
Number one, we will log into our account because that's where we are going to set up all the servers.
We will create a key pillar which we will use to log into our ESI to instance on which Jenkins nexus
and so on our queue will be running.
Then we create the security group for Jenkins Nexus and so on our cube server.
Then we launch the easy to instance with the user data script.
This script will automatically provision your Jenkins server next to server and so on, or cube server.
Then we will conduct the post installation steps.
Will set up the Jenkins user and will install all the necessary plugins that we need for this project.
We set up next this login and we will create a few repositories on Nexus.
From where we'll download the dependencies for Maven and upload our artifact.
Once our pipeline is good.
ALONZO McKEW We really don't need to do much for the post installation.
We'll just log in and we'll test whether it's working or not.
On Git, we will create a GitHub repository.
I hope you already have created a GitHub account.
As mentioned in the prerequisites and that account, you're going to create a GitHub repository and
you're going to migrate my code or this project Vpro file product code into your GitHub repository.
So you have a complete control over that code.
You can commit, you can make changes.
If you use my repository, you cannot commit.
You cannot make changes to my repository.
Once we do that, we integrate our GitHub repository with VTS code and we will test it.
Now still here.
It was kind of prerequisites for our project or the code that we're going to write from Step seven.
We are going to create or write the code for our first job.
That will be the build job.
It will integrate with nexus.
Fetch the necessary dependencies from the Nexus server.
Next, we'll create a GitHub webhook.
Now this is to trigger your job whenever you make a commit a change to your git repository, the Jenkins
job will automatically get triggered.
Then we will do so.
The cube server integration will write the code to run some test and upload the test result to owner
cube server.
Then final stage in our pipeline will be uploading the artifact to the Nexus server.
Now whatever changes is happening in our pipeline, we should get notification for that.
So we are also going to create a Slack notification system.
Whenever there is a change in our pipeline, we get a notification whether it passed or failed.
Now, while doing the project, whenever you are in doubt, what exactly are we doing right now?
You can anytime come to this video and see you are at what step or stage?
So take a moment, rewind the video, look at all the steps once again and join me in the next lecture.
We'll start setting up all the services.