Okay.
I have logged into my account.
I'm in North California region.
You can be in any region of your choice.
Let's go to keepers first and we'll create a key pair.
We'll just have one key to log into all our three instances and we will name it as we profile hyphen
see hyphen key.
I will keep it as PEM format because I will be using git bash or a terminal to log into my instance.
So PEM file.
If you plan to use putty then you can use PCA as well.
But let's keep it.
Pem create.
Keep it.
Saving it in the downloads directory.
Now let's create the security group for our 3c2 instance.
So let's go to security groups.
First, let's create for Jenkins Create Security Group.
Let's name it as Jenkins hyphen SG.
Add in inbound rule.
Now there are many people who make mistakes in and edit the outbound rules.
Please do not do it.
Only in bound rule we will say.
Port 22 allowed from my IP so I can do a search.
And then we will see port 88 of the Jenkins allowed from any IPv4 and 8080.
Once again allowed from any IPV six.
Now generally I'll say it aloud from my IP, but we will be creating a GitHub webhook where GitHub will
be connecting to Jenkins from the internet.
So we are just saying it's allowed ADAT from anywhere.
So GitHub can connect to Jenkins on Port 88.
If we have to update a few more rules here, we'll come back in a moment.
Let's first create this security group ops description, give some description and let's see, create
security group.
Okay.
Next one will create for nexus.
So create security group will call it as.
Nexus g c in the description inbound rule 22 allowed from my IP.
Again so I can do search and port 8081 allowed from my IP.
Now nexus again is a web service will be listing on port 8081.
We access it from the browser and we will access nexus on port 88 one.
So I set my IP.
One more rule we have to give here.
Port 8081 from the Jenkins Security Group.
So just type SVG or you can just search for Jenkins.
You find your Jenkins security group and you add it.
Now this rule so Jenkins can upload artifact to the Nexus server.
And also it will be downloading dependency from the access server so that rule and see create security
group.
Okay.
Last security group sonar creates security group.
We'll call it as.
So on RSG.
Inbound rule.
Once again 22 from my IP so we can as such, we really don't need to do a search to sonar server in
this project.
But just in case, if you want to.
Now sonar cube service port number is 9000.
But we are setting up a Nexis service also in the sonar cube server, which will listen on Port 80.
So we'll see Port 80 allowed from my IP.
Also Port 80 allowed from the Jenkins Security Group.
So SG select Jenkins Security Group.
Now Jenkins will be uploading the test result to the cube server and it connects on the spot.
At least that's what we are going to configure.
Okay, let's create this.
Okay.
So all three security groups are created.
But there's one more entry we need to make in Jenkins Security Group.
In Bound Rule.
Edit This is the Jenkins Security Group.
Edit.
Now we said Jenkins will be connecting to smaller cube server, but sooner Cube Server will be also
sending a report or a result back to Jenkins.
And within when it is connecting back to Jenkins, it will connect it on Port 88.
Now we can give this rule port 88.
And we can select Jenkins Security Group.
Oops.
Sorry.
Jenkins.
So on cube security group.
But anyways, port 88 is open for anywhere.
So.
So the cube server can connect to Jenkins on port 81.
Sorry, port 8080.
Then why I am adding this rule.
This is for your understanding if you have a restricted connection.
Port 88 from my IP.
In such case, if sonar wants to connect to Jenkins, then you need to add this rule.
Port 88 allowed from Sonar Security Group.
So let's see this.
Now, if you're not so good with a and security group and you just want to anyways do the project,
what you can do is in all the port numbers that I have given, just give it from anywhere port 22 from
anywhere.
Port 88 from anywhere.
Port 80, 81 from anywhere.
It's not good from a security point of view, but if you still want to continue with the project, then
you can do that.
One more thing.
If you take more than one day to complete this project and you have a broadband Internet connection,
which most of the people are using, so your public IP will change.
So you have given here in the rules.
Bought 22 allowed from my IP, but tomorrow your IP will be different.
So you need to come back to the security group.
You have to say 22 all out from my IP.
Wherever you have my IP, you just select and you just do it once again and you save it.
Also, you can just do a Google search.
What is my IP?
Find your public IP and you can add that IP also here.
All right.
So if you need a grasp of the understanding or you need to grasp what I suggest I did once again, rewind
the video, watch it once again, and make sure you get or understand all these rules and then wrap
this up and join me in the next lecture.