All right, now let's launch our two instance for Jenkins Nexus and Sona Cube.
But before that, we will see the user data script that we will use to provision these services.
So.
On the browser, go to this link.
It's in the resource section.
That's the GitHub repository that we will be using in this project's.
And over here, come to this dropdown.
These are the branches.
Search for Sy hyphen Jenkins.
Find Sy Hyphen Jenkins.
Click on it.
So we switch to the CI hyphen Jenkins branch.
In this we have a folder here user data.
So click on it.
So here we have Jenkins set up dot search.
Next set of data search.
And so another set of data such.
So let's click on Jenkins set up dot research.
So this is a simple script.
It's actually just the Linux commands that will install Jenkins server.
So we're installing open JDK eight, see certificates later, see certificate maven, git w gate unzip.
And these are all the commands that I have just copied from Jenkins installation documentation.
Now for most of the time this remains the same, but if it changes, you need to make sure you give
right commands for installing Jenkins.
Let's see the next script Nexus.
Now.
Nick says installation is not as simple as Jenkins.
Jenkins is just apt install jenkins and that's it on the ubuntu server.
Next says you'll be setting up on Amazon Linux to which you seem like sent to us and there is no readymade
package for nexus.
We have to download it's binary and create our own service.
Now I'm already assuming you have experience on Linux or you have done DevOps beginners to an advanced
course where you did Linux and bass scripting.
So this is fairly simple.
We install JDK eight, we download a access from this URL.
Over here and we unzip this, extract the next directory.
Sorry.
Next is binary.
To this directory we add an access user.
We give this permission, the nexus user ownership.
And then we create this file next to service file.
All these details will be added into that file so we can use System CTL Command to start and stop or
restart next service and we also enable it.
So next the service comes up at the boot time.
As a DevOps, you should definitely have experience with Linux and batch scripting, so go through the
script and understand this.
You may need to write similar kind of scripts for services that cannot run through system CTL.
You have to make sure you run it through System CD.
Okay, next is Sonar Cube.
It's more complicated than Nexis because we are running multiple services over here.
We are running PostgreSQL Sonar Cube servers and Nexis I'm sorry, Engine X Service.
So let me quickly go through this script for you.
Firstly, we create some system configuration over here in order for the ownership service to run.
In his city.
Alcon fanning limits dot com.
We install open JDK 11.
We install PostgreSQL service.
You make sure we start and enable it.
We create a user called sonar in the PostgreSQL database.
We give the password to it.
We create a database named Sonar.
We grant sonar Kub database sonar user privilege once the PostgreSQL PostgreSQL service is set up.
We will download solar binary and this is similar as Nexus.
From here we extract the zip file, we create a similar cube user and the group.
We create solar properties.
So in the properties file this will have the database information we just created in the previous steps.
Then we have similar cube service file where we'll mention all the detail, where the owner cube binaries
are, how to start and stop it.
And then we say sys CTL enables owner cube and starts on our cube.
Now this is commented it's not going to really start because we need to reboot.
So Owner Cube so is before we started the reboot is because we change some system configuration here.
This will be applied only when you reboot, so you don't need to reboot.
There is a command in the script.
Let's come down.
Okay.
So the service by default listens on post 9000, just like Jenkins listens on AT&T Nexus on 8081.
So Naqib is going to listen on Port 9000 and you can see that in the Sooner Properties file here.
But we will be installing engine service here.
Which listens on port 80 and forwards the request to the sonar cube service on Port 9000.
Why like that?
Well, if you need to do a secure connection to DPS, all this can be handled by the engine server.
So on the cube server can be offloaded.
Once we set up the engine service to forward request to the owner cube service, we are going to enable
engine service and restart is commented here.
We set up the firewall rule and then we say reboot.
So easy to instance will reboot and the owner cube servers, postgres and engine x, everything will
come up with it.
Okay, so those were three scripts.
Take your time, go through them, read them.
If you're not understanding them, then you need to brush up your Linux and bash scripting skills,
which I highly recommend.
Even if you don't want to do that, you can still continue with the project, but those are my recommendations.
Anyways, let's go to a console.
Let's start launching our instance, let's say launch instances.
We'll start with Jenkins Server.
Let's name it as Jenkins Server and we will go with one two and click on this dropdown.
For Select.
Make sure you select open to here and click on this dropdown and you go with open to 20.
Now be very, very careful with this many people select paid AMI so you have to select open to server
20.
You should see a free tier eligible select this one.
Okay.
Scroll down instant type DT to micro will not do.
We are to go with t to small.
Yes, there will be some charges for this project.
T to micro will be very small.
Jenkins will hang a lot.
Even it will crash.
So we need to go with minimum t to small.
There will be some minor charges for it.
Also in your EAW spills OC key pair.
Let's select the profile key that you already created.
Come to network settings and we're going to select existing security group.
Jenkins.
Scroll down and advanced details.
Commit the end user data.
Okay, let's get out Jenkins user data script.
So let's click on Jenkins set up data search.
Copy this.
Make sure you copy the first line as well.
Many people will miss it and then the script won't run.
Yeah.
Very validate once again if the script is correct and say launch instance.
In similar fashion will launch Nexus and Cylinder Cube as well.
Refresh gets coming up.
Let's launch nexus now.
Launch instance.
Nexus server.
And why you have to go on this one for Amazon Linux two, it's already selected here.
Amazon Linux Amazon Linux two.
Come down instance type.
This one is going to be PT two medium.
Come down.
Sam, keep your.
Security group.
This is next.
So selected the next security group.
Advanced details come down.
Let's get our script.
Next set of data such.
Copy it.
Launch instance.
View all instances.
Let's refresh this as an exercise is coming up.
Last one.
Sonar.
So on the server open to.
And go with open to 18.
Scroll down.
Oops.
Not here.
They're open to server 18.
Again.
Make sure you selected the free tier eligible EMI.
Instance type.
Two medium.
Same keeper.
Security group.
This is sonar.
So select the sonar security group.
Advanced details.
Let's get the Sooners script.
Launch instance.
Okay.
Now wait for like five, 10 minutes, and then we will start validating our services.
So take a break for five, 10 minutes.
Come back and join the next lecture.