Okay.
So now let's.
To the post installation steps, starting with Jenkins.
Let's first search to the Jenkins, so copy its public IP.
Open gate bash.
For MapQuest, just use open terminal.
Mention your key we profile.
Username is ubuntu.
So Ubuntu instance and paste the public ip.
Say yes.
Before I continue the step, I want you to note down this important point for the search, which will
be used in Jenkins to GitHub integration.
I'm talking here about search.
Whenever you do a search for the first time to any server.
So I did search to this machine and that's the Jenkins public IP.
Yes.
That you will ask me a question.
This is the fingerprint.
Like an ID card of this search server.
Do you accept it?
And we said here.
Yes.
And then it stores this identity.
Into your home directory.
Next time when you do the search.
So let's clear.
Let's log out.
And let's do a search once again.
This time it will not ask me the question.
See that directly logged in.
Now this process is called us host key checking and it has nothing to do with Jenkins or anything I'm
talking about here.
Purely about search.
We'll have a step where Jenkins will do a search to your GitHub account to access your repository.
That time we need to do this step from Jenkins user.
Okay.
Anyways, we logged in.
Let's do pseudo hyphen.
I clear the screen.
Let's check the service system CTL status jenkins.
It should be in a running state queue to quit from this.
Now let's access it from the browser.
Now let's copy its public IP.
Paste it.
Colon 8080.
That's the port number for Jenkins 88.
Okay.
This thing unlocked.
Jenkins So this is the file which will have the initial password, copy its path, go to the Jenkins
Sicat and paste that pot under the tongue.
Twister.
Paste that part.
Okay.
You get the password.
Copy that.
Be stood there.
Administrator.
Password.
Continue.
Click on install suggested plugins.
It will take some time.
I'll pause the video.
This is done.
Let's set a username.
I'll just set a username as admin and I'll set a password.
Not to give a full name.
I'll just say admin with a capital.
Let's give an email address.
Just give a fake email address.
Okay.
That is the Jenkins you are is going to store in the Jenkins configuration because it gets it from its
IP currently, whatever it is let's see when finish.
Start using Jenkins.
Okay.
We need to install some plug ins in Jenkins, so we'll go to manage Jenkins.
Manage plugins.
If you don't know what a Jenkins plugin is, these are just extra features which you can install.
Like, for example, we will be using Nexus Owner Cube, so we will install those plugins.
So go to available.
And search for the plugins.
So these are the names starting with Maven integration.
Put a checkmark.
Just put a checkmark for now.
Next is GitHub integration.
Put a checkmark.
Now we have a maven build, so we're using Maven integration plugin.
GitHub will integrate Jenkins with GitHub.
So GitHub integration plugin.
Nexus.
Nexus artifact uploader put a checkmark.
Sooner.
So on our cube scanner.
On our cube scanner there.
Slack.
We will be using Slack for the notification.
So search for slack and you see Slack notification check mark.
And for versioning our artifact, our software will be using a plugin called Timestamp.
It's actually called us build timestamp with the checkmark there.
This gives us this variable build underscore timestamp which will have the current timestamp which we
can use to version our artifact.
Okay.
These are good for now.
Make sure you type the correct plugin name.
It is not as good such as Google search.
So the names of the plugin should be exactly what you are looking for.
Put a checkmark on all of that and say install without restart.
Okay.
Scroll till the end and see if everything is success.
We are good.
Click back on Dashboard.
Okay.
This is good for now.
And Jenkins, we have many more things in Jenkins that will be seen in later lectures.
Let's check Nexus now.
So let's click on Nexus, get its public IP.
Let's do an SSH to it.
So we log out from Jenkins here.
Easy to hyphen user.
We have used Amazon Linux too.
The user name is easy to hyphen user.
It's public IP.
So, yes.
I got to do a pseudo hyphen, I.
System CTL status nexus.
Okay.
The service is active.
Let's look at it from the browser.
Portis at 81.
Make sure you copy the correct public IP of Nexis.
Let's click on sign in here.
And it is saying the initial password is in this file, so let's copy this file part.
And let's go to the Nexus.
Yeah.
That's the password.
I mean, it just doesn't give the new line, so we need to copy it properly.
Make sure you don't copy that square bracket.
Just copy this.
So the username is Edwin and the password that we just copied.
Sign in.
Okay.
The setup wizard.
Next.
Okay.
Let's give a password.
Make sure you remember all these passports that you're giving or write it somewhere.
And here we say disable anonymous access.
We don't want anybody to download or upload artifact to our access server only with authentication,
with username and password.
So we'll say disable anonymous access next.
And finish.
Okay.
So we have two major section here in the Nexus.
This is to browse the repository or upload the artifact to the repository.
And this section is for the administration configurations.
So if you remember from the architectural diagram, we are going to upload the artifact to access and
also download dependencies from Nexus.
So we'll have multiple repositories and we will club all the repositories together in a group repository
we will be creating here for repository.
So click on repositories here.
And they create repository.
Maven.
Come here.
Maven hosted will select first.
And we will give it a name.
We profile.
Hyphen release.
Now you can't really give any name, but you need to make sure you mention that name in the Maven configuration
to keep things simple.
Just give the same name as I am giving.
So we prefer release repositories to store our artifact.
We'll upload our tested artifact to Nexus in this repository.
So let's give the name and come down and say, Create repository.
The next repository will be creating create a repository.
And this will be maven to proxy.
Proxy.
Click on that.
Now the purpose of this repository is to store the dependencies.
Our maven tool in Jenkins will download dependencies maven dependencies from this repository.
This is called this proxy repository for Maven.
I will give the name here, the pro maven central, and come down here in proxy remote storage.
Now, Maven will download dependency from this repository, but from where the nexus will download the
dependencies.
So maybe when we ask for a dependency it does not have in this proxy repository.
So it will download it from a you are a maven repository, which is this one.
You can check this URL from the browser.
You will see all the maven dependencies over there.
So if Nexus needs the dependencies to store, it is going to download it from this repository.
Okay.
Let's come down and just create a repository.
One more repository.
This will be also maven hosted.
Its name is Snapshot and you need to change the policy from release to Snapshot.
We are really not going to use this repository, but in your project, if you have snapshot repository
concept, this is how you create it.
A snapshot artifact will have at the end hyphen snapshot an extension.
If you know what I'm saying, you will be able to integrate, if not just create the repository.
What is it?
Create a repository.
Okay.
The last one is going to be the group repository.
And this is going to be maven to group.
This is simply to group all the repositories together.
And this is the name I'm giving here.
It's a group repository.
You need to add the repositories that we created previously.
So click on Maven Central and this arrow.
The Profile release.
Click on that, the profile snapshot.
Click on that.
Yeah.
That's the whole purpose of this repository to group them together.
Create.
Okay.
Once again, we created for repository, we profile release, we profile snapshot v pro maven central
and V Pro Maven Group.
We grouped all these three repositories into repro maven group repository.
That is all the setup that you need to do on Nexis.
Okay.
We have one final thing to validate, which is Stoner Cube.
Now, if everything went fine, just copy its IP and paste it in the browser, the public IP and you
should see.
So the cube login page, you don't need to really do a search, but if you want to search and validate
the service, it's just the service name is Soner System CTL status soner.
The username is admin and the password is admin.
In the real time.
I really, highly, highly recommend to change the password.
Do not use default passwords.
Okay.
So that is all.
We verified all three services.
We did the post installation steps.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.