All right.
So service.
All the services are running fine.
In this lecture, we will be migrating this code.
The Profile Project code.
The branch see hyphen Jenkins.
All this code, we will be migrating in our own git repository.
So.
Log into your GitHub account.
Which you created in Politico sites and they create repository.
And let's give this repository a name.
I will give a name as the Privacy Project.
And it is this name is available so I can take it.
And we will be creating a private repository.
So click on private.
And create a repository.
Okay, now this is how it will be different from what you will be doing in your own actual project.
You will have a source code repository like that, and you will directly have access to it.
You will have your account which will have privilege to make changes to the repository.
But.
In this course.
While we are practicing this, we need to make changes.
Comments and you cannot make change in my repository.
This is my repository.
I cannot give thousands of students the access to my repository, right?
So for that purpose, you have to create your own repository.
Now, you may or may not have this in real time, but you will definitely have a GitHub repository access,
whether it will be your own created repository or the project repository.
So in order to simulate similar behavior, we are creating our own repository here.
So you will have two kinds of access to your git repository, GitHub repository.
One is HTTP based and one is SSH.
We will be using as such.
This is the way forward and a safer approach.
Now how do I migrate this code from this repository to my own repository that we'll be seeing now?
But I also need to set up authentication method from my laptop to this GitHub account for that purpose.
As I said, we'll be using SSH login, so open your git bash or for macOS use open your terminal and
run the command search hyphen key gen and this command just need to run a hyphen keychain, hit enter
and just hit enter.
Enter, enter.
Okay.
Now, this created a public key in this path and a private key in this part.
You need to copy the public key in your GitHub account.
I say public key, not the private key, the one that is highlighted.
So I'm going to clear the screen and I'm going to say cat tilde, which is the symbol of your home directory
slash dot such slash ID underscore RSA dot pub do a cat.
That's the public and that's how it looks.
If it's a private key, it will be written there that it is a private key.
So again, public key copied carefully.
Make sure no extra space.
Copy.
Leave this tab as it is.
Just open another tab and open GitHub.
Make sure logged into your account.
Click on this dropdown here and go to settings.
And come to search and GPG keys.
See new, newest, such key.
Give some name.
Like I will say, this is my laptop key and I will paste it.
Okay.
Once again, public key.
I know I'm repeating again and again, but many people copy the private key, which is quite dangerous.
The private key is the key to open this lock.
So you put the lock, not the key lock here.
And as such key.
Once this is done, let's make a test.
You need to run this command as a search hyphen capital T get at GitHub dotcom.
Okay.
See that?
It says you have successfully authenticated.
It basically used our private key.
Let me show you that.
So it has used this private key to login and connect with this public key.
And this public key is on GitHub.
So that worked.
Okay.
Once we set the authentication, create a folder somewhere, a directory somewhere, I'm creating it
in F drive.
Choose whatever directory you want.
I will call this as project git repo.
And I will do seed into it.
Now create folder wherever you want.
I have f drive, so I'm going to f drive.
Now comes the migration part.
First, I'm going to clone the Vpro file repository, which is a public repository git clone, hyphen
b ci hyphen Jenkins.
Make sure you get the branch name and hit enter.
Okay.
It cloned it to a less.
And you should see this profile project.
We will rename this folder with the name of our repository.
So go back to your tab here.
And that's our project name.
Sorry, repository name.
So copy that name.
This is really not a mandatory step.
You can have folder, any name you want.
Go back to get bash or the terminal.
So we're just renaming just for understanding.
Purpose, as I said, is not mandatory.
Your folder name can be anything.
Okay.
So we renamed it.
Let's get into that folder.
Okay.
You should see here Sy Hyphen Jenkins that name we are in the repository and run this command cat dot
git config.
This is the file in your repository which will have.
The remote you are.
GitHub account repository, whatever you want to call it.
So this early is for V Profile Project.
We are going to replace this with our repository that we created.
So all our code goes to our repository and to do that.
This is the command.
Get remote set URL origin and copy your URL of your repository.
Okay.
Click on set here and copy this.
You look at it carefully.
And hit it.
Okay.
Now, if we do a cat to the config file, you should see now your repository URL.
Now I am going to create here one branch get.
Branch hyphen c min.
Get checkout men.
Oops.
Spelling mistake.
Get check out Main.
Clear the screen.
Okay.
So I have basically two branches now in my repository.
One is CI hyphen Jenkins and one is main.
We'll see how to use this main.
Later, we'll switch back to Sy Hyphen Jenkins.
Okay.
Still, everything is on my local machine, on my laptop.
I need to push this.
So I'm going to say get push, hyphen, hyphen, all origin.
This will push both the branch that I did check out on main and see Jenkins.
OC.
So this is going to our own private repository, the privacy project repository.
Okay.
You see that?
Two branches that went.
And now let's go to GitHub.
Refresh this page.
Okay for our repository, right?
And if you see the code, you should see here two branches, main and C.I. Jenkins.
And that's how we migrated the repository from one account to other account.
One final thing in this video, we will be integrating our GitHub repository with our VTS code.
So go back to get bash.
Make sure you're in the repository and run the command code dot which will open your VTS code editor.
Nola.
Okay.
All right.
Now let's do some test here.
You should know how to commit from voice code.
Commit and push from Vsco to your GitHub repository.
So let's make some test.
Let's go to read MCM file and here there are a few hash.
Let's add a few more hash.
So just for the test, do control TSS which will save this file.
And as soon as you save the file, you will see when notification pops here.
Source Control, click on that.
And here there is a drop down button you can commit and push at the same time.
So you click on it and push.
See?
Yes.
Okay.
If you get this error, click on open git log.
If you're using GitHub git for the first time from your computer, you will get this error.
It is asking you to set your email and your username so all you need to do is just copy this command,
go to get bash or terminal paste it and oops I made a mistake.
Let's fix it.
Directly pasted execute executed also.
So let's give the user dot email.
I'm going to see I am now dev ops at gmail.com.
It's better you give the same email address that you use to create your GitHub account.
And then.
User dot.
Name.
And you can do anything you want.
I'm just going to give my name.
Okay.
This is good.
Now, what it does is it creates a file.
Tilde slashdot git config this file.
That you'll have your email and your username, which it will use to store the information when it is
doing a comment.
So that's done.
Let's go back and let's do once again commit and push.
Yes.
Now either it will open up a window for you to give a commit message or it will open up this file where
you can write a commit commit message.
So I will say first.
Commit type some message and say, put this.
Just checkmark.
Accept this, commit message and save.
And wait for this done.
It is done.
If you want to check that.
Go to your GitHub account.
And you can see readmitted file 43 seconds ago.
Committed.
Right.
All right.
I know a lot of work, but extremely important to do for this project.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.