Okay, so since we have everything set up now, we will start creating our pipeline.
Now, our pipeline needs some dependency.
The first stage of our pipeline is build the artifact from the source code and.
Our artifact will be built by Maven.
So we need to have Maven, and Maven needs JDK Java Development Kit.
Now, we already installed it in Jenkins and in Jenkins we have JDK 11.
So before we run our job, before we create and run our job, we need to make sure we have JDK eight
and MAVEN in the Jenkins and I will show you how to do that.
You need to go to manage Jenkins.
Global tool configuration.
From here we can configure the tools that Jenkins will use.
There is JDC installation and if you scroll down you should see here Maven.
So first lets click on Add JDK.
And we are going to give here a name.
Oracle, JDK eight.
You can give any name, but whatever name you give, make sure you remember it.
And just to be on the safe side, just use the same name I'm using.
This is just a name here.
We have to select what version of Java will be installed.
Now this is one way of installing a JDK.
You select here the JDK eight and you will get here an option to enter the username and password of
Oracle.
You can create an Oracle account and then put a checkmark and that is it.
You can use it.
But the problem recently, we're having a lot of problems with this.
Jenkins is not able to download this JDK from Oracle account.
So we're going to do this.
We are not going to do this install automatically.
We're going to uncheck that option, uncheck this option.
It should be unchecked and we will install a JDK from the command line and then specify its path over
here.
So all you need to do is just switch to the Jenkins instance.
So let's copy its public IP and let's do a search to it.
As I said, chive and I downloads.
So whatever key you have with the Jenkins, specify that and do a search.
So, yes.
Okay, so we just need to run two commands.
One is sudo apt update.
And sudo apt install open.
JDK hyphen eight hyphen JDK.
So we already have JDK 11 in this Jenkins For our project, we need JDK eight.
So it installing predicate.
So you have to JDK in the Jenkins, JDK 11 and JDK eight.
So but if you run the command Java hyphen version.
You should see JDK or Java 11 being used, and that is fine.
Jenkins runs on that.
That is okay.
So how does in the tools we specify JDK eight.
So I'll show you the pseudo hyphen.
I am less user lib jvm.
Oops.
User lib JVM.
So you see in this we have two folders here.
One is Java 1.8 and one is Java 11.
So if you're multiple versions of Java, it's home.
Directories will be here.
So all we need to do is specify this path as the home directory.
So user lib JVM.
Slash.
And this one.
1.8.
Remember Java?
1.8, Not 11.
Not anything else.
Just this one.
Get the spot and then we go back here and we just paste the part over here.
So specifying that this is the Java home directory that you need to use.
So this is open JDK and I have given here name as Oracle JDK.
That is because later we will be using in our code the name as Oracle JDK eight with whatever you give
over here, make sure you remember that or you can come back and check the name so you can specify the
correct name of the tool that you're using in your code.
But for now, this is this.
Just install open JDK and specify its path over here.
That is all.
Scroll down.
Go to MAVEN section, click on Add Maven and this is pretty simple.
You just give the Maven name, so I will give here Maven.
Maven three.
And to select whatever three version it is there.
And that's all save.
Okay, one more thing.
We need to save the Nexis login credential so Jenkins can later use it to upload the artifact.
So we'll go to manage credentials here.
Click on Jenkins.
Global credentials.
And you see a button here, add credentials.
Click on that.
Kind keep user name password give the next login username, which is admin and the password that you
have set for next login.
And give some name here.
I'm going to give Nexus login and again, keep the same name.
If you wish to give different name, make sure you remember that while writing the code.
Create.
All right.
It's time to write the code, run the build job, so we'll go to a VTS code.
Let's click here.
Let's go to the Jenkins file and just select and delete everything.
We'll write it from the scratch.
So first is Pipeline.
Open and close.
Bring it down.
Agent any.
So it can run directly on Jenkins without mentioning any agent.
Tools.
We are using two tools here.
One is Maven.
The other one is JDC.
So make sure you give the same name that you have added in the Jenkins MAVEN three Oracle JDK eight
next stages.
And in that we will have the stage.
Which is for the build.
In that stage.
We have the steps.
And it is going to be a shell command.
Maven.
Come on.
Which is this?
Make sure you put it in single code.
MV and hyphen SX settings dot xml.
We'll go to that file in a moment.
Hyphen the skipped test.
So it is not going to run any test.
So basically it's going to run an install while it is doing it is going to pass some settings and it
will skip the unit test.
Now about the settings, now we want our maven to download dependencies from Nexus.
And that is specified in the XML file.
If you click on this XML file, scroll down.
At the end you see here repository.
The section.
Repositories repository ID.
There is a variable.
We will be defining all these variables so the ID and the URL from where to download the dependency.
So that is the URL and these are the variables.
We will be replacing it with.
The values will mention the variables.
It will replace it with the value.
So next this group repository URL from where it is going to download all the dependencies.
Now, while it wants to download, it also needs other details like what is your proxy repository?
What is the username password?
All those things.
These details are mentioned in the settings XML file.
In the settings dot XML file, you have servers.
Here we have the snapshot repository.
It's username and password.
So this is the nexus username and password release Repository Central repository and group repository.
So in the mirrors here we have the central repository.
So this is supposed to be the proxy, but we grouped the repository together.
So it's going to be the group repository URL and for the authentication, it will take it from here.
Now, if you're a Java guy, you'll understand it very quickly.
If you are not, do not worry.
It's pretty simple, this opening and closing you need to remember.
Mirrors, for example, mirrors.
And that's the opening and slash mirrors.
In those symbol.
This is the closing.
Then the mirrors you have.
Mirror, mirror.
This is the opening and this is the closing.
You will have an ID here for the mirror.
The name of the mirror, The URL of the mirror.
Now the word a mirror is generally used for the URL of a repository or information about a repository.
In Java and Linux.
That's the word used.
And then like that you have server section here.
If you go back to XML, you have your repository section opening and closing.
You need to remember that.
So once again.
Maven is going to look for the repository, this URL for the information that is going to go to the
settings dot XML, get the information from here mirrors and its authentication and server information
from the server entries.
But one piece here is missing.
Still, we have the variables here.
These are all the variables dollar and the curly brace.
These are the variables we need to define these variables that we will define in the Jenkins file.
So just before the stages section here.
Over here.
I will say environment open and close.
And I'll define all the variables that is used in settings dot XML and XML file.
There.
That was quick.
I know.
I just copy paste it.
But you can also do if you copy paste if you want, you can use this Jenkins file from the resource
section, but I recommend you type.
So snappy repo variable value is this v pro file hyphen snapshot.
This is the repository that we created in nexus right?
Nexus Username.
Nexus Password Release Repository name Central Repository name nexus IP that I need to change.
Also you need to change.
So let's go to easy to console.
Nexus and get the private you can not the public IP, private IP.
They are in the same network.
They connect with each other with private IP.
So just give the private IP for data at one Nexus group Repository Name Nexus login.
This we will be using later.
Not now, but still.
I have given you already added the credential.
This is the Nexus login credential name.
They are in the jenkins.
We added nexus login credential.
Just check once again opening and closing properly.
Pipeline opens here and there.
It closes so it highlights stages.
Opening and closing this one stage here, click on that.
That's the stage steps also for the environment variable opening and closing.
So if you click on that curly brace right, it will show you the ending.
Curly brace closing.
Curly All right.
For the tools, we are good.
I'm going to click on control SCE hit control s on your keyboard.
Save it.
Right.
There goes.
Okay, Drop down, comment and push.
So, yes.
You will commit message, I will say including.
Build, job save.
So now we have to click on this checkmark.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's pushing the change.
Okay, that's done.
Let's go to now Jenkins and finally create the job that we wanted from a long time.
At least I wanted to do it for a long time.
Click on New item.
Let's give a name.
We profile CI pipeline.
I will keep all small caps and small create confusion.
So let's keep all small here.
Click on Pipeline.
Say, okay.
Okay, Come down.
Pipeline Script.
Pipeline script from Sxm.
Click on that.
And we select here get.
And we give a repository.
So let's go to our GitHub repository.
Not the Vpro file repository.
This is your own repository, right?
Can that.
Yeah, that's the repository that we created.
Click on this dropdown code and search.
Copy that URL.
Go back to Jenkins.
The you are here now.
In a moment, it's going to throw an error.
Yeah, that one.
And we'll fix that.
Let's add the credentials here.
So add.
Jenkins.
Now we authenticate with our GitHub account with the Keys search key that we have saved here.
We saved the public key and we need to store the private key here.
So on the kind, say a search username with private key.
I'd let's say GitHub log in description.
I also a GitHub login.
Username get.
And private key.
Click on Enter directly here.
Ad and you need to paste the private key over here that we created previously.
Okay, I can clear the screen.
Okay, so cat, tilde, slash dot search, slash, ID, underscore RSA.
This is the private key.
Copied properly.
No extra space.
Right.
Copy here.
Right click.
Copy.
Look at the path once again.
This is the key that we created previously and paste it here.
So Jenkins will also use the same key to authenticate your GitHub account.
Say add.
And select your credential.
Okay, that's done.
But this error is still not going.
This is because it is doing search and it is asking a question.
Do you want to connect it?
Yes or no?
And Jenkins cannot answer that behind the scene.
So we need to search to the Jenkins and make sure we store the GitHub identity.
So get.
The Jenkins Public IP.
And so such hyphen I tilde slash downloads the profile.
It's a high profile city open to trade IP.
So a search to the Jenkins server.
Strange.
I think I copied the wrong IP.
Now I will correct the username I have given wrong.
Open to spelling mistake there.
Yeah.
Okay, clear the screen.
Switch to route user.
From here you have to switch to the Jenkins user.
There is a Jenkins user that is trying to do a search to GitHub account.
And here to run this command.
Replace this URL with your GitHub account.
Copy the repository URL.
Okay.
Lets hate enter here.
Yeah.
And say yes.
So it stores the identity of GitHub into the Jenkins user.
This is where it will store such known host.
Now, it will give you this error.
But don't worry, we don't want to log into that GitHub account here.
We just wanted to store the identity key.
That's done.
Now let's go back to Jenkins.
Okay.
All right, let's do one.
Yeah.
You switch the credentials or you can refresh, but just switch the credential and you will see the
error goes away.
Okay, Come down and make sure you give your branches.
Sy hyphen Jenkins.
You do not have a master branch.
You have the branch ci hyphen jenkins.
And in that branch we have the Jenkins file.
Right.
Jacob Jenkins file.
That's in our repository.
So it's going to fetch the repository.
Take the code from the Jenkins file and execute it.
Let's see if this.
And let's do the test now.
Showtime.
Click on Build Now.
Okay.
It's going to take some time.
Let's click on this progress button here, symbol here, and we'll see what happens.
Okay.
And that started working.
I guess first our code.
That means authentication is working.
And you see there it is installing there, Maven and JDK, you see that.
So the tools that we added it is installing that first.
Okay.
Running our MAVEN command.
Okay, so there it failed.
It failed for a reason because it is not able to find these variables value.
And I thought of fixing this and showing it to you, you know.
But I thought, you know, you should see this error.
You see this variable, right?
It is.
There's there's no value to it.
So let's go to our VTS code.
And let's look at the variables.
Right?
It's snap, underscore, repo nexus, underscore, user nexus, underscore, pass.
It's all underscore there.
Right.
Let's go to settings dot XML and you see here we have hyphen nexus iPhone user nexus hyphen pass.
All right.
So you need to change all that hyphen to underscore so snap underscore repo nexus underscore user nexus
underscore pass.
I'm going to pause the video and do it.
Okay.
I've come to hear.
Everywhere.
Wherever you see invariable hyphen, just replace it with underscore save.
Let's go to pom dot xml.
Bombed out.
Also you have variable underscore.
Their nexus underscore.
Now, if you're thinking, why not just change the variable name?
Right.
But here it is.
Previously this hyphens were allowed, but now in Jenkins, the hyphen is an illegal character in Jenkins
file.
Pipeline code.
Right.
And this.
The hyphen is an illegal character.
So we replace it with underscore.
Right.
Make sure you save this file.
Control less control less save.
Check it once again, I'm going to validate my screen and check once again.
Okay.
I think I'm good.
I'm going to say commit and push.
It's.
And we'll write a message replaced hyphens with underscore.
Watching.
Mark.
See you.
Wait till it sinks.
Let's go to GitHub.
Sorry, Jenkins.
And let's test it once again.
Will Now.
Okay, let's click on this loading bar.
Okay.
Things are working, you see.
It's downloading the dependencies from Nexus now.
See that?
And Nexus in turn is downloading from the MAVEN repository.
I'm going to pause my screen.
This is going to take some time.
All right.
It is a success.
Good job.
If it's not working for you, make sure you check the variable names properly once this is successful.
So what happened is downloaded the dependency from nexus.
Build the artifact, and it stored those dependencies in the Jenkins itself.
It creates a local repository.
So when you click on build now once again.
So it will already have the dependencies.
You see the next job, it's not going to download any dependency because it's already downloaded and
kept it in the jenkins.
Right.
If you go to Nexus.
I was logged out.
So login, go to browse section, click on this and go to browse and go to MAVEN Group repository.
See, these are all the dependencies it has stored it in the Nexus.
And it is coming actually from here.
It's stored here.
The problem even central.
See that?
So group will show all the repositories together.
Okay.
This is awesome.
But there's one problem.
Every time we commit, push our code.
We need to come here and click on build.
Now how about that is automated.
And actually that's how it is supposed to be.
Whenever you make a comment, the pipeline should trigger automatically.
That's what we will be seeing in the next lecture.
So wrap this up and join me in the next one.