GitHub webhook.
The concept is pretty simple and the steps are also very, very simple to to do it.
So the concept is whenever we make a comment, we are writing our code in verse code.
And when we do comment we go to the Jenkins and we click on Build.
Now it should run the job automatically whenever there is a change in the code.
That's the concept.
I'm doing.
It is also very simple.
Few things you need to take care of.
Make sure the Jenkins Security Group.
Jenkins Security Group.
Allows port 88 from anywhere port 88 from any IPV four, sorry, IPV four and any IPV six.
They should be there.
If it's already there, you're good.
So copy the Earl of Jenkins.
Now, if you are going to complete this project today, then only do this.
If you're done for today, then pause the video, close everything, shut down everything, and then
start from this lecture tomorrow.
Why?
Well, because the public IP that we are using of Jenkins, we're going to store it in GitHub.
And if you shut down Jenkins and power on its public IP will change.
I'll show you what I'm telling.
So copy the URL and go to your repository.
Repository setting.
Again, make sure it's your repository, not mine settings, and click on web hooks.
And they add a webhook.
And you pace the you are here and with this you have to give at the end.
GitHub hyphen webhook slash make sure that forward slash at the end that is there.
If you don't have that, it will not work just for slash at the end.
So I was saying this right, if you power off the easy to instance and you power on again, the IP will
change and then you need to come here and update it again.
And I know it's pretty simple to make change, but if the webhook doesn't work, you must be wondering
what's happening.
So that's why I said.
If you're starting if you're doing this, make sure you complete the project today.
Okay.
Content type JSON.
Jason, if you're wondering how to do that in real time, it's pretty simple.
You use the elastic IP in EC2 or you create a load balancer in front of Jenkins.
That's the other way, but elastic IP and load balancer both will not be free.
So that's why we are not doing it.
We are saving some money.
Okay, so whenever there is a commit, it is going to send a JSON payload and keep on saying commit,
commit.
But you can select different, different events also here.
Let me select individual events.
You know, if you're creating a new branch or a tag or if you're deploying new keys, there are many
actions that if someone forks the repository, there are many actions that gets executed on GitHub repository.
Based on your use case, you can select individual events or you can just say no.
If whenever there is a push event, just run the webhook.
Let's see, add webhook.
Okay.
Let's click on this and let's look at the recent deliveries.
Oh, there's a check mark Green check mark.
That is good.
It means it is able to deliver this to the Jenkins.
Jenkins responded back, No, the job did not get triggered.
This is just a test, a ping.
You see that?
It's kind of a ping.
So if it shows Red Cross mark, make sure you check the URL.
Make sure you check the IP.
It is correct.
Make sure Jenkins Security Group allows 88 from anywhere.
Once you fix it, you can.
Re deliver it.
You know, we can test it once again.
Right.
So that's there.
And now we will go to our job.
Jenkins job configure and just a simple check mark here git hub hook trigger for git ACM polling.
Put this checkmark on and save it.
That's it.
It's configured.
Now it's time to test it.
So.
Let's go to a code.
Jenkins file.
Okay.
After this step, I'm going to add here one more section post post installation step.
Once this is completed, what to do?
Well, just print a message.
Now, archiving and we are using this archive artifact plugin.
Which is already installed.
Archive Artifact That's the name of the plugin space artifacts colon and you give the argument this
basically tells that archive everything that ends with dot var.
Now that's the extension of our artifact.
Let me show you.
So click on any job that executed successfully.
And click here on workspaces.
Right.
That's the link.
Click on that.
Okay.
So these are all the data.
The Jenkins pulls the source code and builds the artifact target.
You should have the artifact.
We profile hyphen v two dot var.
So our command simply says find all the file that ends with dot where and archive it.
That's what it says and we'll need that for later purpose.
So we're adding that step.
So that's the post step.
In the same stage, we will add a few more stages here.
So come here.
Where the stage end.
And I'm pasting a code here.
Two more stage.
Pretty simple stage name is test and the step is it is executing a shell command and we can test which
will run our unit test.
It will generate some report that will later upload on Sonar Cube.
But for now we're just running this command textile analysis.
We are running one more maven shell command here argument checks tile colon check style which is going
to use a check style.
This is a code analysis tool which will check for any issues with your code and suggest you on best
practices on vulnerabilities.
I've talked about this in detail in DevOps Beginner's two advanced course.
So two kinds of test.
Unit test.
And could analysis with check style.
Both are Maven command and they're basically shell command that we are executing.
So see if this.
And commit and push.
Now, when we commit and push, it should trigger our job automatically.
Okay.
We'll see.
Updated pipeline with unit test and code.
Analysis.
And see this.
Save.
Yeah.
Alright.
Singing the changes, pushing it and done.
Let's now go to Jenkins and let's see.
This should trigger the job.
There you see that fourth job ID pending.
So it's waiting started.
Nice.
Let's click on this.
Scroll down.
Okay.
This completed, but it is downloading dependency from the MAVEN repository, not from the Nexus because
we missed the command hyphen settings.
So whenever we have the maven come out, we will give it a hyphen, a settings, not XML.
Life in a setting starting similar.
Save it once again.
Let's commit and push.
Make a commit message.
Checkmark save.
And let's wait once again.
Okay.
That again triggered the job or the pipeline.
Let's see now.
Okay.
Now the dependencies are already downloaded in Jenkins.
It's downloading from the Nexis again.
Nice.
Now, this may be a little slower than May repository.
But when you have to use repository manager like Nexus, then you have to then you need to use it.
All right anyways.
Go ahead, test it.
If you need the code, download it from the resource section.
Complete this and join me in the next lecture.