All right.
So we see our pipeline, we have you stage, we have build test external analysis.
So it's building the artifact.
We have seen that in the workspace.
It's running test unit test which generates reports.
It's doing checks to the analysis which also generate reports.
Let's see that in the workspace.
Let's go to the job.
Number five, build ID workspaces.
You click on this and let's go to the target.
So there you have textile result data XML and then you also have sure file reports.
Now these are not really human readable reports.
We need some tool that can store this, analyze it and present it in a proper human readable format.
And that is Soner Kube server a dashboard for your code analysis and your unit test results we have
set up, so our cube server might be tested.
We logged in and we tested.
It's working fine now we need to write the code so it scans.
The code, generate reports and upload it to the Sona Cube server.
And in order to do that, we need two things in Jenkins.
One, we need a sonar scanner tool like we have MAVEN tool, get tool, JDK tool.
We need a sonar scanner tool which will scan the code.
And second, we need the sonar cube server information in Jenkins so Jenkins will know where to upload.
So let's go to Dashboard.
Manny Jenkins.
First, we will set up the sonar scanner tool.
So let's go to Global Tool Configuration.
It's pretty simple.
Just select the tool.
Scroll down sooner Kub scanner.
There you see Arizona Kub scanner.
Give you a name.
I'm giving sonar scanner again for simplicity.
You also give the same name because this is the name we'll be using in our code, that's all.
It's just like adding Maven tool save.
Go to configure system.
Now we need to store the server cube server information in Jenkins.
So go to configure system.
Scroll down, find the sooner section.
Their sonar cube server environment say add sonar cube.
Put this checkmark here.
We will limit as sooner server.
And the sooner you are.
HTTP, colon, slash, slash, and the private IP of the server.
Let's go to s two instances.
So in our server.
Now if you're doing this project for multiple days.
Then you would have already understood the benefit of using private IP.
Yeah, security is one, but the second one is private IP static.
It does not change.
So we power off.
For instance, power on.
We don't need to make changes to the IP addresses.
Okay, come down and you'll have one problem here when you click on credential.
So server authentication token, you need to store the Sonner token here and we'll generate this owner
token first let's go to projects.
Sorry, go to Sona.
Q So on the server dashboard, log in, click on this administrator here and go to my account.
Security.
Give it a name in the generate tokens and say generate.
Now this is for the authentication.
How does Jenkins authenticate to owner cube server that will be with this token?
So copy this token.
Make sure you store it temporarily somewhere.
I do it on the sticky note.
Okay.
So that was our token.
And yeah, so the problem was talking about right when you click on try, try to click on add here.
To add the token, it doesn't do anything.
That's one problem that's been there from a long time.
So all you need to do is just save this.
And come back once again.
Go to Manny Jenkins configure system.
Come down, find your sonar section, and now you click on ADD.
See, that appears.
Click on that Jenkins here.
And kind.
Select.
Secret text.
We are just going to store the token in the text.
Secret.
Paste the secret here the token.
I'll just give a name.
I'll just say the token.
So not token and say add.
And make sure you select the token.
Okay.
That should be selected.
Otherwise you'll have authentication problem.
Yeah.
Here the you are.
You don't need to give Colon 9000 because as I have told you previously, while we are setting up the
queue, we are running engine service in that that runs on port eight.
We are directly accessing it on Port eight.
We're not giving any port here.
So just give the private IP that is it save.
Okay.
So that was the setup.
Now you're going to write the code that is going to upload all the reports to the owner cube server.
And this can get slightly confusing or complicated.
But don't worry.
I'm going to show you the documentation.
Okay.
So I did a simple Google sonar scanner for Jenkins.
I'll put the URL in the resources.
So sonar scanner for Jenkins.
That's the first link.
Click on that.
So we have installed sonar plugin.
That's how we are able to add the sonar information in Jenkins.
But about the code.
We check from the documentation.
Okay.
That's the one, the simplest one.
Let me zoom this one.
So this is what you need to put in your pipeline with solar cube environment and you need to give the
environment name.
Now, this is the sonar scanner name that we have given in Jenkins.
Let me show you.
We go to Manager Jenkins, configure system.
All right.
In the solar cube section here, we have given SONA server, so that is basically the environment name.
Right.
And you can pursue that argument here.
And between this curly braces, you can give the options.
We'll see what options we'll be giving.
Right.
So you can go through this documentation, see.
All right.
One more example here is Shell Command.
So on the scanner home.
There's basically the tool, the sonar scanner tool that we added in.
Jenkins Right.
So with that tool that basically runs the scanning on the code, you can pass more options with that.
We have many more options to pass because we have to upload the unit test results, we have to upload
the check style result and few other things.
All right.
So you can scan with the sonar scanner, you can scan with Gradle, you can scan with Maven.
You see that Maven also has a plugin to scan the code with Sonar Cube.
All right, so take your time.
Go through this in real time like this, you need to find the documentation for your plug in and put
that in your code.
Yes.
You do not need to by heart this this is not at all required.
There's documentation everywhere nowadays.
Okay.
So we'll also do the similar thing with a few more options.
I'll show you that.
Let's go to VS Code.
Faust.
We will put some variables here that we'll be using in our code.
So sonar server equal to sonar server.
This is the sonar server environment name.
We're storing it as a variable sonar scanner.
That's the sooner scanner name that we have given.
So on the scanner, yeah.
If you're given a different name in Jenkins, then this.
Make sure you put it.
Let me check that once again.
That's so sad.
Well, that is correct.
Global tool configuration.
So in the scanner.
Yeah.
That's the name for the tool.
So upfront I created two variables for it, so I don't need to update my code later.
Okay.
Let's come down.
So it's going to be another stage.
And that's this.
I know.
It's pretty simple.
Don't worry.
Stage so analysis.
Environment.
So environment variable.
We're giving sonar scanner home and the tooling, that's the variable.
So that global variable we are storing into this local variable or you can directly give the global
variable name here.
So stage, it has a variable with environment.
We mentioned the variable steps and this is where we give the code.
So under Cuba environment and that's the variable which has the environment name and we are running
sonar scanner tool and passing here multiple options.
Just like we give options or argument in maven similar to that.
Let's see sona dot project key v profile.
That's going to be the project key name then project name v profile project version 1.0 source.
What will be the source code that it needs to scan so CRC slash.
Now that is the directory or folder in our source code.
Let's see that.
Right.
So it fetches this repository.
It has a CRC directory.
So this is the directory that it is going to scan.
That's what I meant by sooner dot sources.
Z slash.
That's the Java binary part.
This is all in the workspace reports part.
This is a unit test report.
Target.
Sure.
Fire reports.
One more report.
Spa exec checks style reports bath.
And if you're wondering, what are these names?
How did I get it?
All I got from the documentation like that, you can pass many parameters to the scanner scanner.
So this basically scans our code.
Take all the reports and upload it to this Cerner server environment, which is stored in Jenkins.
Once again, take a look at all the arguments.
That's the project key name.
This is the project name.
This will appear in the Scanner Cube server version directly to scan Java Binary Report Part one Ensure
for report.
Another one is cocoa.
And then the check style reports part.
We run check style here.
Right.
So it generates the report at this location.
Now we can go to the workspace and check all these files exist in our workspace.
Okay, time to test.
Let's see if this.
And say, go ahead and push.
So give a commit message.
Put that checkmark save.
Okay.
Let's go to Jenkins and check.
Job number six started.
Okay.
Scroll down.
We see a success here and you see it is an analysis successful.
You can browse it from this URL, but we know that's that's the private IP.
We won't be able to check from there directly go to the owner cube server projects.
And there you see that we profile it has 32 bugs, zero vulnerability, 138 code smells.
Now I'm not getting into this.
I just want you to upload the result here and check for the quality.
And it seems quality is parsed.
Everything is good because it has its own quality.
GATES And if you come to Jenkins here.
All right, so go to the job, scroll down and you'll see sonar.
Sonar cue quality get passed for the profile project.
Now this is because it is using default quality gate and as per it, everything is good but.
You may have certain rules for your project and you need to create your own quality gates as well.
Most of the time it is done.
So let's see in the next lecture how we can create our own quality gates and the rule and make sure
it fails the pipeline if the gates if the quality is not passed.