Talking about the quality gates.
We have to set up quality gates on the server cube server.
It's already there for this project.
So in for a profile project, if you go to project settings.
You will see quality gate.
And you will see a default quality get so nervy.
And if you go to quality gates here, click on this and you can see the rules that are set on this quality
gates.
Now, we really not going into these rules, we'll just create our own quality gate with a simple rule
and see if it works or not.
So let's click on Create and create a quality gate.
I'm just giving the name of profile shg save.
And there's no rule.
We'll add rule here.
We'll say add condition.
And will see on overall code and there are many things over here to select from.
I will go for bug because we have seen there are like 30 bugs.
Right.
So let's see if the call if the bug is 25.
Right, it's greater than 25.
Because I want this job to fail.
I want to show you how it fails the pipeline.
So we know that overall bugs are 30 something we are giving 25.
So if this quality gate is applied, then project quality aids will fail.
Okay, so we created a quality gate with a simple rule bugs greater than 25.
Let's go to the projects, click on the project and you need to attach that quality gate through to
this project.
So project setting.
Call the gate and select.
Your quality it.
Okay.
We have to do one more thing over here.
Just like GitHub sends a webhook to Jenkins.
When Jenkins uploads this result, it is going to also wait for Sona server to respond with the result.
We'll add that in the code.
But how does Sona Cube knows?
Where is Jenkins and how to send the information?
That is true to the webhook of this project.
So project settings.
Web hooks.
This seemed like GitHub, but this is for sending the result to Jenkins.
So create a webhook.
Give a name.
I will say Jenkins webhook.
And you have to add this URL.
Make sure there's Jenkins IP here.
Let's get the Jenkins private IP.
Yeah.
Here we can use private IP because they are in the same network.
Nexus owner Cube Jenkins.
They're in the same network.
But GitHub is a different thing altogether on the internet.
Okay.
So the so sorry the Jenkins IP colon 88 slash sona cube hyphen webhook.
Exactly as how you see on my screen.
Except you'll have a different IP for your Jenkins and they create.
Okay.
So that is done here.
Now let's write the code.
So this uploads the result.
But we'll put here one more stage which will wait for the quality gate result.
Okay.
So this is one more stage.
So just after the stage.
So the analysis stage.
Discord.
This is pretty simple.
This is the stage name is quality gate step is time out after one hour.
You can give here the minutes also if you want.
It's going to timeout after one hour when?
This does not respond.
So this plugin here wait for quality gate abort pipeline.
True.
Actually that's really the code timeout is so it doesn't wait for infinity.
It waits for maximum one hour.
You can reduce the time or increase it based on how the analysis goes for you.
And the stage name is Quality Gate.
Let's save this.
Again, this is all code available on the ownership documentation that I have shown you, so you can
copy paste from there and make the changes also.
Literally copy pasted from there and did not make any change at all.
See sooner quality gates.
Okay.
So I made the comment.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Here.
Okay.
Let's wait till this job finishes.
I'm going to pause my video.
Okay.
The pipeline is failed, but we need to see why it failed.
Right.
So click on that.
Go till the end.
And pipeline aborted due to quality gate failure.
It got an error.
Make sure it fails for this reason and not that your code is wrong or syntax is wrong because that will
be another kind of failure.
That's what we wanted.
This is what we intended.
Now, in order to make sure this pipeline passed, we're going to just go to our quality gates and just
raise the bar a little bit.
We profile G.
Instead of 25 will give here 100, like 100 bucks we can tolerate.
And then let's run the pipeline.
We have to run the pipeline manually because we did not make any code change.
So now.
Wait for it to complete.
Okay.
That completed successfully because Quality Gate came out fine.
You see that quality gate is okay.
That's pretty awesome.
We tested our code left, right and center unit test style.
So the scanner and we see our artifact is good.
Now it's time.
To upload our artifact to Nexus Server.
That's what we'll see in the next lecture.
So wrap this up and join me in the next one.