All right.
The last stage in our pipeline is to upload the artifact to an repository.
So in our pipeline code, if we scroll up here, we are archiving the artifact.
And once it is done, you should be seeing here last successful artifact artifact.
You can also go to the job ID, build ID, and you can check in the workspace.
Target from here we are going to upload the artifact.
That's our artifact.
And this needs to be uploaded to Nexis repository.
We created the profile release repository.
This one.
Over here, and every time we upload a new artifact, it should have a different version number.
And the best approach for that is a timestamp.
We need to rename.
This artefact with the timestamp.
And for that purpose we had already installed a plugin build timestamp plugin.
We need to set its value, so you need to go to manage Jenkins.
Configure system.
Scroll down.
You should see a section here.
Their build timestamp.
You can set a time zone and this will be the pattern.
We will change it a little bit.
We'll remove this z and we will just use 2yy.
That is four years, the last two number of the year.
And we'll give you an underscore or let's keep it hyphen, hyphen, hyphen underscore.
So year hyphen month hyphen date underscore our and so here.
We will remove the seconds.
So that's the bill timestamp value.
That will be the pattern of it.
Let's save this and we'll find from the documentation the pipeline code to upload the artifact to Texas
repository.
So let's do a little Google search.
Nick says artefact uploader that's the name of the plugin or you can simply google how to upload artifact
to Nexus using Jenkins Pipeline.
So this documentation from Jenkins itself, there is this GitHub link.
This one, click on this one.
So that's the GitHub link for this plugin we scroll down.
So this is for the Dstl domain specific language and this is for the pipeline.
So you just need to take this code and create a stage and put this code over there.
So let's do that.
Let's go to our VTS code.
Let's come down and stage.
Yeah.
This is where the stage ends.
Okay.
So you need to create a stage.
Stage?
I've given the name as upload artifact.
Open and close curly brace steps.
So in the step, there goes your plugin information.
So next test version.
Next is three.
We're using Nexus three, protocol http.
Next this URL.
So I've given here variable access IP colon next to these variables we have already defined there.
You should add here in Nexus private IP and port 8081, you should also have here Nexus login variable
and its value should be the Nexus login credential which you saved in Jenkins.
So in manage Jenkins manage credentials.
Jenkins.
Global credentials.
So that is the credential.
We saved it very early and that's the ID you have to use the ID, so make sure all the variable values
are correct.
Come down.
Group ID Cuba that will create a folder with the name Cuba.
It will put our artifact inside that.
And for versioning we are using these variables.
These are the Jenkins built in variables.
You can access them by giving e and v dot build underscore ID that will give us the build ID, which
is if we go and come here in the Jenkins job in the pipeline.
So the previous build ID was eight.
And when we run the next pipeline, the build ID number will be nine.
Bill Timestamp.
We have already said that now it's not mandatory to do it in the same fashion.
You can do it any other way for for budgeting, but you need something that changes after every build.
So build it will definitely change and build timestamp will change.
That's a very good combination for versioning.
Next is the repository where we want to upload it, which is a variable v file hyphen release is the
value of it.
So check the code.
The profile release.
Credentials.
This is the login credentials that we saved in Jenkins.
It's variable we have given over here.
Access underscore login.
And this is the information about access.
Now the information about the artifact that you want to upload.
So artifacts and there is a square bracket opening and closing there.
And inside that there is one more square bracket.
And in this, you have the list of arguments.
You can say artifact ID.
I have given here the pro app.
That will be the prefix for our artifact.
And file the artifact that you want to upload.
So we have given its path.
Target slash v profile hyphen v two dot var and type var.
So the artifact name will be like this v pro app hyphen builder id hyphen build timestamp dot var and
it will be uploaded into this repository and it will use this for the authentication on this Nexus server.
So it's usually like this you just copy, paste the code from the documentation, you make your entries
and then you test it.
So let's test it.
I'm going to do control s save it.
And then click here.
Chop down, commit and push.
Yes.
We'll see.
Upload artifact to Nexus Code.
Steve.
And let's see, the pipeline will be triggering in a moment.
That took a few seconds, but anyways.
Nine build.
89.
Let's see for ourself all the logs.
Okay.
So I made a mistake and it is in credentials.
ID you see that?
Exactly.
Suggesting also it's saying that it cannot be used directly.
Do you mean it like this?
So the difference is just basically the double quotes.
So let me fix that.
Yeah.
There.
We need to put the double codes.
Okay.
This one extra double code here.
All right, so all the variables should be like this in the double quotes.
Save.
And then let's commit and push.
Message fixed double quotes for variable checkmark save.
Seeking changes done to trigger another pipeline.
There.
Okay.
Let's scroll down.
This is going to take some time.
I'm going to pause my screen.
Okay.
There it completed.
Successfully uploaded.
Look at the URL here.
It's the Nexis URL repository slash the repository name QR repro app.
That's our artifact ID build timestamp.
Again, that's the artifact version.
Now, obviously this link will not work because that's the private IP will.
We'll go to the Nexus and we are already in the profile release.
Let's refresh this repository and there you see that artifact.
Now go ahead, run the pipeline a few more times.
You will see different different artifacts or maybe same artifacts with different names because we are
not making any code change really the source code.
So I'm going to just run it a few more times just from here, Bill, now.
So the big daddy was ten.
And you see the artifact we blow up hyphen ten.
That's the builder, the hyphen, the time stamp.
Now, this is not your computer's timestamp.
This is the Jenkins server time stamp.
And at the end dot var.
And then you have the link to download the artifact.
I'm going to say Control and click on this.
It opens in a new tab and see it's trying to download the artifact now save.
And we are downloading the artifact.
And this is coming from the Nexus.
So the ops team, if you just have continuous integration, the ops team can download the artifact and
deploy to the servers or release it to the production.
The different mechanisms.
We're going to talk about the delivery part in continuous delivery project.
You can't let me refresh.
Okay.
So you see that?
One more artifact.
So like that, whenever a developer makes a code change, let's look at it once again.
Whenever the developer makes the code change, they commit to the repository.
It is going to build the artifact.
Download Dependency from Nexus Test Unit Test Code Analysis with textile sonar scanner analysis and
uploading all the results on the cube server.
If the quality gates are parsed, then it moves to uploading the artifact to the repository.
That's a complete continuous integration pipeline.
But.
One last thing.
We are coming to the Jenkins and checking whether it's passed or failed.
We can set up a notification system so we don't even need to check in the Jenkins.
We get the notification whether the bill is passed or failed.
And based on the result, we can take the next action or next step.
We will see that in the next lecture.
That is all in this one run.
This pipeline tested a few more times, generate a few artifact, wrap this up and join me in the next
lecture.