All right.
So let's do the final thing to complete our continuous integration pipeline, and that is notification
we will be using Slack.
Now, Slack is one of the most popular notification sorry collaboration tool that is used in IT industry,
but it's not just limited to that.
We're taking slack.
As an example.
You can use any kind of notification system, email notification, and there are a few other plugins
in Jenkins that you can use for notification.
Since Slack is pretty popular nowadays, we'll be using Slack.
Think of Slack as new generation Skype minus the video calls.
It's really a very good collaboration tool.
So we already installed a Slack plugin.
We need to create a Slack account.
Create a channel in that channel is seemed like we have groups.
And then we integrate that with the Jenkins.
And in our code, finally, we will put the stage to send notifications for any pass or field.
So let's search for Slack login.
Just search slack login.
And I will say continue with Google.
So I'll use my Google Mail, this one.
And just continue.
So Slack has these workspaces.
So one workspace, maybe a team or maybe a company where all the users are logged in or connected to.
And in that workspace, we can have different channels, like we have groups, for example, WhatsApp
group.
So in one workspace you can have many channels, many groups.
So we'll see create workspace.
And I will just give some name here like the profile we profile CCD.
That will be my workspace name.
Go next.
So what are we working on?
So let's just say DevOps, c, c, d.
If you want to add any individuals over here, I can give the email address and then they'll get a link
and they can also log in to your workspace.
So I just again give my same email address.
You can skip also this one I'll just say teammates and teammates.
So it will try to open a Slack app if you already have it installed.
So you can install Slack app and you can see Open Slack or you can just say cancel and open it from
the browser.
The recommended way is obviously the app.
Okay.
So it looks the same in the app you want you install the Slack app.
If you open you will see it's exactly similar.
So workspace name is V profile secede and we will create a channel here, create channel and will name
it as Jenkins 60.
And just created.
So this channel is like a group and you can add people in this group, you can give the name or their
email address.
If you already if the users are already have logged into this workspace, you can just give the name
or the email address.
We'll just say automatically add anyone who joins.
So anybody who joins the profile will be automatically added to this channel.
See this?
Okay.
Next.
In order for the Jenkins to authenticate to your workspace, we need to create a token in Slack.
For that, we need to add an app in your Slack account.
So just search for the.
Slack apps or add apps to Slack.
Click on this link.
Search for Jenkins app.
You'll get this Jenkins sigh.
Click on that.
Once see add this app to Slack.
And we choose the channel.
We will say this DevOps.
Oh sorry.
This one Jenkins CD add Jenkins CI integration.
And then it will also give you the steps of how to do this.
We are here just for this token.
So copy this token.
And store it somewhere for now.
So I keep it on my sticky notes.
And just come down.
You will see the token here.
Also, you can regenerate the token if you want, but just save the settings.
Okay.
Now we will go to Jenkins, install the plugin and do the integration.
Keep in mind, the workspace is V Profile CD and the channel is Jenkins CD.
So let's go to Jenkins.
Go to manage Jenkins Configure System.
Find Slack here.
It will be mostly down here.
At the end there we have slack.
So give the workspace which is the profile, secede and credentials.
We need to add the token here.
So add Jenkins.
So the kind you have to select is secret text.
And safe based your token here.
Check.
Yeah, that's the one.
Give an ID name and give a description.
I've just given sonar token.
No, not sonar.
My bad slack token.
So give a name.
Just add.
Select your token slack token and give the channel.
LIM So we have Jenkins secede.
And time to test the setting.
Let's click on Test Connections.
And there is a success.
Now, at time this may happen and you will get a failure over here.
That is probably while adding, while logging, creating workspace we make sometimes mistake.
So what you need to do is just if you are getting error, just sign out from here.
Sign in once again, do the whole setup once again, create the workspace, create channel, go through
the whole step again, create a new workspace, new channel name, install the app, get a token and
then save it and then test it if you get a failure.
But if you get a success, well then good.
Just save this.
Now we will add this information in our pipeline code.
So if there is a success or failure, we want it to send notification to our channel, this channel,
Jenkins said.
All right, so now let's add a post installation step.
So any of the stage fails, we should have a post installation step that sends the notification.
Okay.
Let me before that fix this indentation.
The square bracket matches this one.
So let me just bring it here.
And this parenthesis is for Nexus Artifact Uploader plugin.
So let's bring it here.
Okay, so we have these stages and let's trace this line.
Stage stages.
Line.
That's what that once here.
Now here.
That's where red line number 85, just after line number 85.
That's where the stage complete.
And here we are to start a post installation step.
Okay.
So I am entering the code over here.
I'll explain you that.
It's pretty simple.
Post open and close always block means always this will get executed.
So we are just doing an echo printing this message slack notification Slack sent.
This is the plugin that we installed and we are passing three arguments to it.
One is channel, one is the color and another one is the message.
So it will use all this information and we should see notification in our channel.
We have to give the channel name hash and our channel name is Jenkins Sicced.
Color.
You can use the color code, but here there is a function.
Or a key map that will create in a moment.
But this is how it will work.
Colored map will send this argument.
Current build.
Current result.
Let's see.
What is this current build?
So current build is a global variable that will have many properties like number result, current result,
display name, many other properties which you can fetch when you run the job.
This gets generated in the runtime, so we're using current build, current result.
Current result.
So this will typically return success or unstable or failure.
So what are we really doing with this?
So at the top of the pipeline, we will have a definition here.
So this is what it is calling color map.
And if the argument is parsed as success, it is going to return good.
So success variable value is good and good in Jenkins.
Sorry, good in slack means green color and danger in slack means red color.
So we are dynamically parsing slack the color code good or danger based on how it worked, how it parsed
or failed.
So if the current result is success, we send good color.
But if it returns failure, then we pass danger color code.
You will see how it works.
Next is the message.
What message do you want to send?
Now you can create your customized message we have.
We are giving over here current build current result variable which will give us success or failure.
We have seen that colon job, the text and the job name, which will be our pipeline name, build and
the build number.
And also we are sending the URL.
So the URL comes in the Slack channel.
If it is a failure, you get the link, you click on it.
You can you can see the logs.
All right.
So this can be customized message.
You can make some changes over here.
Alright.
So once you make all the necessary changes in the code, save it.
And let's push and commit.
Give a message.
Save.
That should trigger the pipeline once the changes are synched and once it is completed, we should receive
a notification.
So let's see the pipeline working.
First of all.
Yeah, the pipeline started.
That completed and we should see in the log.
Yeah.
Paused my screen.
It says it is that sending this notification.
Let's look in our Slack app and we see a success notification over here coming from Jenkins.
And you also see the URL.
You click on the other line, it's going to take you to to the job information.
There you can see the console output.
If it fail, you can see why it failed.
And then you can take the action.
So go ahead.
Try to fail.
The pipeline, the way you can fail it.
You make some syntax error committed and you see you get a failed notification.
Maybe over here will instead of MV and we will just make it a V in.
One.
Just some change.
So it feels right.
Save it.
Comment and push testing slack notification saying this.
So I'm not going to.
Jenkins Right.
I will be just waiting for the notification to come on my Slack channel.
Just open my Slack app.
Oh, you see that already?
We got it.
Failure, right?
And we can see why it failed.
All right.
And then you can go to the logs and you can check why it failed and then you can fix the problem.
Right.
So there could be a code related problem.
There could be your pipeline code problem or developers code problem, anything.
We get a notification and then we can see what to do with that.
And if you look at the color scheme, right, green is for success.
Red is for failure.
That's working pretty well.
And that's the message, the whole message that we have constructed there.
I think now you're getting the hang of it about this message build dot result, right?
And then the job name and then the build number and you can see more info at this build URL.
So all that is coming really well together.
And that concludes our project, our pipeline, the continuous integration pipeline completed.
Obviously fix the problem with the code, make sure the pipeline runs.
If you are continuing with the next lectures, it's fine.
Otherwise shut down power off sooner nexus and Jenkins because they are not in free tier.
Stop instances.
Stop.
Now, if you wish to delete Nexis and Sonar, you can.
But don't terminate Jenkins.
Keep it till the end of the course because we will need it in multiple projects.
Nexus If you recreate, make sure you follow the lectures and create all the repositories.
Make sure you do the post installation steps also and so on.
That is pretty simple.
You just need to bring it up.
Login.
Get the token.
If you're not willing to terminate, it's well and good.
Just shut them down.
There will be no charges if you just shut them down.
These three combine have eight, eight, eight GB of volume, that is 24 GB.
So volumes also come under free tier, it's less than 30 GB total.
So it comes under free tier instances are shut down, so there won't be any charges for it.
So just shut them down.
All right.
That was some good work.
Good job.
We'll be seeing in next upcoming projects.
Also, continuous delivery.
That is all in this project.
I will see you in the next one.