I'm in a management console and we're going to launch an easy two instance and install Jenkins on that.
So let's see the installation steps.
So search for Jenkins documentation.
You should find the link.
Jenkins dot IO.
The Jenkins documentation has improved now a lot.
Let's see.
Installing Jenkins.
So the subchapter is you can set it up on Docker, Kubernetes, Linux.
So let's see Linux.
So in Linux you have one two Fedora Red Hat and they're prerequisites and it's really very minimum.
We need really minimum one GB of RAM and some disk space.
So easy to instance should be fine for us the two micro.
So these are the steps for ubuntu installation.
Let's copy all this commands.
That's open text editor.
I will be using Sublime.
You can use Notepad, Notepad plus plus anything.
Let's paste all these commands.
At the end where you see app get installed.
Jenkins Just put a hyphen y.
Go at the top.
So these are the steps of installing Jenkins, but we also have some dependencies that we will be installing.
So for starts with sudo apt update and even before that we have to give this line hash, exclamation
slash bin slash bash.
Keep in mind if you don't give that line, we will be running it from user data.
If you don't give this line, this these commands or the script will not run from easy to user data.
We need to install jdc sudo apt install open.
JDK hyphen 11 hyphen jdc oops.
JDC hyphen y.
So now Jenkins doesn't support to run on JDK eight.
So we are going with JDK 11.
Next, we will also install MAVEN app, install maven hyphen VI so we can run our builds.
But I will be skipping this command for now.
We will see what happens if we do not install the correct tools, what errors we get, and how do we
fix it.
We'll see that.
So these are all the commands to install Jenkins.
Let's copy all this and let's go to our easy to console.
Let's see.
Launch instance.
We'll call it as Jenkins server.
One two.
You have to select here open to 20 and be very careful.
Open to 23 tier eligible this one and not any other.
Open to 20.
Okay, scroll down now.
We can we will start with t to micro, but if you see your Jenkins instance becomes unresponsive, then
you may need to increase its instance type from PT to micro to t to small.
I'm going to directly go with PT to Small here.
Keep it.
We will create a key pair.
They create new key pair and I will call it as Jenkins hyphen key.
Make sure the PEM file is selected here and they create key pair.
Let's save this.
Make sure the Jenkins key is selected there.
In the network setting, click on Edit.
We will create our own security group.
So select create new security group and give the name as Jenkins S.G. hyphen there.
So we need to allow rule as a search 22 from my IP and then add another rule which is 80 sorry, 8080
from my IP now 22.
So we can do such and 88, so we can access it from the browser.
And once your work is done for today, you shut it down.
Tomorrow you power on tomorrow, your public IP may change.
So you need to again come back to the security group of Jenkins and you have to say, edit rule and
my IP select again.
Your IP will change here.
Now in the advanced details, drop down, scroll down, go to user data, and let's copy your script
and paste it there.
A few things to verify.
Make sure hash exclamation bin bash is there and there is hyphen y wherever there is apt install command.
There's JDK 11.
And now let's launch this instance.
Click on that instance ID.
Okay.
After waiting for some time.
Let's check the user interface.
And it's installed successfully.
If you don't get this page, check the security group or log into the Jenkins and check the installation
steps.
So we need to unlock Jenkins and in and this file has the unlock password.
So we log into Jenkins now.
As such, Logan.
So if your installation, your user data does not go through, maybe there could be something wrong
in your user data shell script.
So you can check that by running the command curl and this URL.
This URL girl and this URL, they should return the user data script there.
So if there is a mistake then no problem.
You can run these commands manually one by one.
Let's check the status.
Sys CTL status.
Jenkins.
So Jenkins is active running.
Let's hit queue quit from this.
So if you see it's not active and running, you should see the user data what it is.
If you made a mistake, then run all the commands manually.
Let me clear the screen.
So once the Jenkins is installed, its home directory will be this var lib.
Jenkins.
So this is the home directory of Jenkins.
All the data of Jenkins will be in this directory, and this password file is also in the same directory.
Let's check the password.
That's the unlocked password.
So it will be random.
It will be different for every one.
Space the password and continue.
Okay, so Jenkins main powerhouse are its plug ins, huge collection of plug ins.
And Jenkins has so many popular plug ins, which Jenkins suggests that you should be installing that.
Or you can also select from the popular plug ins.
So lets select plug ins to install.
Now these are some popular plugins that you can go with and you have different section organization
and and administration.
You have these popular plugins.
Then you have build features plugin and this you have SSH agent.
So wherever it's checkmark, that plugin will be installed.
Build tool like maybe we don't want ADD and we want node.js.
So Jenkins is running on a Linux machine, so we will not be able to use RMS build.
But if you integrate Jenkins master with a Windows slave node, then we can run Windows build also.
We'll be seeing that in master slave concept.
Popular build analysis and reporting tools like Cobertura G-Unit.
So go through this list.
Check and uncheck a few.
Doesn't matter, really.
We are going to install plug in manually also.
Whenever the need comes, we'll find the right plugin and install them.
So I'm just going to say install.
And wait for few minutes till the installation is completed.
Time to set a user.
I'll set a user named admin and it will give some password to it.
You can set any user you want, that user will have full access.
Let's see when continue.
So at the time of installation, the Jenkins IP address is this.
So that is going to record in the Jenkins Earl.
And I want you to remember this because easy to instance that we are using is having dynamic IP.
You shut down and then you power on its IP will change.
That will not affect in accessing the Jenkins but there are a few places where we'll be using Jenkins
Earl or Jenkins will be using its own URL and that URL may be older one.
We'll see how to fix it when we get that problem.
But keep this in mind regarding your easy to instance.
If you need a static IP, then go for elastic IP.
But for learning purpose it should be fine.
Save and finish.
Start using Jenkins.
And it says Welcome to Jenkins.
Nice.
A new and better UI.
Okay.
So the first step you see here is creating a job.
And that's what we'll do first.