All right.
So we will be creating our first job.
It will be a build job.
So before we run our job, before we create and run our job, we need to make sure we have JDK eight
and MAVEN in the Jenkins.
And I will show you how to do that.
You need to go to manage Jenkins.
Global tool configuration.
From here we can configure the tools that Jenkins will use.
There is JDK installation and if you scroll down you should see here Maven.
So first lets click on Add JDK.
And we are going to give here a name.
Oracle, JDK eight.
You can give any name, but whatever name you give, make sure you remember it.
And just to be on the safer side, just use the same name I'm using.
This is just a name here.
We have to select what version of Java will be installed.
Now this is one way of installing a JDK.
You select here the JDK eight and you will get here an option to enter the username and password of
Oracle.
You can create an Oracle account and then put a checkmark and that is it.
You can use it.
But the problem recently, we're having a lot of problems with this.
Jenkins is not able to download this JDK from Oracle account.
So we're going to do this.
We are not going to do this install automatically.
We're going to uncheck that option.
Uncheck this option.
It should be unchecked and we will install a JDK from the command line and then specify its path over
here.
So all you need to do is just switch to the Jenkins instance.
So let's copy its public IP and let's do an search to it.
As I said, chive and I downloads.
So whatever key you have with the Jenkins, specify that and do a search.
Yes.
Okay, so we just need to run two commands.
One is sudo apt update.
And a sudo apt install open.
JDK hyphen eight hyphen JDK.
So we already have JDK 11 in this Jenkins For our project, we need JDK eight.
So we're installing JDK.
So you have to JDK in the Jenkins, JDK 11 and JDK eight.
So but if you run the command Java hyphen version.
You should see JDK or Java 11 being used, and that is fine.
Jenkins runs on that.
That is okay.
So how does in the tools we specify JDK eight.
So I'll show you.
So the hyphen I Ellis user lib jvm oops.
User lib JVM.
So you see in this we have two folders here.
One is Java 1.8 and one is Java 11.
So if you're multiple versions of Java, it's home.
Directories will be here.
So all we need to do is specify this path as the home directory.
So user lib JVM.
Slash.
And this one.
1.8.
Remember Java 1.8?
Not 11.
Not anything else.
Just this one.
Get this spot.
And then we go back here and we just paste the part over here.
So specifying that this is the Java home directory that you need to use.
So this is open JDK and I have given here name as Oracle JDK.
That is because later we will be using in our code the name as Oracle JDK eight with whatever you give
over here, make sure you remember that or you can come back and check the name so you can specify the
correct name of the tool that you're using in your code.
But for now, this is this.
Just install open JDK and specify its path over here.
That is all.
Scroll down.
Go to MAVEN section, click on Add Maven and this is pretty simple.
You just give the Maven name, so I will give here Maven.
Maven three.
And to select whatever three version it is there.
And that's all save.
Let's go to Dashboard.
Now, Jenkins did not actually install these tools.
When you run the build job that time, whenever it needs that time, it will install.
So we'll see in the next lecture how to create a job and use the tools that we just added.