I'm in my management console and I will be going to easy to service.
I will launch when?
Easy to instance.
Where I will run the Jenkins service.
If you already have a Jenkins service running, you can use the same one.
If not, just follow me and launch when you see instance with Jenkins service.
Let's first get all the steps of installing Jenkins.
Open a text editor and write down these steps.
Forced sudo apt.
Update.
So we'll be using Ubuntu 22 instance and we'll be running app command to install jenkins and few other
tools after that.
Sudo apt install open key.
Oops.
Hyphen eat hyphen.
JDC, hyphen y.
And.
Sudo apt install maven hyphen y.
Make sure you have the installation command first and then maven.
Don't change the order or don't mix into one command.
Then we'll get the steps of installing Jenkins.
So I just google install Jenkins installing Jenkins the Jenkins dot IO.
Linux.
Debian ubuntu.
Make sure you are in this documentation.
The steps might change whatever steps you see.
Use the same step.
Copy all this command.
Hyphen y.
So wherever you have install an get install or APT install, just make sure you put a hyphen y and at
the beginning of this file, just write this hash, exclamation slash bin bash.
I will show you how we are going to run all these commands.
So let's go to Easy to Dashboard.
Let's say launch instance.
Launch instance.
We'll call it as Jenkins server.
Let's put a hyphen there.
And we will go with open to and we'll select open to 21 to 23 tier eligible.
Make sure you select that one and not any other.
Open to 20 I.
Scroll down instance typed e to micro will be fine.
Let's create a key pair.
We'll give this name as Jenkins key and keep it pem file because I will be using get batch to login.
Okay, come down creating the security group.
We will go to edit in the network setting.
Call it as Jenkins hyphen sg.
Type some description there 22 allowed from my IP and add one more rule which sees port 8080 allowed
from my IP.
Jenkins will run its web service on Port 88.
So we need to allow that rule 88 from my IP so we can access Jenkins on Port 88.
Scroll down.
Go to advanced details.
Come till the end and open your text editor where you have written all the commands.
Select copy and paste it there.
Make sure the first line is this.
Otherwise, this commands will not run.
Yeah.
And let's say launch instance.
View all instances.
So this will take some time.
I will pause my screen and come back when this is ready.
Okay, let's access it on Port 88.
Copy the public IP access on Port 88 and it should ask you to open this file and enter the password
from that file.
So we need to do a search to the Jenkins.
Again, copy the IP open get bash.
This is such hype and I downloads Jenkins key.
Want to add the rate and pace the IP.
To pseudo hyphen i.
Clear the screen.
Cat and let's copy the file name.
That file is.
Copy that.
And that you have the unlocked password.
Password.
In pasted here.
Continue.
We will see install suggested plugins, click on that.
A username I'll give as admin.
And then some password.
Full name and email address.
I will say I'd been at mail dot com save and continue.
See when finish.
Start using Jenkins.
Okay.
We need to install some plugins.
The task that we are going to execute after this.
We need those plugins, so you need to click on Manage Jenkins.
And go to manage plugins.
And click on available.
And a search for.
Pipeline here.
Pipe line.
If you come down, you will see pipeline utility steps.
Click on that checkmark on that and pipeline MAVEN integration check mark on that.
And this is fine.
Let's click on install without restart.
Okay, those plugins are installed.
Now we can start writing our pipeline code and execute some job on a Jenkins.
Now pipeline is really text, so you can use any text editor to write the pipeline.
I'm going to use Intel.
You can use a text, notepad, notepad, plus plus voice code, anything that you prefer.
Later in the project you will see we are going to use voice code or intel.
But now you can use anything you want.
So let's open the text editor.
So I'll use intelligence.
You can really use anything to write Pipeline.
If you're supposed to put this into the motion control system, then you should create a file with named
Jenkins file.
But I'm going to just execute it from the Jenkins job.
So it doesn't matter what I name over here.
But if you're putting it in your project source code, then it should be with this name.
J.
Capital Jenkins file.
First thing is you see pipeline calibrates.
Indentation does not matter.
But it's good to do because it looks good.
Agent I'm saying.
Agent Any I want to execute it on any node.
Master slave does not matter.
And then I'll see.
Stages.
In stages.
I have different stage.
And you see stage and you give parentheses and then you can give the name of the state.
So I'm going to say fetch code.
And open, close curly braces.
And in this, you have steps that will do the actual execution.
If you want to fetch the source code from the pipeline, then you can say git branch.
So it is going to invoke your git plugin.
And then you mentioned the branch name.
Now I'm saying.
So there is a branch in our repository with pipeline as a code named P.
You can check that the Jenkins file already exists over there, but we will not be using that Jenkins
file.
We'll be writing our own file.
You are allow for repository in single code.
If I execute this, it should fetch the source code.
But then we want to do something with the source code.
So we'll write another stage.
Stage?
Inequalities build.
And you step.
Steps.
So if you want to execute Shell command, you can just say as such and in single or double code, you
can give the command that you want to execute, I want to say and install.
So that's our second stage.
Let's write one more stage.
Will give the stage name as test.
Steps.
And I'll see Shell execute and even test for me.
Okay, so we have three stages.
First stage is going to fetch the source code by using the gate plugin.
Second stage is build, which is going to run a step shell command and then install.
Third stage name test is going to run, right?
Is going to run.
One more step a shell command and we in test.
So let's copy this.
And let's go to Jenkins.
So we'll create a new item.
We'll give a name.
Sample pipeline as a code and you have to select here pipeline, not freestyle pipeline and say, okay.
Initially it may look similar, but if you come down, it's a different thing.
You have something called a pipeline.
There is no build or post build action over here.
You have just built triggers, some settings, and then finally the pipeline.
So you can pace your pipeline right over here.
That's one way.
Another way is you can say pipeline script from Seam.
You can select the source code manager.
For example, you can give the URL, you can give the branch, and then in your branch you should have
a file named as Jenkins File Capital.
I'll show you a sample.
So if you come to our source code GitHub repository, you can search for a C pipeline as a code.
At one.
And you see a file called Jenkins file if you click on it.
You should see the entire pipeline.
And there are a lot of things over here.
We'll understand it.
Okay, so you should have Jenkins file in your top level directory.
But we are going to just say here pipeline script and we'll execute the script that we have written.
This is a declarative, again, not a scripted way.
If I'm saying scripting, scripting that just to tell you that we're not creating jobs manually, this
is a declarative way.
I'll also take you through the documentation of Jenkins pipeline as a code.
Now we can see if this.
And we can say build now.
Okay, now you should see stage view.
First stage is happening.
It is fetching the source code.
You can see the logs also there.
All right.
That's little neat.
Then, Bill.
Belongs.
A good test is happening.
Logs.
You can see the logs.
Or you can see the entire log at once by going over here.
And you see a log of every stage, every step that is getting executed.
And it's a success.
If you're wondering where is workspace, then every build will have its own workspace.
So you click on this build ID.
And scroll down these workspaces.
And you can see as a workspace sample pipeline is a code and you see all the data build the source code.
So you should see the artifact as well.
If you're wondering, there's too much of data in this Jenkins file.
Don't worry this documentation for that and we can check it over from there.
And also every plugin that you have used or you want to use will have a documentation to how to write
it in your Jenkins file.
So let's go to the documentation.