So, Jenkins, what are your dog?
And you can click on Pipeline here.
And you can see getting started with Pipeline.
What is Jenkins Pipeline?
You can read about it.
Declarative versus scripted pipeline syntax.
Declarative is now way forward.
Scripted was what you will see, but it's still supported.
There's a syntax and every step is mentioned.
What they do.
Some example of the pipeline like we did build, test and will deploy it also.
The empirical side defining a pipeline, how you can define a pipeline as we did.
That's the way we did pipeline script.
We put our script over there and we executed it.
There's also one more thing.
There is a snippet generator you can generate.
You can mention something over here.
You can give a name and you can click on Generate Pipeline script it will generate.
The snippet for you.
It's in our Jenkins.
Look, some examples are also given over here like steps shall command and executing unit tool to read
the XML.
Deploy.
Expression.
You can put a conditions also.
Defining variables in your Jenkins file.
So you have to say def variable and its value to def really means I'm defining a variable.
I know if you see the only python, if you python if you already use python def there means something
else.
It's defining a function here.
It means defining a variable.
Using environment variable.
You can use environment variable also in your pipeline like build ID build number, which you're going
to use also.
Like this.
Ian.
We don't build it in curly braces.
Curly braces, and you have to say envy and the variable and this is going to return you the build it
can't build it.
So that's how you access variable in your Jenkins file.
Setting variables value dynamically.
Handling credentials.
How can you access credentials?
Usernames and passwords.
So there are a lot of information over here, but you must be using some plugins like we're using Nexus
Artifact uploader plugin or we're using Sonar KUBE scanner plugin.
Those information will not be over here, how to write those things, but you can check that into the
documentation of the plugin itself.
Okay, so I just did a little search Sonar Jenkins plugin and sonar cube documentation you have directly.
You can search that.
You can find that.
So.
Scroll down using a Jenkins pipeline, how you can use that with sonar.
Cuban environment.
You mentioned the environment.
All right.
Printing something over here.
Node any o stage seem fetching the source code stage sooner analysis defining your sooner scanner tool
there.
Let me zoom it a bit.
So like we from global tool configuration, we say sonar scanner.
We want to download sonar scanner from Jenkins global tool configuration.
And we mention it over there.
And then in the pipeline we mentioned which tool you want to use.
We give the name.
So defining variable, actually.
All right.
With sonar cube environment.
Then you give the your sonar cube server detail.
So as in a continuous integration project with Jenkins, we have set up the Jenkins and sonar integration.
All right.
So.
Mannie Jenkins.
Configure system.
And this is where we included there.
So why not keep server?
So we have given the owner hyphen pro you URL and the token.
So this is your owner cube environment.
And I actually have to say switch sooner, Cuban environment, give the environment name and the execution
that you want to do.
So this is going to execute the sonar scanner scanner home, which is declared over here.
So it's going to call this tool run the sonar scanner.
All right.
And there are a few more steps that we are going to mention.
We're going to pass so many parameters to it.
So first, you know how to write a Jenkins file, and then you can put any plug in that you want.
You can go to the plugin documentation.
So once you are done with this, you can terminate your Jenkins server.
In the next project, we will create Jenkins next.
So all the servers once again.
So I recommend you terminate this instance.
So that was some quick view on the Jenkins pipeline.
We'll see this much in detail in the next project.
So wrap this up and join me in the next project.