Welcome to the project.
In this project, we are going to set up a web application stack.
The name of the project is V Profile Project set up local.
Let's understand about this project.
In this project, we will be setting a multi-tier web application stack.
The set up will be locally on your laptop or on your desktop.
There are two reasons why we are doing this project.
The first reason is this project is going to set up a baseline for our upcoming projects.
We are going to do a lot of projects like we're going to deploy a stack on a.
We're going to refactor it.
We're going to containerized our applications.
We're going to deploy the projects on Kubernetes cluster and many more things to do.
All the upcoming projects you need to understand, v profile project first, and for that we are doing
a setup on your on our local machine.
The second reason of doing this project is so you can set up your own lab locally.
If you have any project you're working in, any project, you can set up that entire stack locally and
do all your R&D.
Let's take a scenario from your real time experience.
Let's say you're working in a project and in your project you have varieties of services that you deal
with.
You may be having services like database services, MySQL, PostgreSQL Web services, Apache Engine
X application services, maybe like Tomcat.
Jboss, glassfish
.
Or any other stack like that.
And you may also have a Runbook or a set up document to set up your project stack.
Let's talk about some problems.
You may not be comfortable in making changes in the real servers.
You have the setup document, you have the run book.
But still we lack in confidence in making changes in the real systems.
So you would like to set up a local stack.
You would like to set up all that stack on your local machine probably by using virtual machines.
So you can do that.
But the local setup is complex.
It's time consuming and it's not a repeatable.
So we would love to set up stack locally by using virtual machines so we can do R&D and gain some confidence
on our project.
But since the setup of multiple services is complex, it's time consuming and moreover, we can do it
again and again.
It's not repeatable if you do it manually, so we avoid this setup.
So solutions to our problem.
What we can do is we can have a local set up.
Yes, but it would be automated.
It would be repeatable because we're going to have infrastructure as a code.
So if we have a code to set up the entire stack locally, we can do it as many as time.
It's going to be repeatable.
It's completely automated process.
So you can do as much as R&D you want on your local machine.
All right, Now let's see what all the tools that we need to set up this stack.
So starting with, we will need a hypervisor Oracle VM virtual box we are going to use on which we are
going to set up a virtual machine.
But since this is going to be automated, so for automation we are going to use Vagrant.
And we need to execute some commands, not some many commands.
So we'll be using a command line tool git bash, which will be multipurpose for executing commands and
also for version control.
We can also use an IDE so you can use sublime text or if you are any preference of using Notepad Plus
plus Visual Studio or anything else that also you can use.
You must have installed all these tools already from the prerequisites video.
Let's understand the objective of this once again.
We're going to learn VN automation locally.
This project is going to set up a baseline for upcoming projects.
And we will also learn how to set up many real world projects on our local machine automatically.
So we can do as much as R&D we want.
Now we'll see the architectural design of various services in our project.
We have Nginx, Tomcat, RabbitMQ, Memcached and MySQL service, so we'll see
the architectural design. We will also see one more architectural design.
Of our automated setup, we will have a vagrant, virtual box, git bash and also some scripts and commands.
Okay.
Long story short, we will be setting up a website, a web application.
And this web app is a social networking site written by developers in Java language.
Now, we will understand the flow of this entire stack.
The word stack is used for collection of servicesworking together to create an experience.
In this case, a web.
App or a social networking app.
So we need to set up all these services in our virtual machines and configure together so users get
that experience of a web application.
Okay, so the user opens the browser or the app.
In the browser, the user will enter the URL.
But in this project we don't have a URL.
We have an IP address.
In the next project, we'll see how to set up a URL.
But now we will open a browser or the user will open the browser.
Enter the IP address.
This is the IP address of a load balancer.
And we are going to use Engine X service to create the load balancing experience.
Engine X is a web service just like Apache http D, and it's very commonly used to create the load balancing
experience.
So in one of our VM we will be having engine service and we'll configure it in a way as soon as the
request comes, it is going to route the request to the Tomcat server.
Our Apache Tomcat service.
Apache Tomcat is a Java Web application service.
Once again, Java Web Application Service.
Watch the video and let that sink in.
So if you have a web application written in Java, Tomcat is a very famous service to host it.
So the application, which is written by the developer, will be sitting here.
And if your application needs an external storage, you can use NFS servers.
If you have never heard of NFS, I recommend you do a little research.
We will be talking about this again in a ways, but understand what is a shared storage for now.
If you have cluster of servers and if you need a centralized storage, you can store it in NFS very
commonly used coming back to our application.
So our application will be living here.
The user will get a web page, the user will log in, the login details will be stored in my SQL database
service and will come to that.
Now here, there is also one more service called Rabbit MQ connected to Tomcat.
And your project.
This is really dummy.
It's not functional.
The reason I included this is to create little more complexity so you can practice more.
In future we may be adding a few more services like this, which may be functional.
Maybe Dummy Rabbit MQ is a message broker or also called a Queuing agent to connect to applications together,
you can stream the data from this.
You don't need to dig in much about this as a DevOps engineer, but you should know there is such service
message broker or message queue or queuing agent coming back to our application once again.
So our application which is running in tomcat, accessed by the users and the user will log in with
username and password.
When that happens, our application will run an SQL query to access the user information stored in
MySQL database.
But before it goes to the my SQL database, the request will go to mem cache service.
Mem cache is a database caching.
It will be connected with the my SQL Server.
My SQL Server will store the user information when the first time the request comes to the database,
my SQL, it will be sent from the My SQL Server to the Tomcat and then it will be cache to the cache
server.
So next time a request comes, the same request comes.
It will be accessing the data which is cached in cash service just like you have browser cache.
We also have database caching.
Mem cache is a very famous database caching servers.
Okay, so here's the entire stack.
By your screen.
Take a look.
Once again, rewind the video.
If you need to understand all these services, also do your own research.
It is very important for a DevOps engineer to understand the flow of the stack.
So whenever any issue comes, we can understand where it is originating from.
Like if the user is not able to log in, the web page is coming, user is not able to log in, probably
it is the database service not connected to the application or if the web page is not showing properly,
it's the Tomcat.
Now we cannot dig into each and every service and understand it in detail because as a DevOps.
We are more involved into the implementation rather than the functionality.
And but yes, you should know the functionality.
So if you feel you need to know more about a service, you can do your own research.
But we will be using this service as many times in the course in a as in Docker, in Kubernetes, in
Jenkins Ansible.
So by the end of the course, you'll have a very good hand on all these services.
Let's look at it.
One more architecture of how to implement it.
Another design we have is for our automation stack.
We will be using a vagrant to automate automatically set up our virtual machine.
So Vagrant is going to communicate with Oracle VM Virtual Box, which is the hypervisor and create automatically
virtual machines on that.
Then we'll be using some batch scripts or batch commands to set up our services.
Engine x.
Apache Tomcat.
Mem Rabbit mq MySQL.
So we will automatically create virtual machines from Vagrant Virtual Machine for Engine X, Apache
Tomcat, Mem Cache, Rabbit, MQ and MySQL.
Okay, Finally, let's understand the flow of execution.
First, we're going to set up all our tools from the prerequisite videos.
If you have all this setup already, then you can clone the source code, which will be seen in the
project.
We're going to seed into a vagrant directory in the source code.
There will be a Vagrantfile.
We'll bring up our VMs automatically from that background file, we'll validate all our virtual machines
If they're up and running and able to interact with each other, then we're going to start setting up
all our services one by one, first my SQL, then Mem cache D, then Rabbit MQ, then Tomcat and finally
Nginx.
And of course, we're going to build our application or Java application and deploy it.
Then we're going to finally verify all this from our browser.