Open your browser and access our source code URL.
Switch to branch.
Local setup.
In this branch, you will have a directory.
Vagrant.
We have a four folders here.
We are doing manual provisioning, so we'll be using manual provisioning.
But if you have a mac OS M1 one or M2, then go manual provisioning Mac OS M1 directory.
I have windows here, so I'm going to click here on manual provisioning and also for Mac OS with Intel
CHIP, use this manual provisioning directory.
We have a Vagrantfile and a PDF.
This document will show you how you can set up this entire project step by step.
You can use it as a reference.
And also we have a vagrant file here, of course, which is going to launch all our virtual machines
automatically.
So we will clone this source code on our local machine and we'll get started.
So I'm going to copy the URL.
Open my gate bash.
I'm going to get into f drive.
You can select any place, any directory in your system, Get into that.
If you're using Mac OS for your MacBook, then you can open your terminal.
You should have git already installed and I'm going to run the command git clone and paste the URL.
This is going to clone the entire source code in my local machine.
Now.
Now I should see the file project directory.
That's my repository.
I cd into that.
Let's clear the screen.
I'm going to switch to branch.
Local hyphen setup.
And I see the vagrant directory there.
Let's get into that.
And you see here the four folders based on your operating system.
Get into the right folder.
I'm getting into manual provisioning if you have a mac OS MX one MB two.
Then just see underscore and mako as and one getting to that for a Windows and macOS with Intel chip
get into the manual provisioning directory.
Let me expand it.
Clear the screen.
And we have the vagrant file over here.
Let's see this vagrant file from Sublime text editor.
Okay, open my sublime text editor and I'm going to open folder where I have cloned my source code.
So yes, it's in f drive.
That's the repository.
And we'll say select folder.
Let's expand this.
So we have vagrant directory manual provisioning and the vagrant file there.
Let's understand this vagrantfile first.
Well, we will use this file to launch five virtual machine.
One will be engine X, one Tomcat, one rabbit MQ.
One is memcache and the other one is the db machine.
We have few global settings here.
config Host Manager enabled.
True.
So if you install the plugin.
Then the setting will automatically update hostname in each and every virtual machines.
So in every virtual machine in its host file, the host and IP addresses will be mapped and Gen X virtual
machine will have given name web zero one and it is going to be based on one two operating system.
That's the host name Web zero one, and it has a private IP.
You can keep the same IP.
It does not conflict with your existing network or else you can change the IP.
Don't get virtual machine name is AB zero one and we are going to use CentOS seven operating system
here.
IP address in the same network.
And we're also going to give it an extra boost of RAM one GB of RAM.
Next is a rabbit mq ar mq zero one.
This will be also based on center, a seven operating system and an IP address.
Next name?
Cash.
Name M.C. zero one based on, again, Centre seven and an IP address.
My sequel.
Name is DB zero one Center seven Operating system and again, IP address.
If you see all these IP address are in a same network and then they would be able to communicate also
with each other.
If you want to make any changes like hostname or IP address in scheme and save this file, make the
changes and save the file.
Okay, now let's bring up the stack.
Let's open our get bash.
You should be in this directory where you have the background file.
You can check it once again.
Kurt Wagner and file.
Before you bring up the virtual machine, you have to install this plugin necessarily, otherwise you
will get a host manager Unknown configuration error.
What this settings will do is this will automatically add host entries, map it with their IP addresses
of all the VMs in every virtual machine.
The second plugin is optional.
If you are getting the box FS error, then only install the second plugin.
But first plugin we need to install.
So let's copy that and let's install this plugin.
The plugin is installed beginning to run the command Valorant app, which will bring up all this virtual
machine.
So we already have Oracle VM virtual Box installed.
There's no virtual machine over here now, but in some time you will see all the virtual machine up
over here.
This is going to take some time and I'm going to pause my video.
All right.
All the vrms are up.
First, we have web zero one.
That is one GB of ram.
Then we have AB 011 GB of RAM again.
So total two GB now Rabbit MK 512 GB That's fine.
Ma'am.
Cash five and two and B, So now total three GBPS.
And then finally, DB zero one also five one, two and B, So you will need almost two and a half to
three GB of RAM to set up this stack.
Boogie stack is set up, The beams are set up.
Let's make a test.
Let's validate Vagrant Search Web zero one first.
Cave urine.
Let's check the Etsy host file so this gets automatically updated, as I told you.
And let's see if we are able to ping app zero one.
Yes.
Let's log out from here.
Let's log into app zero one.
Okay, let's check etsy host file in app zero one.
Now it's also updated.
Let's bring the back end services which this machine will try to connect and see zero one.
R.
M.
q01.
And of course, the DB zero one.
Okay, this is important to validate because our engine X is going to connect to our application server
and application server.
Tomcat is going to connect to DB, MSI and Rabbit MQ.
So we need to make this test now.
Let's log out from here.