Okay, now you can open the setup document
and you can follow the setup document.
So we have already done our prerequisites.
Our VM are already set up.
We did vagrant up. All the VMs
are up and we validated everything.
Now it's time for provisioning all these services
we are going to provision, but we are
going to provision it in this order.
First MySQL, then Memcache, then RabbitMQ,
then Tomcat, and then NGINX and
then finally we'll deploy our application.
Okay, let's first set up a MySQL service
and there are many commands over here.
So in this section we
practice executing all these commands.
We will be doing all the setup manually.
In the next section we will see how we
will automate this entire setup by using Bash scripts.
If you understand all the commands well and good.
If you do not understand, do not stress too much.
You will slowly get hold of this.
We will be seeing this product setup on AWS, containers etc...,
different places, so you will get practice of it.
Okay, so let me open my git bash
and I will log into db01.
Okay, I am in.
I'm going to switch to root user sudo -i
So it's a newly provisioned operating system and whenever
and wherever you install or set up a new
operating system, you should update all its packages.
We will be doing it with
yum update command, yum update -y.
This is the command in centos
or any rpm based operating system.
It will read all the old Rpm
packages and update to a newer version.
This is going to take some time.
I'm going to pause my screen and
come back when it is completed.
Okay, that completed.
Now I will be running yum install epel-release.
This will enable EPEL repositories so
I can install many more softwares.
And it's already installed.
Okay, next we will be
installing Git and MariaDB service.
Okay, that got installed.
Now one quick note over here, mariadb
Server or MySQL Server, both are the
same service with different package names.
When it comes to Rpm based i:e CentOS, Fedora,
we will be using MariaDB Hyphen Server package
In Ubuntu we still have MySQL Server.
So if I say MySQL Server
or MariaDB Server, it's the same thing?
Okay, next we will enable and start MariaDB service
systemctl start MariaDB and you see the package
name is different and service name is different.
Sometimes package name and service name
are same, sometimes they are different.
So just need to find that out.
Okay, started and enabled.
Next we will be running a command.
Actually it's a script MySQL
underscore secure underscore installation.
This is going to ask you a series of questions
just to make sure your MySQL service is secure.
So first enter root password.
We do not have any root password.
Now this is the root password for
MySQL service, not for the Linux.
This is not Linux root user.
Just hit enter over here.
And now you need to set root password.
So I'm going to say why yes.
And I'm setting admin123
I also recommend you use the same one just for now.
Hit enter.
Remove anonymous user y disallow root log in remotely.
So with this root, user of MySQL, do you
want to log in from a different computer remotely?
If you want, say yes.
If no, say and I will be keeping it as
yes because we may need to do some testing later.
Remove test database. Yes.
Reload privilege.
It's like refresh. Yes.
Great.
MariaDB service is secure now.
Okay, now we will log into this MariaDB service or
MySQL service by using MySQL client MySQL the user name
root p and you can specify password here itself.
That is the password that I set.
And no space in between P and the password. No space.
Just hit enter.
You will log into my ADB service. This is the prompt.
You see the prompt has changed.
Now Linux command won't work here.
Only SQL command will work.
So this is one SQL command that you are running.
First one, create database accounts.
Make sure every SQL command ends with a semicolon.
So database name account is created.
This is specifically for our view profile project.
Our V profile project will be
storing information in this database.
OK, next command.
Grant all privileges on accounts
database to the user admin.
So this will also create a user admin.
Like we have the root user to log into MySQL.
We are creating here.
Admin user percent means @'%'.
Percent means you can log in from
anywhere, from locally or from remotely.
Also identified by admin123
That is the password of admin user.
And we see we have the same password for the root user.
Okay, you copy paste this or
make sure your syntax is proper.
No mistakes over here.
Hit Enter.
Okay, if you get this error,
better check your syntax now.
Syntax is all correct.
This is all copy paste problem.
I'm going to run the same command, but this time I'm
going to remove this single quote and add it once again.
Yeah, that's right. Not doing anything.
I'm not making any change.
This is copy paste.
Mistake special characters.
Not exactly mistake.
Just remove all the single quote,
add them again and hit enter.
It should work.
I know, surprise, right?
Both the commands are exactly the same.
Won't work.
The other did not.
That is because while doing copy
paste, sometimes special character changes.
That is all I'm going to give this command.
Flush privileges.
Hit enter.
So it's like refresh and then I'm
going to exit out of it.
Exit semicolon and out.
So we are out of SQL prompt.
We are back on our shell.
Okay, next command.
We have created the database, but we
need to feed that with some data.
So we are going to download or clone the source code.
Download data from this link, go into that
directory run this command which will feed all
the SQL query into Accounts database and then
we will check whether it worked or not.
So let's do it.
Let's clone the source code.
This git clone command is basically
going to download all this data.
If you do LS, you should find
a directory here v profile project.
Just do CD.
We have SRC directory in that we
have main in this we have resources.
And here you should have this file dbackup SQL.
You can do a cat to this file.
You can see there are many SQL queries.
You don't need to look into that.
For now, all you need to do is run
all this SQL query on your Accounts database. How?
Like this MySQL u root p password admin123
input redirection SRC mainresourcesdbackup SQL when you're
running this command, make sure you're in V profile
project directory and you have the proper path.
Run this command.
Oops, my mistake.
We have to select the database.
Give the database named accounts.
Now let's log into the database.
We will just give this much directly.
Log into account database.
I am in.
Or wait, let me exit.
Clear the screen once again.
Let me log in and I'm going to say
show tables and you should see all this.
If for some reason you are not seeing this, then
do the set up again and check your previous command.
What you executed.
You can run the history command and you can
see all the commands that you have executed.
Sometimes we make mistake and that is fine.
Just check fix it.
Okay, now this is really not necessary, but if
we run this command system CTL restart mario DB.
If we have some mistake, it
can point out if it restarts. Fine. We are good.
Okay, the SMARTB service is up and running.
We have created the database and we are good here.
Okay, next service is Memcache which is pretty simple.
Just install the packages, start the service and run
this command which will allow access on port.
So let's do it.
Okay, so let's log out from DB and log into MC one.
Switch to root user and first run
yum update y to patch this.
Okay, all the patching is done.
Clear the screen.
Let's install eplase package and now we
will install let me clear the screen
first and let's install Memcache d.
That's the only package we need to install over here.
Okay, package is installed.
Let's start the service and also enable the service.
Let's check its status.
It's active.
We have to run one more command for Memcache so
it can listen on TCP port and UDP port this.
So anyways you're going to access it on TCP port
on this command and we are good to go.
We can validate if it's running on the right
port which is and we see memcache service.
We can see the PID it's open on port.
Okay, Memcache is set up let's log out from
here and let's go to the next service which
is a RabbitMQ RMQ one log into it.
Okay, we are in.
Let's become the root user and let's run
YM update y all the package update completed.
Now let's see the installation steps.
First we need to install some dependencies.
One of them is Aslan and SOCAT.
Installing aslan won't be direct.
We have to download this rpm with Wgatcommand.
Install this Rpm.
This Rpm will set us aslang repositories so
we can install airlines with yum install command.
Once we have erlang and SOCAT installed then we
are going to download a shell script and at
the same time we execute the script.
Once the script is executed, it will set
us repository to install RabbitMQ server packages.
Then with yum install command we
can install RabbitMQ server package.
Then we start and enable the RabbitMQ service
and some configurations to do after that.
So let's get started with this.
Let's install Wget.
Let's clear the screen and go to temp directory.
Download this Rpm.
Let's install it.
And now we should be able
to install erlang and that's completed.
Let's now install RabbitMQ server now with this command
we're going to download the script and pipe it
with bash so it will also execute the script.
Okay, so as this is the repository is set up.
Now let's install RabbitMQ server
and finally it's installed.
Let's start enable the service
and let's check its status.
RabbitMQ service is active.
Now we have some configuration changes with RabbitMQ.
So this command is basically going to
echo this output into this file.
And we also have to create user in RabbitMQ.
So that's the command RabbitMQ CTL add user.
That's the username and that's the password
you can change if you want.
But then remember whatever username and password
you use because same we are going
to give in the configuration file.
Next we are going to give
this user administrator privilege in RabbitMQ.
We do it like this rabbitmqctl set user tag the
username and the tag that you are setting up.
Okay, after making this configuration change, it's
time to bounce the RabbitMQ service.
So the system CTL restart RabbitMQ server if
everything is good, if configuration changes are good,
our RabbitMQ service should be running or else
you can see some error down there.
Okay, still here.
The back end is setup.