db, memcache and rabbitmq. Now we will log into our main hero App 01, where we're going to set up a tomcat
tomcat service.
So in app01, switch to root user, run yum update -Y.
Update completed now, let's set up a epel release repository.
OK.
That is done.
Now, dependency for Tomcat, which is jdk version 1.8
That's the dependency for our vprofile application.
So you also have a higher version of JDK now, but we have to go with 1.8 for our project.
Jdk is installed, few more tools, git maven me and wget, let's install these
OK, these tools are also installed, now we will download Tomcat, so let's go to /tmp dir.
We will download this specific tarball of Tomcat.
OK, we should have the tar ball of Tomcat and let's extract it.
OK, let's clear the screen.
We should see the Tomcat dir.
OK, let's see the next step.
So we have to add a user and which will create the Tomcat home dir for us, Tomcat is the username
and this will be the home directory.
This is where will copy all the Tomcat binaries.
So that command
And now you should have a user called Tomcat and you should have this home directory, /usr/local/tomcat8
/usr/local/tomcat8
And this is where we'll copy all our data.
So cp -r
tomcat dir /*. So copy, everything from there to /usr/local/tomcat
Now, just check, once you should see all these files in /usr/local/tomcat directory.
OK, next step is to give.
Permission ownership of Tomcat user tomcat Group to all the content in the directory, so let's do
ls -l and you will see these are all owned by root users, so let's change that ownership.
We will say chown tomcat.tomcat.
/usr/local/tomcat8, and will give the option -r.So recursively everything
will be owned by tomcat user and the group, so you should see tomcat user ownership and group ownership.
OK.
All right.
Next step is to create this file.
tomcat.service file
And we have this entry over there, with help of this, we can use systemctl command to start, stop,
tomcat service.
So let's open that up with vim.
It's going to be a new file.
OK, I will be using just vi.
And copy all this content carefully.
And past it here being an insert mode, let's do some lines spacing.
OK, so when we say systemctl start tomcat, it is going to run this command.
When we say systemctl stop tomcat, it will run this command.
So we don't need to manually run this command and we can enable the service by using systemctl.
So it comes at the boot time, which is very essential.
Let's save and quit.
Once you make any change to tomcat.service file, you have to say systemctl
systemctl  daemon-reload, so any other kind of services files also you you have in this directory, it will reload all
the changes and now you should be able to do systemctl enable tomcat.
So the service name is same as the file name tomcat.
Oops, that's my mistake.
OK, and then you can say systemctl start tomcat.
And let's check its status now.
And you should see active running if you see some problems over here, like failed.
Make sure you check the content in /usr/local/tomcat8
/usr/local/tomcat8
Check the ownership of this dir and also inside the content should have tomcat ownership and
also verify this systemctl file
If you have the right content or there are no syntax errors.
So check all this fix things do systemctl daemon reload and it should be working, so tomcat
service is up and running.
Now we are going to build artifacts from our source code and deploy to tomcat servers.
So let me clear the screen.
OK.
Let's see, we set up, memcache, rabbitmq is done
tomcat set up is done.
And now code build and deploy, so we're going to clone the source code.
We're going to build the source code by MAVEN and then we're going to deploy our artifact to Tomcat
Web Apps Directory.
So let's do this.
OK, I'm in the /tmp dir still
And I'm going to clone the source code over here, git clone.
OK, source code is cloned, let's get into the source code directory.
git status
So you should be in this branch, local set up branch.
Now, before we build our artifact, we're going to update the configuration file.
That will be that will be used by our application to connect backend services, the database, memcache
and rabbitmq service.
And that file location is.
In the repository, src/main/resources/application. properties file, open this file.
And make the required changes for a database. memcache, rabbitmq, So let's make changes to my
mysql
So we have created our VM and we have the host named DB 01.
And that's the same entry in /etc/host file, so we don't need to change this.
We have created a user admin, so we'll keep the same user over here with password admin one two three.
If you created the admin user with a different password change those, backend service mc01
We have the memcache service with the same name and running on the same port.
We already validated that, rabbitmq rmq01, port 5672
It runs on that port by default, and we created a user in rabbitmq with test and a password
test
So we really don't need to make any change, but this is a very important file, understand this file
very well because in further, the other projects, we have to keep making changes to this files.
So if you're good with all the changes, save and quit this file.
And run the command mvn install from the repository, which is going to build our artifact.
OK.
After some time, command completed successfully.
And it says we have artifact at this location.
ls, ls, so we have a target dir.
Let me clear the screen.
Let's get into the target dir and in this dir, you have vprofile-v2.war
that is our artifact and this we're going to deploy in tomcat server
And we have build the artifact in the Tomcat server itself.
So it's just going to be a copy command.
But first, I'm going to remove the default application of Tomcat, and for that purpose, first I'm
going to shut down.
tomcat service, systemctl stop tomcat
tomcat
Let's check its status if it's down.
And now we will remove the default application, /usr/local/tomcat8, you have webapps dir in this
and in this, you should have a root .If you have root and root.war both,  you can just say
ROOT*, but they'll be just ROOT dir for now.
So just remove that dir.
That's the default application.
It's gone.
And will replace our artifact, sorry, our default application that we just deleted by our artifact,
so will copy our artifact, vprofile-v2.war to /usr/local/tomcat8/webapps
with the name ROOT.war, make sure while you're copying, you give that name.
Let's copy that.
Let's check that it's copied or not.
OK, now we'll start the Tomcat service, so systemctl start Tomcat.
Once you run this command, it should extract the ROOT.war into a ROOT directory.
And now that our application becomes the default application for Tomcat.
After that, wait for a few minutes, our application takes little time to come up.
Now, by the time our Tomcat application is coming up, we'll set up Nginx service, our final service
So lets exit from here.