And let's log into web01, and this is where we are going to set up Nginx website.
web01 is ubuntu machine, all the other VMS were CentOS
web01 is going to be ubuntu.
So as we run yum update, here, we are going to run apt update and upgrade both.
apt upgrade -y
Which will update all the packages.
All right, so upgrade completed successfully, let's log in as the root user now and we will install
finally the Nginx service.
apt install nginx.
And we are going to create a configuration file.
Which will be used to redirect request from nginx to tomcat server on port 880, so the Nginx
will basically act like a load balancer.
So create the file at this location.
Let me show you once again.
That location with that name vproapp, sites-available, this is where we create the configuration
and we create the file with the name vproapp.
And we are going to put this configuration.
So frontent, it's going to listen on port 80, if you access nginx service on port 80, it's going to
route the request to the vproapp server.
app01 on port 8080
If you have multiple application server behind the scene.
Then you can just copy the settings multiple times and you can change the hostname app01, app02
, like that, but we just have one application server and we have given its name and the port number
Tomcat runs by default on port 8080
OK, let's save this file.
And we're going to remove a default application or default website of Nginx, the path is /etc/
nginx/sites-enabled/default
And now we have to create a link, ln -s
Link of our configuration file at this particular location, you can give it with the same name,
vproapp
So this is going to enable our site.
Once the configuration change is is done, restart nginx service.
And that was the final command.
of our stack setup.