So now finally, let's go through the flow of execution, what we did.
We had all the tools that we need.
We cloned the source code, we get in to vagrant directory.
We brought up all our VMS, we validated it, and then we have set up all the services, one by one,
First MySQL, then Memcache, then Rabbitt MQ, Tomcat, Nginx.
And finally, we also deployed our application.
And now it's time to verify our website from the browser.
So we're going to access Nginx service.
So I'm in web01
Let's get its IP address.
192.168.33.11
.
So let's copy that.
Lets open a browser, so just paste the IP address, We are accessing it on port 80, you don't even need
to mention that that's the default port.
http:// and the ip address
And you should see this login page, this is coming from tomcat, So, Nginx is successfully routing
the request to our application server and now let's login.
So we have the username admin_vp, your login with this user and the password is also same
admin_vp, click on login.
If the logging is successful, that means database db01 MySQL server is connected because this user
is coming from the database.
OK, will also verify other backend services. Like rabbitmq, So for admin_vp user
You have few buttons over here.
You can click on Rabbitt MQ.
It should generate some queue.
Let's go back, let's check also memcache, so click on all user, going to load all the users from
the database and store it in memcache.
So let's select a user, let's say the same user.
Let's go for some other user.
So it says Data is from DB and inserted in cache.
OK, let's go back, and if you click same user, you'll see data is coming from cache and you will see
that loading up very quickly.
So we really validated all our services in our stack
So that's awesome.
The entire stack is up and running, we can you even access it.
We checked all the backend services.
Everything is looking good.
Now, we have done this set up.
VM we have created automatically but provisioning, we did manually, now we will see how we can
also provision automatically with some bash scripts.
So for every service that we are setting up tomcat, mysql, memcache, RabbitMQ, all the services
we will provision automatically, we will run, our vagrant will run shell scripts for us.
So let's go to our vm.
Yeah, I'm logged into a zero one, I'm going to exit from here.
And now we'll delete this entire stack, vagrant destroy.
Which will delete all the VMS.
If you want, you can just say vagrant halt, shut it down.
And then with vagrant up, you can bring up any time you want.
But now I'm going to set up the entire stack automatically, so I'm going to delete all these VMS.
db
Memcache.
rabbit MQ.
And finally, not finally, we have application server, we also have web01
So it's going to give you some pop ups on your screen, just say yes to that pop up so it just updates
the host file.
Checking in your virtual box, all your VMS will be gone.
OK, let's wrap up.
So by using vagrant, we created virtual machines automatically on Oracle vm virtual box.
Then we logged into each and every machine executed shell commands.
And we have set up services, first my sql, then rabbit MQ, then Memcache D, then Tomcat and then finally
the Nginx.
Once the stack is ready, we verified as a user from the browser, we access, the nginx service.
Ngins then forwarded the request to Tomcat server, which then forwarded the request to message broker
rabbit MQ and then to Memcache and MySQL server.
So the query that got executed on Target's server was then cache to the memcache server.
So this entire set up of services was manual, in the next video, you will see how to automate the entire
setup.
Thank you for watching this video.
I will see you in the next one.