Welcome to the project.
The name of this project is Continuous Delivery Hybrid.
The reason why we are calling it hybrid is because we're going to use Jenkins as a continuous integration
and a pass and SAS services.
To follow along in this project, you should have done continuous delivery project with Jenkins and
Tool and Continuous Delivery project with us.
So we're going to use existing resource of our previous two projects and also all the knowledge that
you have gathered in this previous two projects.
So in this project we're going to use Jenkins for continuous integration and we're going to use some
PASS and SAS services, like we're going to use code, build Bienstock ideas and a few other services.
Jenkins will be running on Easy two instance, or you can be running it anywhere else.
The situation will be more apt when you have a hybrid environment where where you're running your continuous
integration or some workload on computers and operating systems and also leveraging a s or any cloud
computing managed services.
And that is the reason why we are calling it as a continuous delivery hybrid.
Tools.
So most of the tools are similar.
What we used in continuous integration pipeline, starting with Jenkins for continuous integration Nexis
so NetApp repository for the artifact storage and download soon the cube scanner and toner cube server
for code analysis maven to build our artifact get as the version control system.
Slack for notification, but for the deployment we will be using bienstock.
We will deploy our artifact from Jenkins to a elastic beanstalk and that we will be doing by using a
C ally in the Jenkins.
EWR se three where we will upload our artifact.
So let's see.
Eli running from Jenkins is basically going to upload the artifact to the S3 bucket.
And then update the beans tag environment with new artifact downloading from the S3 bucket.
So I applaud the artifact to with three bucket and then on the bean stack it will fetch that artifact
from the S3 bucket and deploy flow of execution the steps that we are going to take in order to complete
this project.
First we will validate our continuous integration pipeline.
We will power on our Jenkins Nexus owner cube test our pipeline.
Also, we will update the GitHub webhook with the new Jenkins IP.
We will log in or search to Jenkins and install a ally.
If you did previous projects continuous delivery project, this must be already installed.
We will go to our source code repository, git repository and create a new branch for this project for
staging environment.
Then we need to take care of some worse services, starting with creating an S3 bucket where we will
be uploading our artefact.
And this is for the bean stack environment.
We will store the artifact in the bucket so we can.
Deployed to bienstock environment.
I am user with access key for Beans, TAC Policy and S3 policy.
So in Jenkins we use a CLI and it needs the access keys with the correct policy.
We will be doing that in this step.
We'll create a Bienstock application with the name V Pro App and it will create an environment inside
that.
They know a new branch.
We will write the Jenkins file and committed to the git repository.
We'll create a pipeline in Jenkins for the staging environment and test it once it is tested.
Good.
Then we are going to write a Jenkins file for production environment and for production we create a
new Beanstalk environment.
So in the same bean stack application, we will have two environment, one for staging and one for production.
So till the fifth step, we would have already tested the staging environment.
Then for the production, we will create a new beanstalk environment.
Create a new branch for production environment in our git repository.
Write a Jenkins file for a production environment.
Create a pipeline for production and tested.
So if you did previous continuous delivery projects.
And you must have understood it is simpler than the previous one.
So let's get into the action and find out.