Okay.
I have logged into my console.
So we will be doing three simple things.
In this lecture, we test validate our continuous integration pipeline.
We update the Jenkins new IP in GitHub webhook and we log into Jenkins search and install CLI.
So first thing, that's power on all our instances.
I will wait for it to get the IP address already.
Got it.
So you got the public IP for the Jenkins.
Let's copy that.
And let's go to GitHub, our repository that we created previously.
And we'll go to the settings of this repository.
The books.
Edit.
Enter the password.
Change the public IP to the latest one.
Click on update webhook.
Okay.
Let's go back to Jenkins.
Jenkins?
Yeah.
The AP once again.
That's open 80.
80.
Log in.
And let's test the continuous integration pipeline.
We profile CI pipeline build now.
While this is happening, let's do a search to the Jenkins and install a clean.
I am opening my gate bash.
This is a chip and I downloads the profile 61 to.
Okay.
I need to update the security group rule.
Let's go to security.
I get 22 from my IP.
That gives me the new IP.
Okay.
Let's try once again.
Let's clear the screen sudo apt update.
Sudo apt install a w s line.
This is already installed in my jenkins and hopefully it's installed in your machine as well.
In previous continuous delivery projects we installed a CLI, so it should be there.
But if you build a new jenkins, then you need to install it.
Okay.
Let's check the status of our CI pipeline.
That completed successfully.
So we are good to go.
Wrap this up.
Join me in the next lecture where we'll set up some services.