All right.
In this lecture, we will be doing three things.
One, creating an S3 bucket.
Second create I am user with correct policy beans tech policy and as three policy.
Third, creating the beans tag application.
Let's start with.
Am.
Let's go to Imam.
Users.
Add user.
We'll call this a secede hyphen been.
Programmatic access next.
Attach existing policy.
Now this user will be used by a CLI and it needs to first access the S3 bucket to upload and download
the artifact.
So Amazon is three full access and it will also access the bean stack environment.
To deploy the latest artifact from S3 bucket.
So being stack full access also will give to two policy being stack and S3.
Okay.
Let's create the user.
Download the CSV file.
So let's see these credentials in the Jenkins right now.
So go to manage Jenkins.
Manage credentials.
Jenkins.
Global credentials.
Now there's already a credential access keys and secret keys saved in my Jenkins from previous projects,
but that does not have correct policy as we need.
So we create a new credentials.
Will say plus credentials.
We limit as has been crits.
Let's paste the axis key here.
And the secret key.
Now yes, I will be clicking on show and you will be seeing my secret key also.
But after this lecture, I'm going to delete this one.
Create.
Remember this name?
A bean bean creds.
We will be using this in our click command to deploy our artifact to bean stack.
It will be in the Jenkins file.
Now get one thing knocked out.
Let's go to S3.
Let's create an S3 bucket.
So I will say create bucket.
And let's give Bucket a name.
I will call it as a pro C, C, D bin.
Now you make sure you create the bucket with a different name because I'm already using this name.
You will not be able to use this name.
So create a different name of your S3 bucket if you want it unique.
Just add some numbers like that so it becomes unique.
Okay.
So let's just go down.
That's it.
Just create bucket.
Okay.
Now, the last thing is Bienstock.
This is where we'll be deploying our artifact.
You must have already experience with Bienstock if you're following all the projects we used Bienstock.
When we did Re Architecture Project, we hosted a profile application on Bienstock and then we configured
the backend services.
Also in this project will be just configuring Bienstock.
Not the back end services.
So create application.
Let's give it a name.
I will just call it as Vpro app again.
Give a different name.
Make sure it's unique.
Platform Tomcat.
Take all defaults, configure more options.
Custom configuration.
So we will be changing the capacity we will be having.
To micro only, not to too small.
And we will say we need two instances minimum.
Two maximum for.
And save.
Deployment, rolling updates and deployment.
Edit.
So we don't want it to do all at once.
You want to do it one at a time.
So rolling.
So we are seeing two instances to start with and we are going to give size 50%.
So it's going to upgrade one instance at a time.
We will be seeing how it upgrades.
And that is it.
Save.
Okay.
Later, we need to do the health check changes to slash logging for the load for the target group.
We will do that.
Let's create the app now.
So this will take some time.
I'm going to pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
Okay.
After like 5 minutes it completed.
So we have an application.
Let's click on applications.
Application name pro app.
It has an environment, the pro app, hyphen E and V.
This will use for staging and for production.
We'll create one more environment in the same application.
So let's click on this environment.
This environment is running a sample application.
That's the URL of the load balancer.
If you click on that control and click.
So that's the sample application.
And if we come to application versions, we can see this and this is deployed in the environment.
So application can have multiple versions.
You can choose and select to deploy.
On the environment that you want.
We currently just have one environment and the same portion is deployed.
We will see in the next lectures how we are going to upload our own version and deploy it to the right
environment.
So that is all here in this lecture.
Complete this and join me in the next lecture.