Okay.
So we have almost everything ready.
Now it's time to write our pipeline script and test it.
But even before that, we need to do a few more changes, starting with our source code.
Let's open git bash and go to your git repository.
So mine is in.
Here.
Okay.
I'm going to switch to the branch.
Sy hyphen Jenkins.
So this is what we just tested.
Securities integration pipeline is working very well.
From this, I'm going to create another branch.
We name it as secede hyphen gen bean.
And I'll put a stage over there just to show you that this is for the staging environment.
Oh, I need to give a hyphen B so it creates the branch and then switches there.
Okay.
Let's open the voice code.
Code dot.
Okay.
Not this.
CCD Jen Bean Stage Correct.
Branch Let's open the Jenkins file.
So this is the pipeline script for the continuous integration.
We are going to extend it to continuous delivery and deploying it to bean stack.
So we are going to basically run a CLI command.
And.
We are going to mention a few variables over there.
Let me first show you the CLI commands that we'll be executing from our pipeline.
There.
So the first command is to upload the artifact to the S3 bucket.
So we'll take a variable and we'll give this artifact a name, and this artifact will be based on the
build ID so it takes the artifact v profile v two dot var uploads to a three bucket and make sure versions
it next.
The second command is going to create this is a plus Elastic Beanstalk create application version.
So it's going to create a new version upload.
This artifact to the beanstalk.
Now, if you're doing this manually, this is how it is done.
We go to bins tag application version and we say upload and we upload the artifact.
So we choose the file, we upload it.
But this command over here is going to do it from the street pocket.
It's going to download the artifact from the S3 bucket and upload it to Elastic Beanstalk.
Now, this is creating a version, not deploying it.
The third command is going to deploy that version.
So we mentioned the application name.
And the environment name and the Virgin label, the Virgin label we are creating over here.
This will be based on the build ID, whatever current build ID is, that will be the version of our.
Application.
So total three steps.
We will put this into the Jenkins file.
And if you see there are a few variables, let's define those variables.
First, let's go back to VTS code.
In the environment section define those variables.
So their artifact name, I'm naming it as v profile hyphen V builder ID so it's going to take the build
ID from the Jenkins to that will be the artifact name, then the S3 bucket.
Let me change that.
Let's go back to it.
Just three to go back to the S3 bucket.
Get the S3 bucket name.
So that's the name.
Make sure you put your S3 bucket name.
Now it will be definitely different.
You cannot use the same bucket name as I have used, so you must have created a bucket with a different
name.
Then it was EB app name variable the application name.
So the beans stack cancel that.
Application.
So the pro app, that's our application name.
Mm hmm.
Yeah.
Only that much.
Then the environment name.
So that's my environment name.
It's exactly as it is.
Then EB app version.
This variable we are using for the application version in the beans tag.
So we're just giving the build ID, that's all.
If you want, you can add a few things here like repro app, hyphen, builder ID, stuff like that.
But I'm just going to keep it build adding the number.
Now let's add the stage to execute those click command.
So there.
Stage.
We call it as deploy to.
Stage been.
And open close curly brace.
Now those click command needs eight axis keys for the permission for the privilege.
So we will be executing all those click command with width credentials with a credential plugin.
That one open and close curly brace.
So, credentials.
You already saved this in the Jenkins.
Let's get that credential name.
Manny Jenkins.
Now, I remember this very well, but I want you to go and find out yourself what credential you used.
So that's the name I used.
Region is the US West one.
US West one.
This is the region of the Beanstalk.
For me.
Make sure you give the correct region name.
Okay, then.
Okay.
Yeah.
Then our three eight seal command.
So I'm going to paste it here.
You can get that from the resources.
I think you did all in one line.
So a switch.
And then in single code we give the click command.
Not directly.
So the first command uploads the artifact to the S3 bucket.
Second Command creates a new application version in Beanstalk application.
Third is going to deploy that application version to bean stack environment.
So take your time.
Go through these commands and pretty simple commands.
And let's see if this.
And commit and push.
I will call it as being stage pipeline control less.
That checkmark is published.
This branch.
Sure.
Okay.
Now, the next thing is pretty simple.
We create the pipeline and execute it.
But before we do that, one final thing on the bean stack.
So go to B stack environment.
And that's the URL, right?
Let's click on that.
Okay.
So that's the default application, the sample application.
When we deploy our artifact, it will be accessible at slash login and target group, which does the
health check will be checking by default the health slash our application response at slash login.
So we need to update the health check of this environment before the deployment.
So go to our environment configuration.
And come down to the load balancer section.
I think it's up there.
The processes put a checkmark there.
Action.
Edit.
And if you see health, check it slash.
We need to change it to slash log in and save it.
That's not it.
Not just safe.
You also need to apply it.
Once you apply it, we'll start making the change and it will take some time.
You need to wait until this is completely okay.
Now this may go to.
Unhealthy state.
It may go to degraded it.
Not it may.
It will because sample application doesn't respond to its last login if you see that.
So this is what will return in the health check and it will fail.
But don't worry.
Once we deploy our artifact, this will go green.
So don't worry.
If this becomes red, this is supposed to happen.
After we deploy our artifact, it will go to green.
Okay.
Now the final part.
We need to create the pipeline.
So I'm going to say the Jenkins new item.
I will call this a C, C, D hyphen.
Jenkins hyphen bean hyphen stage.
You need to remember this job name very well because we will be mentioning this job in in production
pipeline.
You will see that.
But make sure you give proper name.
Select pipeline and let's copy.
Right.
Copied from the CI pipeline.
So it copies everything.
And then we'll make the change.
Okay.
So make sure this is checkmark.
And pipeline script from a select git mention your repository now I copied everything You must be also
having the job You copy it and you get everything same except you just need to change the branch.
So what is our branch name?
Our branch name is CCD Gen Bin Hyphen stage.
I'll give that.
CI cd hyphen gen.
Jen.
Bean hyphen, stitch.
Oops.
Hyphen, stitch.
Right.
If you don't have the previous jobs, you should have the previous job.
We tested the continuous integration pipeline, so you just copy, you get everything and you just change
the branch name.
And you say, See?
Okay.
Before we do this, let's see if this is done.
We want it to be health severe.
That is fine, but you need to have it stable, not in the deploying state.
So once it is like this, then we can start testing it.
So let's click on Build now.
Okay.
Let's check out the logs.
That failed.
Oh, I make a huge blunder.
So inside the stage you need to have steps, obviously.
So steps.
Open curly brace and close it here.
Now you will not make this mistake because you already have the this pipeline in the resource section.
So it will be incorrect format.
So in the steps you have with a credential, let's verify all the opening and closing of curly brace.
This is for the stage.
This is for the steps and this is for the width.
Credentials can be good.
Let's save this.
Let's commit and push.
Updated steps in the stage.
See what?
To put that checkmark.
Okay.
They should already trigger the pipeline.
Let's go back.
Hmm.
Not yet.
This is strange.
It did not trigger.
Configure.
Between the right branch.
De Jin Bean stage.
Kitchen stage.
Let's go to GitHub.
Three refresh.
Art sees it has a push.
Less than a minute ago.
Then it should have triggered the pipeline.
Okay.
Let's check the Web hooks.
Books.
Edit.
Recent deliveries.
That also went fine.
If we try this one, we deliver.
You deliver this payload?
Yeah.
It's going fine.
Okay.
I'm going to make one more change and test it once again.
Um, this time.
Let's check the read me dot md file.
Okay.
Add some more hash there.
Control less.
Commit and push.
Just.
Web.
Hook.
Checkmark.
Okay.
Let's check once again.
Still not happening.
Let's do a build now.
Oh.
It did not pull the source code, it seems.
Maybe that is the reason.
Well tested once again.
But let this pipeline complete first.
Once again now I think it will work.
Okay.
That's the wrong command that I mentioned there.
And we and it should be controlled less.
Government and push.
And we in command control us.
Put that checkmark.
Okay.
Let's check once again.
Yeah.
Yeah, it triggered.
No, that one was not happening.
Maybe because the code was not pulled.
Okay.
The pipeline got triggered.
Let's wait for it to complete.
Okay.
That is a success.
A successful pipeline.
And let's check our environment.
Let's refresh this.
Okay.
It's in a healthy state and it may take some time.
So hold on.
If it's not there yet, let's keep refreshing.
And the running version still shows sample application, but it has deployed a new application.
You need to just refresh this page.
Now you see running version three, that's the build ID.
Now, if you click on that link control click, you should see our new application deployed.
Right.
You go to the application questions and you should see the new application there.
And that downloaded from the S3 bucket.
So in the S3 bucket, also, you should have that artifact.
So go to your S3 bucket bit.
Yeah.
Object refresh there.
That's the S3 bucket.
And we have the artifact in that.
Right.
So the command uploads the artifact to a three bucket and then it creates then application version there,
and then it will do the deployment to the environment.
Okay.
So that is for the staging environment.
That pipeline production environment is also similar, but there's a little catch and we will talk about
that in the next lecture.
So complete this and join me in the next one.