All right.
It's time to create a pipeline for production environment that is almost similar to staging environment.
As I said, there's a little catch which we'll talk about.
But first, we need to create the production environment.
Let's go to Elastic Beanstalk and go to the applications.
I select your application.
I click on that.
Yeah.
Make sure you are in the application.
You have the environment over here.
This is the staging environment.
We'll create one more environment.
Create new environment.
Web Server Environment Select.
And we'll call it as a pro app, prod, hyphen, E and V.
Same name will give in the domain.
Again, you need to give a different name.
You can add some numbers over here to make it unique.
So click on check availability if it says it's not available.
Make sure you change something over there and it is unique.
Like a platform.
Same it.
Tomcat.
And sample application configure mode option so similar step capacity will change to to micro.
And we'll see.
Load balanced.
Minimum two maximum for.
Let's come down.
See.
Rolling updates and deployments.
Rolling deployment policy and 50%.
So that will be one instance of greed at a time.
See.
And that is it will create the environment.
And we'll wait for it to come up.
So I'll pause my screen and come back when this is ready.
After waiting a few minutes.
It has created the environment, the production environment, and if you click on the link, it will
have the sample application.
Now, before we go ahead and write the pipeline code, we will make the health check change.
Same with it for staging environment.
We will change the load balancer health check from slash to slash login.
So configuration load balancer and then come to the processes.
I can edit and change the health check to slash login.
And apply the change as we did.
Same for the staging environment.
This will also take some time and the health will go to the degraded state.
Once we deploy our artefact, it will come in an okay state.
Okay, let's write our code.
Let's go to get Bash and let me create a new branch.
Get.
Branch git check out hyphen B and this one to.
Prod.
Let's open the code.
Code dot.
Nat opens the voice code.
So he's asking to publish the new branch.
We will be doing that.
But let's make the code change now.
I said there is a catch and this is the catch.
So we have application versions.
Now this version is deployed to the staging environment and let's say it is tested and everything comes
out fine.
Now we need to deploy that same version to the production, right?
If manually, we just put a checkmark action and we can say deploy and we can select the production
environment.
But we have to do this from our Jenkins file intelligently.
So it picks up that version, the same one which is deployed to the staging environment.
How will do that?
Well, turns out it's pretty simple.
Now, for versioning, we're using the build ID.
Let's go to the Jenkins.
So in this right staging pipeline, the latest build out is three.
It is the successful build and this is the same we are using for the version.
So if this complete successfully, it is tested, everything is fine.
We what we would like to fetch the same build I.D. from this pipeline this pipeline into the production
pipeline.
So.
In our Jenkins file for production.
We need to find out a way from where we can fetch the latest build from the staging pipeline, and this
is how it will be done.
We define a variable.
You can use any variable you want.
I just say build number Jenkins dot instance dot get item job name here.
We mentioned the job name.
So let's go to Jenkins.
Let's copy that job name exactly as it is.
And we put it there.
Dart last successful build number which currently is three.
So it's going to this command is going to fetch the builder three and store it into this variable.
Right.
And.
For the artefact name.
We are going to mention that variable, not the builder because if we mention build ID here, it will
be the build ID of this pipeline, the production pipeline, which is wrong.
We want the build idea of staging pipeline so that variable put it there.
So that defines the artifact that you want to deploy and the app version that you want to deploy.
Now that gets us the last successful build number from the staging pipeline, which we use for versioning
and which we use for the naming of the artifact.
But when we come down here.
The commands are to upload the artifact.
Now that is only there in the bucket.
The same artifact we want to deploy.
So we don't want this command.
Let's remove that.
The second one create application version.
Oops.
Create application version that is also already there.
The same version we want to deploy to production.
Right.
So we'll remove that as well.
So only thing remaining is update the environment.
Right.
And with this version.
And that variable we already defined here.
Right.
That vision, which is the last build number so turns out to be just not not we don't need to add anything
in the pipeline.
We need to actually remove the commands.
Right.
So this command is going to simply do this.
It's a big stack.
Yeah, it's going to go to that find that Virgin label and it's going to see action, deploy and selectable
production environment.
That's all it is going to do.
That's all we need to do also.
Okay.
So the rest of the things you do not need.
So let's remove all the other stages.
So I'm going to select all the stages.
Yeah.
Sorry.
All the stages will remove.
This is just a deployment for the production.
Only one stage you need.
Yeah, that's that.
Let's compare stages.
Stage steps.
Okay.
This is good.
Let's see it.
And let's say comet and push.
My plan code for prod.
Put that checkmark.
Let's create a pipeline for this branch.
So let's go to Jenkins.
Oh.
One more thing.
Let's go back to voice code.
The environment name.
We have just kept it as it is.
This is supposed to be the production environment deployment.
So we need to give the production.
Environment name with pro app, hyphen pro or hyphen E and V.
So make sure you update that.
Save it once again, and then we commit and push it once again.
Push to prod e and V control s.
Put that checkmark.
Okay.
Now let's go to Jenkins.
New item.
Clive Jenkins.
I haven't been hyphen proud.
Pipeline and copy everything from.
Yeah.
That one.
Cecil Jenkins.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Been staging.
Now, the only thing we need to change now, after we copied everything, that will be just the branch
name here.
All right, so we created this branch CCD.
Jen Bean hyphen prod.
Let's see if this.
And time to test it.
Wait.
Before you run this pipeline, make sure your environment.
Yeah.
It's settled.
Yes, it will be in civil state, but it is settled.
There's no change happening there.
Okay.
Now let's do build now.
Yeah.
Okay, that failed.
Let's see what happened.
Okay.
Now, this was expected.
When you are trying to fetch the builder ID from another pipeline, another job, it will ask you for
the approval.
Okay.
So administrators can decide, okay, fine.
So control and click on it opens a new tab.
I'd ask for the approval.
Just say approve.
Right.
You need to go back once again.
And you do this a few times.
Run once again, Bill.
Now.
Okay.
It's not giving the signature, though.
I need to go here.
Dashboard Manager Jenkins.
In process script approval.
Click on that.
Hmm.
Doesn't show anything approve.
It should add.
Yeah.
That it should have done here, also approved.
Okay, fine.
We don't need to go there.
Okay.
Just click on Approve, then go back.
And you need to do this a few times.
Because it sets approval for different, different things.
Okay.
One more time.
It failed.
Once again.
Now this is just one time.
Approve.
Okay.
So you see, keep adding things over here for the approval.
All right, so second one there.
Yeah.
Once again, so totally.
I think it's 3 to 4 times.
To get the build.
Number 41 also failed.
Yeah, I know.
It's annoying.
You can.
You just need to do it once and once it is done.
Once it starts running, then every time it will run.
Okay.
I think this is the last time.
True.
I see different different things there.
It's.
It's for the approval.
They now?
Okay.
Yeah, that triggered.
No.
So we did it like, what, four times.
But this is only once.
Okay, so the deployment completed successfully.
Let's check the production environment.
Okay.
So the upgrade is still going on and you see batch one is already completed.
That means one instance deployment is completed.
It's going for the second instance now.
Once both the incidents are upgraded with the latest version.
Then the upgrade will be completed.
Let's wait for a few minutes.
Okay.
They are it completed successfully.
And as you see the running version, it is still showing sample application.
But if you refresh the page.
Then you should see three.
That's the same one deployed for the staging environment also.
Right.
So that's so staging environment.
It has the vision tree and the production environment that is also having the version three.
So there we have successfully tested both the pipeline.
Now it's time to look at in a flow.
So complete this and join me in the next lecture.