Okay.
So let's look at in a flow now.
So we have to pipeline the staging pipeline and production pipeline.
So let's say the developer makes the code change.
Let's switch to.
Check out.
Stage.
You know, why not just do it?
Everything from the voice code.
Once again, code dot.
So I'm in the staging branch.
Right.
And assuming developers are making code change and really we don't make any code change here while practicing,
we just make some changes to read more file.
We'll add some hash there and we'll see control s save assuming developer made the code change.
Right.
Save it and then commit and push.
Okay.
Testing stage pipeline.
Control less so developer made the code change.
They tested it locally.
Now they're going to push it to.
GitHub.
And once they push, that should trigger.
This pipeline, staging pipeline there, it got triggered, right?
So let's wait for it to complete.
Okay.
So after a few minutes, the deployment completed successfully.
Right.
So gets the notification.
And then the software testing team quality assurance or whoever is responsible test it validates it.
Everything is fine.
They give a go ahead to deploy it for the production environment.
All right.
So all we need to do is then we will check out.
To the production branch.
All right.
Okay, let me clear the screen.
Now we need to merge all the change from staging to production.
Since it is tested, everything is good.
So we say get merge.
Merged with the staging branch.
The production branch also comes at the same level as the staging branch once that is done.
Then the.
Sorry.
I need to push it.
Right.
Get push origin.
You can do it from here or you can do it from the VTS code also.
So we push it.
Let's go to.
The production job.
Okay.
There you see that?
It already started.
And if you click it later, it will already complete.
You see that?
That happened very quickly.
So in Bienstock you see we have the new version and the new versions will be also deployed.
Make sure there is a gap in between the staging pipeline and the merge that you do.
And because Bienstock is going to take some time to deploy the latest version.
Right.
So we have two instances, 50%, one instance at a time.
So it's going to take some time for the deployment.
So once the staging environment deployment is completed, then merge the code with the production branch,
which will trigger the production deployment pipeline.
And then it is going to deploy the latest version, which will be same as the staging version.
All right.
Very well.
Once this is tested, all fine.
Try do the deployment a few more times.
See, everything works fine.
And when you are done, some cleanup steps we need to do first.
Starting with.
Now let's shut down Jenkins nexus and sooner QB as you'll see extra instances over here those with the
bean stack instance.
So let's select sonar nexus Jenkins and we'll see.
Stop.
Power off.
And these Bienstock instance will not do anything.
We will delete the beans tag application, which will in turn delete everything for us.
So the application.
Delete the application.
And let's give the application name.
And delete, which in tone will delete delete to other environments, to environments, and then delete
the application if it is not deleted.
This will take some time, so check after some time.
If it is not deleted, then try and delete it multiple times.
Sometimes it just holds.
It is not in the correct state.
We cannot delete it now, so wait and then delete it.
That's all you need to do in the cleanup part.
Delete the profile application and.
Stop your instances.
If you want, you can delete the S3 bucket but the 17.3 and be not big size it multiple versions you
should have right.
So this should not take much space so I won't charge you anything.
But if you want to delete the three bucket first delete all the objects, then delete the SD bucket.
And that's all in the cleanup part.
Keep the instances.
We will need them.
That is all in this lecture.
I will see you in the next one.