Hello and welcome to the prerequisites session.
In this video we are going to talk about what are
the skills that you need to have in this course.
So in order to follow along in this
course, you need to have some understanding about
Linux systems and intermediate knowledge should be fine.
Some basics of scripting knowledge like Bash scripting
or even if you have knowledge of any
other scripting language that is also fine.
Some troubleshooting skills you need to have.
You get into issues and then you find out what is
the what are the problems and then you fix them, which
will be really based on your previous experience with your job
or with some tools that you have learned.
Basics of AWS.
If you have knowledge of EC Two, elastic load,
balancer, s, three buckets, this should be enough.
There are so many other services that we are going to
learn in all these projects that we're going to do and
I'm going to explain about those services, how to use them
and how to include them into the projects.
Some networking and security concepts like
port numbers, protocols, firewalls and securities.
If you already used AWS EC Two, then
things like security group should be fine.
If you have knowledge and security
group that should be fine.
And some basics of virtualization concepts like
virtual machines, virtual storage, virtual networks which
you'd have already used in AWS.
Intermediate understanding of Jenkins or some hands on
experience on Jenkins tool, some hands on experience
on ansible like writing very, very basic, basic
playbooks, having understanding of continuous integration and continuous
delivery and understanding should be fine.
Because we have many projects on continuous integration
and continuous delivery, we are going to do
all that, but having a basic knowledge of
that will be an added advantage.
Basic knowledge of containers, especially docker,
like installing docker engine and running
some very very basic docker containers.
So all these are the predicacides for this course.
The skills that you need to have.
If you feel that you are not so sure
about these skills, then you can even join my
decoding DevOps live online course where I cover DevOps
from the very scratch starting from the Linux machines
and you will get a deep understanding of Jenkins,
ansible continuous integration, continuous delivery, docker kubernetes and many
many AWS services.
That is if you are a total newbie.
But if you don't know any of this tool or any
of this technology that are in the previco sites, then you
can either learn them before you start the course or when
you get into the course, when you get into a project
and you feel that you need to know this technology at
that time, also you can learn.
So all the very best and
good luck for the upcoming project.
Thank you very much for watching.
I'll see you in the next one.