Hello and welcome.
In this video, we will be talking about tools and technologies, prerequisites.
Before you dive into the project videos, you need to set a few things first.
So there will be so many technologies working together in the upcoming project videos.
We need to get ready for that.
Starting with GitHub repository, where we have kept all the code scripts and files which you need in
this course.
So let's see that first.
So open up your browser and you can see GitHub dot com slash dev ops equity club slash view profile
project.
Hey enter.
You should bookmark this link will be using this throughout our course.
In the GitHub repository that we have, you have several branches and based on which project you are,
you will select that particular branch.
I will let you know in the project that which branch will be using for a particular project.
Like for example, if you are doing continuous delivery with Jenkins and Ansible together, then we'll
be selecting this branch.
Or if you're doing a cloud formation, you'll be going to cloud formation branch.
If you're doing Kubernetes, you'll be going to Kubernetes branch.
For Kubernetes itself, you have three different branches cube CD, Cube app, and Kubernetes setup.
So likewise we have several other branches.
Based on the project, I'll tell you which branch you should be using in the project.
If you want, you can clone this for now.
But I will tell you in a few minutes what tool will be using to access this repository.
So whenever I use the word as source code or repository, I mean to see this GitHub repository.
Okay.
Now let's check the other tools and signups that we need to do.
We will be working in three areas in these videos, the tools that we need to install on a laptop or
desktop.
Second, the sign ups that we need to do on some accounts.
And third, some e w s prerequisites that we be doing.
So let's get start with the tool, lets see the tools that we will be installing.
We need Oracle VM VirtualBox Git Bash Vagrant.
And chocolate if you're using Windows System or you can install BRU if you're using macros.
Also we need a few more tools.
JDK eight Maven Intel e.g. which will be your ID if you prefer to use something else like Visual Studio,
or if you have any other personal preference you can go with.
That will be also using Sublime Text Editor.
Also A.W. Seelye And there are a few tools like, for example, TerraForm that will be setting up in
the project itself.
Few places you need to sign up like GitHub.
You also need to purchase a domain.
I will be using GoDaddy platform for that.
If you have any personal preference in that, then you can use any other domain registrar account also
on Docker Hub to store our Docker images and also sorts near cloud.
On edibles.
We need to do a few things.
We need to force to get a free diet account.
Ruleset set one.
I am user with multi-factor authentication.
We'll set a billing alarm and will also get a certificate from a WSP, which we will be using in setting
up H2 DPS.
Secure Connection.
So let's get started with the tools first.