The first tool that we'll be installing is chocolaty.
chocolaty is a tool in Windows to install software through command line like choice install notepad++.
That will be the command to install notepad++.
And this is not a mandatory tool.
You can just search for software on the Internet and download and install also.
But this is just to make your life easy.
So you open PowerShell or command prompt and run the command and install the software.
If you do not want to install chocolaty you are having trouble installing chocolate then you can.
even skip this part.
Then you have to install all the softwares that I show you.
Manually, search on the internet, download and install.
So just search for chocolatey.
This is for windows.
If you're using mac os, then I have another tool for you which is homebrew that I'll show you in a
minute.
So chocolatey will be our tool to install all the other tools.
And first we need to install chocolatey.
And for that, this is the command.
And we're going to run this command on PowerShell.
When we run this command in PowerShell, it will install Chocolaty.
And then we can use chocolate install command to install all the other tools.
So let me open PowerShell first.
You have to open PowerShell as administrator.
So right click and run as administrator.
We need to run a few commands to check.
If we can install chocolatey, you have to run this get execution policy.
command.
If this returns restricted, then we have to run this command.
So it reads All signed for me.
But if you received restricted, then you better run this.
command.
Just say yes to it and then you should be able to install chocolatey. So copy this command,
once you're done, open your PowerShell.
Paste this command if you should just right click.
It should paste. Hit enter.
If you get error like this, that means your antivirus maybe blocking the software to be installed.
I have McAfee and I'm going to disable it.
For 15 minutes.
But now you have to close PowerShell and open it once again.
Let's copy the command.
And let's run it.
Let's hit.
Enter.
And now it started installing Chocolaty.
Once you have chocolatey installed, then you can search for any software in this website.
If you want to install VirtualBox or we can just search for VirtualBox and it will give us the command.
I see.
I understand.
So if you give us the command to install VirtualBox.
So you can just go install VirtualBox.
It will install VirtualBox or any of the software that you are looking for.
Like IntelliJ
Okay.
So you get the commands and then you can install your tools.
That was a convenient tool for Windows user.