Hello and welcome.
In this video, we will see
how to install Homebrew on macOS.
Homebrew is a tool to install softwares or packages.
We will be installing some software or tools in the
next lecture, and we will be using Homebrew on macOS.
So let's search for Homebrew.
So open your browser, search for Homebrew, and
click on the first link, brew sh.
There you see a link or the command.
You just need to copy this command
and run this command on the terminal.
So let's open the terminal.
All right, let's paste the command on
the terminal command v, hit Enter.
Enter.
The password hit Enter.
After the installation, you will see two commands.
I'm going to pace those commands.
This one.
Now, you don't see this after the installation
here, because I have already installed Brew.
But you will see this command.
You can copy and paste this in the terminal.
That's one command.
And the next one.
After running these two commands, you
can start using Brew command.
So if you just type Brew and hit
Enter, you should see some output like this.
Now, by using Brew command, you can install
software so you can search for your software.
We will be installing a tool called Maven.
So let's search for Maven, and you get
the command of how to install Maven.
So just copy this and run it in
your terminal, and Maven will get installed.
That's one example.
Like that, you can search for
any software, for example, JDK.
Or you can search for, let's
say, vagrant, which we'll be using.
So you get the command, find your software,
copy the command, run it in the terminal,
and the software will get installed.
So that is all in this video.
I will see you in the next one,
where we'll install softwares by using brew.
See you in the next one. Bye.