Okay, so now we have a very easy way of installing software on our computer.
So I will show you the list of tools that you have to install based on your operating system.
Windows user and macOS user will execute the respective commands.
So in our repository, in our source code, access the branch prereqs
In this branch there is a PDF.
You can open it here itself.
So for Windows installing tools on Windows, once you have set up the chocolatey, now you can install
all these tools, choco install virtualbox and vagrant, git, JDK8, maven, awscli, Intellij and
Sublime Text Editor. For macOS User.
Same tools, but you have homebrew to install the software and before you start installing the software,
you have to do this.
You open your terminal, execute this command exactly as it is, and then check with cat command.
and this file should contain the letter hyphen -k.
And it should be without any quotes, any double qoute or single qoute if you find it is not correct.
Open that file.
It will be in your home directory.
Make sure this file has hyphen -k option, save it, and then start installing your software's same software
but with brew command.
If you are having mac OS with M1 chip, then you do not need to install virtualbox.
The first command you need to skip.
And you execute all the rest of the commands on your terminal, which will install these softwares except
VirtualBox.
But if you have Mac OS with intel chip, then install virtualbox execute all the commands.
VirtualBox on M1 chip is not supported and we will be installing its replacement, its alternative which
is VMware.
That will be in lecture 19.
So I will be using a choco command.
And installing these tools.
So I will open PowerShell as administrator, macOS user.
You need to just open your terminal.
I will be executing these commands one by one. Simultaneously
MacOS user, You need to execute the brew install command ,one by one. Except for M1  and M2 chip,
The first command is excluded.
Also observe.
I have specified a version over here.
The latest version of VirtualBox is not working with us, or I should say not working with vagrant and
we are having a lot of issues.
So we tested.
This is the version that we will be using for now.
Later, whatever version you see in this document, you may see some version for Vagrant, you may see
some version for Git.
So make sure whatever version you see in the document, you execute that same command.
So right now in the document, if you see this version specified, then execute that version.
Okay, let's download this file so we can copy paste command easily.
Let's click on download.
Let's open that file.
So now we can copy this.
you see that?
Copy that.
Let's open PowerShell.
So I'm going to say PowerShell on my search.
And I have different versions of PowerShell, so you see different versions here.
So just right click on it and say run as administrator only as administrator, not as normal user.
You should see here administrator Windows PowerShell like this, if you don't see it, close it again,
open as administrator, right click and as soon as I right click it copies the command, it starts installing
and is asking me a question.
I will say Capital A to accept all the questions you ask.
So it's going to take a moment, download and install.
Let's go to the next command.
choco install vagrant
I'm going to install all these commands one by one on my PowerShell.
And once I'm done executing all these commands, I'll finally reboot my machine.
I'm done with VirtualBox.
I'm going to install now Vagrant.
Alright, so I have installed all my tools.
I got a small error while I'm installing sublime text.
But anyways, it's working fine.
If you are not able to install any of this tool through chocolatey, then you can also find it from the
internet, download and install it.
Like for example, sublime text editor.
But anyway, Sublime Text editor is installed.
Sublime Text three.
So it's not a problem.
Now, once you're done installing all the tools you need to reboot your machine, the reboot is specifically
for Vagrant.
So if you're done installing all the tools, reboot the machine and continue when you are done.
Okay, so now you should have all these tools installed.
Oracle VirtualBox, GitBash, Vagrant, Chocolatey or homebrew based on your operating system.
JDK8, Maven Intellij and Sublime Text Editor.
If you have these tools now ready, then we can get on to the next thing, which is signing up a few
accounts.