So we'll create an account on GitHub.
We'll talk about purchasing a domain, creating an account on Docker hub, and also creating account
on sonarcloud.
And then after that, we're going to talk about AWS Free tier account and few other changes that
we're going to make in the AWS  account.
So let's get started with GitHub first.
So open your browser.
Go to github.com
It's a simple signup process.
You give a username.
You give the email address, password and say, Sign up.
And from your inbox you confirm that email address and then you should be able to log in to github.com
.
So fill in your right details and sign up.
Okay.
I need to do some verification.
Spiral Galaxy.
Okay, that's the Spiral Galaxy maybe.
Yes.
Okay.
So account verified there.
I don't want any offers on announcements.
I'm going to go for a free plan and that should be fine for our project.
Welcome to GitHub.
So select.
What kind of work do you do?
Mainly.
So I'm going to see a teacher.
And a student.
Oh.
I can select either of it.
Okay.
So I shall be.
I'm a teacher.
Most software engineer.
How much programming experience do you have?
Select whatever you are good at.
Who do you plan to use GitHub for learn git and GitHub, host project.
That should be good for now.
And you can see a complete setup.
After this check your inboxes.
Should get an email verified that email address.
Okay.
So my email is verified.
So that is done.
We have created an account on GitHub.
That should be fine for now.
We use it later.
Next we will talk about purchasing a domain.
So if you have never done this, then I'll show this to you.
Or else if you already know about this, then you can purchase domain from any of the domain registrar.
I will use GoDaddy.
So you can search for a domain like, for example, my dev ops projects or see if this domain is available.
Yeah.
199 per year for me.
So you can say add to cart and you can sign in if you don't have an account with the domain registrar, Create
an account.
purchase a domain and don't go for free domains.
There are also free domains, but we'll be doing so many settings in this DNS.
So we will need a paid domain where we can go to the advanced settings of DNS.
So whatever you feel like you can purchase, dot com, dot in on whatever domain you want, you give a name,
search for it.
You really don't need to get a very expensive one.
Any domain should be fine.
Okay.
Once you made the purchase and then you log in, you should see your domain.
I have groophy.in.
And you should see the DNS records you click on DNS service and you will see a few records.
We are going to add a lot of records.
If you know how to use it, you can start using it already.
But if you don't know, don't worry.
We'll be using it in our projects many times.
Okay, so once you have the domain, the next thing will do is create an account on Docker hub.
We just need to create account, that's all.
So let's go to Docker Hub.
Search for Docker Hub on the net.
You should find Docker Hub site.
Not that that's the wrong one.
Docker hub, hub.docker.com
Okay.
So we'll sign up.
So give some ID.
like a username kubeimran.
I'm giving.
And give your email address and password and say sign up.
I'm not a robot.
Sign up.
You need to choose a plan.
You can go with the free plan.
That should be fine.
Verifying your email address, so I should get an email.
And let me refresh it once again.
So we created an account on Docker hub.
And that's all for now.
On Docker Hub.
We are going to store Docker images on this in the Docker projects.
Ok last thing
In the sign up, we have sonar cloud.
Let's log into the sooner cloud.
sonarcloud.io.
.
Click on it.
And you can sign up with your GitHub account or Bitbucket azure DevOps or GitLab account. We will sign
up with GitHub account.
So as the authorized allowed, I have already signed into my GitHub account from the same browser.
So I'm getting this or else you will get a log in.
window where you
can use your username and password of GitHub account.
We will click on this, create projects manually.
Then you can import all of the things from GitHub, but we really don't have anything on GitHub.
So I'm going to create organization manually, so let's give a name.
So for the time being, I'm giving vprofile-projects.
vprofile-projects.
Now that has to be unique.
So you give your own name.
Every plan should be fine for us and we see clear organization.
So that's our organization name.
vprofile-projects,
You create your own name and a project key.
I'd say vpro-analysis.
Any project name you can give.
And say set up.
That is all this much is fine when we see when we use it into our AWS project.
AWS CICD project.
There you need to mention this organization name and project name so you can take a note or any time
you can log in and find out your organization name and your project name.
All right, then.
That should be all in.
Sign up.
So we are doing good, we have GitHub account now we have a domain, we have created an account on Docker hub
and we have a sonar cloud account and we have configured the organisation and project in sonar cloud.