Next we have to talk about AWS.
We are going to create a free tier account on AWS and also do some changes on that.
Like we will create an IAM user with multi-factor authentication, we will set a billing alarm.
So in case accidently, if you use any expensive service or if you have kept your resources that you have not
cleaned, then we should get bills.
So as soon as a bills are spiking, we should get an alarm.
We should get a notification.
And finally, we're going to create a certificate.
From AWS ACM service, Amazon Certificate Managers Service which will be used for https, secure connection.
Secure connection.
So let's get started with AWS.
All right, so just search for AWS free tier and you will find some links.
This one, Free Cloud Computing Services.
Click on this.
And AWS has created some really nice video explaining you what is free tier and how do you use it?
And also to check if you are exceeding year limit.
So I recommend you take your time and watch these videos.
But in short, I will tell you we are  creating aws free tier account so we can use AWS cloud computing
without paying.
Anything or paying little bit of amount.
Now I see a little bit of amount because we will be crossing our free tier limit in some of projects.
And when we do that, I am going to alert you. Now since this is a complete hands on course and we will
be seeing many production use cases.
Obviously, we need to go more than free tier.
But that would be very minimum, and you really don't need to worry about it.
We will be also setting billing alarms so if we get any bills.
We will get a notification and we can clean our resources.
So I would say just create the free tier account.
Let's click on create a free account.
First giving up the email address.
So that's what I am giving.
I am now DevOps.
Make sure this email address exists because we need to verify this.
Do not use any fake details here.
You can give an account name, so I'm just going to give the same name.
I am now dev ops.
And let's see.
Verify email address.
So let's get the verification code.
Okay.
So I got the verification code in my inbox and I am going to just paste it there.
Verify.
Next is root user password.
Make sure it is longer and it contains alphanumeric character and even symbols.
And if you say you cannot remember such password, then use password managers.
There are many online available.
But really do not give a simple password.
This is going to be your public cloud account.
So be careful with this.
Okay.
Next personal account you go to select and fill in all this detail.
I will quickly fill this and go to the next step.
Okay.
Next comes the card detail.
You can use credit or debit card.
And let me tell you, if it's a debit card, Indian debit card, it will detect ₹2.
And for international call it is going to use $1 which is mentioned over here.
This is verification and it is just to verify your identity.
Do not worry.
It is not going to take any money from your account.
As long as we are in free tier and we keep our account clean, we won't see any bills or very, very
minute bill.
So I will fill in all this detail and go to the next step.
Okay, next comes verification of your phone number.
So give you a phone number and get an estimate and verify this.
Okay.
Then comes next support plan.
So we are really going to use basic support free.
When you're working for a project, there is a chance that the company would have taken a business support.
And I can tell you many of the places I have seen people are not even using the regular support, even
if they have plans.
So check when you're working on a project, if you have a support and if you get into issues with AWS
or Google Cloud or Azure, anything in check if they have support.
And you can directly talk to the tech support team anyway.
And that is for later part, let's just select basic support for now and see complete sign up.
All right.
Congratulations.
It says
And we say thank you.
Let's go to the AWS Management Console.
Okay.
Let's see.
Sign in to console.
So this will be your very regular page to log into a console.
And this account is called a root user account.
So whenever I use the word root user, AWS root user, that means this account which you use to sign
sign up for AWS.
So let's say next.
All right.
captcha.
Password.
Okay.
Now, let me take a pause here and talk about this.
AWS is now offering a new console.
That means the UI, the website, this console is getting updated and this happens very regularly.
It's really difficult to keep updating video simultaneously with the new console.
So you see new console now and a few months you will see a few new things and you it just keep on happening.
That's not a big concern because the features and services that I'm showing you in the video will be
same, but the UI will be different.
So.
I will be constantly updating the course, but then there will be a chance where I will be lagging.
Or like me, many of the instructors are facing this problem.
But that is really not a serious concern for you because UI will be different.
The settings, the features will be same.
So we just need to click instead of left, maybe need to click on right or maybe just need to look a
little bit more.
Well, let me tell you, I'll be constantly updating the video so you will have minimal problems.
So let's switch to new console home.
Okay.
So as we are now in, we will check whether our account is really active or not.
And for that I recommend a small test you will see ec2 hear, which is a virtual machine service
or from here.
Also you can search for service.
EC2.
And you can click on this.
And if you get a screen like I'm getting like instance zero, everything zero.
And you see the details over here.
That means our account is active, it's enabled.
Otherwise you will get some errors over here which will be like verify your phone or card or something
like that.
Click on that and you verify the details.
And if you think everything you have verified, still your account is not active, it is showing errors,
then you check with the support team.
So you go to.
There, support center and you create a ticket and you can chat also with them.
You give them the details.
My account is not active.
They will immediately activate it or maybe take a little bit of time.
Okay.
Now, since we have our account, let's quickly do a few very important things, starting with creating
a user.
The user that we logged in is a root user and I do not recommend using a root user to use AWS services.
We are going to create another user called as just IAM user so find IAM service.
Click on it.
Okay.
So the first thing we see here is security recommendation.
It says Add MFA for root user.
MFA is multi-factor authentication.
So basically you will have a software installed on your phone.
Which is Google authenticator and it is going to show you six digit code and every time you need to enter
that along with your password.
Just like your OTP, SMS based.
This is going to be OTP with Google Authenticator, so we will do that first.
Very important, Add MFA.
And it says Activate MFA, click on this button, see virtual MFA device and continue.
And it will show a QR code.
You need to install Google Authenticator on your phone.
Which is something like this, and you just click on add here and scan the barcode and you will get
a six digit number here which gets refreshed every 30 seconds.
So I will do that on my phone quickly.
Okay.
I just did it.
And you need to enter the MFA code that you get on your app and wait for 32nd it gets refreshed, then
enter the second one and just say Assign MFA.
Okay.
That is done.
Now we'll go to Dashboard.
Okay.
So this is all green.
Let's go to users. Now
We will be using and I am user I will say add user.
Now I will give my username as admin or I will see it admin.
And you have to select your password.
Now, there are two types of access types to access types.
One is console, which is through the browser.
Console means even new access to the browser.
Basically that's called aws console and another one is programmatic access.
This is going to be, we will be using this when we use AWS CLI or when we use automation.
Like when you use Ansible or TerraForm to access AWS resources, then we are going to use this.
For now, do not use this.
And.
One more alert over here.
Access keys.
Secret keys are very, very dangerous.
If you are not careful with them.
So remember this for your life.
If you have access, key and secret key, keep it very, very safe.
Do not post them on public repository or public places.
Make sure nobody has access to it except you.
Because if it is publicly available, it will be immediately hacked and there'll be immediate bitcoin
mining starting in your account.
And you will see huge bills.
It's a big problem when you're working in projects.
If it's your free your personal account.
There'll be some limits to it.
It cannot go more than a certain limit and AWS will alert you.
But for projects, business accounts, you will have unlimited.
Access and so as the hacker will also have.
So if bitcoin mining if not that, then there will be ransom.
And it's very.
This one's very, very common hack that happens with AWS accounts, and it is only if we are
not careful.
Otherwise, it's very, very safe.
So for now, just go with console access, auto generate password, or you can say custom password and
give your own password.
I'll just go with auto generate and this password will be reset when we log in with this.
So let's go next.
Attach existing policy now.
This is what makes it very dangerous or maybe useful policies are permissions for this user.
So I'm saying administrator access because we will use this user throughout the course to do many admin
work.
So we need this policy administrator access go next.
Next review create user.
So I have the username and password.
I'm going to download .csv file.
And that will contain username and password.
Let's close this.
Okay.
Along with this, we need to do also one more thing.
Let's go to Dashboard and we need to customize this link.
This is the link that we, the IAM user, will use to log into the account and it contains the account
ID and I'm going to create an alias instead of account ID so giving some name.
So I'll just see I am now DevOps, same name or you can give a different name.
So that will be the URL for the iam user to log into this account.
save changes.
Okay.
Next we will set up MFA for this user.
Also very important.
Go to this user.
Security credentials.
And will see assign MFA device.
And same process.
Okay.
Good.
Now our account is safe and we have an IAM  user and this user has administrative access permission and
you can add more permission.
I mean, administrator is the maximum, but if you want to create account for anybody else and you don't
want administrator access, you can change the access also like read access or a specific service access.
Okay, good.
Our account is safe.
Secure.
And this is from others.
We also want to safeguard our account from our own actions, which is, irresponsibly
if you kept something ON for a very, very long time, you get huge bills and you should have a billing
alarm.
There are so many horror stories about that.
Even there are many memes floating on the Internet about this.
So if you kept something accidentally ON for a long time.
You can set a billing alarm and you get an email notification that your bill is crossing about certain
dollars and you can check.
And fix those things.
Now get for this one.
We will be going to, not here, this question mark.
Oops.
Sorry.
They have, they keep moving things.
We will go to the billing dashboard and click on Billing Dashboard.
So you can keep checking this.
I recommend, you know, before you go to sleep, just check your bills.
How much it is every night.
Or maybe once you wake up in the morning.
But I'm setting here.
Free tier alerts or billing alerts.
Sorry.
So here you have option billing preferences.
Click on that.
And here, here select receive pdf invoice by email receive free tier usage alerts.
So if you cross your free tier, you will get alerts.
Let's give our email address there.
And receive billing alerts.
So select all these things.
save preference.
Okay.
Now let's click on this AWS logo here.
Let's go back.
And now you have to find a service called as Cloud Watch.
Cloud Watch is monitoring service.
We will be using this monitoring service in our course.
But right now we all we need to monitor is our bills.
And you need to be in this North Virginia region over here.
We will understand later what this region means.
But think of this as like a data center.
So you need to be here in North Virginia.
If you are somewhere else, make sure you select, north Virginia.
And we will go to alarms.
We click on all alarms.
And we will create alarm.
Select your metric on what you want to set the alarm.
You should see billing if you do not see billing.
Make sure you have put those checkmarks on and you are in North Virginia region.
Then only you will see this billing metric over here.
Click on that will set total estimated charge on that.
We want to set the alarm and we'll select the currency USD and select metric.
Now, you really do need to understand this.
now. We have a separate section for this one.
All you need to do is you go here and you say, let's say, five.
So if I say five and my bill crosses more than $5, I will get email notification.
Okay.
So you can set like that and you can say go next.
Now to set notification.
It uses a service called SNS Simple Notification Service.
We need to give our email address here so we do not have any sns topic.
SNS topic basically means there will be mostly an email address attached to the topic.
So we do not have any topic will create new topic and will give topic a name.
I will call this as let's say monitoring team.
We can give any name there and give the email address.
And say create  topic.
Now this topic will exist in North Virginia region.
You can use it any time you want.
You can just select your topic and use it.
We will be using this later, for now, just billing alarms and just say next.
Give alarm a name
I just see billing alert.
.
Or maybe AWS building alert, give something scary, but not too much scary.
Otherwise it will go to spam.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Next.
And this is all our settings and to create alarm.
Okay.
So.
We need to confirm your email address.
So let's go to our inbox, Gmail inbox.
So I get this email in my Gmail because I have a Gmail account, confirm subscription.
Okay.
That's confirmed.
Let's go back.
And we need to wait for a moment.
Okay.
There's a refresh button over here.
You can keep trying that.
Okay.
After a minute or so I get to the status as, okay.
That is because my bill is less than $5.
When it goes more than $5, I get notification and here you should see alarm.
All right, good.
Three things knocked down, created the account, set IAM user with MFA and created billing alarm.
We're doing good.
One more last thing.
We need to create a public certificate for our domain.
We purchased a domain.
And we will use a certificate to validate the certificate with the domain.
But what that really means is you see here to https, any website you see a https, there is this lock
symbol or you click on that and you should see here this connection is secure.
And how do you say it's a secure?
What's the guarantee?
So.
This has a valid certificate.
Now, when we set up our project, we will be also setting up HTTPS secure connection.
And what validates that is the certificate, which is tied to your domain.
So this certificate is tied to Amazon.com domain.
Now click on this and you should see the certificates that this certificate is for this.
Certificate details, certification path, etc. Now.
If you do not understand anything.
Whatever I said about the certificate.
Do not worry.
We have the project.
were we will we use it.
All you need to do is you need to go to the service called ACM Certificate Manager.
And remember the zone outside the region where you're creating the certificate.
Now we're creating a certificate from AWS itself and this one is going to be free.
You can also purchase certificate from other providers also.
But we will keep it free.
So we said it was cert and will request a public certificate, go next.
And you need to give your domain name here and you have to say star dot your domain.
So I have a domain.
k8s
k8sengineers.com
Make sure you're giving the right domain here.
I see many people are making typographical mistake in this one.
Be careful.
Give proper domain name.
And then how is this certificate validated with this domain that the certificate belongs to this domain?
How is it validated?
Well, we can do DNS validation.
or  email validation.
DNS validation is quick, so give a name to the certificate we will say name.
I will say same thing k8s
This.
So I have multiple domains.
I have grroophy.in, k8sengineers and few other.
So I'm just showing you with this domain, whatever domain you purchased, give the correct name over
here.
k8sengineers.com
Like that, request.
Now for a moment, you won't see anything over here.
Just click on this refresh button and you should see there is a certificate I.D. and it is pending validation.
So it is not verified.
The way we verify this will click on this ID here.
Scroll down.
And you see here.
CNAME name
and CNAME Value
CNAME Value.
You need to create this record.
Where you created your domain.
So I created on GoDaddy.
And I'm going to create this record over there.
If you still do not see this, refresh your page.
You will see that.
And now let me go to GoDaddy.
Okay.
So I go to my products and these are my two products two domain grouchy.in and k8sengineers I'm going
to go to k8sengineers.
I click here on Manage Domain.
Now, this UI may also change, so you just need to.
Manage DNS if you don't find the option as I am showing you would here.
Check with them or just search you will find it.
Go to manage DNS.
And you need to come over here.
DNS Records.
Now, DNS Records are basically mapping that for this IP address or for this name.
This is the IP address or for this name.
You have some other names.
For example I'll show you www maps to k8sengineers.com.
So that's one record like that.
We'll see how to create records later.
For now, what you need to do is you need to say ADD.
And you need to select here, CNAME.
And here you give the name, and here you give the value.
Okay.
So copy that.
That goes in the name.
Pasted there.
And just a moment.
I'm going to remove this full stop.
Okay.
Copy the value.
Paste it there again.
I'll remove this full stop.
And say add record.
Now when you click on add record, it will tell you that this record should be like this.
All right.
When you're trying to see what it is, trying to create a record like this here, k8sengineers.com
k8sengineers.com
Which is wrong.
It should be like this.
So you say yes, this is good and save.
Okay.
So the record is created and our ACM service, which is this one, it will try to resolve this name
with this value and that may take a few minutes or sometimes even an hour.
Very rarely takes an hour, but just wait for some time.
So you need to just keep checking whether it is pending validation or is it issued.
So keep refreshing this in a minute or 5 minutes like that and you should see this ok in some time.
So I will wait for a few minutes.
Okay, that was like just a minute or so and I get the certificate issued.
You should see that if you're not seeing this for a long, long time, still showing pending validation,
then delete the certificate created once again.
And again, add the record because mostly it's typographical mistake.
And if you think everything is perfect, you verified nothing is wrong, then check with your domain
registrar whether your domain is active or not.
Sometimes you just create a domain and it's not even active.
Okay.
So check with, like if I have issue I will check with GoDaddy.
I will check with the support that I created this record.
It's not working.
And there should be help helping you.
All right.
That was good.
And really good job.
We have set AWS account in a very, very practical way.
Oh, one thing is missing.
We have to log in with the IAM user so we will sign out.
Okay.
I just signed out without getting the URL, so I'm going to log in again.
With my root account.
I'm logging in with the root account.
Okay.
I'm going to refresh this one.
I dunno, I have many times problem with this.
wrong captcha it says many times.
Okay.
See it's asking MFA code now that's how you're secure.
Let's go to IAM.
And you can find the link over here.
There you see.
Copy that URL and just put it in the browser.
And that's my account name.
imnowdevops and I think I have same as my username.
That's a sign in.
Oh my bad.
I have the username as itadmin that I have created and I downloaded the CSV file which has the password.
Also, I know I'm showing you the password, but this will be reset.
So account name is imnowdevops, username is this.
And that's the password.
And we will see signing.
MFA code.
Okay.
Resetting the password, it will ask you to reset the password.
Confirm password change.
Switch to new console.
Nice.
Now we are done and you can use this.
IAM user.
Throughout the course.
Whenever you have a problem, go back to your root user and you can use the root user also.
But I recommend always use this.
IAM user.
All right.
That is all in the setup part.
Alright.
So we have installed a lot of tools on our system.
We have signed up on multiple accounts and we have made AWS account useful and secure for us.
All the tools are installed.
We have signed up to these four places, GitHub domain, Docker hub,sonar cloud and we have created
AWS free tier account
IAM user with the MFA , Billing Alarm and Certificate, so we're going to use all these things throughout
our projects different, different projects.
So wrap this up and join me in project videos.
Thank you very much for watching this one.