In third phase.
Now we have the stack ready.
VPC stack is there.
All the instances are up and running.
We have the controller.
Third phase is all about doing search to all these instances and doing the execution, installing packages
and running all the operating system commands.
It's not possible to controller to do a search to this instance because they are in a different VPC.
They are in the file.
VPC Air controller is in default VPC.
The controller is in default VPC.
All the instances are in the profile VPC and they're in private subnet, so you cannot access it from
the outside world.
One way is you can do VPC peering and that will be fine when you do the execution first time.
But if you want to do a regular execution, you need to have your controller in the Vpro file VPC.
What you can do is you can use the Bastion host as a controller, you can install Ansible there, you
can install BOTO and pull your clone your playbooks and execute it from there.
That's one way.
And that will be also convenient, right?
Just directly to access to Bastion host.
Run the Ansible setup, set up the IAM role and execute playbooks from there.
But.
If that is more confusing to you, The easiest solution is you can create an army of controller and
launch the instance from that army into V profile VPC.
That will be much easier.
So your controller will be just like a bastion host in the public subnet so you can access it.
And then from there you can execute your playbook.
So I'm going to do that.
I'm going to create an EMI.
Image Create image, image of controller and limitless controller.
EMI.
And see create image.
So am I is getting created.
It's going to take some time.
Now, very important point to note over here, If you're doing this in the project in a real time environment,
then remember when you are going to launch your controller.
In your secure VPC, then it will be just like the Bastion host.
So as I talked about the Bastion host.
It should be stable, safe and secure.
Same applies then to our controller machine also, and it will be much better if we use a hardened army
from Amazon marketplace.
Like from.
Center of internet security or any other army.
The hardened army that you prefer.
You better go with an hardened army.
So it becomes very difficult to exploit your controller machine.
If you want to try any hardened army, you can do that.
But let me tell you, it's not going to be free.
There are charges for the hardened armies.
We have seen that.
So for the project exercises that you're are doing, you can keep it as we are doing.
But in a project, make sure you take a hardened army.
Okay.
So am I still is available now I can launch it.
So I'll go with PT to Micro and I'm going to select a VPC that we created and we're going to select
a public subnet.
We can select public subnet two.
We already have Bastion host in public Subnet one.
And that should be it.
Let's go.
Next.
Will give a name as v profile hyphen controller.
Security group.
I'm going to put it in the same security group as the Bastion host security group.
So we can do a search to Bastion host so we can do a search to the controller.
Host also.
Also.
Our V Profile Stack Security group allows 22 access from Bastion hosts, so it makes sense to use Bastion
host security group.
Let's launch.
Will keep the same login key.
So once our v profile controller is up in the VPC.
And we profile VPC.
It got created.
Now we don't need this controller, the older one, so we can just delete that dominated action instance
state.
Dominate.
We get the IP of a new controller.
And let's make a login.
Yeah.
Let's log in.
Now, remember, this is the exact clone of our previous controller.
There is very less difference apart from its being it being in a different network in a V profile VPC.
Okay.
Everything is up to date.
You can make a login test from here.
We'll log into one of the instance.
From our V profile stack, we have the login key.
Can use that login key as a I find I log in key and we need to get the IP.
Private IP.
Username.
They are all ubuntu so you should.
Username should be ubuntu.
And.
Yes, we are able to log in.
That's awesome.
Log out.