Now.
Now let's start writing a playbook to provision our entire stack.
Okay, So now in our repository, we had this previous playbooks that we used to set up VPC and launch
instances.
We'll just close all of this.
To avoid any clutter.
Okay, First we need to take care of our variables.
So we already have in group bars.
We have the variables, the IP addresses of for all our machines.
We also have the inventory file.
We need one more variable.
I'm going to create a new file here.
DB RV group.
Create that file text file.
So we'll give DB user, DB pass and DB name the three variables.
We'll also need to templates that we'll be pushing it to our application server and web server respectively.
So we'll create a template directory here.
In this templates, we'll create two files.
Application dot j to.
This is going to be our application properties file.
So the data for this file you can pick up from our source code so you can go to our repository, we
profile project and you can go to VB hyphen branch or any CD branch.
You can go.
HRC main.
Resources.
Application date properties file.
Let's copy it.
Okay.
We don't need to make any change here.
DB 0101 This is we're going to prepare a host file.
It is the host file and push it on every machine so our application server should be able to connect
to with to the backend with their names.
Okay, we need one more template.
For engine x engine x v pro g two For simplicity.
Keep the same name for now.
There's going to be the routing entry for when we access engine service.
It's going to route to the application server.
So that should be the content.
If we access it on Port 80, it's going to listen on port it.
It's going to route the request to app zero one on Port 88.
These two configurations are important.
So when it routes to application server application Server four backend is going to use this file to
route to database cache and rabbit MQ.
DB password admin and DB user admin and password one to admin.
One, two, three.
You mentioned the same in the variables file, so we're going to use that in our playbook.
Also for rabbit to test user and test password.
Okay, that should be good.
Let's close this one for now.
Except this one provision stack.
Now we'll create ansible configuration file.
So does the configuration file.
In default settings, we have inventory inventory hyphen vpro.
Which is this file.
Post key checking false Forks five.
That's not mandatory setting log file.
It will also create a log file in current working directory.
Timeout 15 seconds privilege escalation becomes Yes.
You don't need to mention it in your playbook as this connection tries to time.
We need that for some of our execution.
Okay, so by now you should have two variables file DB server, host IP two templates, application
G, two engine x, Vpro or G two and simple configuration file and inventory file.