Now.
I'm going to write a side note with my playbook first.
The master playbook that is going to call all the other playbooks so you can see the flow of execution
as well.
So at this level provision, stack level, I'm going to create a file named as site dot YAML.
This is going to be a master playbook.
And that's the content.
So we have first we're going to import Playbook build.
This playbook is going to build the artifact locally on the control machine.
Then another playbook will get executed.
This is going to update the host file, the Etsy host file.
It will use all the IP address that we have mentioned in the variables file.
Next is DB will playbook will execute so it or it will execute This playbook is going to install the
database make sure it's up and running.
DB deploy ML is going to take our SQL file.
And we'll run all the SQL queries from that.
So DB, a SQL file will be pushed by build, ML file and build ML file will take the source code and
build the artifact.
The same time, we'll also push the SQL file so DB deploy DB deployed.
ML can execute that.
Next will be Mom Cash Playbook, which is going to install, start and make sure cash is running on
port 112, one one.
Then Rabbit and CU Playbook, which will install all the rabbit MQ dependencies.
Install rabbit MQ create rabbit Q user with password and some privilege.
Next is Application Server playbook.
This playbook is going to install and set up Tomcat servers and also deploy the artifact.
The artifact will be built by build file and we'll already push it from this playbook to application
server in the temp directory.
And this playbook is going to take that artifact from temp directory and deploy it in.
Tomcat Home Directory.
Next.
Finally, the Vimal file, which is going to provision Engine X service.
Application server app server file is going to use this template application due to website.
Primal Playbook is going to use this template engine X with pro dot J2.
So we are going to write all this file in the same order.
Now let's save this and I would also like to commit it.
Commit.
And I would also like to push it.
Okay, let's fetch that.
There's not going to be any execution now because we have not written any new playbooks.
But you should see we have provision stack directory.
In that we have inventory file ansible configuration file login key side can now in inventory.
It's mentioning the login key.
Can't log in key for all the instance which we have already copied.
And this is not part of your version Control.
We are not keeping keys in the version control so you should not see this keys from your ID, You will
not see it anywhere because in the get ignored file we are saying ignore PEM files.