Now let's start writing our playbook one by one in the same order.
So for now, I'm going to close all this.
And I'll open.
Vimal billed Vimal we have to create first.
So in the same order.
Provision Stack file build dot y.
L.
OC build playbook will get executed locally on the local host on the controller machine.
Let's become.
Yes, we don't need to give that, but because it's already an ansible configuration file.
But that's fine.
So we're going to first install some dependencies by using APT module in a loop, we're going to run
this git open JDK eight and MAVEN.
Next.
By using Git module, we're going to clone our repository.
Branch VP hyphen rim.
We're going to put it into this directory and register output into a variable.
Then we'll run the we'll use command module and we'll run the command and even install.
And it will do a CD change directory into V profile hyphen repo right there.
Only if there is a commit.
So get underscore status dot changed.
All right.
So this will be true if there is any new commit.
It's only if a new commit is there?
I would like to build it and register the output into this variable.
Now we should have the artifact.
So by using copy module, we'll copy the artifacts source.
So we profile report target slash star dot var Any var file in the target directory will be copied to
the files directory.
So we should also have a files directory then.
So let's create a files directory.
And we make sure we create some empty file in that so it can keep track of this path.
Okay, so in the file directory route dot var artifact will be copied.
Then we're going to copy the SQL file into the files directory again.
So we profile repo Z Main Resources DB backup dot SQL file will be copied into this directory with this
name.
Let's save this.
If you don't wish to write all the steps, then you can copy all this from our source code repository.
As of now, I'm going to save this.
Commit this.
It's a build playbook.
Okay, First I will just run this playbook individually, not through Cytomel, just to make a test.
So let's pull everything.
So we should have now built vimal file a files directory also.
Let's run the playbook.
Okay, while this is happening, we'll write the next playbook.