The next playbook is set.
Host IP map dot html.
So let's create a file.
This playbook is very simple.
It's just going to include the variable group was host IP.
So all these variables will be available in the playbook.
It's going to use block in file module.
It is the host file of all the hosts.
It's it's going to get executed on all the hosts, including.
Web app rabbit MQ mem cache db everything.
If you wish, we can also update the control machine over here, so let's check in our inventory file.
That all the hosts, including the control machine, the local host controller machine.
So in this machine also it will get updated.
So you don't need to do anything.
So let's see if this comet.
Yeah.
Let's go back.
And by the time this playbook is also executed, let's see the output.
It should be in the files directory.
So we have route dot, var and the SQL file.
That's nice.
Now, let's pull our source code.
Now you should see the new playbook.
Let's execute it.
Now that's done.
That was very quick.
Let's check the host file.
This is you can log into every machine and check, but we can check it really on the local machine.
Also controller.
Right now, we can really do quickly access to that login and you can see open to.
At the rate we can say zero one, let's test it.
And seems working.
Yeah.
That's good.
Let's log out.
Now we'll write all our playbook and we'll execute them from Wireman.
Guess the site will.
You can close this, you can close this whole strip build and test.