Next is db dot mil playbook.
Let's copy that name.
This playbook is also very simple server provisioning playbook.
It will provision my SQL servers so it works on DB server group.
First task is installing packages and we have a list of packages we are running package module in a
loop.
So my SQL Server, my SQL client, Python hyphen, my SQL DB, Python three hyphen, my SQL DB.
Now this is 4012012 18.
This is for open to 20 onwards.
And in if you're running this, click on open to 20, you will get an error.
You will not see Python, my hyphen, my SQL db.
And that is fine.
We are saying ignore errors.
If you don't put this ignore errors, then this task will fail if it does not find this or this.
So in one 220, you will get an error for this one.
And the error will be ignored.
So it will continue to the next task.
Next task is to start.
By using my SQL user module, we're going to create the user named that is coming from the variables
file.
There.
Also the deepening.
And will give it full privilege.
Host percent So we can log in it from a remote machine.
We're going to create database with my SQL DB module.
DB name variable again.
So accounts DB will get created.
With line file module.
We're going to search for search in this file.
We're going to search for bind address.
If it starts from the beginning of the line, if it's present, then we're going to replace it with
bind hyphen.
And also we would like to take the backup of that file and we'll notify to a handler.
And the handler will restart the MySQL service after making the configuration change.
We would really like to restart the service.
So that's DB ML.
Let's save it.
Committed.
And we'll push all at once.
So let's wait for the push for now.
Next playbook is dbx deploy.
This is also very simple playbook.
It's just going to deploy the SQL file.
Executing again on DB server group gathering fact No.
We're going to copy the SQL file.
From the files directory.
It's not here, but it is definitely in our controller machine where we did the execution.
It's there and I don't want to commit it into the version Control also, not the var file.
So we'll update our git ignore file over here.
And we'll say anything that ends with DOT SQL.
And also anything that ends with dot var.
Should be excluded.
Also, when you do this, make sure you run, get ad dot and get commit.
When you run get ad dot, it's going to give you a hint to run this command to exclude that from the
cache since it's already committed.
So it removes from the cache and then you run the command, it removes from the cache, and then you're
going to make a commit, get commit.
And then push it.
Get push.
Often you're done with that.
Make sure you fetch the latest changes in your ID.
So I don't want to push the date.
I don't want to put the data that is generated in the runtime like SQL file artifact.
So we're using the get ignored file to ignore those files.
Okay, so then this copy module is going to copy the SQL file to temp directory.
And then with my SQL DB module for the database named accounts, we can use variable also here.
Yeah.
So I'm using variable DB name login, user login, password, state import.
And then you give the target.
So is a SQL file that we have copied over here in the temp directory.
It will import it in the database.
And then there is a handler, which is really not required.
But if you want, you can use the handler for this to restart the MySQL service.
Let's see if this commit.
Okay, that's database deployed.