Next playbook cache will.
This is also a very easy playbook.
Executing on MSI server group with apt module very installing mem cache.
We start and enable mem cache service and then we enable the remote login.
So with line in file module, we're going to search anything that starts with hyphen L and replace it
with hyphen l 0.0.0.
So then Mukesh will listen on all the IP addresses, not just the local IP.
We can take backup of the file before it make changes, and then we call the handler to restart cache
service.
So that's pretty simple.
Playbook.
Install the package, start and enable make configuration change.
Restart the service.