Next playbook is for Rabbit MQ, which is also similar, but it has few extra steps for the dependencies.
It has a lot of dependencies.
So I'll create the playbook.
So getting executed on our MQ server group.
First we have to install Erlang.
For that we need to add the repository detail By using APT module we say DEP and we say this is the
repository.
Link.
And with apt underscore key module, we add the key.
To authenticate that repository.
Then we say install Erlang with APT module, we install Erlang.
Now airline will get installed from this repository but we have to run apt update also.
So update caching module which will run apt update and then install Erlang.
Appropriate will be done in an interval of 86400 seconds.
That's 24 hours.
Okay, then one more module.
APT underscore repository.
We're going to add this repository.
This is for rabbit MQ.
Once we have this repository, we can use ABT module to install Rabbit MCU Server update cache.
Yes, it's going to run app update.
It's going to fetch the packages list from here and install rabbit MQ server.
And then once we have rabbit MQ, we'll start and enable the service.
Little configuration change with copy module.
We're going to copy this content.
Into this rabbit MQ configuration file.
Once we made the configuration, we're going to bounce the rabbit MQ service.
So it's say notify restart, rabbit MQ.
So at the end you have the handler which will get called.
Rabbit MQ underscore user module to add a rabbit MQ user.
Thankfully, we have such module.
Otherwise we have to use the command module.
So rabbit MQ user module, we're going to add user name test, password test.
And if you go back to a template application to.
Be using the same user.
So if you're making any changes over here, then you make sure you make the changes over here as well.
Or you can declare them as a variable and you can refer in both the places.
Get few options to give all the privileges tag administrator and call the handler.
So once the user is created, it can call the handler, but handler will be called at the end.
Next we have to install one plugin rabbit mq underscore plugin module is there to install rabbit mq
plug in rabbit view underscore management.
And so, again, calling the handler now, the handler will be called because this is the last task.
Handler will be called and Rabbit, you will get restarted a little longer playbook compared to DB and
Mem cache only because we have a lot of dependencies and we are also adding user of rabbit MQ and installing
a rabbit MQ plugin.
Apart from that, this playbook is as similar as DB or mem cache playbook.
Install packages, start an enable service, make some configuration change and restart the service.
So let's see if this commit this.