I'll get next playbook.
He's the application server or main hero Tomcat.
So let's hope not at this level.
Provision stack file.
Okay, There is a mistake.
I have created A.I.M. and rabbit MKT via email.
Not in provision stack directory, so let me move it.
Also rapid MQ.
Okay, so let's get started writing with apps or playbook.
Okay.
This is a rather a very long playbook, but it is same or the similar playbook that we used in a project.
Continuous delivery with Jenkins and Ansible.
In that project we used an Ansible playbook which will set up the Tomcat service.
So it's the same playbook as that, except this is only for Ubuntu 18 or 20.
Now also, you can use it for 1 to 16 as well.
But the playbook, which was in continuous delivery project, that was for multi operating system,
even enterprise Linux 67012 1415 1618 20 except 20.
Okay, so we have two variables over here.
Timestamp This variable is used to take the backup of a file, so we're going to use this variable.
We can assign it in the runtime from the fact variable.
So it will have the current timestamp.
Tomcat URL variable, which is the URL from where it's going to download the tomcat tarball.
So install JDK with apt module, then a download the tarball with get your URL module at this location.
Ad user tomcat sorry ad a group tomcat then ad user tomcat at this home directory.
So this will be the home directory of this user and also the Tomcat user.
Local Tomcat eight.
Then we create a temporary directory with file module.
Slash temp slash tomcat eight state directory.
Then we'll archive.
Our Tomcat eight that we have downloaded in temp directory under this directory tomcat temp slash Tomcat
eight This is for temporary purpose, so you can archive it with the archive module and we stored the
output into the variable.
So it's going to list all the files you have in list files.
Yes.
So it's going to return all the output when it extracts that will be stored into this variable.
From that output, we will extract the Tomcat Tomcat directory name by using this style.
So we're going to basically slice it in that JSON value.
You have a key called files.
It is a list.
So first element in the list and that will be.
The path of the Tomcat.
But I don't want we don't want the path.
You're going to split that.
Where there is a forward slash and we get the first name in the pot.
So we get the directory name of Tomcat where it gets extracted.
So here we are just printing it.
But here with synchronize module, we're going to sync that directory which is extracted with us, our
local tomcat.
So all the content from this directory will be copied to us, our local tomcat.
Eight.
And synchronize module is going to work for source locally.
So we have to say delegate to inventory underscore host name.
So wherever this is getting executed, it will assume that the source is at that location, the remote
location.
Otherwise it will think sources local.
Then we change the ownership of user local tomcat directory.
With file module we give the ownership Tomcat tomcat and we extracted the content in this directory.
Now we'll make the tomcat user and the group as the owner of this file.
And then we are going to push a template that we have to create now.
At this location.
This is going to be the system D file so we can manage Tomcat with system CTL Command or the service
module.
So we have to create one more template.
So I'm going to copy that name.
Is it templates?
Okay, so that's the system D file.
When we say system C, it'll start Tomcat, then it will execute the script.
When we say systems, it'll stop Tomcat, It will execute that script.
Let's see if this.
So this template will be pushed at this location.
So service name will be Tomcat eight.
And then we a system D system D demand reload.
So it's going to reload this configuration.
And now we can start managing Tomcat with Service Command.
So service Tomcat eight started.
So it's going to start the Tomcat service.
So all those steps we took till here from the beginning is so we can manage Tomcat with service module.
Okay.
Next you're going to collect information about the existing artifact if it exist.
So we'll store with start module.
We're going to collect the information and we'll store it into this variable.
This will be useful to take the backup so if this file does not exist, will not take the backup like
that.
So for the for the first installation, first provisioning, this may not exist.
Or if you delete it, then your backup task will fail.
So we're going to use that variable to compare that.
So then we start stop the Tomcat service and now comes where we're going to deploy our artifact.
So we have to we first stop the Tomcat service and then we have block and rescue.
And so the main block is this.
So I need to ask Phil in this blog, The rescue will come and it will start the Tomcat service, because
if any task fails, the Playbook execution will stop and the Tomcat service will be stay straight,
stop.
Right.
Because you're stopping the Tomcat service over here, right?
I'm the execution field.
The Tomcat service will be stopped.
All right.
The final step outside of this block is to start the Tomcat service, but it will not come here if any
of that task fails.
So that's why we have a rescue.
So it's if this task fails, any of this task fails, then.
Execute this like that.
So our main block, we actually have nested block.
We have the main block.
This is our main block.
Still here.
And we have a nested block in this.
We'll come to this.
So let's start with the first task in our block.
First task is archiving the artifact.
So this is the path existing application.
We're going to take it's backup with archive module at this location by using the timestamp variable
that we have.
Already created.
So in the runtime this when you execute the playbook, this will have the latest timestamp.
So it will take back up of this file with this name only then.
This returns to artifact underscore stat dot stat dot exist, its value will be true.
If this file exist.
And so the stat model, we are collecting the information of this file root directory and we store it
into this variable and that will have a key called us stat don't exist.
If this is true, then only it's going to take the backup or else it will skip it.
And when we take the backup, we store the output into a variable archive underscore info.
Next us.
This is our main backup.
We are also going to take an instant backup for instant rollback.
So we're going to seed into this tree.
Which shell model?
We're running a copy command.
We're going to copy the root directory with old underscore root name.
So existing application, we're taking an instant backup.
So in case of failure, we can do instant rollback.
So that backup taken, That backup taken.
And now we're going to delete our artifacts.
So we're going to run file module in the inner loop.
We present these two files, root and root dot var.
And it will say file this part state absent it will remove these two files.
Only if this is true.
Archive, underscoring for change.
So restoring the output over here.
That means if the backup completes successfully.
Key changed over here will be true, or else it will be false if this feels.
Cancel.
If the backup completes successfully, then only it will delete the artifact.
That's what this condition means.
Which makes sense.
If you have a backup, then we delete the artifact.
Otherwise we don't delete like that.
Okay, so till here, we have only backup.
Now there is a nested block and rescue.
It's very simple.
BLOCK copy module.
We're going to copy our artifact, which was created with the build file.
So the build playbook.
Right.
Open.
So that's the build playbook, right?
So we're building the artifact and we are keeping it at this location.
Now app seller Playbook.
We have a copy task which is going to copy that artifact which was built and deployed to the target
machine at this location.
Now there's a default Tomcat application path.
And store the output.
If in any case this fails, it's not able to deploy for some reason.
Then the rescue will come and it will rescue command.
We'll copy the old underscore root directory with the name root instant rollback by going into this
directory.
Kim.
Or else anything fails in the main block, the rescue will come and we'll start the Tomcat service.
But if everything goes well.
Then it's going to take the backup, delete the artifact.
Right.
And then copy our new artifact to this location.
All right.
And then finally, it will start the Tomcat service next to start the Tomcat service.
Then we wait for some time with wait for module.
When we start the Tomcat service, sometimes it takes a longer time to extract root.
Dot var with the name route.
But we archive takes time.
So we're going to wait for this part to be available, because if it's not available, we cannot push
our configuration file inside that.
So we wait.
As long as this is not available.
If it's if it's available, then we use template module.
We copy our template application to.
Write the application properties file.
At this location.
So when the artifact gets extracted, you have root directory right in that you have web enough classes
in that you have application properties file.
This file will have information about the back end services.
Right.
My SQL mem cache rabbit MQ, all the backend services detail it will have.
So that's our final touch.
Once we do that, once the configuration is copied, we say notify restart, Tomcat.
So a handler will be called.
Which is going to restart the Tomcat service and our deployment should complete.
Let me commit that.
See Tom KITT.
Playbook.
Commit.