Okay.
Our next playbook insight dot via email is web dot ML, which is going to provision engine service.
Just going to install engine service, change the configuration bounce engine service.
That's it.
Let's name it.
Web dot ML, same name.
Getting executed on web server group using apt module where installing engine service update caching.
Yes.
In an interval of 24 hours.
So an update will run only in the interval of 24 hours after 24 hours have passed, then start and enable
engine service with service module and with file module.
We are going to remove the default engine x website, which is a dislocation.
So we say with file module.
This is the path state absence.
It's going to remove this file.
And then it's going to push our own configuration file with template module engine X configuration engine
X for J2.
That's the configuration.
So it's going to engine X will listen on Port 80 and any request that comes will be forwarded to AB
zero one on Port 88.
Kim, let's go back.
So that will be deployed at this location inside siphon available directory.
And then you have to create a link to enable the site.
So with file module we are creating a link with sites hyphen available the file that we copied.
And the destination is this.
So this is going to be the link state link.
Once that is done, that's the configuration changes you.
Then you call the handler to restart engine service.
The handler will restart engine service and that's the last playbook.
Let's save it.
Committed engine start engine ICS playbook.