Okay.
Now, let's get into the controller.
Let's run.
Get, pull, set, pull.
All the changes that we made.
This is good.
Let's go to provision Stack.
If we're going to execute side of playbook again.
So if you already executed Beloit via email and this file which set up the host entries, these two
file will get executed once again.
Then DB dot ML will set up the database service.
DB deploy will deploy SQL file.
MEM cache is going to set up mem cache service.
Rabbit MQ is going to set up rabbit MQ server application server is going to install setup, tomcat
and deploy artifact.
Also, anything fails, it's going to roll back as well.
And finally, Engine X will be set up by web dot ML.
Once the engine comes up, starts serving the request, it will be also in the load balancer will show.
In the instances it will show in service once the Internet service comes up.
All right.
Let's do it.
And simple hyphen playbook.
Side dot y.