Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we will see how to create virtual machines on a mac OS.
This is more specific to the M1 chip.
The most popular Veeam creation tool is Oracle Veeam Virtual Box.
But on mac OS M1 chip, it is not supported.
So we will be using VMware desktop to create virtual machines and to automatically create virtual machines.
We will be using Vagrant.
So we have to set up a vagrant plus a VMware desktop Fusion in this lecture also.
Then we will see how to create a virtual machine by using Vagrant and VMware.
Together we will create a Ubuntu operating system, VM and another VM with Fedora, which is similar
to CentOS operating system.
Okay, so this is the ten step guide of how to set up a virtual machine on your Mac OS.
So download this document and from the resource section and go through it.
Most of them are commands that we will be running on the terminal.
Also, you have to create an account on a VMware.
I've given the link over here, but most of the steps are going to be getting executed on the terminal.
So let's open the terminal.
And let's run the commands one by one.
Forced installing Rosetta.
So just copy paste the command.
Second installing vagrant with brew.
Okay, next.
Third, you need to create an account on a VMware website here.
So sign up, create an account, then login with that account and there is a link.
Click on that and download VMware Fusion and install it.
So after logged in, once you click on the link, you should come to this page.
Download VMware Fusion.
Open the software.
Click on that.
And it should start the installation.
OC open system preferences.
And provide accessibility to VMware Fusion.
Click on this lock.
Enter your password.
And put a checkmark on VMware Fusion there and that is installed and it has permission now.
Okay, Next.
Copy this command and create a link.
This link is created.
Now we will use this link and download VMware provider, so let's copy this link.
Okay.
So once this is downloaded, install it.
Double click on that icon and it should start the installation.
Enter your password.
Next install this vagrant plugin.
Okay, so we are now done with the setup.
Now it's time to create a virtual machine by using Vagrant and VMware.
So let me clear the screen here.
And let me make this full screen terminal.
I guess we are going to create two virtual machine.
One is open to other, one is Fedora.
Fedora is similar to send to a seven or just send to us whenever I see centers for Windows user.
You have to understand that I'm talking about Fedora for MacBook M1 and M2 chip.
I'll come to that point in a moment.
Let's go to the document first.
Okay, So the steps are we need to create this folder VMs open to inside that we need to place a file
called Vagrant file with V Capital, and the content of that file will be this.
Okay, so let's create the folders or directories.
So come back to the terminal, run p w d command, see where you are users.
Imran I'm in my home directory.
I do ls.
Look here.
I'm going to get into the desktop directory.
So CD desktop in that we are going to create a folder called us VMs.
We go into that VMs folder and inside that we're going to create a folder called as Ubuntu.
That's the first.
Let's, let's create one more folder.
Federal.
Okay, then let's get into the Ubuntu folder.
Run p w d command.
You should be in this place if you are ever lost.
Just type c d and hit enter.
You will come back to your home directory.
This is the symbol of the home directory, this tilde.
So I'm in my home directory.
I'm going to get into desktop VMs open to.
Let's clear the screen.
Once again, we're going to run the command volume.
This is a text editor and we give the file name, vagrant file.
Make sure the file name is exactly as it is V Capital, all the other small and there is no extension
at the end.
And hit enter.
When you do this, this is going to open up a file with the name of Vagrant file.
And you should see here new and the file name.
You need to get into insert mode.
Type I as in India.
And you will see you are in insert mode here.
Now you can type the content over here.
But not typing just anything.
We are going to copy this content.
Select this content Control authority command.
See?
Go back to the terminal Command V.
Paste it.
Now escape.
Make sure you hit escape.
The insert mode will be gone.
Now you have to hit.
Colon w q save and quit.
Or write and quit.
Hit.
Enter.
You do less and now you will see a vagrant file.
Here.
You can run cat command to print the content of this file.
Cat Vagrant file.
Now let's understand a few lines of this code.
Later, we will dive deep into Valorant in the background section.
But for now, a few things you need to understand.
One is the box name here.
Config dot vm, dot box box.
You can also call them as images VM images.
These are readymade images available on Vagrant Cloud.
So when we run the command vagrant up, it is going to first download this box and then create a VM
from that.
And the IPO of the film will be this.
And we are using VMware desktop to create VMs.
Okay, So let me take you to one green cloud.
Okay, so just search for Vagrant Cloud on Google.
And that's the first link.
So there are many boxes over here or images over here.
We need to find appropriate one.
So in the dropdown, click on VMware desktop because we are using VMware desktop and Mac OS, M one
and M two.
Chip has the erm architecture just type erm in the search.
And you will see all the ARM based boxes for VMware desktop.
Now, they're not many and many of them doesn't work properly with our setup.
The box team that I have selected is the one that I tested it and many people have tested it.
It works very well.
And we will be using this box.
But if you want to find the boxes, a different box, I have shown you how you can do that.
You can just change it over here.
Now, this box I'm using this version, this is specific version that we want.
Now.
If you're using any other box, do not mention any version.
It will just download the latest version of the box.
This version again is only for this box.
And we are going to run a command of vagrant up.
Which will.
Download the box first.
Now I already have this box downloaded in the machine so it is not going to download once again for
you first time.
It is going to download and bring up a VM.
It is going to open up this UI which will show you the VM coming up.
You don't need to do anything over here.
Just minimize this.
Or maybe take a look and then minimize.
You need to be on the terminal only.
I see the VM is coming up.
You see, it took hardly a minute to bring up the VM.
First time.
It will take a little long.
Now the VM is up to log in.
Inside this VM, you need to run the command vagrant search.
Ragland said.
You need to make sure you are in that same folder.
So this will log in in the VM.
Now you see the prompt has changed.
Look at this prompt and look at the previous prompt.
This was the MacBook Prompt and now we are in the VM.
This is the VM prompt.
You run the command.
Pseudo hyphen i.
And when the command ip id r show to see whether you got the IP address or not, that's the IP address
of your VM.
Yep, That's all here.
Just exit.
Once again type exit.
Till you come back to your prompt, you're logged out of the venue.
Exit the last time we are back.
Now, let me clear the screen.
You can run the command vagrant status to check the status or status of your VM, and it says it is
running.
We are going to power off.
Vagrant.
Halt!
Which is to power off or shut down.
That's off.
Let's check the status once again.
You can do the up arrow and go to the previous command.
Migrant status.
Okay.
You see, it is not running.
Now you can any time just run vagrant up as it sees and bring up the VM.
If you don't need it, you can also delete it.
Vagrant and destroy.
Yes.
Why?
For yes.
And it is going to delete.
Destroy means delete the VM.
The VM will be gone.
If you run Vagrant up, the VM will come back.
But it is going to be a new VM after that.
Now that's about open to.
Let's go to now fedora.
So again type CD and hit enter.
Clear the screen.
Let's go to desktop vms.
Fedora.
And let's do the same over here.
There's no file here now.
V, I am vagrant file.
Once again.
V Capital.
Hit enter.
Get into the insert mode.
I as in India.
Within insert mode.
Let's go to the document.
And this is the setting or configuration for Fedora.
Let's copy all this.
Command C.
Let's go back.
Come on.
V basted.
Okay.
Here, you see the box name?
It's different for open two.
We had an open two box for here for Federer.
Obviously we have Federer 35 box.
And whenever I see center is seven or center is eight, anything sent to us in the lectures for Windows
user, that means for MacBook, M1 and M1 chip, sorry, M1 and M2 chip, you need to go with this box.
Federer 35.
Exactly this box you can experiment with other box later, but for now, just keep that box escape colon.
W q say when could.
And we're going to say vagrant up.
Which will bring up a federal VMM for us.
Okay.
Again, it opens up this DUI.
It can minimize that.
We are not using that.
We'll be using terminal.
Okay, the VM is up.
Let's check migrant status.
Right.
It's running.
Let me clear the screen.
Let's do vagrant search to log in now.
I will be logging into the federal VM now.
Right.
And I need to be in that directory.
See the prompt?
I'm in the VM pseudo hyphen i.
IP ADR show.
Yeah.
Got vip v good exit.
And once again, exit.
And we are back to our MacBook.
Okay.
Now let's power off.
Or I can just delete it and destroy.
I can do that as well.
Hyphen, hyphen, hyphen, hyphen force.
Forcefully delete the VM.
Don't ask me any question.
Just delete it like that.
And whenever you want to bring up the theme or any theme.
So I'm back to a normal terminal.
I'm in the home directory, I go to VMs.
Sorry, I go to desktop VMs.
I can type.
I go to one, two.
There's the vagrant file, and I can just do vagrant up.
Or you can check the status first.
Vagrant up.
And this will bring up the VM or create a new VM if it does not exist.
Okay.
Since this is coming up.
Now it's already up.
Anyways, a few important points that I want to add.
Compared to Windows user, you will see Windows user have will have option of many other boxes compared
to MacBook M1 and M2 chip.
The problem is actually the M1 and M2 chip.
There are not many boxes available for this architecture.
So for we will be using these specific boxes that I have mentioned later in the Vagrant section once
you become proficient with Vagrant.
After Linux we have vagrant session.
Once you become proficient, then you can do your experiments.
But till then keep the boxes.
Same name of the boxes as I have shown you now.
Keep in mind we have limited choice when it comes to M1 and M2 chip.
So do not worry too much about the commands that you have seen, the text, the code that you have seen.
You will be learning all that in detail later in Linux session.
You're going to get very proficient with command line in Wagner and we'll be learning a lot of Wagner
and then later we'll be doing batch scripting, we'll be doing cloud computing.
So it will take some time to become proficient with all this.
This is just the VM set up.
So take it easy, bring up the VM.
That's all we need to do for now.
All right, then.
That is all in this lecture.
I will see you in the next one.