Welcome to the project.
This is an AWS. project, the name of this project is.
Refactoring with AWS.
So from our previous project, we have seen, we deployed the vprofile application stack on our local
machine and also on AWS Cloud.
From our previous project, we already know how to host our Web application stack on AWS Cloud.
And we used lift and shift strategy.
In this project, we will re architecture or refactor our services.
This strategy is called re architecture or refactoring.
This approach is used to boost agility or to improve business continuity.
So we can add new features, scale effectively and easily and have very good performance for our application
workload.
So let's take a scenario, let's say you're working on a project where the services are running on physical
machine, virtual machines or even cloud machines, like could be even ec2 instances.
And you're dealing with various services for your application workload.
You could be having databases, you could be having application, webservers, network services
like DNS, DHCP and many more services.
To manage all this, you need you need multiple teams, you need cloud computing team if you're using
cloud computing platforms.
You need virtualization team if you're doing virtualization on your data center, datacenter operations
team, monitoring team, sys admin team and few other teams will get involved in managing all this application
workload.
So there's really too much operational overhead.
Your teams are struggling for the uptime and regular scaling requirement.
Upfront capital expenditure and regular operational expenditure, if you're using your own local data
center and the processes will be manual and will be very difficult to automate.
If you have virtualization.
All these processes will be time consuming and very expensive.
So we can really use a cloud platform, but instead of using infrastructure as a service, will be using
mostly PASS and SAAS services, platform as a service and software as a service.
So if you're talking about AWS, we will not be going with regular instances, but will be using some
cloud managed services from AWS and cloud means we can code our infrastructure so we can have infrastructure
as a code.
And SAAS services are very easy to manage, flexible, elastic in nature.
Scaling will be mostly taken care of by the cloud vendor.
And of course, it's going to be pay as you go model.
With lots and lots of automation that we can do, so refactoring our application really gives us an
easy infrastructure to manage, very good performance, very convenient to scale, and you will not need
huge teams to manage all this.
So let's see AWS services that we are going to use in this project.
So instead of using regular ec2 instance to install our services, we will be using Beanstalk service.
And the service will in turn create an ec2 instance and host our application on it.
We don't need to manage this instance manually.
Beanstal service will take care of it.
Beanstalk service will also have a load balancer.
It will also have auto scaling.
An S3 bucket for storing the artifacts.
Or we can use even our own extra bucket.
Now, that's all about Frontend, let's talk about backbend.
In Backend, for database we will use RDS instances.
It's really like a platform as a service, so you get a database platform to choose from, you fill
in the requirements and the database is up and running in no time.
Scaling will be very easy.
Regular backups will be taken automatically.
And so many more amazing things with it.
We're going to use elasticache service instead of memcache, ActiveMQ in place of RabbittMQ.
Route 53 for DNS.
And cloud front for content delivery network.
So if you have a global audience, then using cloud front for content delivery network will be very
easy and convenient.
Let's keep the objective in mind.
We need a flexible infrastructure, very flexible, actually pay as we go model, infrastructure as a code,
and we need PASS and SAAS services for ease of managing our infrastructure.
So to have a low operational overhead.
So let's do a quick comparison between the services that we are going to use, Beanstalk for Tomcat instance
replacement, Beanstalk again will have load balancer and auto scaling.
EFS or S3 we can use instead of using NFS.
RDS, instead of having MySQL on VM/Ec2. Elasticache instead of memcache and active MQ instead
of Rabbitt MQ on VM/Ec2instance. Route 53 for DNS. Cloud Front to serve our global audience
content delivery network.
OK, time to see the architecture of our project, we'll be having ec2 instances, ELB auto scaling
from Beanstalk, S3, RDS elasticache, AcrtiveMQ, Route 53 and cloud front.
So user will access our URL, which will be resolved to an end point from Amazon Route 53.
The end point will be off Amazon cloud front content delivery network, which will cache so many things
to server the global audience.
From there, the request will be redirected to application load balancer, which is part of your elastic
Beanstalk, Application load balancer, will forward the request to EC2instance, which is in an auto
scaling group. Here our Tomcat application service, will be running and all this will be part of
Elastic Beanstalk.
There will be also Amazon cloud watch alarms that will be monitoring auto scaling group and will scale
out and scaling based on the requirement.
There will be a bucket where artifacts will be stored and we can deploy our latest artifact by just
clicking a button.
So our entire frontend will be managed by Beantalk. For Backend instead of rabbit MQ, we're
using Amazon MQ.
Instead of using memcache on ec2 instance, we're using elasticache.
And instead of using database running on ec2 instance, we are going to use Amazon RDS
So the user will access an end point.
That end point will be off Amazon cloud front that will send the request to application load balancer
in the Beanstalk that will forward the request to instances in the autoscaling group.
All this will be monitored by Amazon cloud, which alarms The artifacts will be stored in the S3 bucket.
For backend
It's going to access AmazonMQ, Elastic Cache and Amazon RDS Service.
Again, I recommend you to pause the video and watch this design once again.
Let's see the flow of execution now.
First we will obviously login to our AWS Account. We will create key pair for our Beanstalk instance, or Beanstalk
will launch an ec2 instance, so we will create a key pair, So in case you need to login, can use that key pair.
We'll create security group for backend services, elasticache, RDS and active MQ.
Then we will create RDS.
ElastiCache and Amazon active MQ.
Then we'll create Elastic Beanstalk Environment.
Next, we will update our backend security group to allow traffic from beanstalk security group so when beanstalk
gets created.
It will also create security group for its ec2 instance and also load balancer.
So we will allow traffic from beanstalk instance security group to access our backend services which are
in backend security group.
We're putting all our backend services in one security group, and they will need to interact with
each other, so we will also update backend security group.
So it allows the internal traffic.
So by now, our backend services will be also up and running, RDS will be up and running and we
need to initialize our RDS database.
So launch an ec2 instance.
And from there we will do a MySQL login to our RDS and initialize our database.
If you follow to our previous project, you know, our profile application returns to page at /login
so we need to change health check in Beanstalk.
So when we deploy our artifact, it should do a health check on /login.
And we will also add 443 https listener to our elastic load balancer, so ELB will be also to again get created
automatically by Beanstalk, it will be part of your Beanstalk environment.
Then we will build artifacts from our source code with the backend information.
So by now we should have endpoint of RDS, Endpoint of Amazon MQ and Endpoint of elasticache. We will feed
this information in our application properties file and we'll build the artifact.
Then we'll deploy the artifact to Beanstalk environment.
And we will create a content delivery network, using Amazon cloud front with SSL certificate, of course,
for https connection.
Once we have this, ready, we can update our load balancer and endpoint in GoDaddy, or we can also do
this on Amazon Route 53, public dns zones.
Once all this is ready, finally will test it from the URL.
OK, now let's make this happen.
So if you're done watching the intro, join me on AWS console.