So I'm logged into my AWS console and I'm in North Virginia region.
First thing we'll do is we'll create Key pair, Log-in Key pair for our beanstalk ec2 instance, it's not mandatory
to log into Beanstalk ec2 instance, but if you're troubleshooting and we would really like to
know what's happening inside the ec2 instance, then we can use the key to login.
So let's be on safer side create a key pair.
So we will name it as vprofile-bean-key
And I'll use pem format.
Now, create key pair
So private keys downloaded to my machine abd that is the public key.
OK, next, we will create a security group for our backend services.
So let's go to security group.
And will say create security group, lets give security group, a name vprofile-
-backend-sg
OK, this should be good, lets give some description.
Security group for.
Backend
services
OK, that's the rule.
I'll just add a dummy rule, which will be of no use.
I will say that a 22 allowed from my IP now all the backend services that we are going to use elastic
cache, RDS and ActiveMQ, we will create in a private network so we anyways will not be able to access
from our public network, from the public IP.
OK, but we are just creating this giving this rule so we can add one very important rule.
All the services in this same security group should be able to interact with each other.
So we will say.
All traffic, where is all traffic? There, all traffic allowed.
By itself, its own security group ID.
And that could have not been available before creating the security group, so that's why the dumb rule.
OK, let's ssave the changes
We will come back and add one more rule over here to allow access from beanstalk ec2 instance,
but for that we need to first create beanstalk instance and then we will do changes in the security
rules.