Okay.
Next, what we'll do, we'll create back end services.
So let's go to ideas.
First, let's create database.
Relational database service.
Okay, there it comes.
So we will go to.
Subnet groups first will create subnet group and we are going to place our instance in that subnet group.
If you have a separate VPC then this is very useful.
So let's say create DB subnet group.
Let's give it a name.
We profile hyphen ideas hyphen sub hyphen group.
You know.
I just copy something in the description.
So we have this one VPC default VPC.
But in later project, you will see we're going to create our own custom VPC.
And we're going to place services in or in our own custom VPC.
For now, we'll just select this.
Availability zone.
So we'll say all the availability zones.
Choose as per the requirement.
And all the subnets.
In those availabilities zones.
Sororities, instance, will be pleased in any of this subnets.
And let's create.
Now let's go to parameter groups.
Parameter groups are the setting or configuration of your ideas database service.
Now ideas gives you my skill.
Oracle Postgres.
Maria Rigby and you do not have any login as such login where you can log into an instance and make
the configuration changes of the service or the parameters settings of those service.
So RDA gives you this features parameter group where you can create.
Your own parameter group with all the settings and you can inject to your ideas instance.
And this is only if you're a DB geek, if you understand what are the parameters you got recommendations
from the vendor or an architect or a consultant that these parameters, your config configuration you
need, you need to change.
Then you can create your own parameter group and inject it to your instance.
Okay, so let's create a parameter group and select the service.
So we will be using my SQL.
5.7 or 5.6, but not my school eight.
So I'm selecting here 5.7.
My skill.
And let's give group a name and a description.
And just click on Create.
Now the parameter group is created with default settings.
Default parameters.
You click on that and you can see 21 pages of parameters and there are many.
If you are a DB geek, go ahead, explore it.
If you are not.
Leave them as it is.
These parameters are settings.
Are only four people who understand the database parameters or configurations.
So if you want to make change, so select your parameter, You can go to first edit parameters and you
can find your parameter, for example, password length, and you can mention the length.
And whenever you make any changes, you need to save it.
There are some dropdowns.
Also password policy you can drop down and can select it once again, if you know what you are doing,
then only make the changes.
Otherwise leave them as it is.
Cancel editing.
Okay, so now we have subnet group, we have security group and we have parameter group.
He will create this instance and inject all these settings into that.
So let's click on databases.
Create database.
And we'll select a standard create.
You can easily create this instance by just selecting this button.
But we'll select.
We'll see all the options.
So engine type, we are going to use my SQL as per our pre profile project.
But I really recommend you to try Amazon Aurora.
If you have to use my SQL Media debut or PostgreSQL, then instead of this you can try Amazon Aurora.
There are immense benefit offer.
There are immense benefits offered like it runs more faster five times faster than my SQL and three
times faster than PostgreSQL.
With 1/10 of the cost.
So that's pretty amazing.
And if you have serverless architecture, then you can very easily use Amazon Aurora as well.
It has storage, auto scaling and so many amazing and storage, auto healing and so many amazing concepts.
So I recommend you try Amazon Aurora, but there will be not a single instance for Amazon Aurora minimum.
You have to go with multi AC.
So we'll try to keep it.
Low cost, simple, single instance.
For our project, so we'll go with my SQL.
Scroll down.
Let's select the version of my skill.
Before I move ahead.
If you do not see the option of my school, go with my advice.
And then again, you need to go back to Parameters group and create parameters for my deep.
Because some people reported that they don't see my skull in some region.
So you can use my lab that is similar to that.
So we'll keep my skull.
If you're in North Virginia, you should see my skull.
Virgin.
We will go with five.
My skill 5.7.
So I'll go with my SQL.
5.7.22.
So any five version is fine.
Come down.
Three templates production dev and test free tier to be on a safer side.
Make sure you select free tier.
So it will use all the free to air settings of ideas.
But I will be going with different test because I want to show you other settings as well.
Now the difference between production and dev and test is this production gives you multi AC multiple
ideas.
Instance one primary active.
Second one standby.
And the volume type also will be provisioned IOPS.
It will be faster volume, but you must have already guessed this will not come free and in fact it
is expensive.
So for the project will keep and test.
You can keep free tier also so you don't accidentally select any paid service.
But I will keep dev and test single ideas instance normal volume type so it will come under free tier.
Let's come down.
Okay.
Database name.
Let's give.
Name v profile hyphen radius hyphen My SQL.
And we'll see the username.
We'll keep it the same admin and password we'll see auto generate.
DB instance, class is similar to AC two instances, so be careful.
This by default it will be db rm five extra large.
And this is MACD.
Then you have our cities and cities, which is considered really good for production databases.
But again, they are expensive.
Both classes will go with these are low cost and you have t three micro, you don't have t two micro
now.
But if you want to select TW two micro, you can say include previous generation classes.
And then you can find t two micro as well.
If you don't find it too micro, you can work out with RT three Micro.
Both are fine.
RT three Micro gives you two CPU.
RT two Micro gives you one CPU.
And three micro is also network and storage optimized.
So to keep it under three tier low cost, go to RT to micro.
I will be keeping it as RT three micro.
Storage minimum.
You can go 20 GB.
General purpose storage for production.
Go with provisioned IOPS if necessary.
If necessary.
If there's too much workload, too much of IO then go with provisioned IOPS.
You can even monitor all this from monitoring console.
If the IO is high then you can switch to provisioned IOPS.
Enable our storage auto scaling so you can go maximum here.
The default value is 1000, so it starts with 20 GB and CO can go maximum till 1000 as we mentioning.
Make it easy for production.
Make sure you have multiple you create multi easy.
But for fraud.
But again, to keep it low cost, we can create a single instance itself.
That should be fine.
But anyways, go with multi ac.
So I'll have one primary and one secondary.
VPC.
Default.
Subnet group.
We created our own subnet group.
We're going to select that public access.
No, it's going to be private.
Security group will select our security group.
We profile back and see.
Come on.
Okay.
I should cancel this one and select We profile back in SG.
Yes, this is good.
3306 port number.
That's fine.
Password authentication.
Are you going to keep any additional configuration?
We would like to have a database named accounts for our V profile project, which will also initialize
parameters Group.
Select your parameter group that you are going to use.
Regular backup?
Yes.
Backup retention period.
Seven days.
You can go as high as 35 days, but we'll keep it as seven days only.
You can specify a backup window.
But for now, I'll keep no preference.
We can even change the settings later.
Copy tags to Snapshot.
Snapshot.
Enable enhanced monitoring.
If you want, you can disable it to save some cost for your project.
I'll keep it on, but you can disable for practicing.
You can go as low as one second for the granularity that's going to be too much.
Logs, we will say, I want to export all the logs to cloud watch.
Audit log Error.
Log.
General logs.
Quick Slow.
Query log.
Let's keep enable auto miner version of grid.
So automatically our database is patched.
Can select a maintenance window if you want.
And enable delete production.
So it says it's going to cost us around $30.
But that's for a month.
It's a monthly cost.
You're not going to run it for a month.
Anyway, we selected as much as three tier as we can.
Let's create database now.
So this will take some time.
Make sure you save you credential details and copy your credentials to a text file so you can use it
later.
We're going to feed this information in our application properties file, so make sure you copy this.
So let me use my sticky notes.
And copy username and password for now.
Melody?
Yes.
Okay, So this is going to taste this is going to take some time.
So this is going to take some time.
Instead of waiting, we will create our other backend services.