So next we'll create elastic cache.
So search for elastic.
Elastic cash.
Yeah.
Their in-memory cache.
So same thing.
Let's create the parameter group subnet group and then we'll create the radius sorry elastic cache instance.
So click on create parameter group.
We'll give it a name.
We profile mem cache G parameter group.
Semen description I'm giving family.
So you see two major family members cash and readies.
We need cash D and we will go with cash D 1.4.
If you see 1.5 that also you can use.
But let's go with 1.4.
And they create.
Once you create, you should see your parameter group here.
And similar thing.
As we have seen in ideas, of course, different parameters, but you can select parameters, make changes,
save them.
But we are keeping all the default parameters.
Now let's go to.
Subnet groups.
Let's create the subnet group.
So click on create subnet group.
Give a name.
We profile mem cache d subnet group same and description.
So we select our default VPC.
And all the subnets in the availability zone are already selected.
If you don't see them, click on Manage.
Make sure you select them.
And see.
Choose.
Since they are by default selected.
I'll just keep it as it is and I will say create.
So we have parameters group, we have subnet group and we have also the security group that we created
previously.
Now let's go to get started or you can directly go to the cluster.
I'll say get started.
In the cluster, I will just select my cluster.
A cloud.
Name.
V profile elastic cache hyphen service See email given the description.
Engine version will go with 1.4.
Parameters group.
We have to select our parameter group that we created earlier Node type.
Be careful over here by default.
It's a very large instance type.
So we need.
T to micro half a gram.
That is fine for us.
Number of nude single.
Subnet group setting.
So anyway selected our subnet group that we created.
So let's keep it.
If you don't see it, select the dropdown, find your subnet group, select it.
Availability zone.
We will just keep it as no preference.
Just say next.
Security group.
Click on Manage.
Find your security group.
We profile back end as G.
So all our backend services are going into backend security group.
You can select a maintenance window.
But I'll just keep it as no preference for any notification you can select.
As in this topic, if you don't see your as in this topic, keep it disabled.
That is fine.
Dagg will see.
Name.
We profile just cash service and see next.
Review all the settings, especially the node type.
You parameter group subnet group security group Check everything and say create.
So this will take some time to create by the time.
Let's go to the next service.
So create the elastic service and join me in the next lecture.