So now let's create rabbit MQ.
The service name is active MQ.
So search for the service name is Amazon MQ.
If you just type rabbit MQ, it will show up.
Select it.
Let's click on Get started.
So you have a two engine over here.
Apache active MQ and Rabbit MQ.
We will go with rabbit MQ go next single instance broker is fine, but for production workload you should
select cluster deployment.
But again, in order to keep our project low, cost or no cost will keep single instance broker.
Go next.
Broker name as a V profile item.
Q broker instance type again, make sure you select the smaller one over here.
T three Micro.
There is no T two micro here.
We have T three micro.
Rabbit.
You access the username and password.
I'll keep the username as a rabbit and password as okay.
Anyways, I will show you the password.
Because I will be deleting this and this will be a private rabbit MQ instance.
You anyways won't be able to access it.
So anything to all characters and make sure you save this.
Before you create the instance.
After that, you won't be able to see this.
So use capital, small numbers, symbols.
Additional settings.
Broker engine version will keep it the default one.
If you want to store the logs of this to cloud watch, you can select this.
But if the log size grow more, you need to pay for it.
So just not select it.
Network and security.
We will be having private access because we need this as a backend service for our beans stack.
For instance, it will be privately accessing rabbit MQ.
We are not accessing it publicly over the internet, so we'll keep it private.
Access that will be also safe.
Use the default VPC subnet, so we have no separate VPC.
We'll just use the default VPC security group.
We select the existing security group we have.
Yeah, it has already selected that.
Now console is getting intelligent day by day.
And if you don't see this selected, then make sure you select your own security group and uncheck the
default security group.
Maintenance will keep it default.
Automatic maintenance maintenance window will say no preference.
Tag will add name tag.
We profile our MQ zero one.
And let's see next.
So review all the settings, especially the broker instance type.
It should be t three micro.
Otherwise you will end up paying for it.
Last chance to see your password.
After this, you won't be able to see this.
And they create broker.
Now for safety.
I have stored the password into my sticky note temporarily.
You can also do that.
So all three backend services are created.
One last thing left in the backend, which is DB initialization.
We need to log into our instance or my SQL login, create database and deploy our schema.
So we'll do that in the next lecture.
Wrap this up and join me in the next one.