Okay, so let's go to ideas service.
We need to initialize our database so we'll collect information or for instance, its endpoint.
It should be ready by now.
And for this will launch an easy to instance, we'll log into this radius database.
Let's copy its endpoint by the time.
And we'll put it in our.
Sticky notes so we can use it later.
So I'm going to launch an easy.
For instance, let's click on launch instances.
Let's name it as my school hyphen client.
So you can give whatever settings you want.
This is a temporary instance just to initialize the database.
Then we'll terminate it.
OS I'll go with Ubuntu to open to 18.
We'll install my SQL client in that if you prefer to use CentOS or Amazon Linux, that is also fine,
but you should know what you are doing.
The only purpose here is install my skill client, log into IDs instance and initialize the database
and then we delete it.
So any linux OS is fine due to micro instance, I will keep it log in.
Key will use the same one that we created previously.
You can create your own key over here if you want.
Again, this is just temporary.
Okay, So we need to create a security group for this one.
A separate one we're going to say edit.
And we'll create security group, we will call it as my SQL client.
SG.
And I will keep the description also same.
The rules will be simple.
We'll just say 22 aloud from my IP.
Or he can keep it anywhere.
So once this is launch, we are going to login and install my SQL client.
That's the first thing.
If you want, you can use the user data section and you can mention the command to install my skill
client.
Pseudo apt update pseudo apt install my school hyphen client.
Oops.
Client spelling.
Now, if this is sent to us, then the package name is Maria DB in Amazon Linux.
Also the package is Maria.
DB if it's open to my skill hyphen client.
Anyways, we'll run this command again later.
Launch instance.
So, for instance, I'd.
Instance, is in running state.
Let's get its public IP.
Let's log into it.
When two users.
First thing I will do, I am going to run app update over here in this instance.
I'm going to install my SQL client so I can connect to this endpoint.
Then let's install my SQL client.
My SQL client is installed.
Now we can log into ideas endpoint, but the security group will not let us.
Let's try that.
My SQL hyphen edge.
And point.
Hyphen your username admin.
I would be.
So not able to connect.
So that's because we have the security group of our back end instance.
It should allow for 3306.
I just search for my school.
From our MySQL security group.
So this is a security group, for instance, that we just launched.
We give a description.
And let's see rule.
Let's check once again.
Just cancel this.
Now we are in let's run show databases.
So we have the database named accounts and we're going to initialize this database with the schema that
we have in our source code.
So let's come out of this.
And clone the source code.
Get clone.
And the source code URL.
Let's get into the repository.
So you have to shift to branch.
S refactor this branch.
So let's switch to it.
Get check out e w s hyphen re factor.
So.
Let's get into Z Mane resources directory.
We have DB backup, a skill file.
Let's initialize our database with this schema.
Accounts and skew input redirection.
Okay.
Let's log in and make a test.
Show tables.
And we got three tables created.
That's what we need.
Can exit from here.
Ideas is initialized.