Okay, so all our backend services are ready.
Let's collect the information so we profile our ideas.
My skill.
Let's get its endpoint.
Copy that and I'm going to store it in the sticky notes.
And yes instance and point there.
Username Password.
Let's go to rabbit MQ.
I have opened it in this tab Rabbit MQ That is in running state.
And let's come down.
And this is the end point we need.
From that slash, slash till this dot com.
Copy this.
Now we need to store all this information in application properties file.
Now, I also want you to collect one more information.
The port number.
So.
Here you see the port number is 56711.
That one just went there.
And for this it is 3306.
Now these information goes in our application.
You have seen that when we deployed our product, we profile on the VMs, we used application properties
file to give detail of backend services.
Same, We did it in a lift in shift.
So for our application properties file, we are collecting this information and also this will be port
numbers will be helpful while we create security group rules.
Now the last one is the elastic cache.
So let's go to Elastic Cache.
Managed cluster there.
Here.
We just need the endpoint.
So let's copy this endpoint.
And the port number, of course.
One, one, two, one, one.
Okay, so those are the details of our backend services.
Now let's go to Beanstalk and create our Beanstalk instance where we'll host our application.
So search for Beanstalk here.
Oops.
Been stuck.
Elastic Beanstalk.
So if you're greeted with this screen, just click on create application or you can go to applications
here and then click on Create Application.
So I'm going to click here, Create application.
Application name.
I will give v profile hyphen.
Java hyphen app.
Now application.
Think of it as a big container where you can create multiple environments.
Let's see that in a moment.
So let's give Dag.
I will give project tag here.
You cannot give name tag that will be used by this project.
I will say this is for V Profile Project platform.
You have many different platforms like we have different engine type in ideas here, we have different
platform type, you have dot net, Docker, Java, Node, GCP, PHP, Python, Ruby, Tomcat.
Now we know we run our application on Tomcat.
So we'll just select Tomcat here.
We'll go with.
The default here.
Tomcat 8.5 Correcto 11.
Now correcto is really Java so it doesn't use open JDK, it uses its own Java Curto running on 64 bit
Amazon Linux.
So it's going to be an easy to.
Instance with the army of Amazon Linux and keep the default version and fast we will.
Go with the sample application.
Later, we'll upload our code, but we will click on this button.
Configure more options.
Because we need to tweak many settings here.
Okay, scroll up.
We'll click on custom Configuration here.
You can go with the predefined settings here, but we will select our settings.
First, let's go to instances edit.
The instance we will put in the back end security group.
So here is the security group select we profile back in SG.
Now Bienstock gives you instance and it gives you load balancer.
We'll put our load balancer in a different security group instance.
We'll put it in the back end security group.
Now let's go to route volume type.
You can keep it default, container default, or you can go with general purpose or you can you can
mention the GBS volume size, or we'll just keep it as container, which is default.
And let's see if this.
Capacity.
Let's edit this.
So these are the details of your auto scaling group.
We instruct will have an auto scaling group to manage your instances and we will say load balance,
not single instance.
We need multiple instances and it should be automatically scaled.
Will keep minimum instances two and maximum you can keep how many ever you want, because we are really
not going to scale it.
But in real time, make sure you have proper restriction minimum and maximum minimum while keep two
for high availability.
Now let's come down instance type.
It can use the mix, but we'll just keep it to micro, to keep it low cost availability zone, just
keep any placement, any.
So here you can say how many availability zones do you want to use?
Any one, any two, any three.
And you can here select the number of the, the available availability zones.
So we just keep this default.
We'll let it create instance in any availability zone scaling trigger for auto scaling group, there
are multiple metrics.
Now you have network out, which is very popular for web applications like we profile is a web application,
but then you have CPU utilization, you have network in, you have disk.
We'll keep it network out.
So if the network traffic is going out on a larger amount, it will launch more instances.
So scale out if more data is served to the user.
If less data is served to the user.
Skill in.
And we keep all the default settings here.
Just keep save.
You might need to scroll up and scroll down because I know for some reason it by default it scrolls
down automatically.
So that was.
Capacity.
And next is load balancer will make changes to the load balancer later.
But let's just quickly see the settings of load balancer.
You have by default application load balancer.
Listener is 80.
We need four for three, which we will add later.
And health check for our V profile application is slash login.
So we need to change that also.
All this will change later.
Access log.
If you wish, you can store it on the S3 bucket.
You can choose the S3 bucket.
You can create a bucket and choose it.
But let's not do that.
Unnecessary cost for now.
Just cancel it.
Okay.
Next is rolling updates and deployments.
Let's edit this.
This is one of the most interesting feature of being stack.
So deployment policy, when you upload your artifact to stack, when you deploy your artifact, how
do you want to get it deployed?
I mean, there are different policies like all at once, all the instances.
So if you have ten instances, all the ten instances will be brought down and they will be upgraded.
So of course there will be downtime.
Rolling is better.
So let's say you have ten instances and you specify here percentage as 20.
So the batch size.
So 20% of ten is two instances.
So two instances at a time will be upgraded, which is very good.
We just have two instances, so we'll keep this as 50%.
Now there are other deployment policies also.
They're really good.
But this extra cost for that rolling with additional batch side, it is going to launch extra instances
for the upgrade immutable.
It's going to launch the entire new stack.
So if you have ten instance, it's going to launch ten new instances.
So it's not going to deploy the artifact on the same instance.
It's going to be new instance traffic splitting.
This is what typical blue green deployment where you can route a certain percentage of traffic only
to the newer version.
So let's say 10% traffic goes to the new instances and the rest goes to the old instances.
And then every 5 minutes, if if it's good, every 5 minutes, it will be increasing like that.
10%, 10%, 10%.
It's a safer option when you want to roll out something new to your user and you're not so sure how
users will react.
So you can do traffic splitting.
Now I recommend you go through Bienstock stack documentation and read about this deployment policies.
So when the situation comes, you can select the right policy for you.
For now, we'll go with rolling 50% batch size.
And take everything else.
A default.
Let's see.
See if.
Next is security.
Edit So this is the security key pair.
So Beanstalk will launch easy to instance, if you want to log into that instance, you need the key
pair.
And that is the reason we created this key pair earlier.
I am instance profile.
You say create instance profile.
If you already see a beanstalk instance profile over there, you can select that.
Or let's just say create instance profile and say save.
Next is monitoring.
We will not do anything here.
Just let's see.
The settings enhanced will keep it as it is for low rolling deployments.
We will need this.
But if you're going with single instance, go with basic monitoring enhanced.
There will be extra charges for enhanced.
But anyways, once our work is done, we will delete it so we will not be charged for it.
So just cancel it.
Okay.
Notification.
You can send the notification to an email address here.
You can mention that.
Network setting.
You can select your own VPC, but we will just use the default VPC.
Database.
You can mention your own ideas which will be tied up with your beanstalk instance.
Now, for production, this is not recommended.
You need to have a separate idea that you created and Beanstalk instance separate for production purpose.
So the lifecycle of both are not tied together.
If you delete beans tag, you don't want your database to get deleted.
Dag added tag.
Let's give name tag.
Name is already reserved.
Right.
Project.
We profile.
And we will receive.
Okay.
I want you to take your time, go through all the settings, read them, digest as much as possible,
or obviously you will not be able to digest all the settings, but you will know that there are these
these kinds of settings.
Don't try to buy heart anything.
Just go through them.
Okay, now we'll click on Create App, but it is going to do two things.
It is going to create the application and inside the application it will create the environment.
All these settings that we are giving is for our environment.
You can have multiple environments.
Also, let's create and see for ourself.
Now, this is going to take time, a lot of time.
So if you need a break, this is the time.
I will pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
Okay, so my application is ready after a few minutes and inside that it has an environment.
Now, as I told you, all the settings that we gave was for the environment.
You can create multiple environments inside an application like dev environment, queue environment,
production, environment like that.
So let's click on the application.
And you see that is the environment name that we had given when creating Bean Stack.
We profile Java app.
It has added hyphen and void.
And you see it's in terminated state.
Now, if you are creating Bean for the first time in the region, you will also get this.
If you don't get this, your environment is good, it's fine.
But if you get this terminated and you look at the error, the instance profile.
Value associated with the environment is invalid.
So.
Let's go back to the environment.
If you get this terminated, create a new environment and give similar settings.
It is going to be web server environment.
Application name.
We select our application name.
We profile Java app.
Tag project v profile environment.
Name will keep it hyphen prod and for the domain just use the same name.
Just make sure we give this V as small not capital.
So this will be the endpoint of your load balancer check availability and it is available.
You can use this name.
How I can say this will be the Earl of your website.
Obviously, we'll have our own name also, which will redirect to this name, but we'll see that later.
Platform same thing.
Tomcat.
Keep it default.
Configure more options.
So you see, this is similar to what we created previously, but that was terminated.
So we are creating a new one.
So all the setting similar instances.
Let's select our V profile back end security group save.
Capacity.
Load balanced.
Minimum, to instance, maximum.
I'll keep it as eight.
Do you do?
Micro instances only.
Scaling trigger.
Keep it default save.
Rolling updates and deployments.
Ruling.
Bat size 50%.
And see this.
Security.
This is why it failed previously.
If you're wondering why it was terminated, that is because there was no service role and we did not
select anything over here.
But now you see there is a service role.
This is the service role we have to select.
Now.
This service role will have permissions privileges to access other services like S3, Cloud watch and
all.
Sound similar if you already have experience with it.
As you know, I am role.
This is the I am roll which has policies in it.
So it was not there previously.
We did not select it.
So the instance got terminated.
We will select it now.
This name and key payer.
Now I am instance profile.
If you see the profile with this name then only selected.
Otherwise do not select anything, just keep it empty.
Don't even click on the dropdown.
Let me repeat it once again.
I am instance Pro file.
Keep it blank select only if you see this name as elastic beans tag hyphen easy to hyphen role then
only selected say save.
Okay, so we saved that.
So if we do not select, it will create the rule with the same name.
Monitoring will keep it enhanced.
One more lasting tags.
We will be adding the project tag.
We profile and save.
Once it's click on Create Environment.
Okay, so this will take some time.
So take a break.
Come back after 5 minutes.