Okay, so environment is ready.
It's in the OC health state and you should see the URL here.
If you just click on it, it should open the default application.
So if you go to an environment.
We have here application versions.
You can see there is an application version labeled Sample application.
This is currently deployed.
We will be deploying our V profile artifact here that will see in the next video.
But before we do that, we need to make few changes in the security group of backend services.
Our application from bean stack instance easy to instance.
So if you go to easy to console.
You should see these two easy instances created by Beanstalk.
Our application will be inside this and this will connect.
To the backend services.
Back services will be in the backend security group.
So if you go to security group.
We have a high profile bank and security group, so instances in V Profile Java App Prod Security Group
will connect to back end services which are in back and security group.
So we need to make changes to the inbound rule of back and security group.
So select your back end security group.
Go to inbound rules.
Edit inbound rules.
So you see, there are no rules which allows access from the Bean Stack security group.
So we need to add the rule first.
Rule you will add is 3306.
This is for the IDS connectivity.
So Beanstalk instance, which is in this security group we profile Java abroad, should be able to connect
on Port 3306.
Next.
One.
One, two, one, one, four.
Ma'am.
Cash.
Again, select.
Dean Stack Security Group.
One more service.
Amazon MQ.
Port number 5671.
Again.
Select Bienstock Security Group.
Now, this is very specific based on the specific port numbers, but you can add one more rule.
Instead of adding all these rules, you can add just one rule, say all traffic allowed from.
Bienstock security group, which is simple rule.
But from a security perspective, we should give specific rules.
I will keep both.
But if you see your application is not able to connect to back end security group, check your security
group rules of background and make sure you add correct rules.
Save Rule.
Inbound rules Created.
Do not touch the outbound rule.
Just the inbound rules.
So that was about security group.
The next thing we will be doing is.
An environment.
Load balancer.
So let's go to an environment configuration.
And find the load balancer settings.
Edit.
We have bought 80 as a listener.
Four load balancer will add one more.
Extra DPS port four for three, choose the certificate.
And see ad.
Scroll down.
We see here processes.
Put a checkmark here.
Action.
Edit Now this is the health check that we are editing.
So our application is living in this URL slash login.
So once we deploy our artifact.
And when the application comes up, the URL will be the load balancer endpoint slash login.
So health check should be done over there at slash login.
So make sure you update that.
Stickiness in the sessions.
Make sure you enable stickiness.
This is specific to a V profile application, so if the user access the load balancer, the load balancer
connects to the easy instance, and if stickiness is enabled, it will always connect to the same easy
to instance.
If it is not enabled, then it may route it to other instance also.
And the user, the current user who is logged in may lose the session as well.
So we have multiple instances for high availability, but when the user connects to an instance, the
user is connected to the same easy to instances.
Instance.
Sorry, save.
If you want, you can store the access log of the load balancer two and three bucket.
You need to create an S3 bucket first.
But we will not select this.
So only two things.
Add four for three.
Select your cert and make sure you change the health check to slash login.
And say apply.
Once you apply.
It will make the changes and the systems, the environment health will transition from okay to severe.
That is fine after we deploy our artifact.
This will come in the Oak State.
So.
Apply all the changes, save them and then join me in the next video where we'll deploy the artifact.