Okay, Now's the time to build our application from source code and deploy to beanstalk environment.
So I'll do it locally on my laptop.
So I'll go to the drive.
If you have not cloned the source code here.
And make sure you clone it.
I already have it.
So I'm not going to clone.
I will just do seed into that.
Get pull for any changes.
Get branch hyphen a.
So we will check out.
Refactor this branch and hit enter.
Let's clear the screen.
So from the prerequisite video, you should already have Maven and JDK installed on your machine.
And we'll build the artifact.
But before that, we have to make change to the application properties file.
We updated with right detail.
My SQL will give the radius endpoint there, which we already copied in our sticky notes.
Username was admin and password.
We had generated automatically that also we had saved.
Metcash.
So the elastic cash end point.
And you don't need to mention port number.
It's already mentioned here in the configuration.
Robert McHugh.
It's an Abbott MQ endpoint.
Again.
Port number don't need to give here.
Five, six, seven one.
Username was rabbit and password.
Also we have made changes.
Verify once again, make sure all the details are right, if you're sure about it.
Can save it.
Let's go back to V Profile Project Directory.
Okay, time to Bill.
We'll say move an install.
I guess, after some time.
Build is completed.
If we see in the target directory, we should see our artifact and we're going to upload this artifact
or bienstock environment and let's do it.
So go back to Amazon console.
You see the health is transition to severe but it is going to change back.
Application version.
Can say upload.
Can give some version if you want.
Will say v profile hyphen v 2.5.
And you can choose file.
Make sure you go to your repository where you have created Target.
We profile v two dot var.
And let's see.
Upload.
So it is uploading if you see down there that I'm not able to catch it.
Uploading 40%.
42%.
Yeah, it's jumping.
90% uploading.
Okay, It's done.
So it's waiting for being stuck now.
Let's try and click.
You don't need to click.
Okay.
That is uploaded, but that just uploading it has just uploaded our artifact into an S3 bucket.
Automatically we're going to select our version now.
Action.
And we'll say deploy.
When we say deploy, you can select your environment.
If your multiple environment will list it.
We just have one environment and that's the name we're going to say deploy.
So let's go to the environment section.
And we'll see the.
Events Environment update is starting.
So if we have to wait for some time before it complete.
Now the status is okay.
The health is good.
And this whole time in the upgrade was happening.
Our services didn't go down because we have selected Rolling upgrade.
We can even see that in the events.
So let's go to events.
And we can see a whole lot of events, four pages of events are there.
You scroll down, you see the environment update is starting and deploying a new version.
So batch one.
So we have two instance.
So batch one means 50%.
We selected so one instance.
So when it completes execution on batch one and by the time the second instance will be already up and
running when it completed batch one, one instance upgrade completed, then it started batch to choose
the second instance.
You can even see the instance ID here.
So it's a rolling upgrade 50% one instance at a time because we have two instance.
Now let's go and check our endpoint.
And we should see the login page.
It's up and running, but we will make a DNS entry first.
We'll go to GoDaddy.
We'll make a DNS entry.
We profile groovy dot endpoints to this LP.
So I'm in my GoDaddy DNS management.
I'll say add record.
CNN record.
And I will say we profile points to and we'll copy the end point.
And put it over there.
Let's see.
See?
So entry's updated and you can wait for some time in order to your ISP can cache this DNS request.
HTTPS colon slash slash v profile dot groovy dot n.
Let's check.
And it's coming up.
So https secure login.
You can check the certificate as well.
Since the certificate is valid.
It's provided by Amazon.
So it should be a secure login.
Let's try to get into this.
Admin underscore vip password admin underscore vip.
Let's hit login.
Before we login.
We also need to make one more change to our beanstalk.
We need to enable stickiness for our load balancer.
So let's go to beanstalk configuration.
Select Edit our load balancer.
In the processes put a checkmark on the default process.
Edit Scroll down.
And see stickiness policy enabled and say save.
Once you say we need to apply these changes.
So you hit on apply.
So this is going to take a moment.
So in a few minutes or a few seconds, should I say an environment update has completed successfully?
Let's check our URL once again.
Let's refresh.
It's up.
Let's try and log in again at one underscore VP password.
Same.
Well again.
And we are in.
So this is also validated now.
Let's check rabbit MQ.
Rabbit Abbott initiated.
Let's go back.
So we are using active service and yes, our instance is able to connect to active servers.
Now let's check elastic cache all user.
So you see the list of users and lets select any user.
So data is inserted in cache.
In elastic cache.
Go back.
And it's click the same user.
And you will see data is from cash.
So we verified beans, TAC ideas, elastic cash, active MQ.
Now my side is really sitting in North Virginia region and I have, let's say, global audience users
around the world.
So to serve the global audience generally, content content delivery network is used and it is very,
very expensive because you need to have data center or caching location at so many places then around
the world, which is extremely expensive setup.
We can use an eight service cloud front, which is a content delivery network very easily.