Okay, so then let's go to cloud front.
It is the content delivery network.
Now, if you're not aware about cloud front, I'm sorry, I should call it as content delivery network.
Cloud Front is the seed of AWS.
If you do not know what is a seed an.
Then go ahead, read all this and do your own research as well.
It's a pretty simple concept, but it needs vast coverage, multiple data centers around the globe.
So your website data will be cached around the world so you can serve a global audience easily, quickly.
So once your application stack is up and running, you can use a seed network to distribute your content
around the world.
So a cloud front or Amazon Cloud front is a seed in which you can use very easily.
So let's see.
Create cloud front distribution.
First thing here.
Origin Domain.
You can directly select your S3 bucket or load balancer, which is search from cloud front or you can
give.
Your domain name v profile dot goofy dot n.
That's what I have.
I have already updated this in my GoDaddy account, which points to the load balancer.
Or you can directly do the load balancer if you're not going to use the domain name.
But let's use our origin domain name.
As we mentioned in GoDaddy.
And let's come down.
Or gin pot.
Keep it as it is because our application automatically redirects to slash logging.
We don't need to mention that.
And come down.
We were Protocol policy will keep http https if you want to serve both the traffic.
Allowed to be method.
I will select all.
Get head options put post batch delete, and then let's come down.
You keep all this things default.
Settings.
So this is about the pricing.
If you want.
It was to use all its edge location for the cloud front.
Here, I'll show you 300 plus edge location.
So if you select in cloud front.
All education.
It will distribute it in all the education location.
Or you can be specific.
If you're in North America and Europe, you can just select this and not you as in your users.
You can select this one as well, which includes Europe, Asia, Middle East and Africa.
We'll keep it all at your location, because I know you people are watching this course from different,
different parts of the world.
I also have students in 150 countries, so I don't know where you will be sitting.
So it's better to use all edge locations.
So in case you want to verify, you can verify easily.
Okay, let's come down.
Alternate domain name.
We are using an alternate domain name V profile dot goofy dot n.
That's mine.
Put your domain over here.
Your C name.
We are going with four for three https connection, so we need to select the certificate.
So select the certificate, SSL certificate and security policy.
I'm going with the TLS v one Now, for some reason, if your cloud front distribution is not working,
you try switching it back and forth.
Among these different policies.
Atlas V one definitely works for our V profile project, so I'm selecting that and then let's come down.
And I think we are good.
Let's click on Create Distribution.
Before that, let's just verify once again.
So origin domain v profile dot goofy dot n protocol match viewer were.
Yes, it's good I checked it.
You need to select match we were.
So user access http or https we can serve both.
Okay, let's come down.
Use all edge location SSL certificate selector tls v one.
All good.
Let's click on Create Distribution.
So it is creating.
You see last modified deploying and this may take a very, very long time.
You will see statuses enabled, but the deploying this may take a very long time.
So if you need a break, take a break.
Come back maybe like in half an hour.
So I will also pause my screen.
Take a break, and then I will come back.
So see you back in a few minutes.