Okay, So after some time the status is enabled, it is deployed so we can again access this URL on
HTTPS protocol from our browser.
But.
As a user, we won't be able to see the difference that it is coming.
It is sold from the edge location of cloud front or is it coming directly from the instance from that
region?
So to inspect that, I'm going to inspect the element while we access the website in our browser.
So I'm opening Firefox here, just a different browser.
So there is no caching in that browser yet.
And I have opened the incognito mode or Firefox.
Just use an alternate browser.
Don't use the same browser that you used previously to access.
Your application.
So I will say https colon slash slash v profile dot goofy.
Dot rn and LP is the URL.
And we'll run F12 and refresh the browser once again.
And let's see this.
So you can see via you can see the cloud front near a distribution and point there.
So our website is really getting now support from cloud front distribution.
And that was pretty amazing job.
Now we have our entire stack and we are using PASS and SAS services.
We are not directly using EC2 instances.
So we have been stack radius, elastic cache, Amazon message queue and cloud front distribution behind
the scene.
Stack is also using S3 bucket cloud watch for monitoring.
So this entire setup is going to give us very low operational overhead.
So you do need many admins or many, many cloud engineers to manage the entire setup.
So let's revise our architecture now.
User Access Amazon Route 53 to Cloud Front Application Load Balancer, which is part of Bean Stack.
Monitored by cloud.
Watch alarms.
Artifacts in S3 buckets.
Amazon MQ instead of Rabbit MQ AC two instance, we are using Amazon MQ.
Elastic cash.
Instead of using cash from an easy for instance, and Amazon ideas instead of using my SQL running on
an E two instance.
So if you have hosted Zone in Amazon Route 53, you can even add the entry.
Instead of GoDaddy, you can add the entry over here.
It's in the Route 53 itself.
Are you going to use both Route 53 for Subdomain and GoDaddy for the domain?
Now let's fall back to our Amazon console.
We need to do cleanup.
We have not many things.
I don't want you to be running all this if you're not using it.
Even though we try to keep things under free tier, but there are storage is volume, there's cloud
front.
It's better we delete everything to save our bills starting from let's delete cloud front so you can't
directly delete it.
First you have to disable it.
And it's going to take some time to disable by the time.
Let's go and start dealing.
Deleting other services.
So ideas.
Let's delete our ideas.
Instance.
So don't copy the final snapshot.
Just say acknowledge and say delete me.
Delete.
Let's go to elastic cache Action.
Oops, It's not showing.
Action.
Right.
After refreshing the browser delete.
Amazon MQ.
Confirmation.
Give the name of the broker.
Delete.
Let's go to Beanstalk, and this will also take a very long time to delete.
Select it.
First, let's delete the environment.
That's.
Thing that has all the resources.
And in application, if you delete or not, it's just going to be a name or container.
So it's not going to charge you anything but delete the environment.
So last thing, make sure you delete your distribution.
Once it is, it says deployed in progress.
You will see here it has disabled and this will be deployed.
Then you can select it and delete it.
So that was pretty awesome.
We'll see more amazing things on Cloud and DevOps and CCD in other projects.
And that would be all in this project.
Thank you very much for watching.
I will see you in the next one.