A very warm welcome to our next project.
The next project is about continuous delivery for Docker containers.
You can see four or off Docker containers in this project will be continuously building Docker images
and deploying it to Kubernetes cluster.
So let's understand the scenario.
Problem, statement and solution.
We'll understand when such projects are implemented.
You will see mostly such projects in microservice architecture.
But it's not.
But it's not just about microservice architecture.
Anywhere.
You have containers, Docker containers.
There you can implement such kind of projects.
But mostly today is the time of microservice architecture.
And if an application has microservice design, then they will be containerized.
The application.
So you would have a containerized application, probably Docker images.
And then the developers are making continuous code changes.
They are making the product better and better and better.
So the build and release and ops team really need to cope with these regular code changes.
So with continuous chord changes, there has to be continuous build and test process.
It has to be regular build of your containers.
And if you containers are getting built regularly, it needs to be deployed regularly.
Now, possibly the container images can be automated locally itself building of container images, but
the deployment goes to the operations team.
And operations team will be maintaining and managing container orchestration tools like Kubernetes cluster.
And they will be in charge of running your containers.
So the request goes to the ops team to deploy Docker images on any container runtime environment like
Docker.
So we know there will be continuous chord changes, continuous building of images.
So the ops team will get continuous deployment requests.
Now, first of all, the manual deployment process creates a dependency.
Here.
The team is dependent on the ops team folder for the deployment.
Which really breaks the chain of continuous delivery.
And of course, it's time consuming.
So primarily we need to automate the build and release process of container images.
As we are building continuously Docker images, we also need to deploy continuously.
And this should be as fast as the code commits are happening.
So as soon as a developer makes a code change, we should automatically build a docker image and should
be able to also deploy it automatically to an orchestration environment like Kubernetes.
So we need to have a continuous deployment process.
So, yes, we are talking about a continuous delivery or a continuous deployment pipeline.
For Docker containers.
So in this project, we are going to use a variety of tools.
Let's see the tools that we're going to use in this project.
Starting with Kubernetes cluster.
Which will be your container orchestration tool and docker engine.
Which will be using to build our Docker images and also to test our Docker images.
Jenkins will be using as a seed server Docker hub where we'll be hosting our Docker images.
Helm will be using for packaging and deploying our images to combat this cluster.
And not just Docker images, the complete stack of our applications we can deploy with help.
And that's what we're going to do.
We'll be using Git as a version control system maven to build our Java code and software cube server
for the code analysis.
The objective of this project is very simple.
We have to do continuous delivery for containers, especially the Docker containers.
All right, let's see the architectural design for this project.
Okay, so when the developer makes a code change to the git repository, it will be committed to git
hub.
We're going to push the code to GitHub.
Jenkins is going to fetch the code and this code will also include Docker file, which will be used
to build the Docker image.
Jenkins file.
We're going to use pipeline as a code and also the helm charts.
So Jenkins is going to fetch all the changes.
Will do its test.
We'll do the code analysis by using check style and sonar Q scanner and will upload the result to.
On the cube server.
I'm going to use sonar cube server in this project.
If you wish to use a sonar cloud, you can do that.
If all the quality gates are good on the code, then we're going to build the artifact with Maven and
then a Docker build process will start, which will build a Docker image.
If everything is good and everything passes, then the Docker image will be pushed to Docker Hub.
Where we're going to maintain our Docker Docker repository.
If this push is successful, then we're going to use help from Jenkins.
We're going to basically add our cops VM as a slave, and we're going to run help from there.
So Jenkins will be running.
Helm charts will deploy help charts to the Kubernetes cluster.
This help chart deployment will create everything for us if we wish to.
Along with parts running through deployments, we can also set up a services.
Secrets of volumes.
Everything through help charts.
If you already have those things, it will only implement the changes like a new image tag for an application
pod.
So let's see now the flow of execution step by step, what we are going to do in this project.
And then we'll implement all this.
We need to have a continuous integration setup.
We need a Jenkins sooner cube nexus.
We can skip if you want.
Basically similar setup as we did in the continuous integration project.
We need a Docker hub account.
You can use the same as you use in the Containerization project.
If you wish, you can create a new Docker River account also.
Speaking to the store, the Docker hub credential in Jenkins.
We're going to set up Docker engines, Docker engine in Jenkins.
We need few extra plug ins along with what we already have for content integration.
We need a Docker pipeline plugin, Docker plugin and pipeline utility plugin.
We're going to use pipeline as a code in this project.
So we need the pipeline utility plugin.
Then we'll create this cluster with cops, as we did in the Kubernetes setup project.
So you should have done already all the prerequisites for cops.
We're just going to run the command to run the Kubernetes, to create the Kubernetes cluster by using
cops.
Then we'll install hell in the cops VM.
We're going to have cops on an easy instance as we have Jenkins Sonar Cuban access.
We'll also have cops.
VM From where?
We're the cops, to instance, from where we'll create the Kubernetes cluster and we install Helm in
that.
Then we'll create help charts.
We'll be also putting variables in them for an application image.
And then we'll test the charts in the Kubernetes cluster.
In the test namespace, we'll create a namespace, and we're going to test our charts in that here.
When I say charge, that means your entire stack, our entire V profile stack in this case.
We're going to add our cops themed cops, easy to instance, as a Jenkins slave.
Will create a pipeline code.
It's going to be it's going to be declarative where we'll mention the build test, Docker, build process
and help chart deployment process.
We didn't need to update our Git repository with help charts that we have created.
Docker file for application image and Jenkins file where we created the pipeline code.
Once we have all this ready, we're going to create a Jenkins job for Pipeline.
We're going to run and test it.
Okay, then what are you waiting for?
Let's just dive in.