So I'm in my management console and I have 3c2 instances running over here.
One is cops.
So the server and the Jenkins server.
As discussed previously, you should have continuous integration setup already in place.
If you don't have, I recommend you pause the video and set up Jenkins server sooner.
Cube Server Nexus server will not be required if you already created this stack by using cloud formation.
Then you can stop the Nexus server.
Cops, for instance, should be ready with all the prerequisites.
As we did in Cuba, is a set of projects and we'll get into that.
But first, let me take you through the source code.
So in our source code, we profile project Source code a search for the branch secede hyphen cube.
In this branch.
We have our Java source code, which is in the RC directory which will build from Jenkins and generate
the artifact.
We have a docker file.
So with the Docker build process, we're going to create a Docker image.
So the artifact generated from our source code will be copied into.
This location in the Docker image.
This is the same as the Containerization project where we have created all these Docker files.
So we're going to use this Docker file.
We're going to continuously deliver our application image.
So we have to generate Docker image for our application running on Tomcat.
So we need that Docker file in this repository.
We have a Jenkins file.
So we are going to use a pipeline as a code in this project.
We're going to write this Jenkins file.
But if you wish to skip writing this Jenkins file, you can directly use this from our source code.
And we'll get into all the steps in that I would like to point out here first.
The Kubernetes deploy stage, which will be running from.
Slave labeled as cops.
And in this.
We're going to run Helm Command.
So for the Helm Command, we provide the charts.
Location charts will be all the definition file for our Kubernetes objects like deployment service Secret,
as we did it one in one of the Kubernetes project where we have executed a Java application on Kubernetes
cluster.
So same definition file we have in this chart.
Let's see the chart.
So there is a home directory.
In this.
We have profile charts.
And if you see here in the templates directory, you will see a same definition file as we used in.
One of our companies project where we deployed the Java application on Kubernetes cluster.
We are more focused on this definition file application deployment.
So from Jenkins, we're going to build the image, upload it to a Docker hub account.
And this definition file we're going to mention in the image location, a variable helm uses a go language
templating format.
So that's how we mention variable in helm.
And this variable will be passing from the Jenkins file.
So in the Jenkins file.
But we have the deployment stage.
Where we're using Helm Command to deploy our charts.
This is the location of our chart.
We have just seen it and we are passing the value for the variable app image.
There.
And that value will be again, variable.
So we're dynamically parsing the image name and the tag in our charts.
There.
So it will deploy the latest image to the company's cluster.
We'll get more into this helm charts and writing this Jenkins file.
Let's log into Jenkins first, set up a solar cube integration, and then we'll create this cluster
from Copse.
So I'll get the IP of Jenkins.
I mean, Jenkins.
Let me open Sony Cube Server.
Again, if you wish to use SoundCloud over here, you can do that.
So generate a new token.
Let's keep that.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Manny Jenkins.
Configure system.
We'll keep that name Sonar Pro, because that's the same name in our Jenkins file.
If you have any different name, then change it to Sonar Pro, because we're going to use that name.
So make sure the same name is over here.
Let's get this honor Cube, Private IP.
Let's add the token.
Let's copy the token.
Let's save this.
And we'll select our right token.
Let's save these settings.
Also, you have to make sure the Jenkins security group allows connection from sonar and sonar.
Security Group allows connection from Jenkins.
So I'll go to Jenkins Security group.
Inbound.
I drew all traffic from Jenkins security Group.
Now I'm going to say the Sooner Security group, we are updating the Jenkins security group.
We are allowing all traffic from sooner security group.
Same will do for the sonar security group.
Let's go to sonar security group.
Edit Inbound drone.
So if you see, I already have a rule, all traffic allowed from sonar security group.
If you don't have these rules, add them or update them.
I already have.
So I'm going to not do it for sooner.
Okay, Next.
So we have a stage in our Jenkins file which is going to push the image to Docker Hub.
So we get your Docker hub credentials.
So I have a Docker hub account over here.
Q Imran, it currently does not have anything, any repository or no organization.
I'm going to use this one.
You can create either a new one or you can use the same as you used in the Containerization project.
Now we'll store the details of Docker Hub logins into Jenkins credentials.
So let's go to manage Jenkins.
Manage credentials.
I will see ad credentials.
Q The login username for Docker Hub and the login password.
The idea and description name we will be giving.
Same as in the Jenkins file.
So registry credential we are using registry credential variable.
The name is Docker Hub, so we're going to use the same name, Docker Hub.
And for the description also seem.
And let's add that.
Next step is to install Docker engine in the Jenkins server.
So let's log into the Jenkins server.
So I'll open my gate bash.
I have the login key.
So let's go through the Docker installation step from Docker documentation.
So our jenkins is running on Ubuntu.
So I'm going to install docker in ubuntu.
So let's find that document.
Docker is installed in Jenkins.
Let's check.
Notes system CD status, of course.
So Dockery is running in Jenkins The reason we install Docker in Jenkins because we're going to run
Docker build command from Jenkins.
So if we try to do that, let's log in as the Jenkins user.
Sue hyphen Jenkins.
And if you tried to run any Docker command, it will throw you permission denied.
That's because only root user can run Docker commands or any any user who is part of Docker group can
run the Docker commands.
So let's add a Jenkins user.
In the Docker group.
So Laguna is a route user or a run pseudo.
We run the command user mod.
Hyphen.
E.
G.
Group name is Joker.
There will be a group named as Docker already created in your system when you install Docker in Jenkins.
So we are adding a Jenkins user into Docker group.
Yes.
Check that ID, Jenkins.
Jenkins is there is part of Docker group now.
Now if you access the Jenkins user, if you log in as Jenkins user, you should be able to run the Docker
command.
So run this test.
If this works fine, we should be good.
But that's from the command line variable.
To switch to Jenkins user and run the Docker commands with Jenkins process, which is already running,
will not have that access because it is not yet loaded.
So we can restart a Jenkins service if that also don't solve the purpose, you can just reboot the Jenkins
machine.
Once you add Jenkins to Docker group.
Just for the safe side, you can reboot the Jenkins machine.
So I'm going to do that.
Wait for a moment for Jenkins instance to come up, and then we'll move to the next stage.