How Jenkins should be up.
Let's try to log in.
And we are in.
This is fine.
We can log out from here.
Let's go to a browser.
Let's refresh the Jenkins page.
I recommend you have Jenkins of TX to small minimum TX to micro will run very slow, so make sure you
have Jenkins TX to small.
Do you do?
My cross should also run, but it will be a little slower.
Next, we'll create the Kubernetes cluster from cops.
But before that, let's install a few plugins.
So let's go to manage Jenkins.
Manage plugins.
Available.
We need the Docker plugin.
So a Docker pipeline and a Docker plugin.
And we'll also need the pipeline utility.
Pipeline and utility steps.
This is for Jenkins pipeline as a code.
Sort of put a checkmark on all these three plugins, Docker Pipeline, Docker and pipeline utility steps
and say install without a restart.
All right, While this is happening, let's log into our cops.
Easy, to instance.
From here, we're going to create Kubernetes cluster.
So in my history, I already have the command to create the Kubernetes cluster.
I'm going to create it with the same name.
I'm going to use the same bucket.
You can use exactly the same setup as you did in Cuba in this setup project.
Zones.
We are changing.
We are running it currently.
I'm running it currently in Oregon region, so I'm going to give write zone names.
US west to a and us vest to be.
I'll use these two zones.
Node.
Count two is fine.
T2 Micro should be fine master size due to micro fine and the same DNS zone name.
Let's hit enter.
Cops Update Cluster.
We should actually create the cluster.
So the creation process started and as we know, it's going to take some time.
By the time we will install Helme in this copse issue, for instance.
So let's go to helm documentation.
Helm search.
So there is no plugin that I could found and I did not find any plugin of Helme in Jenkins.
But maybe by the time you're watching the video you should find some plugin.
But anyways, you don't need that help plugin.
We are going to add the corpse issue two instance as a slave to Jenkins and will run Helm command.
From cops itself.
So we really don't need that plugin.
V but need to install help in this instance.
So let's go to documentation.
So if you don't know about helm, Hell basically is a packaging system for definition files.
We can package our entire all the definitions for our project stack and we can also deploy to cover
this cluster.
So instead of managing all the definition file for deployment service volumes, all the different different
definition file, we maintain and manage separately.
Instead of that, we can use Helm to package all of them and run them or update them on Kubernetes cluster.
So it is Helme helps you manage Kubernetes Application Help Charts.
Charts are actually the collection of our definition files, so we can define everything by using charts.
If you want to learn a few more things about Helm, you can check the Quick Start guide.
You can check the architecture of Helm.
And there's a small interaction video as well.
There's so many things in helm, but to get started with we, we can create the package in helm and
we can deploy our application by using Helm.
Let's go to get started.
So political sites.
We need a communist cluster.
We should already have all the security configuration.
It is saying installing and configuring Helme.
So let's install helme.
So let's go to the official release page.
We can do it through home rules of your MacBook, but we're installing it on a Linux instance.
Let's check the installation guide.
So we just need to download the binary, extract it and put it to use our local bin held pot.
So let's download that.
The latest one will go with.
So Linux aimed 64.
That should be fine.
Is it a download link?
Let's check it.
Yeah, that's a download link.
Let's copy it.
Copy link, address.
Let's go to a COPS instance.
So downloaded Helme.
I'm going to extract it our exit.
V.
F.
L.
Should have Linux aimed 64 directory.
So we have this binary we are going to move it to.
Move.
Hell, yeah.
We're going to move it to use our local bin.
The name?
Same name.
Helm.
And let's see if we can access helm.
Hyphen hyphen help.
Yes.
Okay, so we have this set up now.
We are going to prepare our repository with all the data.
We'll create charts in that.
We'll have the Docker file and the Jenkins file.
Before that, let's check whether we have our COVID cluster up or not.
It's up and running.
So we'll prepare the repository next.