Get into your GitHub account.
Create a new repository.
Now this is optional.
If you want to use repository from our source code, you can use that repository.
You can just watch or you can create your own repository and feed all the data.
At the end of the day, everything will be same.
I will name it as secede.
I think cube hyphen docker.
I'll keep it public.
Create a repository.
Will fetch the URL and let's clone it.
That is all.
I will you sorry I set you all.
I'll use https URL for now.
Okay, let's get into that.
Also clone our source code repository will need a lot of data from there.
We will Project Repository.
Let's clone that.
So clearly separately.
Don't clone it in the same directory.
So you should have our source code repository and the repository that you just created.
Let's get into our source code repository and we're going to switch to branch VP hyphen a docker.
That's that is the content that you should see in this branch.
We have a darker branch.
And we're going to copy all of this recursively to.
Of a repository.
Again, if you wish to skip this, you can use.
Just directly the secede cube branch from our source code and all the data is already mentioned over
here.
We are just preparing the same data in a different repository, in a different branch.
Okay, so here we don't need the Docker hyphen db Docker hyphen web.
We don't need compose.
We don't need Ansible.
In Docker hyphen app directory.
You should have the Docker file to build our application image.
Let's copy it, move it to the main directory, the top level directory of the repository.
So you should have docker file here and then if you want, you can remove docker hyphen app directly.
We already have a directory over here.
We can remove this because we're going to prepare our own.
Okay, so you should have Docker file at this location.
This docker file and equipment is directory.
The pro app.
And we need all these templates.
Okay, let's come at the top level here.
We'll create a directory called a helm.
We get into this directory and we're going to run a command helm create.
And the chart name.
So I'm going to give you profile charts.
Same name you can also give because that's mentioned in our Jenkins file.
There the helm directory.
We profile charts.
So this should create this V profile charge directory if you get inside this.
You should find a template directory.
And there are some sample templates.
I'm going to remove all this.
And here we'll put our definition files.
So let's copy.
From the Kubernetes Pro app.
Copy everything to helm Z Profile charts templates.
And we should see our definition files in the charts templates directory.
Let's get into this territory and we profile charts templates.
Let's clear the screen.
Okay.
So the image, the Docker image that you're going to build regularly and deploy will be our application.
So this we profile application deployment dot ML file.
Here we are mentioning the image and this is the image that will be building it regularly and deploying
it so there cannot be a static value.
We need to give a variable over here which will pass automatically through.
Jenkins So to give variables.
In health charts.
You have to do it like this to curly braces.
In between two curly braces, you have to say dot values and the variable name.
So I'll give the variable name as app image.
So when we run help command, we're going to pass the value of our app image.
So it will have the latest image name and the latest tag.
So let's save this file.
Actually, there are so many places where we can where you can mention the variables like the labels,
port number, the port name, container name.
And you can pass all those values while you're running Help command.
Or you can also mention those values in variables file.
There is a variables file values file.
Sorry value dot yaml.
You can mention the values in yaml format also, but we'll keep only this much.
We'll just pass one variable through jenkins automatically.
So that is done.
And now it's time to test these health charts.
And to do that to do this, I'm going to create a different namespace.
It'll create namespace test.
And I'm going to run the command helm install help Install command is going to read the charts and run
it.
We want to do it in the namespace test where we just created.
Will you?
Our charts name v profile hyphen stack.
And we'll get the part of our charts.
We profile charts and we have to pass the value I can have and set.
The variable was app image.
And we are to pass its value.
So if you have a Docker hub account already and you have our application image, you can pass the value
over there or you can do the same as I'm doing.
You can use my image also.
It's a public image.
So I have an image already.
So I'm passing the image in the repository part and the tag, which is nine for me.
So you can use my same image or better from the Containerization project you have for application image.
You should have build it so it can pass.
The same with the tag.
Let's hit enter.
You should get output something like this.
You can see helm list.
Now I have to provide the namespace hyphen hyphen.
It's copied from here, so by default it's going to check it from the default namespace.
Okay.
You should see Cube.
It'll get all.
And if I do Hyphen, I have a namespace test.
You should see everything getting created or already created.
You see our pods, our service deployment, replica sets.
So the complete stack deployment by using one simple command help install.
And creating charts is not so great, nor not such a difficult thing.
You have already seen that, but the main complexity lies in the variables, the variables that we define
in our definition file and go for language format and then mentioning its value.
And there are so many things you can do with help.
You can store this help charts into repositories.
You can fetch it from there.
Deploy it.
But this is the main zest of packaging and deploying your entire stack.
So now we will delete it.
We don't need it.
We just want to test it.
You can access the load balancer URL and you can check the entire application log in.
Should be working.
It's basically the same definition file that we have used in our previous projects.
So now I'm going to remove.
Should I say delete and delete and I will give the name v profile stack I have given and have to mention
namespace.
Okay.
So it is uninstalled.
We have to wait for some time.
It will delete everything.
We'll also create one more namespace now, which we're going to use from Jenkins.
Give the namespace as prod.
So by the time we should have these things in our repository help charts and Docker file.
And, of course, our source code.
Next, we're going to write Jenkins file.
We're going to do it on our system.
So if you have created a separate repository like me, as I did over here, then you push all the changes.
Okay, so I pushed all the changes to the GitHub repository.
Okay, It's there.
Now.
We have to do one last thing.
We have to create a Jenkins file in this repository.
And then we'll run that Jenkins file from cops.
From Jenkins.
We're going to have Jenkins pipeline as a code.
So we'll do that next.