So now we'll get started.
With Jenkins file.
As we discussed, we're going to have Pipeline as a code, so we'll write a Jenkins file.
So open your IntelliJ and let's create a new project from portion control.
So from the same repository as we have committed the code.
Again, if you have not written or you have not created the repository, you can use our secede Q branch
from our GitHub repository.
Or if you have created, then clone the source code.
Okay, So you should see your health charts over here.
We're going to create a new file.
Named as Jenkins filed J Capital.
So from the project.
Jenkins pipeline as a code we should have.
The Jenkins file will use the same and will make the changes.
So in the branch pipeline is a code.
Okay, this is in the repository view Profile project Repository.
You should have in pipeline as a code branch.
You should have Jenkins file.
So we'll take this file, we'll copy everything, and then we'll make the changes.
So we are not uploading Artifact to Nexis, so we are going to remove this stage.
Make sure you take it correctly.
Where this curly braces is closed.
Let's remove that.
I scroll up.
We should have the sort of nexus variable that we were passing, so let's remove those things.
Also, I'll just keep artifact version and I'll remove these variables.
We don't need them.
We're going to define two new variables over here.
We'll have a variable called us a registry.
And your Docker hub account name minus important visual path.
Slash the image name, which I'll just say the pro app.
I'll give it.
I'm not using this account.
I'm using this cube.
Imran So I'll give that name.
The pro app doc.
But whatever they make them you want to prefer.
But make sure the account name is right.
Next.
We have created a credential.
In Jenkins.
So we'll store that name over here.
Registry Credential.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Managed Jenkins managed credentials.
So we have created the Docker Hub credential.
So if you have to give the same name.
As a Docker hub.
I'll put that in single code.
Oh, double code.
Artifact version.
This we are not using.
So I'm going to remove this variable also.
We do need this step to clone the source code.
We are putting everything in the same source code, so we don't need that stage.
Wait a second.
It properly with proper curly braces.
So let's go down after sonar cloud analysis on our code analysis.
So here.
The next stage will create is to build the image.
So we'll see.
Stage.
Build.
Docker app image.
That's a very long name.
I'll just say build app image.
This.
I'm going to put in parentheses, of course.
Steps.
In this.
I'll give a script.
I'll give you a variable name.
I can give anything here Docker image, but I'll make sure I'll use the same in the next one.
I'm going to use a function called Docker Dot Build Registry, which will use the registry name as we
have defined over here.
So for this one, a docker file should be present in the source code and we have the Docker file over
here.
So it's going to run the Docker build command.
Plus with this, we're going to give the tag, so I'm going to say plus.
Colon.
All right, So this name will be concatenated with this colon.
And for the tag, I'm going to say build, underscore number.
Or we can say build ideas or we can just add a view over there.
So this stage should build my Docker image.
Next stage will be deploying the Docker image or uploading the Docker image to Docker Hub.
Stage.
Upload image.
So the function is a docker.
Dot width.
Registry.
This is we can pass our credential with it.
And the variable registry credential variable we created there.
So this function, we are passing the registry credentials.
And with this credential we are going to call the function Docker image.
Dot push.
So we have stored the func the object over here.
So same thing we are giving docker image.
There is no dot over there.
Docker image.
Dot push.
So the image and we are passing the bill number.
We build them.
So that particular tag of the image will be pushed.
Will also pass the latest.
So we should have a latest image.
This.
I can put it in single code if I want.
So we don't want to keep collecting the images every time we run the job.
Every time it's going to generate a new image which is going to take the disk space of our Jenkins.
We are running this on the Jenkins, so we are going to remove the Docker images also as we are building
it.
So that stage will remove the Docker image.
You have to see here we.
So Docker RMI dollar registry, which is the variable over there, our image part.
Dollar v dollar bill number.
So it's going to remove the image which got generated latest.
Next stage will be deploying it to the Kubernetes cluster, and we are going to run the command from
cops.
So we have to add the cops, easy to instance, as a slave to Jenkins.
So we'll do that first before we added this.
So let's go to Jenkins.
We'll get into our cops issue, for instance.
So if you are logged out of cops, log in again.
We'll create a directory here in the home directory itself.
Jenkins hyphen slave.
We need to install JDK.
So I'm going to install open JDK hyphen eight hyphen JDK.
So I already have it installed.
If you don't have, you'll get the installation.
We need a JDK so we can add Jenkins or we can add the scopes VMM as a slave to Jenkins master.
So we need JDK or Java and you Java version for that minimum eight.
And if we need a directory.
So instead of creating the directory in here, we'll create it in the directory that should be better
and are.
And then we also need to give ownership of open to user.
We are going to use open to user from Jenkins to access the slave.
So we have need to give the ownership of Jenkins sorry ubuntu user to this directory.
So Jenkins master will keep its agent and workspace in this directory.
And we're going to use search from Jenkins to log in to this copy city instance with a one to user.
So one user should own this directory.
And we should already have Java.
Now let's go to Jenkins.
All right, before we add the slave, we need to update the cops security group.
Jenkins is going to do a search to this cop's instance.
So we are going to add the rule 22 from a Jenkins security group.
Okay, so this should allow Jenkins to do such.
Update that security group of the cops.
Now we can add it as a slave.
Let's go to Manager Jenkins.
Manage nodes and clouds.
Let's add a new node.
Will give me as cops.
So because in my Jenkins files also I'll say agent scopes so I can give your cops small.
That's fine.
But label I'm going to give.
Nice cops in caps.
The remote route directory.
That's the victory.
Use this note as much as possible know we will only select it and use it.
From our job will select this particular node.
Launch agent method via search.
So private IP of the cops issue, for instance.
Let's copy the private IP.
Credentials.
We're going to add the login user and the login key.
So I'll say such username with private key.
Username is open to.
And the cops insurance login key private key Will.
We'll store it over here.
So let's log out from cops at.
See your cops login key.
Just do a get to it and copy all the content.
And pasted over there.
Mm.
US cops login.
Let's see.
Ad.
A safe.
Okay, let me check the configuration once again.
Credential we did not select.
We want to cost a host.
Q Verification strategy.
We're going to say non verifying verification strategy.
So it does not ask any question for search.
And let's see if.
Let's see if we launch Agent.
So it says agent is connected, which is good.
She's a very good sign.
Okay.
And the label is cops.
All caps.
So we're going to run help command from here.
And we already have tested the helm command from our corp cc2 instance.
We have already done that.
It works.
So in our Jenkins file, we'll mention that.
So we're going to mention the stage.
Kubernetes deploy.
And this job will be running from the agent.
We have to give the label.
Cops.
And the steps that we're going to run.
Is the helm command.
So it will be a shell command.
So.
Helm upgrade.
Hyphen hyphen install.
So does not exist will create it.
If it only exists, it's going to upgrade it with all the changes force.
Let's give the name of our stack.
We profile hyphen stack.
And the chart pot.
Helm slash So chart is in helm slash V profile hyphen charts.
We profile.
Charts.
Charts and we have to pass the image hyphen and set AAP image.
The variable value we have to mention and this is there in our templates.
All right, app image.
This variable value we have to pass.
Which is.
Registry.
Colon.
Dollar.
Curly braces.
We build.
Underscore number.
No, I don't have to give me here or here.
It's here.
Yeah.
Okay, One more lasting in this command.
We have to give the namespace.
Hyphen hyphen.
Namespace.
So we created the namespace named as Broad and we want our charts to be deployed in the prod namespace
that's verify this command once again, help upgrade install for V profile stack.
That's the name of our chart.
Part of our charts.
We profile charts.
Set App Image Equal to dollar Registry.
Colon v.
Dollar bill number.
Namespace fraud.
This seems good to me.
I'm going to save this and commit it.
Jenkins file.
I just say commit.
And I'll push it.
Changes have been uploaded.
Okay, So in our source code, we also have no Jenkins file.
One last thing in the Jenkins file.
We have the tooling of the sonar cube as my sonar scanner for.
So I'm going to go to Jenkins and add the tool with the same name.
Global tool configuration.
Sooner.
Scanner.
So either I can change the name here itself.
Well, we can add a new tool also.
So let's do it.
Okay.
I think we are all set for the Jenkins file.
In the source code.
It's going to clone the source code.
Build the Artifact unit test integration, test check style and uploading result running the sonar scanner
and uploading result to sonar hyphen pro, which you already did.
Check the quality gates and then build our image.
Upload our image to Docker Hub.
Remove the unused image and deploy amplification to cover this cluster by using helm.