All of this looks good.
Let's test it on Jenkins.
Let's create a new job in Jenkins.
Mm.
Cube secede.
Pipeline.
Scroll down.
We're going to copy clone the source code from Git.
So I prepared a new repository and I'm going to give that.
If you have not done it.
Then use the Vpro file project repository.
And the Branch Cube CD Cube.
You can use that.
Since I created everything from the scratch.
So I'm going to use that Branch is master.
Okay, so I don't need to change any branch.
Jenkins file?
Yes.
Save.
Okay, time to test it.
Let's build now.
So that is going to take some time.
So I'm going to pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
There seemed to be a failure at the sonar cube level.
Let's find out.
What is it?
So the job is failing.
Cannot be reached sooner, Cube server cannot be reached.
That should be the IP address of Owner Cube.
Let's check it.
One 7231 731.
And that seems right for me.
Probably it's then the security group.
Let's check the security group.
I think I have the wrong rule.
So all traffic allowed from Jenkins Security group.
That's the Jenkins security group.
To save.
Okay, let's run it once again.
So there seems to be one more failure, but it's actually not a failure.
The pipeline has aborted.
Let's check the output.
So analysis was successful.
It should have uploaded everything to other cube server.
So we have all the output over here.
We can also create quality gates for this.
You already have one previous quality gate.
If you want to create a new one, you can create that.
And let's attach the quality gates.
To a project.
Quality gates.
But the problem was not this.
We need to set up the web hook.
If you see here.
Checking status of sojourner Cup tasks.
So Jenkins is waiting for a sonar cube to respond back with the quality gate status.
But but sorry, Sonar Cube has no idea about where is Jenkins.
So we have to set up a web hook for that.
We need to do this in pipeline as a code.
Previously, if you remember, if in normal freestyle project where we give the quality gates and in
the Jenkins itself, we mention where to check the quality gates in Jenkins.
Configure system.
So we have quality gates ownership.
So we mention the detail over here.
But in pipeline as a code, we are not using this.
We're expecting Sonner Q to know Jenkins.
And for that purpose, we need to create a web hook for this.
So get into your Sonner Q Project.
Project Settings.
Web Hooks.
It says no web hook defined will create a web hook to give a name.
Jenkins Web hook.
So we have to give the URL at HTTP colon slash slash the private IP of Jenkins will use.
Colon 88 slash, we have to say sooner Cube hyphen, verb hook.
This is fine.
Let's create it.
And we shall tested once again.
Cube sued.
That's really the job.
All right.
This time it seems it completed successfully.
Let's check the logs.
So in the queue, which is quality gate is okay.
Docker build process starts if you see it has taken the right name.
Version V three.
That's the build ID.
And that it builds the image successfully.
And then the Docker login to Docker hub account log in succeeded.
And pushing the image to Docker Hub.
So in Docker Hub, we have the images or image with two different tag latest and V three.
Docker.
RMI removes the unused image once it is uploaded to Docker Hub.
We don't need it on Jenkins, so we are removing it.
And then finally the helm upgrade install command.
If you see the app image name is correct.
It's time to log into our cops two instance and verify that as well.
Helm list.
Hyphen.
Namespace.
Prod.
And we see charts are deployed.
We should see our parts also keep Ctrl get parts.
Of course in namespace prod.
So that's our part.
Let's check the image.
Keep still.
Describe.
Bond.
Skew the board name.
Now again, the namespace.
And we should see the image with v3q It'll get a.
C.
Why forever namespace fraud.
That's the load balancer URL.
Let's check it.
And our application is up already.
Let's try log in.
I'd be honored to score VP.
Password admin.
Underscore VP.
Scared in.
And the DB is verified there.
So the entire application stack is deployed successfully by using help from Jenkins and fetching the
latest image for our application.
Now whenever a developer makes a code change.
You can configure a build trigger.
Paul Lithium or you can do it for every minute also.
Receive this.
Then every time there is a comet.
On the repository on this branch.
This pipeline will get triggered.
The latest image will be built and stored on Docker Hub.
And that same latest image will be deployed to our Kubernetes cluster by using Hel.
So let's reiterate, the architectural design developer makes a code change.
It goes to GitHub.
In GitHub, we have source code, Docker file helm charts.
Everything will be fetched by Jenkins.
Unit test integration test sonar code analysis will be conducted.
Result will be uploaded to sonar cube server.
The quality gates will be checked.
Based on the status pass or fail.
If it's passed, then a docker image can be built and then we can push this Docker image to Docker Hub,
which can be then later downloaded over the Kubernetes cluster.
We are doing it through Helme.
We're using Helm to deploy the charts to the Kubernetes cluster.
If you're done with this, then try a few more build.
See how the latest image is deployed by helm to the Kubernetes cluster automatically from Jenkins.
And once you are done experimenting with all this, you can then delete your cluster.
So I'm on cops issue, for instance, and I'm going to delete this cluster.
Now cops delete cluster.
Once this is done, I will shut down my cops etc. instance, I'll keep it so I can launch as many as
time birds cluster as I want.
And it also shut down my jenkins.
So cube server.
If you want, you can dominate.
But I recommend you take It's a backup.
As I have explained in the secede project, how to take backup of your CD stack, taking the backup
and storing it on S3 bucket.
You can do that.
So you can then later reuse it through cloud formation.
You can launch the entire stack and do more and more experiments.
So I hope you have enjoyed and learned a lot in this project.
Whenever you are in a microservice architecture application design, then you will get such problems
of continuous deployment and you can solve them by using continuous delivery of your Docker images to
the Kubernetes cluster.
Thank you very much for watching this video.
I will see you in the next one.