Forming a eastlack with cloud formation, that's what we're going to do in this project.
Welcome.
In this project, we're going to set up a stack of some services by using cloud formation.
OK, in this project, we're going to set up a CCD stack or a restore or CCD Jack Honorables on Eatables
Easy to insurgences.
We're going to set up our Jenkins' Nexxus, Sonoko Windows Server application server and database server.
And yes, you can use this project for yourself, actually.
This project is for you to help you do all your R&D pipeline.
But that does not mean there is no real world use case for this.
We do similar things in real time, maybe instead of Jenkins' next.
So we have a stack of some other services.
So you want to bring back your Stacho services to life from a backup that you have taken somewhere you
can use a similar approach.
Now let's understand why we are doing this project.
OK, we know for you or in a project, if you have to continuously maintain servers, easy instances
or any server with storage, there is a cost to it.
If it's continuously running, there'll be long term charges.
So we might think of taking a backup through RMI, taken Amayo, for instance, and storage dump it.
But then there's storage costs.
One, two are fine, but if you are like 10, 15, then the storage cost is more OK.
So then we can delete it and then we can manually setup everything again.
But that's time consuming.
Now imagine you have to set up the entire ACSU stack, Nexxus Jenkins on a cube again and again and
again, as you've been doing in the projects, which is fine for project using step by step.
You can do it right.
But new technologies are changing the new new plug ins in Jenkins, a new new ways of doing city pipeline.
And you need to do all those R&D.
So doing a set up every time, if you don't want to dig back up, it will be time consuming.
Plus, there is huge chances of making human error and it's also difficult to remember what we did in
this such in such situations we can use.
Cloud formation enables us to confirmation is in automation tool or an automation service provided by
AWB, if you have gone through confirmation introductory videos, if you already know confirmation,
you know, once you have your templates ready, it will be so easy to launch your stack.
Plus, if it's automated, then there is no chance of making human errors.
In cloud formation, we like template so we can maintain the state of the infrastructure and cloud formation
and you can compare your template with the existing state of your infrastructure and make the differential
changes just like terraform.
And if everything are in template, text file, you can do version control, you have infrastructure
as a code, then it's repeatable.
You can do it as many as time for different different environments, reuseable for different different
environments and different different scopes.
OK, so we are going to use cloud formation, as I already discussed, and automate our established
cloud services.
So confirmation acts like a configuration management tool for eatables account.
Let's just reiterate once again, what are we going to do in this project?
We are going to set up a select stack for our profile project, will have Jenkins', will have a nexus,
will have a Sonoko observer, plus some other services like Tomcat, MySQL, Memcache Robotham in the
backend services.
And we're going to fetch our data from the S3 bucket to restore the data that we have taken back up
in continuous delivery and project.
I've made a video in every project.
You can check how to take backup of your KRYSTEXXA.
You already need that backup in the next three buckets stored.
We are going to use that backup to restore our industry stack.
All right, then, let's make it happen.
OK, let's understand the flow of execution.
I hope you have gone through the introductory videos of cloud formation or you already have some experience
with permission.
So we're going to check your data on the three bucket we have taken back up in CD project of Jenkins'
next to Sonakshi, taken the data back tarballs on a three bucket.
So we're going to check that.
We're going to go down the bucket.
Namenda files file names in that S3 bucket.
We're going to create one more extra bucket to upload our templates that we're going to write.
So we're just going to create in this step, we'll just create the bucket and we'll create a folder
named Stack Hyphen template inside that initially keep the same folder name.
Then later, if you want, you can change.
Then you have to change the templates also.
We didn't know down the bucket in the folder names, so we are two things to note down now.
We have an extra bucket where we have the data backup, so we have to narrow down its name and file
names and another history bucket where we are going to upload our templates, the cloud formation template.
So we are going to go down that bucket name and the folder name inside that.
OK, we already have data now we can get started, we can create a key keeper that will be used to log
into instances that will get launched.
We are going to write a root template named Create Dot Wireman, you can choose to write a different
name also.
So this will be exoskeleton.
What we are going to do, this will be the main template.
That is that that is going to call the child templates.
So the child templates going to then write the child templates for CCD three roll document, a template
that is going to create an S3 three role which will be attached to two instances.
Then we're going to write another child template, Jenkins Dot Wireman, which will set up jinking service
on Ecija instance, download backup from the S3 Buchard, and for that we need the extra role.
But in this place, which is going to write, we are not going to execute.
We can run a test though, where the idea is to run everything from the root template as nested stack.
We're going to do a nested stack.
Then you begin to write a Nexus Dot Yamal template and it's going to set up Nexus, download the up
and restore it sooner, setting up Sooner Cube server and then restoring from the backup Windows Test
Server.
This is just provision and execute some powerful command.
Application server, which is going to set up to get service and download it to configurations from
the S3 bucket.
Database server just providing the service with some initial data, that's all.
Once we have it, we're going to update all this child name on the part in the three bucket into the
root template, once all our templates are ready template and all the child templates then begin to
upload.
All our child emptied the bucket that he created.
In the folder stack hyphen template.
And if you don't hear the final step is to create the Néstor tag by using our template secret template
document.
All right, then, let's get started.