Any time in the project, if you wish to see the resources that we're using, you can use it as confirmation
documentation.
That's one thing.
And also all the templates that you're going to write in this project are already available in our repository.
So either you can clone it in your local machine if you don't have already clone or you can just check
it from the browser.
Also, cloud formation is the branch in the repository.
Kudi project.
So that's our main route to complete.
So all the code of the root template.
And also our child emplace.
For example, let's take example of C.A.T. history rule so you can see already the template is available
over here.
This is for your reference.
We're going to do all this step by step.
We're going to create each and every file, link all of them together through route template.
And then we're going to create the stack.
OK, as already discussed, you should have already a backup on your S3 bucket of our S.A.T. data.
OK, so I have a bucket named CD Hyphen, detA, Hyphen V profile, and in this bucket I have Jenkins'
backup Nexxus Backup, PostgreSQL Sooner Cube and Tomcat user SML.
Also context are similar to configuration file and for archives.
I'm going to keep this tab open because I will need the bucket name and I will also need this file name
that I'm going to put in my templates.
OK, I'm going to create one more bucket.
I will leave it as a profile hyphen.
S.I Sudi.
IFN templates.
I'm creating in the same region, Ohio region, willing to store our child templates into this bucket
or create this bucket.
Gave me that bucket and we have to create a folder with a specific name, stack hyphen template.
If you wish to create it with a different name, no down its name, so we're going to update this in
our automation template.
This is it, I'm going to upload my child template and address three Buchard that I have my back up
stored.
If you don't have this backup backup still don't worry, you can still follow along in the project.
Only thing is that you won't be able to restore the data, that's all.
But the project execution will go on fine anyways.
OK, now we're going to create a keeper.
Let me go to the Secret to Service.
Let's create a keeper.
We have to remember its name or any of us will get a job.
We can select the keeper and give them a CIA CD hyphen, STAC hyphen key.
Create Kiefer.
OK, now let's start writing our templates, so let me open in.
There is a cloud formation plugin in intelligence.
I already have it installed, if you want, you can install that.
Logging section, check for eatables cloud formation template and have it installed.
Out, you can just Google it, obvious cloud formation plugin.
Intelligence, you can install it like that.
Also.
Once you have it installed, restart your ID.