OK, so let's create a new project here.
Just just a project.
Empty project.
Namely, does cloud formation.
I think project.
This window.
OK, first, we're going to write a master template, the template.
OK, if you have a little plug in installed, you should see your established cloud formation, Yamal
complete.
We're going to name the standard a CD.
Template DOT.
Choose any other name if you wish to.
No problem.
OK, we don't need this, so we're going to take two parameters.
One is skipper.
We just keep your description.
We'll see.
See, I see the stack.
Key type.
OK, he said to keep working him so it will already list our existing keeper in the region that we are
creating one more, we are going to take his IP myopia limit.
This is what the security group that we are going to create for instances.
So our security group will already have 22 already from IP.
So we don't need to add the manually.
You can if you want, you can give a default value if you don't want to move that line and you can enter
it when, you know, when recruiting, creating the stack.
So to parameter it will accept and then let's define the resources.
So this is the route template, master template.
This template is going to call the child template.
You can refer to the documentation available as confirmation documentation, working with nested stacks,
so you understand how it really works.
You have a master template and you can call the other child templates.
This will do mostly for reusability so the child can use individually or you can group all of them together.
And, you know, Master Orroroo template can call the child tax.
We call them as nested stack.
I was using the word child's tag just for the understanding so you can use the nested stack or the child's
stack in any other rootstock, or you can use them individually also.
There's also example of how to do it, you have templates.
Anyways, I'm going to take you through all those things, so let's go back to it.
So I'm going to see resources for some and it's not highlighting my cloud formation syntax.
You can write invited.
So we have to give the name of your child Templer child stack or the nastiest tax.
So first I'm going to say a street rule for C.A.T. that's going to be our foster template.
And we have to see type.
Eatables, confirmation stack and the properties.
Part of your child, completely UNTAC.
So that's done through a city budget, we already have an extra budget where we're going to upload our
template.
So I'm going to first give the dummy UOL, then we'll update it.
The mural is in not the complete Ural.
So should he be as close as three Amazon able dot com slash and the bucket name that we created for
our templates?
Let's your that.
So in this we are going to upload our template.
So copy that name.
Slash and the template name, the template that we're going to create, we have not yet created, so
we're going to name this later.
So this is going to be my first stack.
The next stack I would like to launch is Jenkins' instance.
Jenkins' instance.
A similar thing.
But you see, it depends on option over here, so I'm creating a dependency I'm seeing first create
this deck and then only create this deck.
So if cloud formation is trying to create this target, will it is a depends on so it will go to that
stack and will create that stack forced.
Can also hear the directly named STAC hyphen template.
We are going to put.
Our template in this directory industry, Buchard.
Stack contemplate.
OK, the template name, how we are going to get that in the end once you're done getting all the child
templates.
Also with this, I'm going to pass the two parameters that I am taking over here, keep air and my IP
to this template, so I'm going to see parameters within and I'm going to use a different name to pass
it.
Key name, use the similar properties that I'm using.
Otherwise, you'll have a problem later of referring it.
So I'm going to see a ref key here.
So Parameter Keenan will be passed when the stack is creating and its value will be keeping whatever
we select over here while creating this tag, its value will be assigned to this parameter when we pass
to the stack.
So when you are launching Jenkins' instance through the stack.
Through the template, we need to keep your name and we also need an IP.
To put in a security group ruled my IP, I'm going to refer to my.
Exactly same name after you hear what I'm doing, taking over here, so its value will be assigned over
here and you pass to this particular stack.
Jenkins, for instance.
OK, now, similarly, I give information of all the child STAC.
OK, AB 01 QE.
And this depends on Jenkins' instance, so if cloud formation is trying to launch this stack at, then
it will see depends on Jenkins' instance, it will go and try to launch this.
That also depends on estriol also kind of creating a dependency, a spiral dependency.
This will get created, then this will get created and then this will get created.
So it's going to be in all of that we are defining.
Template, you all, we are going to give the template name later, again, we are passing two properties
name and the IP address, same with the Nexus server.
Depends on Jenkins' instance.
Template Eurail Pass passing two parameters keep and IP address Zauner server same.
Database server, same databases are back and actually not just database, but Rabbit Memcache will
be also set up over here.
And also Windows Server, if you want to run the software testing, if you wish to not create any of
the child's tag, just comment them, OK?
Just use hash and comment them.
You don't need to remove them.
Just put it over there.
Just comment them like you don't want a database of doing one application and you don't want Windows
Server.
You can comment if you just want continuous integration setup and Jenkins' Nexus and so Nasso just comment
all the others.
So it's not like a child.
Jack, I'm saving it for now, but I'm going to come back and update this.