OK, next template is our.
First template in our CDs is Astraea rule for Cecilio giving the right template for this.
And it was confirmation Yamal downplayed.
Amy, the CIA sued three rule dot, yeah.
And I don't need this if you have never created a resource stream and you never created a rule, I am
role, then you can check from the documentation how to create it for Mission User Guide.
Let's go to template reference resources and property.
I am also so let's find the IMS service, I am I there I am.
And I am role, let's click on that.
OK, let's make it smaller.
We're going to use Jason.
Now, Jason, Yemen, so that these are the properties can directly go to the example and see how it
is done.
OK, so there are two things done when we create I am through cloud formation template, we have to
create the role and we have to create the profile instance profile.
When you do it through console, this gets you just create the role and we create the instant profile
you don't need to create separately.
So resources, the name, the logical odor, you can give it Iblis, I am rural properties, you have
assume rule policy document the vision statement effect, allow principle service that is going to use
this rule.
That's where our main attention is.
So this role we're going to create is going to be for EU action estis assume roles that can assume that
role.
OK, Path is Route Policy's name of a policy.
Policy document, vision, no statement effect, allow action, what action you can define the actions,
read, write, list, all the other actions.
Resources for which resource?
This is for easy to solve is so easy to do so we can take action on which resource S3.
Dinamo would what are you are actually going to use Stryder, OK, so then instanced profile, including
instanced profiler's illogicality path route disinformation rules.
The role that you created up here would rule that illogicality.
OK, so this creates the instant profile also, if you want to know more about all these options, everything
is mentioned in the documentation, you can read about them a role in what you have to give police's
permission, boundaries you can set forth.
What are the path that we are setting.
OK, I'm going to take this example and I'm going to make changes toward.
Kopi.
OK, first, the logical idea will change as a VP, like we profile as three role, that should be fine.
I'm going to as I assign you don't do so.
This is fine.
There's no ruling given over here I'm going to give the ruling name.
That's the option name.
OK, so that's the only way I'm going to give OK, now to showing everything that you see, it's showing
the documentation also.
That's pretty nice.
OK, so you don't need to go to chlorpromazine.
Also, every time I saw the confirmation documentation, you don't need to go, OK, that is going to
create the policy.
I'm going to give policies and different name.
The profile is three full access.
Resource allocation, the resource which I'm going I'm going to give Iran a W.S. Colen history, so
you have to give it in air.
Informatica.
Star, that is important.
OK, for instance, profi, we can change this illogicality, we can change this name also OK, with
Phoebe instanced profile, Raffo refer to Zietz only showing that as red does not exist because that's
the name we have given to our.
Resource.
Yes, OK.
Also, you can give name your instant profile, instant profile name, that's the option.
And the name.
OK, see this?
And ladies, again, in our motion control, so you can any time go and check.
Combatted.
That's yeah, that's already open to.
So, you know, go to the cloud formation branch, check CCD, all dot Yamal, compare it with your
template.
OK, one more thing we have to do over here is we have to.
Export the information of this role so it can be imported in the next Templer, Jenkins is going to
assume this role and we to attach this role to the Jenkins' instance.
So we have to export the data from here so we can import, so not like we're exporting the detail about
this role so it can be imported in other template like Jenkins'.
For that, we use Output's.
Outputs.
And we can give some name, like I'm saying, BP free all details.
Description, if you want, why it's not highlighting syntax.
OK, value.
The capital there.
So we have to actually refer to the profile name, exclamation.
It just this.
OK, so this is the output, so this will print the output, but we want to export it.
So here to give an option export.
And you have to give me name, so I'm going to give the name of this template, see this as three.
Rule, which is important to give the rule in the name of the template, codicils the name, or either
you can use the variable dollar calibrates, you can establish track name, we can use that also.
And then hyphen some name.
So so this will be actually the name of the variable that we can import it later in the next template.
OK, so this template is ready, this should create an three roll, I'm sorry, and I am roll with S3
full access and should export the details of it.
So next it can imported.