OK, so let's create the next template.
For Jenkins instance, I'll give first parameters, the parameters that are supplied to this template.
First parameter.
So give some name, description, type, string, default value so you can set C.A.T. estriol.
So this should be the name of the template that is sending the output.
OK, C.A.T., estradiol.
So the value it exports can be the story into this parameter.
OK.
Secret template.
OK, this, but this template is sending two parameters Kinnamon my IP, so we have to accept those
two parameters also.
My IP type string.
Same name has is given over here.
Kini, nyp kini.
Third parameter.
Incidence type type string default value due to micro.
If you wish, you can change it while you're launching the instance.
So four parameters, really.
One is coming from our output.
In case you roll the other two next to coming from your master template or template key name in my IP.
And this is just a parameter whose value you can change it while you're launching this attack based
on which region this is launch, we're going to launch an easy distance from this.
So we have to set the EMI values based on the region.
We're going to do mapping.
Mappings, some name, give your region name, EMI and the EMI ID.
So this is open to 18 Amedee, so check your region, find the amenities, they should be safe, but
if it changes or if you're not able if you're getting an error, not able to find this Amedee while
you're launching this attack, then find the Amedee from the region that you use and make these entries
over there.
OK, so I may be launching it into this region just one or two or US one or U.S. West one.
So I've just given the list of the region that I generally use.
Make a list like that and find DMORT.
OK, now we'll give the resource to launch Odyssey instance, so resources.
Let's take it one level down.
And Amy, does Jenkins' in in Jenkins' instance.
OK, Colin.
Type.
Less colon, colon to.
Capital, the colon colon instance, and then properties.
Instance type, so revoted instance time, we're taking the parameter NEITZEL By default to two micro.
OK, next, probably the key name, again, referring to key name over here that comes from your master
template.
OK, so user input that will be sent to the stimulate child template and then it will be assigned all
here in this property.
OK, next image.
OK, so finding a map and then let's give.
So finding my in my region map, that's name.
It was a region that we have the value of the region where we are launching it.
So if you're doing it on us E two, then we'll get this right, because we said in that region, Emek
is the key.
So it's going to find that EMI and then the value will be taken and will be assigned to imagery sometimes.
And value is going to be joining with Jenkins' in this particular region.
So that is going to give us the region naem security groups.
I have not yet created the security group resource, but will Laforet it will create a security group
resource with this logical Odey Casal.
We already have the name.
OK, I am instance.
Profile.
If this is the one that we have already exported from C.A.T. history role and we are going to you imported,
so I'm going to say function.
Import.
Value.
Colin.
And I'm going to use function sub, which is going to substitute now dubh sub.
Donna.
So there again, this is going to have the exported value.
And inside that, we have.
That very.
So that we have the idea of your instanced profile.
So.
Import valediction to import disvalue and store it into this.
So this instance profile can be attached to the U.S. Dunstan's.
Which will give a street full access so this instance can download data from the EU budget, which will
need now in the user data.
We're going to write the script and have the script to set up Jenkins' instance.
OK, so that is the user data function, base64, base64, Wal-Mart substitute is a script, so things
that we already did install JDK install me one good unzip, install A.W. Seelie and then.
Steps to install Jenkins, wait for 10 seconds, stop Jenkins, now Jenkins is installed, going to
stop Jenkins, wait for 10 seconds and then I'm going to download.
Data from the S3 Buckett in Vasiliev.
OK, so you have to give the bucket name over here on which you have taken the backup.
OK, that bucket name.
And which are already given and the archive file.
Jenkins underscores 60 jobs, dialogue and.
OK, so it's going to copy that file from the EU budget and put it in Vasiliev directly, then we do
see to validate it, to then be extracted, we change the ownership of the directive jenkins' jenkins'
user and then reboot.
Not mandatory, but safe to do reboot, not really mandatory, but nevertheless I do it so, you know,
everything gets loaded perfectly fine.
OK, now it's time to clear the Jenkins' Security Group.
You have to make sure in this particular incident, yeah.
OK, I'll see Jenkins.
ASG.
I have not recruited the Jenkins security group, but the logical idea I will give, same as I have
mentioned over here, Jenkins is chief.
So I don't have any issues.
Two simple rules.
For the security group.
In Greece, 22 allowed from maybe OK, now this might be your offering is coming over here, maybe then
it is.
Supplied from here.
From your master template, which is going to be coming as a user input or the default value will be
passed.
OK, then I'm just giving from anywhere you can again change it to.
Jeff Miyabe.
My IP.
OK, that should be fine.
OK, we're going to output some value for printing and we're going to output the value of the jinking
security group to next instances, the next other instances that we are going to create is going to
allow port all traffic from jinking security group.
So when this dinking security group gets created, it will have an idea that we have to export for the
next template, plus a few more values to print.
OK, output.
We're just printing things.
Maintenance, public IP address value.
Gedda attribute jenkins' instance dot, public IP.
So jenkins' instance, dot public IP is going to return the public IP.
To getting the attribute there is just footprinting, also the private IP, OK, instance ID.
This just just for fun, OK?
All these three things, if you don't want to print it, fine, because anyways, once we launch the
instances, we can get that eyepiece by going to issue two instances.
But this is important.
We want the jinking security group to be exported for the next templated, so give us some name jinking
security group, some description value will be function, get attribute jenkins' security group gruppioni.
The two values are part of this function jenkins' as they are.
And the group.
So it's going to down a group idea and this is then exported to with this name Jinkx hyphen Asgharzadeh,
which then can be used in other templates that we are going to create.
Now, again, if you wish to refer for this template.
So go to the repository.
OK, you can read all the details from here.