Let's create the next template now after this, you can create it in any order, I'll go for next.
This next nexxus don't Yamal.
Parameters seem as what we are doing it in Jenkins' plus one extra parameter, so I just copy everything
from here.
Plus, one more parameter, which will be the jinking security group, OK, so Jenkins Astatke name,
that's the name I'm giving for the property type string defoliating.
This is the name of the template.
OK, that's why I was telling you, use similar name as I'm using.
Or if you're using a different name for your template, then make sure you're giving right name.
Viniar.
Importing the values back then, other three same properties.
OK, next is mappings of EMI so that also we can copy from here again.
OK, next is resourced to launch, for instance, this will be similar to the JENKINS'.
Resources that are illogicality, sutta instance, instant's deep kini am I don't need this.
Some dags.
Security groups referring to a security group that is not yet created, but we are going to created
instant profile and import value.
So it can dash that role user data script that will be different, of course, but similar process you're
going to set up next to us through a script and then you're going to download the backup from a bucket
and then extracted.
OK, so installing this is this will be for the center.
I have to actually remove this map and this is not going to be for.
Want to do this, I have to do mapping the image of the Center seven instance, I can take that from
the repository.
Schirach.
Nexxus.
These are the areas of the Centerstone instance, it's easy for me to copy if you want your for you
also you can copy it from the repository, but if you want, you can find the right amedee for yourself
and change the values there.
OK, let's go through this.
So installing JDK, installing A.W. Seelie.
Creating, directing AppNexus, creating a temporary or directly nexus in temp.
Download Nexxus from this URL.
And get it to take your name and remove the Tarbell sync temporariness, it directly will be extracted
to slash Nexxus.
And the user nexxus give the permission to this directory, so seems to have what we did in the CD project.
OK, then set up a system defined so you can manage Nexus with systems.
You come on.
Make sure you make a configuration change so you can run Nexxus Services, Nexxus user and start and
enable Nexus service by here, you should have the Nexus service up and running.
Next step is to download our data from the S3 bucket.
It allows us to keep.
But downloader of director.
So Kudayev, when you die, when we profile, that's my bucket name.
Yeah, and the archaic name Nexxus Hyphen, Kudi hyphen, vibro hyphen ProductID Desert.
What your name, whatever name you have taken, you give the right name here now directly go to obdurately
stop Nixa service, extract the Nexus Bako.
Make sure you tune the permission and then you start there and enable the next service finally rebooted,
that should set up the next service with the data, OK?
Next is the Nexus security group that we are creating.
So I'm giving the logical Odey, which I have used already here.
Their security group, NextG.
Yeah, these things should match otherwise this Cusato solitudes 22 from IP data from IP 088, one from
IP nine.
But one more thing, right?
The JENKINS' is going to upload the artifact to Nexus.
So Jenkins' also needs to connect to Nexxus on Port Aditi one.
So this will create the security group, but then we need to update it with one more rule.
So I'm going to give a new logical idea here and see a nexus.
She interests going to use a new resource over here.
That one security group in Greece, which will inject new rules to an existing security group, properties
group, so for which security groups are trying to do this, so the U2 security group ID.
So for the security group, the same security group that the security nexuses astrological.
Odey So I have it in the same.
Template.
So I can use git attribute function.
So I'm going to function, get attribute Nexxus as a group, so that one.
And when I say group three, I get the group idea or hear something, security group ingress rule for
this particular group.
Next, a security group.
What is the rule?
Rule is IP Protocol TCP from 81 to 80, 81 allowed from a security group, from jinking security group.
So I have to say here.
Source.
So security group and why is this endangered their.
OK, this is fine sauce security group.
And now to give the Jenkins security group I.D., but we're exporting that.
Right, and Jenkins, their export named Genk hyphenates Jodi.
OK, so that is the name of the template, OK, hyphen is that should give Yemeni security group that
variable and we are taking it, accepting it.
We're here.
The name injunct so I can really see.
After imported the value a function import value.
And then substitute with Dawla Jenkins TICC name, so the variable I'm using over here, this is going
to return the Jenkins stack name.
Which actually I am storing it over here in the properties, OK?
Jenkins Techmeme and its value will be Jinkx, which is the name of the template.
OK, so that is like Genk hyphen is Jidi, which is going to give me the security group that is getting
exploded over here.
So the biggest problem, really, in Néstor Stack is exporting and importing value, once you get hold
of this one, exporting, importing, then Mr. Stack is really amazing thing, OK?
The only trouble that we face is exporting and importing values.
So surpassing values between two downplayed.
Remember, three steps of this.
You export something.
Then you take as a parameter input for that and then you use them.
OK, so it's three steps, multiple functions are involved over here, import value, export, import,
sub.
But once you get hold of this one, then you will always do next attack because it's very good for reusability.
And I can use this template individually or I can use it with the stack, also with the Néstor stack.