OK, so the other template should be just similar.
Next, we're going to set up, so let's see if this.
Civil liberties sonar.
Darte Yamal.
OK, this is as similar as the Jenkintown played via accepting.
The rolling Jenkins stack name we have parameter for IP name that also is coming from the master route
template, instant type mapping and mapping.
Resources logical.
In that instance, we are launching an instance, Sudheer Properties.
His name, image I.D., some tag security groups honor S.G., which is mentioned down there instanced
profile, same import value roll template name, there's a variable.
So in its value will be this.
OK, and that is coming from our master template.
Now, sorry, from this generation.
Across the street, all this value will be assigned over here and that is passed down.
Warrior Rolton proclaims its value will be Cadastral Hyphen Vestris?
S profile name.
That one CD30 downplayed.
OK, same thing what we did in Nexxus and Jenkins, OK, user data.
OK, see the entire sonor set up as we did in Sikri Pipeline.
OK, till the engineers set up the differences, we copy the.
Backup is three bucket name.
Your archive name downloaded to opt, this is sooner back up.
Extracted.
Give the permission, then the PostgreSQL sonar cube is when you bring up it's going to create a lot
of schemas in the polls.
Gursky also taken its backup, also extracted to Vasilyev.
Downloaded to Ghaleb, extracted, changed the permission start PostgreSQL and starts Owner-Occupied
and rebooted Sonor Cube.
This is necessary, OK, there's some issue so just keep that reboot once everything is done.
It bounced the reboot the entire instant's and your data will be back up.
OK, so no security group 22 allowed from my iPad, allowed from IP.
And also, we are adding a rule to allow a different Jenkins.
Jenkins is going to upload the report to Sonakshi observers of U.S. security group in Greece.
Sooner's, Ezgi.
OK, not once on the Regi group idea offered.
Social Security group.
The Jenkins' security group like.
And so when he says IP protocol minus one, that means all the protocol, all the protocol.
So like all traffic allowed from Jenkins like that, OK, we are updating also Jenkins' security group.
Yes.
In Sonar Templated updating jenkins' security group, because this traffic is going to be both Sonor
and Jenkins' so soon.
That allows all traffic from jinking security groups.
S.V. We are saying security group Ingress Gruppo, the import value jinking security group.
OK, all traffic.
So Security Group will be soon our security group.
You can see this is just the opposite of what we are doing over here.
Here we are allowing all traffic from jinking security group to Sonor.
Here we are allowing all traffic from Social Security group to jenkins'.
OK, and this is of templated updating the Jenkins' security group here, and we can do that because
we are exporting the Jenkins' security group Idee.
We can import it, use it security group, use the resource and update the rules, it care.
So that is sooner, let's see it.
Check it.
Very far from it, Sonador, Yamal from the repository.
If everything is good.