OK, next, I will talk about the Windows Server.
OK, when guest dark yammered.
And this is also as similar as the setup of Jenkins, Nexis and sonar, except this is Windows Server.
So, Amy, it's of course, what will be of the Windows Server accepting this parameter for the rule
name Jenkins template name Libicki, name an instance due to small and bigger incidents like Sonorant
Nexus mapping of Microsoft Windows Server.
OK, resource windows test, logical and easy to instant's again, instant type keaney imagery.
Remove that.
Tag security group, wind test, S.G., which will go down there.
It's just profile, again, importing the value of the role profile name, user base64, sub power shall
not shelter power shell.
So installing May one, the spelling mistake there.
Google Chrome get.
And creating a jenkins' directly.
So some powerful commands there.
What's going on is just going to set chocolate and then we're going to use chocolate to install Judy.
Give me one Google Chrome and get the Windows Test Security Group.
So one rule three three eight nine and out from my IP, and then we're updating it, security group,
security group, Ingress Windows Distinguished Operating Group.
All protocol, Social Security group jinking.
So we're allowing all traffic from jinking security group.
Then again, I'm updating jinking security group here also like we did in sonar back the other way.
Right, this allows all traffic from Jenkins and this resource is going to update jinking security group
and allow all traffic from Windows Security Group.
Yet here again, you can use get tribute, right, because it's creating and getting written the same
template so I can see when Industries G.
If you start logical idea of the security group group, so get the security group idea of windows and
that will be upgraded in the security rules.