OK, let's see that.
OK, next hour, Tomcat application server.
So named this the zero one QE darte YAML.
So, again, similar story.
Taking parameters.
Ahmed mapping.
Went to him, OK?
We want to embrace launching the instance.
With the right role, so for this Tomcat server that gets created, will also download data actually
to configuration file that you already have interestedly Buckett.
Contact Tzadik, Semillon Tomcat uses Dodig Semmel, if you followed through the backup video, then
you would have taken backup of these two files as well.
OK, so the user data to install JDK download timecards set up Tomcat Hartill here we are setting up
Tomcat and then it is to download the Tomcat user's XML file.
At this location, us, our local Tomcat at Constant Caduceus SML, so this file will be overwritten
with the file that we are deploying.
Also, context, Artec, Semmel.
We shall be or return at this location.
OK, change ownership, Tom, get down here to use our local downgraded.
Create a system, define.
Start any animal down, get service, so as seen provisioning of a Doncasters that we did in products.
OK, then, security group, that's the logical as G 22 allowed from my iPad, allowed from anywhere,
because we're going to run software testing exit from the Internet.
So I'm single out from anywhere.
OK, then upgrade the security group rule.
It put 88 allowed from Jenkins.
Jenkins is going to upload the artifact to Tomcat, so we're going to see AT&T allowed from the Jenkins
security group.
And then we're going to output value over here, application security globally, the Dompierre security
group.
Now, this will be used in that database template again, that we are going right next and the last
one.
So the proposed group, we're going to export it with this name, the Peru app 01 Culiacan is the template
name hyphenated.
OK, see this?