OK, final template.
Is B zero one.
QE darte Yamal.
You're going to need to write it again, just copied from the repository.
Same thing launching any instance damaged provisioning the instance with the user data.
This is sent seven.
OK, so install database and we are not downloading anything from the EU budget.
Over here is normal.
Mystikal, Memcache and Rabu provisioning for We Profile Project.
OK, so three sources will be running over here and it's running on two to Micronesians and that is
fine as long as it does not crack.
OK, but if it cracks, then, you know, try changing the instant time that we should be better.
OK, security group Rule 22 allowed from my IP and changing, updating the security group rule.
Saying all protocol of the Rudbeck, the security group for databased.
All protocol allowed from application security guru.
So here parameters, we are taking abstract name value zero hyphen Kuai.
Wheat exporting it here.
And then we're accepting our here in this parameter and then the way we're using it over here.
Again, I tell you, it's going to be three levels, right, export except as a parameter and then import
the value.
So this hyphen is is going to return the acidy from here.
And that should create your database instance.