OK, this is it, I'm going to do one thing, I'm going to create a director here named this stack hyphen
template, which is similar to same folder name as we created in the three Buchard.
But it's not it does not have any impact here.
Just for the sake of understanding.
I'm just going to move all child and plate.
To stand there actually make you can't move this or move.
OK, let's try one by one.
No.
It's not walking from here.
I just do it from the show.
I'm going to move all of them to Stack downplayed.
And then I'm going to bring back the CIA CD.
Template here.
And just for understanding, it's not going to make any change.
In fact.
OK, we have one last thing to do in the templates.
So in a route template, we have to give all the child in place name.
So Azriel for Kulina templated CDs, three older women aren't seeing Sudie as three year old daughter
Hawaii.
OK, like that update, all the templates with the right, you all begin to upload it to the S3 bucket
if you have not yet done it.
But let's give the name first and then we'll upload.
OK, we understood why I'm to be cured or why Animal Sonador, why animal next to I email I'm the one
kuai I am a Jenkins doctor, I am a three year old daughter.
I am an updated update your IP as well, whatever your current diabetes.
So you don't need to try it again.
And you as you can override that later.
OK, now time to upload our child template to a three bucket.
OK, so go to the bucket that you created for your template, get into the directly stack hyphen template.
Kaseem name.
Stack hyphen template.
OK, so it should be same named as in the all upload.
Our final OK, go to your territory where you have the template stack template, copy all of them.
And they applaud.
Session has expired, Gary Log-in.
And upload.
OK, all of them are uploaded.
OK, so compared again, your bucket name slash template, so the stack template directly anda template
name with the URL if there is any mistake corrected.
OK, market names, the directly slash the template name seemed completely.
As you applauded in the bucket, once you're confirmed, everything is good.
Then let's go to the cloud formation service.
OK, and will create Jack.
Upload template.
OK, so your route template, OK, Scotty template, not Winemiller template, which is in turn is going
to call all your child templates, all your nested stack template, which are already uploaded in the
bucket.
OK, so this template is going to call.
All these templates, which is already mentioned in the template template, you can check in the designer
who were in designer.
And see if there is any syntax error, anything you can fix that get, you see the lines that actually
depends on.
I validate.
See if there is any syntax that a template is valid, but it's going to only validate the root template.
Create Stack.
Let's go next.
You can to name just the profile hyphen S.I Sude hyphen STAC.
OK, parameters, you already created a key restack you and select that, change your IP if it's different,
that is the value coming from the template.
I'm good with that.
Let's go next.
And next.
OK, when you're creating a nested stack, you will get this, I acknowledge that Eatables confirmation
might create a resource because recruiting I'm a resource and this option you will get might require
the following capability, capability to expand.
Just put a checkmark there and to create stack.
This is going to take some time, so I'm going to pause my skin and come back when this is completed.