OK, so after some time, the stack complete stack creation completed and we have remained stagnant,
has created the nested stack you see there, you can check the nested stack output as.
And drinking Jenkins instance is Sonic Observer.
Nexus server.
All right, and all the other sports services.
Let's check the output's.
Now, output here.
We're not printing anything in this main template S3.
Yeah, so Disvalue we're exporting says the key name, and this is the export name.
Jenkins, so we are exporting food, things like Jenkins' instance, ID, IP address, not exporting
Saidy, printing ID, private IP, public IP, the one that we are exporting.
Mr. Jenkins security.
Krupali.
That's the value.
OK, so on that observer, you're not exporting anything here next to server, not exporting anything.
Application server, the Tomcat that we are exporting at this name.
That's Disvalue.
Which is used in our DB STAC.
Windows to serve are not exporting anything, server, nothing, OK?
Let's see all our services, let's go to you to.
But I have to read this.
OK, let's check running instances for instances we have.
OK, so we should have Nexxus server database server, jenkins' application servers or not server.
Let's check the next jenkins' again.
Let's log into Jenkins'.
Coolen, 88 Lydiard.
I should directly just login pages, so it is back with the data.
How do you see the jobs?
And all the plug ins, everything, water, we have taken the backup in city project that is restored
back.
You can check all the other services like that.
You can log into Nexus, Sonor Cube, all these instances and you can check the data.
But does a record stack has the data and all data.
So things like IP address of Nexus Server, for example.
It will be in all right, so you have to update those things.
That's an old IP when we took the backup to the new IP will be different.
And that is the one I told you should make those changes.
Sievert.
Also in a big job, big project.
The downloading artifact, if you're downloading artifacts from the Nexus, then you know, you should
have you have to update those IP addresses in the properties Nexxus IP address.
Talking about Sonakshi observers, Sustainer, KUB details you mention in the Conficker beach.
Configure system.
And so that's an old private type of Nexxus server.
You should update that Dukan will be old, so you have to generally should generate a new token.
There should be same token because Sonor CubeSat will also be restored, but it could have expired.
So it's better you log into Soknacki Observer, generate a new token.
All right, let's see, so in the Q.
OK, so it took time to set up the Sonoko to provision the Internet on YouTube, and there was also
a reboot.
So once your stack is ready, wait for like 10 minutes or 15 minutes, let your entire stack become
stable, let everything get provision.
It will automatically come up.
OK, so the Sonakshi Observer.
Log-in.
So you should see your project, we all all the data that you have stored previously generate the new
Tolkan.
All right, copy it and then restore it back.
All right, add a new credentialled story or talk on the new on IP address also for the quality gates.
Also, you should have the token there.
Also change the IP address to the new IP address, make all the changes and then you should be good
to go.
You can just run your pipeline and tested later.
But we are not getting into that into this project.
We already covered that in secret projects.
So this project should be of a great help to you, really where you want.
You have your templates ready when you want it and just launch the entire stack, do all your R&D learning
and you plug it in.
Jenkins, you're trying something new, new integration with Jenkins' integrating gink into something
new, some new other new tools so you don't need to keep this instance is always light when you want.
It can bring up make changes your back up online.
And they should also give you idea how Mr. Stack really work.
When you're working on a project, there'll be so many things you can ride solo, single, single templates.
Yeah.
For different project where you need you can combine them through.
Good template.
OK, once you're done testing everything, then you can just delete your stack.
OK, so you delete the root template and that is going to delete all the other templates.
Also, one more thing.
If you're making any changes to the child template with the nested templates, then make sure you upload
it back to the EU Buchard.
OK, any change you make to your templates, Shalgam plates.
All right, any time you make change, you upload it back to the history bucket because your routine
is going to read it from here.
So it should be updated here.
Once you're done testing all this, just delete your template that is going to delete all the child
templates as well.
Child stacks.
Also, one more last thing.
If you don't want to create all the resources, you just maybe you want Jenkins' next year or we want
just Jenkins' next year sooner.
You don't want other services just coming them.
OK, put hash over there to all this, which you don't want to spend this entire resource commented
and then launch it.
So, you know, those, that particular instance will not be launched and you wish you can check our
repository.
And access this templates and use them.
OK, then that should be all in this project.
Thank you very much for watching.
I hope you have learned a lot.
So keep practicing.
I will see you in the next one.