Presenting DevOps projects.
If you are a DevOps engineer and struggling to streamline your tools and services, unable to keep up
with new DevOps tools,
don't worry, I have 18 plus DevOps projects for your practice.
Hi, my name is Imran.
I have got 11 plus years of experience in DevOps and cloud computing.
I am a creative person with lots of ideas in DevOps which I implement in projects.
I am a Red Hat certified architect with cloud and DevOps skills certified in Ansible, OpenStack cluster
office, OpenShift, Kubernetes and Puppet.
You need a boost.
I am certified in systems DevOps, professional and also a security specialist.
I am also certified in DevOps foundations.
A VMware Professional, a Red Hat certified engineer, and also certified in Python from IDEX.
I can show you how to work from a sketch or scratch to a concept in DevOps.
And these are some of my expertise.
Okay, let's get down to business now.
Let's dig into the list of dev ops projects.
3 to 1.
Now, let's go.
Automate your project deployment locally by using vibrant virtual box and bash scripting.
This is a foundation project services used in this projects are engine X, Tomcat rabbit, MQ mem cache
and my skill.
Learn how to lift and shift your web application project to a cloud.
Services used easy to auto scaling, load balancers, cloud watch allowance and Route 53.
Learn how to refactor your web application on a cloud by using services like radius, Elastic Cache,
Amazon, NQ Cloud, Front, FS plus all the services used in the previous project.
Continuous integration of Java project by using Jenkins Git Maven Nexus Sonar Cube Check style and Slack
channel.
Continuous integration on a cloud by using a services like code commit code Build code artifact sonar
cloud and sense and three buckets.
Continuous delivery of java projects by using Jenkins Git Maven, Nexus, Sony Cube, Selenium Tomcat,
my SQL mem cache and rabbit MQ continuous delivery on a cloud by using services like code commit code
Build code Artifact Solid Cloud code Deploy code pipeline bean stack ideas and few other services.
Configuration Management and automation of all your sources in your project by using Ansible.
Set up eight of Lewis Cloud Stack using Ansible.
Continuous delivery project using Ansible in the mix of Jenkins pipeline.
Continuous delivery project by combining Jenkins pipeline with services like Beanstalk and ideas.
Learn how to containerized entire project stack by using Docker Docker builds Docker Hub and Docker
compose.
Learn how to set up Kubernetes cluster for production container runtime by using cups and cube.
Set up entire web application Java stack on Kubernetes cluster.
64 containers by combining Jenkins pipeline with Docker Docker Hub and Kubernetes.
Learn about eight of this security concepts and their implementation on your project and pipeline.
Vote.
Permission to set up your entire project stack on a cloud.
TerraForm.
You set up your entire project stack on a cloud.
Gain confidence, experience and lots of hands on experience with these projects.