Continuous integration is an automated process in DevOps.
Which generates software and its features quickly and efficiently.
Hi, my name is Imran.
Watch this video at the end to have a solid understanding on this process, in theory and in practice,
both.
Developers write several lines of code while creating a software
working in a team.
It's an ideal practice to store all this code at a centralized place.
This centralized repository is called a version control system like GitHub.
Everyday developers will pull and push code such repositories several times in a day.
So code changes or code commit happens continuously.
This code will be moved to build server on build server.
This code will be build, tested and evaluated, which generates the software, or we call it artifact
at this stage.
This artifact or software will be stored in a software repository.
Artifact or software is really an archive of files generated from the build process based on the programming
language.
This artifact will be packaged in a specific format.
Artifact packaging format could be war or jar in Java. DLL/EXE/MSI in Windows or even ZIP/Tar ball
From repository
It will be shipped to servers for further testing.
After deploying this artifact on the servers, software testers can conduct further testing, and once
they approve, it can be shipped to production servers.
So that's how it works or does it?
Let's dig in and find out.
These developers are creating a software model and have worked for three weeks straight.
That's a lot of code, really.
Oh sure, you can take some break.
Your job's done for now.
And as per the process, all this code will be fetched by the Build server, and this code is build tested.
and oh boy, lots of errors, bugs, conflicts, build failures.
Now Developers have to fix all these defects, have to rewrite the code at several places.
Lot of rework, really.
This could have been much easier if the problem was detected very early in the process, but then code
was collected with defects for three weeks.
And now, yeah, you have to fix all that.
So the code is getting merged into the repository, but not really getting integrated.
The solution to this is a very simple and a continuous process after every single commit from the developers,
the code should be built and tested, so no waiting and collecting all these codes with bugs, but then
developer commits several times in a day, so it's not humanly possible to do a build & release several
times in a day.
I mean, the manual process so that's simple, just automated.
So when the developer commits any code and automated process, will fetch the code, build it tested
and send a notification if there is any failure.
As soon as the developers receives a failed notification, he or she will fix the code and commit it
again.
So again, build and test new changes, if it's good, then it can be versioned and stored in a software
repository.
And it's all automated.  Like this.
Any defects can be caught as soon as it's merged with the code.
Let's see it in a cyclic view.
This automated process is called continuous integration, or CI in short.
The goal of CI  is to detect defects at a very early stage, so it does not multiply.
IDE is used by developers for coding.
These IDE will be integrated with version control system to store and version the good.
Build tools based on the programming language.
Software repositories to store artifacts.
Continuous integration tools that integrate everything.