Welcome to the project.
This project is about containerization.
We're going to see in this project how we can containerized an existing application.
But first, I will talk about when you should really start content raising or when you should use any
container technology.
What are the real use cases for that?
And I'll also inspire you based on the statistics that we have in the current market.
So let's understand the scenario first.
So let's say you have a multi tier application stack or you have many, many services in an application
stack that you manage as an operations team or as DevOps team.
And these services are running on Veeam.
It could be VMs of the VMware environment or it could be cloud environment like EC two instances on
a cloud, or it could be your running on physical machines in your own data center.
Point is you're running it on operating systems.
And as today's trend agile, we need to do continuous deployment for any changes.
Are not any changes, many changes and the continuous changes in today's time.
And we continuously do the we continually continuously need to do the deployments.
Let's see problems with this scenario.
Forces.
We have to spend a lot of money.
We have to either procure the resource or even if you're doing it on cloud platform, there's regular
operational expenditure, your regular bills you have.
And it's not just about spending.
Are we really using all those resources or not?
If you are running, let's say, an application service or a web service and it is having ten GB of
RAM, is it really using ten GB of RAM RAM like overall or if you take an average of of an entire year,
you will find out how much resource wastage is there and that resource resource wastage is very expensive.
So we are spending a lot to set up our multi tier application stack.
Also, when we are doing deployments, there are always chances of making human errors.
Automation can save that a lot.
But then again, you would be having different kinds of environment dev staging production and they
will be having different different versions, different.
They would not be in sync.
And the time is today of microservice architecture.
If you want to use microservice architecture and implement on OS directly running on the virtual machine,
then you will end up spending a lot of money because in microservice you have multiple substack in a
stack.
And the point is, we are not using all that resources.
Mostly there'll be resource wastages.
Also our environments are not in sync and that because of that reason, application is not portable.
If it works on deaf, there are chances it will fail on queue environment.
If it works on queue with there are chances it may fail on production environment.
Containers are really the solution that we are looking for.
If you can containerized an application, then you can save a lot of money because containers uses very
less resource.
Because there are no operating systems in that.
And if you're using low resources, then it's very much suitable for a microservice architecture.
So we don't have to spend a lot of money.
In containers.
Deployments are done via images.
So if you package your images properly with all the dependencies, all the binaries, all the libraries
necessary, then if it works on your laptop, it's going to work on a queue environment.
The same thing is going to be working on production environment because we have same container image
across all our environments.
And that should also make our stack reusable.
We can use the same stack across multiple environments.
It's repeatable.
We can very quickly imitate our stack from production to queue queue to production.
So there remains benefit that we get.
If you're container using our application, let's see some statistics.
Static statistics over here are to inspire you.
Really?
There are 50% of the organization have already made half of their application containers or the containerized
half of their application.
You can see.
And 50% today is a huge number.
And 29% out of them are running it, running containers for production.
The production sites, the production applications are powered by containers.
If you are a heavy cloud user, then you should know 78% of those people are using a platform to run
their containers.
If you are DevOps, then it's automatically assumed by 81% of the organization that you would be containerized
in the application or managing the containers.
So being DevOps, it directly affects us.
So let's see the tools that we're going to use in this project to customize our application.
So we are going to use a Docker as our container runtime environment to build images and we're going
to contemporize our V profile application stack.
In our very first projects where we have seen how to set up this stack on virtual machines, then we
have also seen how we can run it on a cloud by using lift and shift and RE architecture, the same V
profile application stack.
We have multiple services, Engine X, Tomcat, MySQL, mem, cache, rabbit and queue.
So this is the existing application.
We are going to containerized this application and run on Docker containers.
When I say Docker is a tool, we are not going to just use the Docker engine.
There will be Docker Compose and Docker Hub as well to host our images.
Let's see the steps that we are going to take.
So you should be aware about the steps to set up our V profile stack.
And for that, you can go and check again.
And our first project where we are setting up a V profile application manually on virtual machines.
Once we know that, then we'll find the right base.
Images from Docker Hub for all the services that we're using.
Engine X, Tomcat, MySQL mem Cache Rabbit MQ.
Once we find the right base image, then we're going to write a docker file.
For the services that we need.
Customization, like, for example, Tomcat, we're going to deploy our artifact inside that.
So that needs customization.
Engine X, we need some our own configuration changes or my we need to have our own data, our own table,
our own schema.
So we'll figure out which service we need customization and we're going to write Docker file for it.
And with that, we're going to build the image.
Then once we have the image ready, we're going to use Docker to test all our containers.
So we have a multi container environment, we have engine x, Tomcat, mem cache rabbit MQ, my SQL.
So we're going to write a Docker compose file which will launch all these containers together from the
image that we have built.
Once we have that, we're going to test it.
If it checks, if everything checks out, fine, then we are going to host our images on Docker Hub.
So we'll push our images on Docker Hub.
Okay, then let's get started.
Let's do containerization using Docker.
But before that, let's see the architectural design.
So first we're going to fetch in our source code from our git repository.
And we're going to do the entire Docker workflow.
First, we're going to write Docker file.
For the services that needs customization.
So we have Engine X, Tomcat and MySQL, so we have to write three Docker files.
Once we have written Docker file in our source code, then we are going to use a Docker build command
which will get executed on a Docker engine in a Docker file.
We should have mentioned the base image.
This base images will be pulled from Docker Hub.
So Tomcat, Engine X and MySQL, these are three images that we are going to pull and customize them.
So Docker will Command is going to read the Docker file.
Build our image.
Once our images are ready, we're going to use a Docker compose.
We'll mention all the containers with the images and then we're going to test it.
Once it checks out, fine, then we're going to push our Docker images, the customised Docker images,
to Docker Hub in our own account.
So that's the entire Docker workflow that we are going to do.
To do this, you should have basic understanding of what is a container, what is Docker, how it works,
and you should have some hands on experience with Docker, like how to run a Docker container.
And very, very basic things of Dockers.
So if you're done here, join me in the exercise.