So I'm on GitHub on our Repository V profile hyphen project.
I'm on branch local hyphen setup.
In this branch there is a vagrant directory.
And we have manual provisioning.
And these are a pdf to set up our services.
As I discussed previously, you should have already set up this project locally on your machine, manually
or automatically, and you should know what are the steps that are involved in setting up a V profile
project.
Because this is the project which we are going to contain arise.
So if you have not done it, I recommend you do that project first.
We profile set up locally.
So in this project.
We have six services, but we used five services Engine X Rabbit, MQ, Tomcat, MEM Cache and MySQL.
Is my skill set up document.
So if we have to contain a race or mix equal set up, then we should know what our steps that we have
taken.
If you just need a MySQL service running with username, database and password, then you can directly
fetch an image from Docker Hub.
So it is good to go to our hub Explore.
Search for image.
My school.
So we have my skull image over there.
It's an official image.
Official image, and it's quite popular.
And this is Linux based x86 64 bit as in our project.
Also, we're running my SQL service on a Linux machine.
And we need MySQL 5.6.
Or any five major vision and major vision five and minor vision can be anything.
So.
Support the tax and respect your Dr. Phil links.
So we have five or six so we can go with that tag.
We can see or hear.
What are the steps to run this container from the image Docker run in name given name hyphen E.
We set a variable which is going to set a MySQL root password hyphen D for background and the image
name colon the tag.
We should be very well-versed with the image that you're going to use in our project.
We should know everything about that image.
Like, what are the variables that we need to set, for example?
And other things like port numbers, home directories, all those things you should be aware about.
How we can put it in Docker compose is also.
Document of that.
You want to check the log, you can see Docker logs and the container name configuration file if you
want, if you want to change the configuration of our MySQL service.
And this is the file if you want to put our own configuration file.
Then we can volume map this with our host directory with hyphen v option.
So our configuration located in this directory can be mapped with this directory inside the container.
So read this document very well so you can follow along with me.
Environment Variable.
My SQL root password.
We can set my SQL database.
We can set.
So let's go to our document.
So we are setting up my SQL, my DB, my SQL Secure installation, and we are creating user called us
Admin.
Identified by ID one one, two, three.
The password is a username and password we have to set.
We can set that through variables.
We are to create a database named accounts so we can do that also.
By setting a variable.
My SQL underscore database and we can set the value accounts.
Still here.
It may not look that.
It may not seem that we need to make any customization.
But if you see, we are also.
Returning some queries from this file which create our schema.
So how can we do that?
So if we come down over here, there's initializing a fresh instance.
So as per the document, it says that when you run the container, when you bring up the container,
you put anything with an extension of dot ssh or dot SQL or dot, dot GZ.
In this part of the container.
Then the files will be executed in alphabetical order.
So, DOT SQL, we have a skill file.
And we can put it into this location when bringing up the container and those files will be initiated.
And that means we really need to make no customization.
We need to create our own image.
So my SQL, we definitely need to create our own image into customize.
Mom cash setup.
We install mimecast service, we start an enabled mimecast service and we run it on port 112, one one.
It's very simple setup.
I think we should be able to find an image on Docker hub which can do that.
We don't need customization.
Let's check.
Let's search for mem cache RD.
And there is an image managed.
So you don't need any special customisation.
We just want to run the service on port.
One, one, two, one, one.
Does it support that we run cache service image variants?
Okay.
It seems like there is not much information about the port over here.
Let's try to find one.
One, two, one, one.
There's no such information, so we can check the Docker file.
Let's check the latest Docker file.
And we should look for export support.
Exports.
One, one, two, one, one.
I think that should be good.
Then it runs mimecast service on port 112, one one.
So we don't need to make any customization.
Okay, so that's good.
Let's check out other service.
Rabbit.
MQ Rabbit MQ is quite a long set of we have seen.
That's because of the dependencies.
But if we have the directly a service from a container, we don't need to do those, all those dependencies.
So we can find an image that runs Rabbit Q service.
We need some customization.
We need a user called test with password test.
Or we can give different username password, but we need a rabbit MQ user and we need with a tag administrator.
So let's find an image of rabbit and let's see if we can do that customization or else we have to build
our image.
Okay, this rabbit on cue.
So we can run rabbit surveys like that.
Ideally, you should run these containers on some machine and check them.
Test them before we try to use them.
But we'll do along the way.
So it has support for some along cookie.
We don't need those things.
Node name.
We don't need to set up any node name management plugin.
We may need a management plugin so that option is there.
We can do that and the steps to do it with default.
Username and password.
Guessed guessed.
So default username and password is guessed guessed.
But can we override that if you need our own username and password setting Default username and password.
Yes, we can set this user this variable.
Default user and pass.
So I think this is good.
So if we don't then need to make any customization, we can just take this image, official image,
and we can use it in our project.
All right.
So, so far, only my SQL image that we need to customize.
Ma'am cache rabbit name Q Both We can use official image directly.
Tomcat.
Now, this is our main hero.
This is where our artifact lives.
And definitely there is no question that we have to customize and create our own image for this because
of product or artifact is really going to run on this.
So you won't find anyone who is giving you an image that has your application.
So you have to take a tomcat image, that is for sure.
But what all customization we need is find out about apart from artifact.
So steps are to set up Tomcat service so we can find an image for that.
So here we are.
Good.
Now it could build and deploy.
So we need to build our artifact.
We have to update this application on properties file so we can put that into our artifact itself before
even we build.
We can update application properties file with back end services, name, port number, username and
password and.
That's said.
So we need to take a Tomcat image, Tomcat container and we need to put our artifact with right back
end details in application properties file.
So that is the only customization we need.
Okay, so my SQL and Tomcat.
We need to create our own image engine setup engine.
We need to run the engine service with this configuration.
So we may need to build or we may not need to build.
There are two ways to do it.
While we run a container, we can put our configuration in that while running it like as a volume.
Or we can build an image with this configuration file.
So this configuration is always there in our image.
So whatever suits your need, you can go with that.
So we will build image also for engineers.