Okay, so since we made our decisions on what images to build.
Once we build our images, we'll be hosting it on Docker Hub.
So if you don't have Docker Hub account still, then sign up, create an account on Docker Hub and log
in once you log in.
Get into organisations.
We're going to create an organization so we can collaboratively work together.
In our team.
So I will go with the free team.
Okay.
But, you know, this really is a good option.
But it's, you know, we just want to practice on a project so free one should be fine.
So organization namespace.
So we'll say we profile.
Company name.
I'm going to give visual path.
And I will say create organization.
So what are the benefits of organization, really?
Well, one thing for sure is we can collaborate.
We can have for for the free account.
We can have three members.
If you want more members to collaborate, we need to pay, but that should be fine for now.
We can have repositories named as the organization's name and not the account name.
You can also create teams, different teams over here.
Settings.
If you go linked accounts, you can link your GitHub or Bitbucket Bitbucket account with this.
Docker also provides you continuous integration.
As soon as there is a commit, it can fetch your docker file and build the image for you.
So you don't need to set up your own continuous integration pipeline which will be convenient.
You can set default privacy.
So by default we have public.
But we can go private.
But then we need multiple private repositories and we don't have because we are on a free account.
We have notification as well.
We can send notification of build failures on email or on Slack, and that should be convenient.
So this is good.
I have created an organization.
You also create an organization with whatever name you prefer.