Okay, I'm in my system.
I have opened gate bash and I'm going to launch a virtual machine with Vagrant.
We're going to build, run and test our Docker images and containers in this virtual machine.
If you wish to run it on easy to instance on us or if you have any other platform that you're using,
you can go with that.
We just need an open to operating system where we can run our Docker commands.
So I will create a directory Docker hyphen engine.
I'll get into that.
I'll see if I grant in it or one two slash bionic 64.
So that's 1 to 18 operating system.
So it created a vagrant file.
I am also going to give it an IP address so I can access from my browser also when I'm making a test.
Oh, you can also use the APIs offered.
So let's give some IP.
I'll give 33.12.
That should be fine.
Make sure that IP does not conflict with your network.
If you wish to give extra RAM size, you can do that, but this should be fine for now.
Let's see if I get it up.
KVM sop let me log into it.
First thing I'm going to do is I'm going to install docker engine on that.
Let me clear the screen.
Okay, let's go to Docker documentation.
Docs dot docker dot com.
First we have download and install.
Let's install it for we're looking for Docker for Linux.
Specifically you want to.
If you're using an existing Docker engine, you can remove the older versions of Docker engine.
So I'm going to go through the steps.
First Running App update.
Installing some dependencies.
Setting up a stable repositories from where our Docker engine can be installed.
A GPG key error.
Let's add the GPG key.
And let's run the command again.
That is done now.
Time to install Docker engine.
We don't need to run app update because our ad app Repository Command already updated the repository,
but still, let's do it for the sake of documentation.
And then let's install Docker engine.
We should have no docker installed.
Let's check the Docker version.
So I have 1903 13 version currently.
This should be fine.
I want the Ubuntu user or the current user normal user.
I have a current user to run Docker command which will not be possible by default.
Get permission denied.
So we need to add.
Vagrant user into docker group.
Pseudo user mod.
Hyphen e.
Hyphen Capital G.
Group name Docker and the user name Vagrant.
That should be done.
You can exit and log in again.
Or we can say source Bashar see file also.
Jay So vagrant user is part of Docker group and we can run now Docker commands, which is good.
So the Docker engine is definitely running.
We are able to run the Docker command.