Now we're going to fetch our source code and we'll write Docker file to build three images Engine X,
Tomcat and MySQL.
I will use intelligence to fetch the code.
I'm going to store this project in the same place where we have created the vagrant file so we can access
it from our VM also.
So let's go file.
New project from version Control.
So our source code.
Docker engine.
This is the directory where I'm going to create my repository.
I will create a new directory inside this new folder.
So if we profile hyphen project.
Okay.
Make sure it's in the same directory where you have the vagrant file.
So it'll be easy for us to build images from our docker file then.
Okay.
Let's clone it.
Okay, let's shift to the branch.
Dr..
In VP hyphen Docker Ranch.
You already have the Docker file.
If you wish, you can check those Docker files as well.
But we're going to build it from scratch.
Check out this branch.
Okay.
In Docker hyphen files in this directory, we'll write our Docker files.
Docker find reference documentation from Docker Hub.
If you don't have hands on building a Docker image, then you can check it from here.
How to build a Docker image.
You need to have a docker file.
Dr. File de Capital there.
And once you have Docker file, you're given the information about the image.
You can run the command Docker build.
Hyphen t your account name and slash the image name.
Account name will be.
The one that we have over here.
We can create a repository already in our organization.
So you go to repositories.
We need three images, so we already create a repository for it.
In our organization, we profile.
I will name first one V profile app.
This repository name will be for our Tomcat image.
And we're going to go with public repository.
To create.
Okay, So that will be the path of our repository V profile slash our repository name colon.
The tag like that, we'll build two more repository or we'll create two more repositories.
Create a repository.
And so if you profile.
Web where will host engineers?
Make sure you have selected your organization.
To create.
Let's create one more for my school.
We profile DB.
Mm hmm.
Repository.
Again create a repository.
We profile DB.
Create.
Okay.
Now, in our organization.
We profile.
We should have.
Three repositories can and will use them.
So we need three Docker files to build our image and then we are going to host it after building it.
We're going to push it to Docker Hub.
Like this.
We can build we can get that output.
And then we can push it.
So if you don't have Hansen Docker file, you can check this documentation.
The few instruction, common instruction that will be using.
From instruction in the Docker file.
The Docker file is a series of instruction from instruction.
We give the base image.
We already have figured out our base images Tomcat, MySQL and Engine X.
We just need to figure out the right tag so we can mention the base image.
This is a simple docker file from the base image.
Copy.
A file from your machine to the containers directory.
Run is going to execute this command.
This is Windows Command.
We have Linux containers, we're going to build the next images.
So obviously it'll be using Linux commands.
These are the instruction ad copy, the expose from label stop signal user volume work directory.
We'll be using some of them or most of them.
So you can see all the instruction with examples in great detail over here from seemed.
Run.
This is about run the command that you want to execute to build our image in the container.
Seemed to mention the binaries that we want to run in order to run the process in the container.
One example.
There is one example.
Label, which are like tags that we have seen in key value pairs.
Maintenance is deprecated.
So if you are already using it, stop using it.
Expose when we are running our binary.
Let's say we are running Tomcat Catalina Search run.
So it's going to run the service, run bind the process on Port 8080.
So we have to then say expose 88.
So expose is used for that.
Ian, if you want to set any environment variable, we'll try that.
We don't need any environment variable, but.
We'll just set some environment variable.
And if you want to push any file into your container.
Like in this example, any file that starts with home will be pushed into the container directory at
this location.
Add and is also copy which are similar, but ADD has more options and can also extract your zip file.
Copy which is similar to AD.
A copy and it will be very useful when you want to put your own customized data while building the image.
You want to push a configuration file into your container while you're building the image, or you want
to push your artifact that you're going to do.
We have entry point, which we still have higher priority than command.
Where we can mention a command, and with command we can pass the arguments.
We'll see that.
So for example, this.
Entry points when you run a container built with from this docker file.
As soon as you run the container, it's going to run the command top hyphen B, space hyphen C So command
water you mentioned in CMD will come as an argument over here.
Which you if you want, you can override it.
Like as in this example, Dr. Run.
The name of the image top hyphen etch.
These are some samples.
If you don't have a gain, if you don't have hands on experience on Docker file, I recommend you try
a few of them.
Like, for example, this one, which is very popular.
So this is going to fetch an image Debian install Apache two on it.
Expose it on port eight and for 43a volume will be exposed on multiple volumes.
Var dub dub dub var log Apache two slash etsi slash Apache two.
So you'll have three volumes which you can map with your host machine.
Entry point.
So as soon as you run the container, it's going to run this command.
Apache.
Ctrl hyphen, d foreground.
This is a very popular example to practice one, because this is very easy.
And also you would have already used a particular script.
So it's easy to understand this.
So you can build a Docker file with this, build a container and test it.