Okay.
Now, let's start building our images.
So we'll do it in this directory.
We'll create a subdirectory inside this.
New directory.
I will name it as app.
And in this, I'm going to write a Docker file.
The Docker file is its own format de capital.
You have to make sure that Docker file.
First instruction we are going to give is from.
And we're going to give the base image over here.
If you see intelligence has already detected that it's a docker file, you see a D over there and you
can see some options run on Docker.
So you can specify on which Docker engine you want to run this Docker file.
So if you want, you can install a plugin Docker plugin into IntelliJ, but it's not required.
We're going to build it through our VM anyways.
So bass image.
So let's go to Docker Hub and explore.
Tomcat.
So we are going to use this Tomcat image.
And there are many, many tags in it because it's also very popular.
We're going to go with it.
G.
11.
We can see all this in the tags.
So if you want to test it, you can say Docker run hyphen t hyphen forum.
And you can test this.
Catalina bass.
It's going to be us, our local Tomcat eight.
Our web apps will be inside this.
Nothing much about this.
Tags.
I'm going to use eight hyphen g 11.
This tag.
You have several other tags you can try from, but this is more suitable for our application V profile
application.
So let's write Tomcat image.
Colon eight hyphen.
Got 11.
That's from.
I would like to remove the default application.
So I'm going to run a command.
The home directory is user local tomcat and in that you should have a web apps.
I want to remove any default application or any application from that.
So when you run the build Docker build, it's going to bring up a container with this image.
Remove anything that is in the apps directory and we would like to copy our artifact, which you're
going to build.
Target slash v profile hyphen v two.
Dot that.
So we have not yet built it, but we're going to build it and we'll have it at this location and this
relative path.
We're going to copy it into us.
Are there is a mistake.
US are.
User Local Tomcat eight Web apps.
With the name root.
Dot var.
So it becomes our default application if you're going to expose it on port 88 because the process runs
on port 88 anyways.
That will be mentioned in the Tomcat image.
But I'm trying to use as many as options, as many as instructions as I can see CMD.
I will say.
Catalina dot as such.
Comma.
John.
So this binder, this script will be called, which is going to run the Tomcat process, and it's already
defined in the Tomcat image, so I don't need to build anything extra.
I would also like to set work directory.
Web apps.
I will set it this one.
So any command I run will be executed from here now, or I will just keep it at user local tomcat eight
which anyways will be there in the tomcat.
Image volume.
I will say user local Tomcat eight again.
So if I want I can.
Attach any local volume or even bind mount with this directory and I can sync this directory with my
host machine directory.
This is fine.
Let's see it.
Okay, let's build other two Docker file.