So we'll create one more directory in this.
Named DB.
And we'll write another Docker file in this.
For this will be using my skull.
My skull tag 5.6 or 5.7 we can use.
Not eight.
It doesn't work with their application.
So we can go with 5.7 or we can also go with five or six.
We have to set the usernames and passwords.
So we can do it through environment variables.
My SQL root Password.
My SQL database.
And my SQL user, if you want to set up any other user, will be using the root user and we'll set a
password for this by setting value to this variable.
And we'll also initialize it with our SQL file.
So we'll be putting our SQL file in this location so we can use add or copy command to do that.
Let's build the Docker file from.
My SQL.
I'm using the tag 5.7.25, which is.
Relevant with our V profile application.
Ian, we.
My SQL root password and I'm going to save a pro DB pass.
One more database so it can create a database named as accounts.
And we can use add or copy command to copy your SQL file in that.
So we will copy the SQL file from our source code.
So SQL file is DB underscore backup SQL.
And as per documentation, we have to push it in this location.
Okay, let's copy this SQL file in this directory.
So if you have in the source code.
Mean.
Resources.
That's the file.
So let's copy it.
And this location.
Yeah, it's there.
So when we have it in this place, when we say Doctor Bill is going to copy this SQL file into our container.
Okay, one more.