For engine X.
Directory web.
Create a docker file in this.
So we can see from engineers any version is fine.
Default is fine.
So it's going to fetch the default image.
Let's also give some label.
I will give project.
Equal to.
The profile.
Q Also, one more.
Author.
And I'll give my name.
And if you can also use this label for our other Docker files, let's put that DB or here as well.
Okay, so the engine X image that we're going to use from the Docker hub, we need to change configuration
in that.
So that's an image we can use the latest version.
Let's see.
Where does it hold the configuration?
That's engine X main configuration file.
We have some variables we can use.
Our own configuration can be pushed in this location quarter D so we can have multiple configuration
in that directory.
So we can put it in the templates directory inside that and that will send it the configuration over
here, the output or here.
So this is the default configuration file.
If you want, we can erase this or we can put it in the templates directory in the config config file,
which will automatically replace this.
We will remove this configuration file, default one, and then we'll put our own configuration file
in that.
So changes to Tron Command and I see atom hyphen RF.
And remove that configuration file, which is the default one, and copy our configuration file caps.
So we'll build our own configuration file with this name and we're going to place it.
And dislocation.
With name for pro app dot conf.
So that becomes our default application.
We'll also have to create this file, so let's copy this name and the same location.
Okay, So that should be the configuration.
It's going to listen on Port 80 and it's going to forward the request to a container named Pro App on
Port 88.
So based on this configuration, we have to understand the container that we're going to run with.
Our application has to be of this name.
We have to run the container with this name in a Docker environment.
In a Kubernetes environment, we have to run service with this name.
And also we have to be careful.
We run it on this port.
Okay, let's see if all these files and we're going to not commit them.
Before we build and test it.