In order to build and test our application container, we need the artifact now, with the right application
properties file for our V profile application.
So let's get in our VM.
That's where we are running Docker.
And we're going to go to Directory slash Vagrant, which is a single directory, and we should find
our Vpro file project directory there.
And we find the Docker files directory there that we created and all the other three directories.
So if we have Docker files in every directory plus in DB directory, we have a DB SQL file and in web
directory we also have the engine configuration file.
We have to make sure in the app directory we put our artifact path staggered slash v pro file hyphen
v two dot var.
So let's build our artifact.
V profile project.
So being the directory source code directory where we have bombed out the XML file, we need MAVEN and
for me when we need JDK, so we'll first install JDK.
Open JDK hyphen eight hyphen JDK.
Should be fine.
Okay, so let's install JDK and also we need to install MAVEN after that.
So that's going to take some time.
I'll pause my screen and come back when it's done.
Okay, so the installation completed.
Now we are going to build our artifact, but before that, we need to fill in the detail of our backend
services.
So our application container can connect to backend services.
DB Mem cache rabbit MQ.
So in RC directory in our source code main resources, we have application properties file.
Okay, so the backend service name for DB is Wipro DB.
So we have to make sure we launch the container with this name on port.
Exposed on port 3306 and it should have a database named accounts username root and password with pro
db pass.
If you check our DB Docker file.
We are setting the PDB bar and accounts database in that.
And this path is for the root user, this password, my SQL route user.
So that is taken care.
But we have to make sure when we run the container, it should be with this name.
If you're going to run the DB container with a different name, then make sure you make the changes
over here and also the port number.
Similar way mem cache container should be running with this name.
If you wish to change the name of the container, then make sure you change it.
Also the port number one.
One, two, one, one.
Rabbit MK Repro MK zero one should be the name of the container Port 15672.
User guest and the password.
Should be also guessed.
So while we're building the images, we have to take care of these things.
We're building the DB image.
So we need to take care of this user password and port numbers.
But anyways, just my SQL container is exposed on port 3306.
And anyways, we are going to map a host port with it so we can connect it from outside also.
This is for initial test.
But in Kubernetes, Kubernetes, this may change.
So this application properties file is apt for our Docker environment and we really don't need to make
any change now.
Let's build our artifact.
So in the project directory, we're going to say move an install.
This is going to take some time and I will pause my screen and come back when it is completed.
Case the bill is completed so we should have target v profile.
Hyphen v dot var.
Let's clear the screen.
There.
That's v profile v two dot var.
We have a docker file over here at this location, the same place.
We have to copy our target directory, or you can just copy the artifact, but it should be in the target
directory.
So Docker files.
App.
So the docket file is going to copy the artifact at this location.
Since the same location, we have target directory.
And we have profile hyphen v2 dot var.
If you wish to delete all those things you can delete except the artifact.
Okay.
We're all set.
A three doctor files are ready with the data.
Now we're going to build the images.
So let's do it one by one.
Let's get into the Docker Files Directory app.
Commands Docker build hyphen t and we have to give the account name, slash the image name.
We already have created the repository on Docker Hub.
Repositories.
So that's going to be the path.
We profile slash we pro app.
We can copy it from here.
And he will also give a tag.
We won the capital.
And let's say you enter.
We have to mention the Docker file part.
So I'm just going to say DART.
The Docker file is in current working directory.
Started building first.
It's going to fetch the image.
Tomcat image.
There touching the image.
So this is going to read our Docker file and execute every instruction.
And finally, the output should be we should have an image with this name.
Okay, that is completed.
Let's check Docker images.
And we have our image.
Let's build the other two image.
DB.
Again.
Docker build hyphen t.
Let's get our repository path.
DB.
Colon.
51..
Touching the Michael image that is completed.
Let's check again Docker images.
Okay.
That is also ready.
Okay, final image web.
That's the engine x image Docker build hyphen t.
Let's copy the part.
With one dot.
It's affecting the Internet's image.
Completed.
All right.
So we have three images that are customized.
We need to more image Robert McEwan cache.
We don't need any customization on that.
So we're going to simply pull them, say Docker pull Engine X without any tag.
So it's going to take the latest.
Not engine X, engine x.
We already have docker pull mem cache dx.
Yes, that image managed.
From our official Docker registry.
Let's pull it.
Dr..
Pull rabbit MQ.
The official rabbit image.
Let's pull it.
Okay, So we should be good by now.
So we have all the images that we need.
And Unix my SQL Tomcat Rabbit, MQ and MAM.
So if we have successfully containerized we can say, but we cannot guarantee that as long as we don't
test it.
And we're going to test it with Docker compose.