Will use Docker compose to run all these containers and connect them together.
And for this we need to install Docker compose.
Dr. Campos Documentation docs dot, dot, dot com slash Campos.
Dr. Campos reads a file.
Dr. Hyphen, Campos Will.
You mention the containers services.
You see over there are actually the containers.
So in this example, you have a web container and you have a red is container container named Web and
container named Red is red is container is going to be built.
It's going to be run from an image.
It's going to fetch this image and run the container.
And there are no options over here.
Just fetch the container and run it.
That's all.
But for web container there is a build dot, so there should be a Docker file present.
So it's going to build container, build an image from a Docker file and run a container with this name
ports.
It's going to expose or map port 5000 with the container port 5000.
Volumes so you can attach multiple volumes.
Hyphen dot current working directory will be mapped with slash code directory in the container and one
more volume log Volume zero.
This volume is created over here.
Volumes the name of the volume.
So it's going to create that volume and then map that volume with the container volume.
So this is a sample Docker compose file.
You have.
Once you have written a Docker compose ML file, you say Docker compose up, it will bring up all the
containers together in the same network like this.
We have to create a docker compose file.
We have to mention all our services, all our containers with the right details, right?
But first we need to install Docker compose.
So let's go to install compose.
Linux.
You're going to do it.
And our Vagrant VM, which is Linux, so let's copy that command which is going to download the Docker
compose binary.
And let's piece it.
Okay, so it kept it out.
Here, use our local docker compose.
This should not be a read only this should be not in executable mode, so we have to give it executable
permission.
For all the user.
And I have to say pseudo.
For that.
And should have the command.
Dr. Campos hyphen hyphen version.
Dr. Campos is set.
It's time to write Doggett Campos yaml file and we'll do it through intelligent.
And I'll write it here at the top level.
File Docker hyphen compose dot ml.
Okay, first diversion.
So I'm going to use version three.
3.8 is mentioned.
In this sample Docker compose file.
But we are good with the third version.
Services.
And now name of the containers.
Name of the container should be, as we have referred it, in application properties file and Engine
X configuration file.
Tomcat should be with this name.
DB Which should be.
DB There should be cash.
There should be rabbit.
MQ And of course, the port numbers also, we have to take care.
We'll also need a volume.
So.
I will see volumes.
Colon.
I'll create a volume name with pure DB data.
So a local volume which will map with our DB container var lib, my SQL directory.
So let's say the pro DB.
That's the container name.
Again, once again, the name is based on what I have given in application properties file.
Okay.
Image.
So our image.
Docker images.
DPI.
And Jack, we have given we won.
There is no latest tax, so we have to make sure we then we give the tag.
Okay.
Ports.
I need to list.
In double quotes.
I'm going to map 3306 host port with the container port 3306.
If you're not sure about the exposed port, if you have taken an existing image so you can just inspect
against it, Docker inspect and you can give.
Your image.
And you can find the exposed port.
3306 is also 33060.
But this is what we're going to use to access the MySQL service.
So like that you can run inspect on mem cache, rabbit, MQ, all the other images that we have built
and find the right exposed port and even the volumes.
So volume var lib, my SQL, this we're going to map with the volume that we created or we are going
to create through compose file.
Volumes.
And list of volumes.
So we're going to map our volume that we get created with.
Var lib my SQL.
So all the data from while lib my SQL will be downloaded over here in DB volume and we'll not lose our
data.
We also need to set an environment variable.
It's already in the image.
But if it's not, then you can do it at the runtime.
My SQL root password were pro db pass pro db pass.
So you can fake a password in the docker file and then you can put the right password when you are going
to run your container.
Okay.
That was about Debbie.
That should be fine for the DB.
Now let's do for the cash.
So cash container we're going to.
This name?
Prakash is zero.
One.
I'll give you a new line character.
So we are just taking an official image mem cache dx which we are already downloaded and we just need
to mention the ports.
No other customizations required.
11211.
Marked with one.
1211.
Okay.
Next rabbit MQ.
Port.
One five, six, seven two.
Guest.
Guest The credential.
Image.
Rabbit AMCU official image.
Ports.
1567215672.
Two.
Okay.
If you also need to set the username and password, we have not built a customized image official image.
So we can change data in the run time by giving the rabbit MQ default user and password.
Sure, Mitch.
Like setting the username and password.
So.
So you have given guest.
Anyways, this is the default user and password, but I'm showing you if you want to override, if you
make changes over here, the username and password, then you can set the default user and password.
Okay.
Then our main hero.
The pro app.
So based on the engine configuration.
The name of the container.
Image.
And that's the one.
Colon v one.
Ports.
8080 mapping with ADHD, we have also exposed a volume.
So if we'd like, you can create a volume and map it.
With the Vpro app, you can run a docker inspect.
And check the exposed volume.
That one.
But will also create a volume where pro app data.
I see volumes.
Hyphen the pro.
App data.
Okay.
And finally, the engine X.
So if you wish in this case, you can give any name like v, Pro web or V, pro engine X, whatever
you want.
Because venue is going to directly first access this container and then it's going to forward the request
to the pro app.
And the pro app is going to refer to back end containers.
So you can give any name because this is the front end image.
Colon v one.
Ports.
I'm going to map the default port at HTTP default port with the container port.
If you wish, you can have any other exposed port.
If Port eight is busy on your docker engine, then you can map any other port if you wish.
But I'll keep it default.
I don't have anything running on Port 80 on my Vagrant VM, so that is fine.
Let's save this.
Okay, let's review once again.
So we have two volumes that will get created.
The pro db container will get created with this name from this image will be exposed on port 3306 Container
port 3306 Mapping the volume setting environment variable then mem cache with this name with an official
image and only the port rabbit MQ image Official Rabbit image port 15672 and setting the user name and
password with variables.
Tomcat v Pro app.
That's the name image that we have.
Build our customized image port AT&T and also are mapping a volume with user local Tomcat web apps and
finally Engine X again with our own built image port exposed 80 mapped with container port 80.
So all of this seems to be good.
It's time to test it now.
So let's go to a docker engine.
We have installed Docker compose over there.
So we have option.
Let's see how often I can help.
We can see Dr. Campos up, but then we have so many options you can use.
Dr. Campos up and a few other options, which we'll see.
And we're going to run it in the background.
First, let's run it in the foreground, Docker hyphen compose of We have to be in the Docker compose
directory.
Which is in slash Vagrant profile project.
That we have docker compose y html.
And let's create a directory called us compose and let's put it over there.
Not mandatory, but.
Oops.
To just.
Compass.
Okay, We create a directory, compose, we move Docker compose inside that.
Just to have a good view, that's all.