Darker hyphen.
Compose up.
Let's hit enter.
Okay.
There is an error in our docket compose file.
Docker compose colon we have given which it says an invalid syntax.
And we have to actually give equal to.
As we did over here, got carried away because of the YAML syntax.
So let's see if that.
Let's try once again.
Okay, this is good.
It is creating a network name compose default.
Create a two volumes.
I created the volume.
Yes.
And then creating containers.
And all the output is coming on the screen because we're running it on the foreground.
If you want to run it in the background, we can give hyphen the option.
But let's just run it in the foreground.
Let's see all the logs.
Let's test it.
If you're good, then we'll run it also in the background.
Okay.
Tomcat is up squaring the rabbit MQ.
You'll see some rabbit MQ errors.
You can ignore them.
Okay, let's check.
So we have given IP address to our VM.
And we can check it from the compose file or compose from one file.
I'll open another gate.
Bash.
Migrant file is in F drive.
Yeah.
At this spot.
EV Drive Docker engine.
This is the file.
This is the place where I have the vagrant file.
And in the vagrant file we have mentioned the IP address, static IP.
So let's access our Docker engine.
IP address and Port 80, which is mapped to an engine x container on Port 80.
But port it is any US default we don't even need to mention it lets access.
Okay, so we get the login page and this login page is coming from Tomcat.
So Engine X is redirecting request to Tomcat app, which is good.
Let's try to log in now admin, underscore VP and same password admin underscore VPI.
And we are able to log in.
That means the Tomcat container is also able to connect to the DB container.
So all this user information is coming from the database.
Let's check Rabbit McHugh.
And that is also good.
Let's check Mama Cash.
Let's take a user.
K data is inserted in cache.
That's a success.
Let's click once again.
Data is coming from cache, so all our services are validated.
We have successfully containerized our application.