So once you've performed all your tests and you feel now your containers are right, then you can finally
push your images to Docker Hub.
So let's go to.
Oh, sure.
Okay.
I have to close this control.
See if I do control C, all the containers will be stopped.
But we'll bring it up again.
We'll run it in the background.
So we have to say Docker compose hyphen up, hyphen, hyphen d, So it's going to be running in background.
Then we will not be seeing the logs.
If you wish to see log of any container, you can just say Docker logs and you can give a container
name like compose a pro DB.
So it should show you all the logs.
So that's fine.
Now it's time to push our image to Docker Hub.
So we are going to do Docker login.
If you're using Docker Hub, you just need to say Docker login.
By default, it will go to Docker Hub.
So I'm going to give my account name.
And password.
And it says Login succeeded.
I have logged in and it's very easy to push.
I'm just going to say Docker push.
Let's push our app image first.
Colon tag we have to mention because there's no latest.
So it's pushing it on Docker Hub now.
That one image goes up on Docker Hub.
Lets push push the other image web.
And one more.
DB.
Okay.
The third image also.
Now let's go to Docker Hub.
Our repositories.
Okay, so let's see.
DB.
Okay, so there's a V1 tag.
And you can anytime, say, Docker pool.
It's a public repository, so anybody in the world can say Dr. Poole and the image name and pull it.
See the tags there.
Bills.
So if you want, you can have your Docker half file on your GitHub or Bitbucket and you can link it
with Docker Hub and it can for every comment, it will fetch your image, fetch all your Docker, have
file and build the image.
It can do that for you.