Okay, So let's reiterate what all we did.
We have fetched the source code.
On the branch, Doctor.
We create a Docker files directory.
Inside we have app directory.
We created a Docker file for app, and for that we have built our artifact.
So a docker file for our application image.
For DB image.
We have a docker file which is pushing the SQL file.
And another Docker file for Engine X, our web container, which is also copying the configuration file.
Once we had this, all these three Docker file with the data for engine X, the configuration file for
DB, the SQL file for application, the artifact.
Once we have prepared all this, we build the image and then we run all of them together with the Docker
compose file along with the images that we have built.
DB We also have a cache image, the official image, a rabbit image, which is official.
We have not made any changes there.
Also application, that's the image that we created.
So container for the pro app and the pro web.
Now, anybody in the world with this docker compose file can just say, Docker compose up and we'll
have exactly the same setup.
It's very much portable.
These are public images.
So anybody in the world, that's why I said anybody can fetch this image.
So with this Docker compose file, if you just run it on your Docker engine, you will have exactly
the same setup on your laptop and dev environment, queue, environment, production, environment,
anywhere.
Let's retrace the steps that we did.
You should know the steps to set up your stack on VMs locally or remotely anywhere.
You should know the steps to set up each and every service in your entire stack.
Once you know that you can find your right base image from Docker Hub can write Docker file to customize
your image.
You can use Docker compose file to run multi containers and test it.
Once you are done, you can host the image to Docker Hub.
And that's exactly what we did.
We cloned our source code.
We did a darker file with the right data.
We set Docker bill, which fetched the bass image from Docker Hub.
We use Docker compose to test it.
When we find it is good.
Then we pushed it back to Docker Hub.
So that was it.
In this project, I hope you have learned a lot and gain some rich experience in container using your
application.
Thank you very much for watching.
I'll see you in the next one.