So the same source code, url.
Branch.
local-setup
And we have a vagrant dir.
In this, we have automated provisioning dir.
In this dir, we have a vagrantfile.
Which we'll see in a moment in detail, application properties file that will be used by our application
to connect backend services and some bunch of Shell scripts.
If you have not yet cloned the source code, I recommend you clone the source code, git clone and the
URL.
So since I already have it cloned and it's in my f drive, I'm going to get into this directory, let
me expand it.
So, again, vagrant dir, inside that we have automated provisioning and there we have a vagrant
file, application.properties file and bunch of shell scripts.
This will look much better from sublime text editor.
So let's open sublime text editor.
Let's access our source code from here.
So first, we will be seeing.
Our Vagrantfile
So it's almost similar background file, as we had in the previous project, the difference in this
vagrant file is we have shell scripts executing for every vm and the order is also different.
We are setting up db machine db01 and this will execute a Shell script, my sql, which we already
have here.
So this script will get executed, the script is going to set up my sql Service, initialize the database,
take care of the firewall rule as well.
And then next, we will be setting up memcache service, so memcache again, it's Centos7, it's
going to execute the script memcache.sh. This is also a very simple script.
It's going to install memcache service and make sure it's up and running.
Next, we have a rabbit MQ service, so it's going to bring up our rmq01, C Centos7 and execute
rabbitmq.sh shell script on that.
Let's see, this script.
Again, same commands as we executed in the previous project.
With  little tweaks, of course, so it can run automatically.
Next service is app01
Again, Centos7, and will execute the script tomcat.sh
So this could look a little longer because it's going to also it's not only just going to install Tomcat,
but also going to set up our application, build and deploy.
So first it installs the dependencies JDK.
tomcat and it's going to set up.
tomcat service with systemctl
It's going to create the service file.
And once the Tomcat gets service is up and running.
Cloning the source code.
And building the source code, removing the default application of tomcat, copying our artifact, start
the tomcat service, wait for a few seconds.
And will copy application.properties file.
So as every vagrant vm, will have a sync dir /vagrant, so whatever data you see, where the vagrantfile
file is located will be synched automatically with /vagrant dir, so our application.properties
file will be existing there.
So we have to make sure before this comes up, we edit we edit this application.properties file
with right details. So before we even provision the stack, we have to make sure we update application
DOT properties file.
So backend database information is given db01, username and password, memcache and Memcache port number.
Rabbit MQ hostname, it's port number.
username and password.
So all the information in this application properties file is based on the script that we are executing,
like in my sql, we are setting up the user admin and password admin.
admin123
Right there.
So our application properties file also have the user admin and admin123 is the password.
So if you make any change to these Shell scripts, make sure you make the changes to the application
properties file as well.
Because our Tomcat Shell script is going to copy application properties file.
To tomcat ROOT directly and then finally restart tomcat service.
OK, last vm from a vagrant.
Its going to be Nginx.
web01, Ubuntu operating system, script, it will execute is Nginx.sh., let's see the
script.
So that's pretty simple, apt update, install Nginx and create the vproapp file.
With these settings, so this is the backend server name app 01 and Port 8080 and then move this vproapp file
to this directory, remove the default application, create a link and finally start and enable Nginx
service.
So everything is interrelated together through this vagrant file.
So let's get into action now and we we're going to take very little action.
Maximum action will be taken by Vagrant.