So open your git bash, get into
the source code, vagrant dir, automated provisioning.
And the action is only this much, we are going to say  vagrant up.
And it will start bringing bringing up all the machines, let's check virtual box.
So first, it's bringing up the db machine, I'm going to pause my screen and resume when the provisioning
scripts start getting executed.
So db01 vm is up and running, but our vagrant is waiting for it to become stable, once it becomes
stable, it will start running the Shell script.
OK, there we go, provisioning scripts, started getting executed.
So it's running mysql.sh script and this process is going to take a very long time, db
provisioning is completed successfully.
Memcache provisioning has started now.
Memcache provisioning is completed.
And now the rabbitmq setup has started.
So you see, we are not logging really into the VMS and setting up the services, vagrant is doing
that for us.
This entire setup will take somewhere from 15 minutes to half an hour based on your Internet speed.
I'm just fast forwarding the video so you don't waste time in watching all this output. RMQ provisioning
started.
And it will also take a very, very long time because it's going to run yum update, install Erlang
socat
Which has lots of dependencies, here also provisioning time is really based on your Internet speed.
I will fast forward the video till app01
app01  provisioning started.
OK, now the build process has started in app01.
app01 provisioning completed successfully, web01 has started.
And web01 also completed successfully, and now it's time to validate out stack.
So we will access web01  from our browser, we can use the IP address.
In Vagrantfile, from vagrantfile and you can even log in from Vagrant File, you can get the IP address, that's
a static IP or we can even use the hostname.
So let's open the browser.
And we'll just say http://web01, that should forward request to tomcat
Let's log in, admin_vp
Same password.
And we are in, so db is validated, let's click on Rabbit MQ RMQ is Validated.
And memcache select a user.
Data is inserted in cache
And cache is also validated.
So in this video, you have seen how we have provisioned the entire stack, with just one command
just did vagrant up and all the heavy lifting is done by vagrant.
Now, if you wish, you can keep the stack and bring down all the VMS, vagrant halt.
stack is down.
All the VMs are powered off.
You can check vagrant status also.
So we have the stack, but it's powered off, if you want, you can bring it up anytime you want.
You can just save Vagrant up from the same dir.
So since vagrant will do provisioning only once when the VMS are created, if the VMS already exist
and you say vagrant up, it will just bring up all these VMs.
So from problems of provisioning manually, which was time-Consuming and not repeatable , from there,
we have a local set up now which is completely automated.
Repeatable.
And its infrastructure as a code.
Thank you very much for watching the video and completing the project.
Good job there.
I'll be seeing you in the next project.
Till then, keep practicing.