Okay, I'm in my management console and I'm going to first go to the service code commit.
Okay.
In the left side, you see all the services Anyways that we need are here.
Code commit code, artifact code, build code, deploy code pipeline so you can use an axis, all these
services from one single pane.
Okay.
If you go to some other region, like, for example, if you go to North California, not California
region does not have code, artifact service and few other.
So if you don't see code artifact, check your region.
Probably you're in a region that does not have code artifact service.
I'm in North Virginia.
For this project, you can use any region of your choice.
But just make sure there is a code artifact service over there.
Let's go to code commit repository and we'll say create repository here.
We'll give Repository a name, we will name it as V profile hyphen repo, or I'll say we profile hyphen
code hyphen repo.
You can give some description over there and few tags.
If you'd like to enable Amazon Code Guru for Java project, you can put a checkmark over there so it
will improve your code quality.
It will give you it will do code analysis and give you the result, which is a very convenient service.
So directly developers instead of building and then doing code analysis, they can test it automatically
with code guru service as well.
Okay, I'm going to create this repository.
And you can access this repository by using HTTPS connection and SSH connection.
SDP comes with username and password and there is always a risk of exposing your password.
So search is a preferred method and will use this method.
So there are steps how you can configure it.
We're going to follow this.
But in order to do that, we also need an I am user.
So I will go to IAM service.
So an IAM user that you are going to create will have access to a service.
So let's go to user add user.
And let's give a username.
Mm v profile hyphen Code hyphen admin.
So for the time being, we'll just see Programatic access.
But we are not going to use access keys anyways.
We're going to use SSH credentials.
Our policy.
So if you want, you can directly give code, commit full access, but that will give access to all
the code commit repository.
So we want specific, we only need for the repository that we created.
So we'll create policy.
Will choose the service.
Code commit.
You can fine tune all kinds of actions that this policy can take.
List.
Reid I'll just give all I can just select over here also, because I'm going to be very specific.
I'm talking about only my code repository that I created resources.
We'll talk about the specific resource add in.
Region.
So our repository is in US East one.
And the repository name.
So we'll get a repository name.
We profile hyphen code hyphen repo.
So I'm being very specific.
I'm saying this repository in this region.
If you want to put some conditions, you can do that.
But we are going to skip this one and we'll say review policy.
We'll give this policy a name.
So I'm going to say we profile code admin repository, full access.
That's quite a long name.
We can even give a better description.
And they create policy.
And it will scan for this.
We profile.
I have a code admin repository, full access.
So I'm going to select my policy.
And I can just check it once again if I want.
You can see all the actions.
I'm going to go back to this place where we are creating user.
From here.
We click on Create Policy.
We already have a policy now.
So refresh this once again and paste your policy name.
So you can see the policy selected.
Go next.
You can use some tag if you want.
And to create user.
Okay, so a user get created with the policy.
And I'm going to close this again.
Go to your user.
Security credentials.
So we really don't need access key and secret key.
So you can either make it inactive or better just delete these keys.
We don't need it.
We need keys for a code commit.
So we have to upload ssh public key.
So a gendered squeeze from our local machine.
So let's open gate bash to generate keys.
We're going to issue the command key gen.
And we'll keep it at that location, but with a different name.
Let me test for pro hyphen code.
Commit.
Underscore underscore rc.
I will keep created with this name.
Once the keys are created, let's go to our directory and you can see they're the private key.
They're the public key.
So let's catch the public key.
Let's copy it.
And let's store it.
Let's see, upload as a public key.
Be stood there, make sure there are no extra space or anything just to upload.
And you will get an such key ID over here.
Now we'll create a config file a this config file.
I see in place.
Let's create a config file which as such will use.
So when we use the code commit service at that time, it's going to use the in the config file that
will be mentioned.
If it's code commit is the host name, then use this access key, this username and this key to login.
So there you have.
So if the host is.
Did code commit.
Then the user name changed that to the user.
Let's copy this user as kid.
Mention it there and the file name that we created.
So let's verify the file name once again.
And that's the file name.
So for you, I will create.
You will create this config file in the repository.
You can check in a branch sai hyphen, a w s and you can find this config file which you can use.
See if this.
We also have to make sure that our config file permissions should be 600.
In Linux, this will be mandatory.
Okay.
Now, let's make a test with our credentials.
Run this command search space.
This URL hit enter.
And it says you have successfully authenticated our search.
So our authentication is really working for troubleshooting purpose.
If there's something not working, you can use an hyphen v option.
And you can see much in detail what key is being used, what user, all that you can see for troubleshooting
purposes.
Okay, now I can really clone my repository.
Also, let's test it.
I'll go to the temp directory.
So repository clone URL and we'll use zoo URL.
Is just a test.
We're going to do it a little different, but just run a test like this.
Get clone.
So this will also validate whether you your user has privilege on this repository or not.
Yes.
If you're able to successfully clone this, then that means.
User that you used.
I am user that also has privilege to access this repository.
Once you have cloned, then you can put the data and commit it back, but you're going to do little
different.
We already have a code repository from GitHub that we clone.
We're going to transition that code repository from GitHub to code commit.
So I will go to my f drive.
Well, if you don't have the source code, you can clone it.
If your done previous project, you should already have cloned it.
Okay.
Like I already have it, so I'm going to switch.
To my repository.
And this is a git repository.
Yes.
And but the remote repository over here is.
GitHub.
So what are data that we push?
It gets sync to GitHub remote repository.
Instead of this, we will be having our code commit repository.
So let's do the transition.
So first just run the command git branch hyphen a list all your branches and check out to the branch
that you want to use that you want to push to code commit.
First I'm going to check out the master branch.
Okay, then I'm going to run this command.
Which lists all the branches.
It does not get the branch that has head and the master name.
And we're going to use the cut command and field three, which will just give us.
The branch name so we can very easily.
Get the branch name.
I'm going to send all this output to a file temp slash if you wish to do it like this automatically.
Otherwise you can just run git, check out command as many branches you have that you can run or you
can do it like this quickly, automatically.
I just named his branches.
I guess I have all the branches in ten branches file and I'm now going to run it on a for loop.
For.
I in?
Back tactics Kit.
Do a CO dollar I and you can just first print it whether it's really printing the right branch name.
Yes.
Now, instead of doing an echo and printing it, we are going to do get check out dollar.
I really a quick way to check out all the branches.
If you have many branches then it will be stupid to run get check out that many times, you know, just
do some automation and get over with it.
Okay.
We did get check out to all the branches.
Let's run it.
Branch hyphen.
I see that these branches are all checked out or checked out.
Next, if you have some tags in your repository, you can say get fetch, hyphen, hyphen tags.
Once you are good with this, then we are going to remove the remote repository which is currently GitHub
origin.
Get remote item origin.
And we will add our code commit repository, git remote, add origin and the URL.
So let's get that search review URL.
Closeness is such.
And said, enter now you can check in your config file it config file.
Remote repository is now code comment.
That's nice.
Now let's push all our changes.
Get push.
Origin hyphen.
Hyphen.
All.
All these branches are now on code comet repository.
If you have any tag, you can push all your tags as well.
Get push hyphen hyphen tags.
You'll absolutely have some tags.
Okay, Once that is done, let's check.
Let's go to repository.
Must check our repository.
And come on.
Yeah.
Okay, great.
Brunch with the master.
Brunch?
Yeah.
Is the master brunch?
Yes.
And we should have our CI hyphen plus branch.
There.
Okay, So in this branch, you have some files and files.
You'll see more files over here.
One is a search config file and a few other files over here.
Okay.
So you can use this for the search config.
Other files we have will come to it in a moment.
Now let's switch your attention to code artifact.
Getting started.
So now we'll create a repository in code artefact, which will be used by our build job maven, build
job or MAVEN, build your download dependencies from here.
So we'll create repository.
Okay, let's give the name as v profile hyphen maven hyphen repo and give some description.
So public upstream repository.
I want to have Maven Central store.
So from here it's going to download the dependency and keep it.
And we profile Maven repo repository.
Let's go next.
Yes, we want to create it for this account.
You have to select a domain and it'll give a domain name.
So we'll give a domain name as I'm going to give it as visual path.
And this should be good.
Let's go.
Next.
So you see the external connection.
It is telling.
Domain.
It is going to use this visual path.
It will have a Maven central store repository.
Which is connected to this group repository.
So we really created our repository.
Oh, not yet.
Let's click on Create Repository.
Okay, let's go to click on Repository and you should see two repositories now.
This is what is going to store the dependencies.
So you can click on it and you can see how you can connect to it.
There is a view connection, instruction.
Select package manager MVPs.
And so if you're going to use package manager MVPs and if you're going to run like MVPs and install
right, we will need dependencies.
So what you need to do, you need to run this command which is going to give you a token.
We have to use an IAM user and we feed the information in settings dot XML file.
Made information.
So we'll do all this.
We already have settings dot xml file with the details.
We're going to just make the changes over there.
But before that, we need to export this variable, which actually is going to run a command, a base
code artifact, get authorization token.
And this command has to be done with a user privilege.
I am a user, so we're going to now create an I am user for this.
So let's go back to IM console user.
Say add user and we'll limit as we profile hyphen code artifact.
Hyphen admin been.
Programatic access we need for this one.
Policy.
So I'll just say code artefact.
So for this one, you can also create your own policy.
But to keep it simple for this one, I'm going to use code artifact admin access policy.
Or you can create your own policy and you can only target your own repository.
So Aaron should be your own code artifact repository.
But for now, I'll just keep it.
It managed policy.
Let's go next.
I'll download the credentials.
Now you need to have a CLI in your system because we are going to run that export command.
And we're going to run this command on our local machine.
So we need a blue collar for this.
So from previous project, if you have not installed a blue CLI, then I recommend you install them.
So you can do it through PowerShell.
PowerShell width.
We have to open with admin run as administrator.
And you can use Choko install command.
If you have not installed it, install it now.
I already have it installed so I'm not going to run it again.
So you can run a configure and set up the credentials that you have just downloaded.
So from my credentials file, I'm going to overwrite the existing credentials.
Well, anyways, I'm going to delete this user, so I don't mind showing it to you now, but it's quite
very dangerous if you expose this credentials.
So make sure you give you a right region.
US East one is right for me, so I'll keep it as it is output for my JSON.
Okay, once you have this setup.
Will copy this command and run it.
Which should give us a token and return.
A cool dollar.
Let me see.
Does it have value or not?
And there's a token.
So we're going to store this token.
Some parameter store from where our code job is going to get it.
But now it's time.
Before we do that.
Now it's time to change our settings.
Dot XML file.
So let's go to our repository.
And switch to.
Cy hyphenate s.
So you'll see a settings dot XML file over here.
So we have to make some changes over here.
So we'll keep username as it goes over there.
And there is a variable which we are going to define from some parameters to it.
As I told you.
To login and.
You are over here repository URL.
So we are going to change that.
Copy that.
And let's face it over there.
For Miller.
So the name domain name here changed the domain name.
To the domain name that you have used.
I have used domain name as visual path.
You can really get the details from here also, if you want and change this URL as well and make sure
to give that a forward slash after that URL.
Okay.
This should be good over here.
Let's save and quit this.
We will also update our XML file with the URL.
You can keep the idea name same.
It really does not matter here.
Let's just see if this.
And we are going to make the chief commit the changes.
Get at dot, get comet hyphen, m, c updated poem and settings with code artifact details.
Okay.
And then we'll push it.
This is going to go all the way to our repository.
Oh.
Get push.
Origin si hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
This should have been updated in our code repository.
I would also like to show one more setting over here to you.
So in that XML file, we have also given one more setting.
In this particular branch.
We have this setting.
We are setting up a variable timestamp so it will automatically get the timestamp in this format and
this will be used to version our artifact.
Okay.
So these two lines there.
Which will be useful in the build project.
Okay, So now we're going to set up a code analysis job, which is going to do some honor code analysis
in code build.
And for that, we need a sonar cloud account.
So you go to SoundCloud dot IO from your browser and you can log in with your gate credentials if you
want GitHub credential or Bitbucket with any of these four.
You can create an account.
I already have an account with GitHub.
So once you log in with your GitHub or any credentials, once you sign up with this, you will come
over here.
So it will look almost similar to so on the cube server that we have used in continuous integration.
Jenkins project.
But this is cloud based.
So first thing we'll do over here is we're going to generate a token.
So your user go to my account Security.
And give it token name v Profile hyphen Sonar hyphen Cloud.
To generate.
So you'll get a token.
Save it somewhere safe.
For the time being, I'm going to keep it in my sticky notes.
Okay.
Now from this plus symbol see analyze new project.
So when you sign up, you should already have an organization name that you have created over here and
you can see all the repository from your organization.
But we are just testing it.
We're not going to scan all these repositories.
I'll say create project manually.
Okay, so choose the organization.
And let's give a project key like we give sonar key sonar project key.
Similar to that, we'll give it over here, we'll name it as V profile hyphen repo.
That's all I'll keep the name.
I can only go with public because I have a free account.
If you have a paid account, you can go with private also set up.
Okay.
By now, we should have some details.
Let me put them into sticky note.
That's the token.
Project name we have is v profile hyphen repo.
The sooner cloud URL is https Colon slash slash sooner cloud dot io.
Organization I'm using is Dev Ops Actual D Club.
That's the name of my organization that I've used in the Sony cloud.
There you can see and we profile repo.
So we need this for details and we're going to store this information into a parameter store.
So let's go back to our console.
Nagin said, Done with this.
And we'll search for the service.
Some systems manager service.
A very easy way to set up or store variables over here.
This secret manager, which is quite expensive, so as you can try that also, but I'm going to go with
systems manager parameter store.
Here.
We'll store these variables.
Okay, so let's create parameter.
Forced will create this organization.
Name and value string.
Okay, string text and we'll just you the name of the organization.
Just that.
And let's create parameter.
Next parameter will give the host.
That will be our sonar cloud.
You are all.
Okay, So let's create that also.
Script.
Next parameter name of the project.
Which we have given us a v profile hyphen repo.
Create.
One more parameter.
This will be our sonar token, the token that we have generated.
And this value.
I don't want to be taxed.
Oh, sorry.
Not string value, just secure string.
So it will encrypt the value that I put over here because I don't want to show this value to everyone.
Maybe for that reason I will just encrypt it.
Make sure there is not any extra space or anything.
And you say create parameter.
So we have four parameters.
Will also create one more parameter.
And this parameter is for our code artifact token.
So we have executed cli cli command, which has given us this variable, exported this variable.
And we're going to copy this.
And we named the parameter as code artifact hyphen token.
Okay.
Again, this is a token, so I'm going to say secure string and paste the value there.
And to create parameter.
All right.
So currently I have these parameters.
Four for Sony Cloud integration and one is for Code Artefact.
Now is the time to create the Build project.
So.
Let's go to build project.
You can go from here.
You can just say build and you can say build project or you can just search for the service code.
Build from there.
Code build.
Okay.
Our first job, first billed job will be to do code analysis on our code analysis.
So let's create a project, create, build project.
Is like we're creating Jenkins job similar to that.
So we'll name this job as we profile hyphen build.
Source code comet, our repository.
You can see the repository over here.
Branch.
We are going to use A.
S hyphen plus branch.
And scroll down operating system.
We are going to run a MAVEN command.
So open two should be fine.
Runtime Environment Default Standard Image 3.0.
Okay, let's scroll down.
So this is going to create a service role.
And just to make it unique, I'll put some numbers over here, like 12.
And we later update this roll so it can access the parameter store that we have saved.
Okay, But first, let's create it.
Okay, so we have to use a build spec file.
So you can use a build spec file from version control, but we're going to say insert, build command
and switch to editor.
And this is where we're going to copy our build spec file content.
So build spec file is in our source code.
In sci hyphenate branch, you have a files directory in that you have sonar build spec file.
You can just get it and copy its content.
And let's select all based it.
We'll go through this build spec file in a moment.
So we'll just read it from here itself.
.0.2 environment variable from parameter store that we have saved.
So we are going to set up here five variables and its value.
We're going to give from the parameter store that we have set phases in install phase.
We are installing JDBC and we have a command.
We are going to copy our settings dot XML file to slash root, dot M to settings dot xml.
So setting dot xml anyways has to be in this place.
So we're using a copy command to copy that file.
Settings dot XML is already in our source code which will be moved to this place, which will have the
information about our code artifact repository.
Then we have pre build phase.
We are running commands, running apt update.
We're installing check style and GQ with W great command.
We're downloading maven here.
We extract maven.
We create a link for MAVEN.
Then we download sonar scanner.
We unzip the sonar scanner.
We explored the path for four sonar.
And then the build commands.
Of course, in the build phase commands, we have MAVEN test, we're going to run check style, MAVEN
check style and MAVEN sonar with all the parameters that we are passing.
So in our login data, log in.
That one.
So all the parameters that we are saving over here, all the variables that we are saving over here,
we're using it.
Then we wait for 5 seconds and there is a command which is going to store the result and result dot
JSON file.
We get this file.
And with an e condition, we check the status, the quality gate passes.
This job will be returning an exit code zero all or else it will return non zero.
So basically this is going to fail the job if your quality gates are not passing.
Okay, so we are good with this, so we need to make few changes though the parameters value from some
parameter store.
So host value we can just give directly.
Host It's already there for login.
That's really the sonar token, so let's give it its value as sonar token or whatever named of variable
that you have saved it with the owner token with organization name variable, we have given us organization
itself so we can keep it as it is project.
We have given variables project.
Code artefact or token.
We have saved it as code artifact hyphen token that variable.
So as you have used the variable name in the parameter store, so you have to give it with the same
name.
So it's going to access the parameter store and store all the variable these values.
And let's check again.
I think should be good.
We have not yet set any quality.
Gates will set it later.
Let's crawl down.
And I'm not going to store any artifacts from here.
Cloud watch logs.
I will put a checkmark on there.
I'll give a group name.
We profile Hyphen and Virginia.
I find sooner.
Or in Virginia.
Build.
See?
Logs stream name I'll say sooner build job.
So we can see the output streaming really from here.
That should be all in this job.
Let's say create, build project.
Before we run and test it, we have to update.
The role that we have used over here, and we have to give the privilege so it can access some parameters
to our.
Okay, so you can find the role name from Edit Environment Section.
You can find the road name there.
That's the road name.
Let's copy that and say cancel here.
Yes, of course.
Discard.
We'll go to I am service.
We'll go to role section.
We'll find that role.
There is that role.
Let's edit that role.
We have to give some policy.
We're going to say attach policy.
So we'll create our own policy.
I choose the service.
And some.
Actually, it should be with the name system manager.
So to manage the service action.
Okay, so in list we need describe parameters in a read.
We will need this describe document parameters.
Indeed.
Again, get parameters, get parameter history and get parameter get parameters.
Both get parameters by depth.
If you have created parameter store one inside another.
So you have to give this.
And that should be it.
No.
Right.
No tagging.
You can give Aaron if you want, but let's keep it that much for now and let's say review policy.
For resources, you can give a specific URL.
But I'm going to say any in this account and review policy.
Let's give this policy a name.
V profile hyphen.
Sooner.
Parameters.
Axis.
That's quite a long name.
I'll put Same in the description.
Create policy.
Okay, The policy is created.
I have to go back to rules, actually.
Get the name.
It's like the roll attach policies.
So honor some name I have given.
We profile sonar parameter access the checkmark attach policy.
Okay, so we updated that.
Now, this role will have the privilege to access some parameters to.
Which this villager will need.
Now, let's make a test.
Let's click on Start build.
And this is going to do the code scanning branch I'll keep same.
Start build.
This is going to take some time.
Let's go to phase details.
Switch to build log if you are done seeing the face because build dog will really hang your browser.
Sometimes.
As of now, things are going fine.
Okay, install phase is going on.
That successful pre build phase is going on.
Pre completed build started a view from the build log you see from the code artefact it is downloading
the dependencies.
Oh and this is okay there.
Yeah.
So from code artifact.
Okay, I missed it again.
So it's very difficult to scroll up and scroll in over here.
Even I tried all the browsers Edge, Chrome, Firefox.
This is always very slow.
You see there.
Then you miss it again.
Okay.
We got a few other logs.
So if we go to our code artefact, let's go to another tab code artifact repository.
One central.
And you should see here the dependency maven dependency getting stored.
So it's storing the dependency over here.
From here it is providing to your build job, to the build job.
And you have like so many dependencies, right?
Okay.
And it will keep updating it.
Okay, this is anyways hanging.
I'll go to code build from here.
Build project.
It's still in progress.
So this is going to take some time, at least initially.
First time.
It takes a very long time.
Fees details.
So I'm going to pause the screen and come back once this is finished.
I'll get that completed successfully.
That was pretty awesome.
Let's see the result.
So this is a sonar code analysis job, so it should have published result in sonar cloud.
So go to sonar cloud, go to your projects and you can see your project over there.
It has 92 bugs for vulnerabilities and blah, blah, blah.
If we want, we can set quality gates on this.
So I can see quality gates.
I can go to quality gates and I can create my own quality gate.
I will say V profile quality gates, that name.
See it.
And let's add a condition.
And I'm going to see an oral code and let's set it for bugs.
I will see value anything that is greater than 50.
So lets first fail.
Try to fail this job.
Okay, we'll give like 50.
We know that currently we have 92 bugs.
Condition.
So we have one rule in this quality.
GATES Let's go to our project.
And for our project we are going to set up this quality gates.
Quality get in the administration instead of default, we're going to use our own quality gates.
Okay, this is nice.
So this quality gate is going to fail your job.
If your box are greater than 50 and let's test it.
Court.
Well, to test it, we need to run this job again.
And you will see at the finalizing state or the completed state, it's going to fail the job, so let's
say.
Go to the build and let's start build.
Let's run it once again.
I will take all those defaults and we'll just start build.
Fees details.
Okay, So I'm going to pause my screen and come back once this is done.
Okay, so this is completed with a failure, of course.
So if you see in the build phase, it has error executing while this command is running.
So that this clearly shows the quality gate has failed.
Let's tweak our call the gates back.
So you can change the rule or I'll just go back to the default sona rule.
And we can test and test run the job and test it once again.
But we'll do it later with the pipeline.
I have given the name of this job as the profile build, I should have given V profile code analysis.
But that's just the naming convention for a description in that we can't change the name now, but we
can change the description.
Sonar analysis.
So on our code analysis, we'll give that in the description update configuration.
Okay, Now time to create our next job, which is going to build the artifact.
So let's go to build a project.
Mm.
We profile hyphen, build hyphen artifact.
So scored our repository branch.
C.
Hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
It's going to be almost similar.
Build spec file will be different.
Amazon Linux so open to will use.
Standard image Standard 3.0.
Okay, this is going to create a service role.
And this also we have to update so it can access the parameter store.
This job needs the parameter of our code artifact token.
At one token access, it needs source code.
Artifact token.
So for that, we need to update this role later.
Okay, build commands, insert, build command, switch to Ed and let's see our source code.
So I build spec file in the source code.
Let's add files.
And here you have build, underscore, build spec file.
So you copy all this content.
Select all based.
Okay.
Parameter store variable code Artifact auth token will give it value as code artifact hyphen token.
The variable that we created in parameter store.
So that's only one thing we need to change over here.
Install.
We need JDBC settings data XML file gets copied, Prebuilt command we are installing.
Let's see it from here.
This is better view.
A little bigger view.
Right.
So installing JDK there we are copying settings java xml file from our source code to dot m two directory
into directory.
Then apt update and we install GQ, we install apache maven extract it, create a link for it, and
then we run the command env and clean install hyphens.
Skip test.
So I don't want to run unit test and code analysis over here.
So I'm just going to say skip test and artifacts file and the file, you have to give the list of the
files.
So any file that ends with not valid directory in the target directory, any file that ends with DOT,
where will be our artifact and our artifact will have a timestamp as well.
We have updated or a prompt XML file.
They're so artifact will even have a timestamp.
And that we'll finally upload it to the SD bucket.
So.
Everything copied over here.
So here we are not saying anything.
Log group name.
So I'll select the same log group that I selected for the previous project.
Logs.
So they have the same group for the screen name.
I will just say billed job.
To create build project.
Okay, Last one thing in this job.
Bailout effect job.
Edit.
Environment.
We'll copy the rule name.
And we'll go to Imam.
Rules.
The search for a role.
Nope.
Not found.
Oh, I think I need to refresh this.
Yeah.
There it is.
Attach policy.
We already have a policy created.
We'll use that.
That was for solar we created.
The same policy will lead.
This policy gives permission to access the same parameter store.
Let's attach this policy.
And we should be good.
Cancel this.
Okay, time to test this job as well.
Let's say start, build.
Single build.
Same branch.
They start build.
Bill has started to phase details and this will also take some time.
I'll pause my screen by the time and we'll come back once this is done.
Okay, so this job completed successfully.
Can completed.
Now we have to do one more thing.
We have to set up notification as well.
Before we set up our pipeline, I would also like to set up notification with that and we'll use SNS.
So we will go to SNS service.
Okay, So first we'll go to topics and we'll create topic.
And let's give topic a name.
We'll say V, profile hyphen, pipeline and hyphen notification.
And just to create topic first.
Once this is created, we'll create a subscription for this topic.
And we will use email.
You can use other things as Q as lambda https.
I'll use email here and I'll give the email address that I'm going to use to receive my notifications.
Could be a group email for developers or a monitoring team.
So I'll say create subscription.
And it is pending confirmation.
So I have to go to my inbox, look for an email from this notification, and I have to say confirm subscription.
I guess in my inbox I got this mail.
I say confirm subscription.
That's all.
Let's refresh this.
It's confirmed.
Now.
I can use this.
I will use this on subscription or sorry.
The topic the topic name to send the notification for my build progress.
Let's come back to the code build service and finally, we're going to connect everything together with
the pipeline.
And yes, we have to upload the artifact to S3 bucket that also will do after after we create our pipeline.
So I'm going to go to Pipeline and say create pipeline.
Let's give a name.
V profile.
Hyphen Sci hyphen Pipeline.
A continuous integration pipeline.
Let it create a role.
And just go next.
Source provider code commit.
Our repository.
And the branch c hyphenated us.
And this we set.
So whenever there is a new commit cloud watch events will detect that and trigger the pipeline.
Or you can use a core pipeline.
Also, this will check periodically, same like we did in Jenkins.
But this is the one that is recommended cloud watch events.
Let's go next build provider.
The code bill is our bill provider.
We'll give the project name.
So first I will add this project.
We profile build project only this project, and then we'll update with other projects.
Go next.
Deployer.
I'm going to use a plus three.
And this will set later.
We'll just skip the stage.
Skip?
And great pipeline.
Okay.
The pipeline already has started.
I will say stop execution.
Stop and wait.
Okay.
That started this one as well.
It's trying to stop the build process.
You can continue it also.
It's not a problem, but I'm going to add a few more jobs over here.
Did the pipeline.
First will integrate our test job, the code analysis.
I'll just give the name as test.
Add actions group.
Action name sooner.
Hyphen Code hyphen Analysis Action Provider Code build.
Project.
Name e profile build single build and see done.
Now input artifact.
I have to specify the input artifact.
The source code.
It Input artifact.
Go ten.
And see done.
Okay, so pulls the code tested and runs the build job to generate the artifact.
Next stage we're going to add is we're going to deploy the artifact to a three bucket.
So we'll give add stage name as deploy.
Edit Add action group.
Action name will say deploy.
Two three action provider.
Amazon SE three.
Input artifact that gets generated from the build artifact.
So build job is going to generate the artifacts.
So that's going to be the input artifact on this job.
And we have to set a bucket also.
So let's create an S3 bucket.
Create bucket.
So I'll give name as V profile.
And give some number.
V Profile 12.
Build hyphen Artifact.
Make sure you create it in the same region.
Create.
Search for the bucket that we just created.
And in that we'll also create a folder will name it as we profile, or we'll just name it as Pipeline.
If an artifact.
Create folder.
Copy its name first.
No.
Sorry.
Save.
Okay, let's go to code Pipeline.
You have to cancel the job and again, create the action.
Say add action group.
Action name deployed to.
It's three.
Action provider.
Amazon is three.
Build artifact for input artifacts.
So our build job generates the artifact that's going to be input for this, and the output will be sent
to the bucket.
Inside this directory.
And we'll also say extract, file before deploy or artifact as part of that XML file or artifact will
have build timestamp also.
And it will be a zip file.
So it's going to extract that zip file and then put it into this directory.
Now let's say done.
And see down here.
And see if the pipeline.
Care.
So.
One is the source code.
Second is the test.
Third is the build job and the fourth is deploying artifact to three bucket.
Okay, one more last thing pending.
We have to set the notification.
So let's go to settings.
Notifications.
Create notification rule.
So you want to give basic information.
You want to give full information again, based on your choice.
Let's give this notification a name.
We profile hyphen c hyphen pipeline hyphen notification.
And what action.
So if the job is failed, if it has started, it has succeeded.
Or we can just see all and you can just remove what you don't need.
And let's go to Target says topic.
We'll keep this topic.
We'll choose our topic that we created and say submit.
Okay.
This is set.
Notification is set.
Now, let's go to our pipeline.
And it's showtime.
Let's click on a release change.
Release.
So fetch the cord.
And it's going to run test.
So I will pause my screen now and come back when this is completed.
Okay.
After a few minutes, this is completed.
The test job completed.
Successfully billed.
Job completed successfully, and it has deployed the artifact to S3 bucket.
Let's go and check the bucket.
In the directory.
And we see the artifact with the timestamp.
Okay.
You can run one more test by committing the code.
So if the developer makes a code, change to the repository.
It should automatically detect that and trigger the pipeline.
Let's test that also.
So let's open.
Get back.
You can use the ID as the developer.
Users like Intel AG.
And this is the code comet.
Yes.
And let's make some changes.
So let's open read me dot MD file.
And just please extra hash.
So we are not making any serious code change, but we are making change to some file which should be
detected.
It had Dot.
Get comet hyphen M.
Testing code pipeline.
And time to push.
So get push.
Origin ci hyphen.
E.
W.
S on this branch if there is any comment.
Then it should be detected by events, cloud watch events, and that should trigger the pipeline.
Let's check it.
Okay.
Nothing yet.
Let's refresh the screen.
All right.
You see that?
That started?
It's in progress.
So you have to wait a few more minutes for this to complete, and then you can see the artifact in the
three bucket.
Now let's reiterate what we did.