Okay, so now you have a complete continuous integration pipeline.
The next task will be to deploy our artifact to some environment.
So as discussed in this project, we are going to use beans tag as the target where we're going to host
our application.
It's also disposable environment.
If you want, you can use it for production also.
And we're going to have an ideas database instance for database if you're interested in active MQ and
rabbit MQ.
So you can include these two services also and elastic cache service and active MQ service.
But even if you don't use, that's not going to stop you to do anything in this project.
So now let's go to Beanstalk service and create a beanstalk environment.
Just go to application.
Create application.
So we'll name it as a V profile hyphen app.
Scroll down.
Platform We will choose Platform Tomcat.
And first, we'll keep the sample code and then we'll make changes when we deploy.
Before we deploy the artifact, we're going to make some health checks changes also as we did in our
previous projects.
First capacity, we'll have load balanced instance.
So we have minimum two and maximum.
We are saying it can scale to four.
And you can give the number as per your requirement.
And we'll keep everything else default here.
Keep your log in, Keep it.
So in case if you have to log in, then you can create a key pair and attach it before you create the
environment.
I'm going to use the same key pair, which I used for the C process.
See it.
And these are the only two changes I'm making right now.
And tags.
Let's kill some tag project.
We profile.
Okay, let's create an app.
So this is going to take some time to create the stack by the time we'll go to the service.