So let's see.
Create database.
Standard.
Will keep my SQL.
We should make sure you are going with five or six.
That's apt for our project.
We profile to keep it simple and under free tier, select this option.
Free tier so there is no chance of making any mistake.
So you will be in the free tier.
Otherwise database can really get expensive.
So limit us v profile c.
I.
C.
D.
I can project.
My skull.
Will keep that username.
Will c auto generate password?
So DBD to micro obviously because we selected free tier.
Single availability zone should be fine for our exercise project.
Exercise.
Additional connectivity information.
So it should be in the private network.
We are not exposing it to the public.
Security group will say create new so it creates a security group.
Will give some name to it.
We profile hyphen ci seed hyphen radius hyphen my SQL.
I find g.
It's quite a long name, but it will do will be easy to recognize.
Additional configuration, we need to create a database named accounts.
And once this is created, once this is up and running, we have to deploy the schemas also on this.
And I'm going to keep everything else default and let's say create database.
So you can change the parameters based on your requirement.
But for the project, this should be fine.
You credentials detail, and I'm going to store that into my sticky notes.
So let me copy that.
Be there.
So do you know when you generate credential?
Do not refresh the page, otherwise you lose it.
Then you have to reset the password.
So once you create, it will generate the credentials and quickly copy it somewhere safe.
A username, of course, admin.
And sometimes you'll also see the endpoint.