By now, we should have a security group for ideas and being stuck in environment created so we can
make changes.
So let's go to S.E. to service.
So instance security group ID, we have to get first.
Okay, so I have a few other instances.
You can ignore them.
Okay.
This is the bean instance.
And it's a security group ID we have to get.
So that's the security group ID copy this being stacked.
Security group ID.
Go to security group and find our IDs security group.
Their naming convention helps us.
That's the security group.
So we have to add a rule here.
It says 3306 from my IP, but since it's a private ideas instance anyways, we will not be able to access
it from our IP, but Beanstalk instance should be able to access this because our application on the
beanstalk will need to access the ideas which is going to be in the security group and we'll give the
description also like that allow the profile app to.
Connect radius on 83306.
DU proper description.
It will be very good when you come back after some time.
You know, you can easily understand why you have added this rule.
So this instance is in the state of backing up, but we should be able to connect to it.
So we're going to log into our beans tag instance, going to store beans, tag instance, and from there
we're going to log into radius.
So that will also perform a test.
And also we need to deploy the schemas.
So let's get the public IP of this beanstalk instance.
It will not be an ideal practice to log into Beanstalk instance and make changes.
So the good way will be you can launch a separate instance in the same VPC and then you can access ideas.
But for this project, this will do.
We don't have too many moving parts.
Okay, so copy the IP.
Let's do an SSH to it.
So the key that I have used ci hyphen v profile.
User is easy to hyphen user.
This is a Amazon Linux, so that will be the user.
And the IP address.
So there will be one weird thing on the bean stack.
Easy, for instance, when actually very bad thing.
So security group will allow 22 from anywhere.
That's not good.
But since, you know, it is made for the convenience of developers and testers so unnecessary they
don't need to know, make rule changes, port numbers, protocol.
Right.
So you know, they just made 22 from anywhere but make it safer.
Just say 22 from my IP.
Rule even though it will be disposable environment.
But there could be a lot of confidential information there in your instance.
Right.
So make sure you don't expose it.
So if you see from the beginning we are taking care of security group rule, we are not exposing things
totally.
And that's for your own safety, your project safety.
It will give you a little trouble, but it's all worth it.
So we did a search and we're in this beanstalk instance.
And from here we have to log into ideas.
So let's get the ideas endpoint.
And I'll also store it in my sticky notes so we can use it later also.
Okay, so we need my SQL client here.
So in the Beanstalk instance, I'm going to install my SQL client.
So yum, install my SQL.
And also we need Git because we're going to clone our source code where we have the SQL file.
We're going to get a SQL file from there.
We're going to run the SQL queries.
So we install both these tools.
Install.
So let's make a test first.
My SQL hyphen edge.
Let's put the endpoint.
I have a new admin hyphen p.
It's not recommended you put the password on the shell, but since you have already seen it.
And anyways, I'm going to delete that.
And also it's a private instance.
I don't mind.
But you should not put password like that on the shell.
Okay.
Be able to log in, show databases.
So if you are not able to log in from your beans tag instance to your IDs, then check your security
group rules.
Okay, now let's clone the source code.
So get clone.
And this was the reason I was telling, you know, you don't make changes to your beanstalk instance
because you download source code and do many things here.
Install softwares.
Okay, we will check out the branch CD Hyphenate SE.
And.
We will go to Z.
Mean resources.
We have DB backup SQL file and let's run this queries on our ideas from here.
So give the database name and put it addiction your SQL file pot.
And let's log in and check once again.
Show.
We'll just say use accounts.
Show tables.
So you should see this schema, these three tables, and we're good.