So people stage is set.
We have been stacked environment and we have ideas, except we need to make a little health check on
our beanstalk environment if it's ready.
Okay, It's ready.
And I'm going to make a little change over here.
Health check.
We're going to deploy our artifact on interactive.
Our application will be at slash logging.
So we need to make a health check there.
Slash login that you do.
And if you're planning to have HTTPS and all those stuff that we did in our project, you can do that
as well.
But for this project, you don't need to do all those things.
This is going to be a disposable environment.
Let's apply these changes.
When we apply these changes, this will go into a severe state.
But let's not worry about it.
Once we deploy our artifact, it will come back to normal state.