So now the stage is set completely.
Let's come to our code pipeline now.
Okay, So first let's go to our repository code.
Repository.
So we are using this branch sci hyphenate.
So far we're going to use this branch KD hyphen eight.
CI hyphen branch.
We have updated the palm dot and settings dot XML file, but in this branch you have to make the changes
and you can do it from here itself.
Let's create a duplicate tab.
In this staff.
We will be in ci hyphen a branch.
And we will open pubmed XML.
And it should have the entry of our code artifact repository.
Yeah.
There.
So let's copy that.
Now be in kd hyphen ws branch open palm dot xml file.
And edit so you can edit it from here itself, which is really cool.
I don't want to go back to my shell and do it again so you can make the repository changes over there.
Yeah.
So, you know, you should have the code artifact repository URL there.
Okay, let's give our name.
My name and email address.
You can just fake some email address if you want.
That's not really my email address of mine, actually.
So anyways, I just wanted to be in the commit, that's all.
That XML is updated.
Go to again another tab.
Make sure you see hyphen eight plus branch.
And open settings.
Dot xml file.
Okay.
And we need this entire file.
Copy this entire file.
And.
And make sure you're in the right branch.
Okay.
See, we have.
This is the branch that we are updating.
Settings dot xml file.
Edit.
So that before some, you know, fake or default entries in the previous file.
So I'm just overwriting it with the right entries.
Again skew the name.
Yeah.
Commit.
I should give some comment message.
But anyways, we are not really making any serious code change.
Now if you make any change to PSI hyphenate branch, remember your pipeline will get triggered.
That's also one more reason we're using a different branch.
So you're going to push the source code that we're going to give you, right to code repository and
you will see all the branches, you'll see CD hyphenate, any branch also, so you can just select it
and make the changes.
So remember settings, dot XML and XML file.
We are giving these entries so our maven can download artifact from code artifact.
It can download it from that URL.