Okay, Now I'm going to create a separate build job, which is going to build the artifact for the deployment.
So let's go to build.
Build project.
And we already have these two jobs here.
Also, we need to make some changes.
We profile hyphen build.
This job is running code analysis.
We can check the build spec file.
What it is doing.
And so it's running the sonar code analysis.
So this will be also in our pipeline.
So we have to change the source code here also.
So edit source.
And change the branch from c hyphen to c.
D.
Hyphen.
And just update source.
Same for the other job as well, which is building our artifact or storing to store in the S3 bucket.
This job also makes sure you change the source code.
Branch.
Two seed hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
You can actually use sci fi blues branch also, but there are little changes in that XML file for this
particular project.
So if you're on CD Hyphenate Blues branch, you will not have any problem.
Okay.
Now we'll create one one more build project over here, which will build the artifact to deploy it on
bean stack.
You can edit the existing build project also, but I don't want you to disturb your existing jobs.
Which would be good for your revision also later.
Okay, so I'm going to name this job as V profile Build and release.
Build and release and we'll give a number over here.
We profile 14 just to make it unique, that's all, because it will create a role with this name.
So I want it to be unique.
Code commit repository v Profile.
Code repo.
And branch.
Yes.
Right.
CD hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
OC.
Operating System Open to Runtime Environment Standard Image 3.0.
Now, this will create a new role with this name.
Either we can do that and then but we have to then edit this role again so it can access some parameter
if you remember.
And instead of that, we can use our existing role.
So let's go to build project.
Existing build project.
Just showing you the easier way.
Right.
Edit environment.
And copy the roll.
This role.
We already updated with some parameter policy.
So.
This will be good and easier for us.
So let's give the role.
Now, sorry you have to say existing role and you give the role name and you select it over here.
The complete urn has to be given not just the role name.
So using existing role, the original configuration none.
We don't need this insert build commands switch to ed.
So the build spec file again, it's in our source code.
So either you can access it from GitHub or if you you must have already definitely signed it with this
repository as well.
So just switch to CD hyphen eight plus branch.
Go to files.
And there are these build spec files.
So build a release, build spec file this one.
So we have to define some parameters.
First thing is environment variable.
We are setting from parameter store.
So artifact token.
If you are getting authentication error while the build job is running, you have to generate this token
once again.
And then update the parameter.
You're going to update the IDs, endpoint radius, user and password.
These variables we're going to put into parameter store.
And then we can access it from here.
Installing JDK copying settings dot xml file to this location.
You already updated settings dot XML file and three set command.
Search and replace.
You're going to search for the database password.
And replace it with the password that we have.
Setting out parameter store and so application properties file we are changing with the password, with
the username and also the endpoint.
So before we build the artifact, we'll update application properties file.
Once that is updated, we install some tools.
JQ we download Maven, we create a link for Maven.
So these are pre-built commands.
And then finally, build command MV and clean install skip test.
Since we're running tests already on the sonar job.
So we don't want to run test over here artifacts.
Now, this is important here.
Artifact.
So base directory, we say this is going to be our base directory.
So it's going to do CD into that directory.
And this directly.
We have our files.
So instead of uploading the entire artifact, like, instead of uploading the file, the artifact we
are uploading on the beans tag the content of this directory.
There are various ways to do it.
You can check the build spec documentation.
We're just saying all the content from this directory will be zipped and then upload it to the target.
So artifact really is in this bucket.
Sorry, in this directory.
So that's our build spec file.
So let's copy this.
And put it in your bill spec file here.
Okay.
Next.
Artifact.
If you want to upload the artifact to the bucket, we can do that.
But we're already uploading artifact from the previous job, so you don't need to do it here.
Log group name will give some log group name.
We'll say v profile hyphen ci cd hyphen logs, stream name.
We'll say build and release.
Good job.
All right.
That should be it.
And this job, let's create.
Okay, before we test it, we need to worry about the parameters.
We need to set this parameter in the parameter store.
Okay, First, let's generate the latest token.
And to do that, we can get the command here from code artifact.
Maven Central store.
We have connection instructions for Maven.
And that's the command.
Now, if you're following the project, well, you should already have a CLI and authentication configured
over here, so you can just put paste your command and get bash.
So it's it is going to run this command, get the token and we'll check the token.
It's there.
Let's copy this token and we will go to parameter stores and put these values over there.
Okay, let's search for the service systems manager.
This is very important part.
The build job will need parameters If they are not able to find it, you're going to get errors.
So code artifact token, that's the parameter we stored and it's encrypted.
We can really see it because we have the key.
We're going to edit this.
And update the entry over here.
If you have just recently executed this pipeline.
So you don't need to update it.
But you know, after second day, third date one when the token expires, then you run this command,
get your token and update it over here.
Okay, a few more parameters you have to create for ideas.
Ideas, End point.
We have to create ideas, user ideas, path.
So let's create these three parameters.
Create parameter.
So make sure we have the exact same name adds hyphen endpoint.
I see it's normal string and the value.
So I already copied it in my note.
Sticky notes.
Create parameter.
Another parameter ideas user.
That's simple.
That is admin.
Just admin.
Create parameter.
Ideas pass.
So it's possible database password.
It has to be encrypted.
Should store it encrypted.
Secure string.
And the password.
Also, I have kept it out here.
Now, the encryption is not really for you because you are already seeing the video.
But when you do it in your project, right, it's important.
This will prevent the accidental exposure of your passwords.
So good.
We have given updated our token.
We've created three new entries over here which will be used by our build spec file code build job.
So this job build and release job.
When we run.
So build spec file is going to access parameter store.
Right and use these variables.
Can use this variable and assign the value from parameters to night.
And those variables we're using here.
To update our application properties file.
Okay.
This should be good.
We can test this job.
Just start build.
So this is really not going to give us any great result, but we can just test whether it's working
or not.
Once we connect it in the pipeline, then only this job will make some sense.