Okay.
While this is happening, we'll create another job, which will be for our software testing.
And for this, you need endpoints also.
So endpoints have been stacked.
So let's get started.
Let's create the job and we will name it as software testing.
So could commit.
Our source code repository there.
And branch.
Will be Selenium Auto scripts.
So this branch will have our Selenium automation scripts.
And image.
This has to be executed on a Windows machine.
So we are going to select Windows Server 2019.
Runtime base.
Image.
So only one option you have.
Let's go.
Next.
Again, we'll be using existing role.
So let's get our real name.
So build project or CI build project.
Check the environment.
And you should have the rule name.
Existing real estate and just select it.
I always recommend you give some unique number because when you're practicing, it will create role.
And then when you create the job with similar name, the role will be already existing.
So there will be a conflict when you say new service role.
So give a number some unique numbers so it creates a unique role name.
Okay, that's it.
Here.
Insert, build, command.
The switch to Ed and we have a separate build spec file for our Windows machine, which is going to
run our selenium test suit.
So let's go to a repository.
Source code.
Repository.
Again.
N.
KD hyphen.
E.
W.
S branch.
It finds.
When bill spect women.
So let's understand this build spec file.
So we just have series of commands over here.
First it's going to set up chocolaty.
Then you can use cocoa, install JDK eight.
So go install MAVEN show, go install Google Chrome.
We'll need Google Chrome.
So we'll install that git.
And we create a directory here output directory where the output screenshot will be stored.
And then we have start sleep 360 seconds.
So we're going to halt the execution for 3/62 before we run the selenium test suit.
Because once the deployment happens, this job will get triggered.
And OpenStack, if you have multiple instances and it's going to take time for the deployment.
All right.
So that's why we are waiting for 360 seconds before the deployment completes.
And if that is less, we can even increase that time.
Or I'll just go with 500 seconds.
Now, I updated that in the build spec file when I add.
Okay, So it's going to run a clean test.
And we are passing parameter.
This URL will be checked.
So we have to update the URL and username and the password and the location where it is going to store
the screenshot.
So let's copy this file.
Select all.
Be seated.
Make sure there are no errors.
If there is any YAML syntax error, it will highlight.
Sometimes everything will seem fine, but you will see an error that this is not recommended here.
There could be an invisible invisible characters.
So if such case happens, you know, just if it's showing over here.
So just do it like this is go backspace.
So it's going to eliminate all the invisible special character.
Okay, so once we run the suit.
It's going to generate the output.
And we are saying all the output that is generated is our artifact.
We're going to upload all that to S3 bucket.
So we'll also need an S3 bucket for this.
So let's go to S3.
And let's create a bucket.
Mm.
V pro file secede.
Test output.
And just to make it unique, let's put some number like 56.
Make sure it's in the same region where you're creating your pipeline.
So mine is in not Virginia.
So I have selected North Virginia here to create.
Look, you come back to your code belt job.
Artifacts.
Now, here we're going to select three and we'll select our bucket name.
And it's not showing the bucket name and there is no refresh button also here.
So if you create the bucket while creating the job, it will not update.
So we have to cancel this job and create it again.
No problem.
We can create it very quickly.
Images, software testing.
Could commit as the source.
Repository.
Branch.
Selenium Auto scripts.
Operating system, Windows Server 2019 Runtime base and the default image.
Existing role.
So let's go to our code build.
From the build project.
Copy the rule name.
Paste it over here and select that.
Okay, let's scroll down.
Insert, build commands.
Switch to editor.
And copy.
Our win underscore bid spectrum will file select all based.
Make sure there are no indentation error.
And now we should see our S3 bucket.
We profile CCD test output 56.
If you want to create a subfolder inside that, you can mention that or enable semantic versioning.
So if you have given versioning, then you have different versions of the artifact.
We'll see.
Zip it.
So in the bucket, we'll have a zipped artifact.
Log group name.
So I'll give the same group name that we used for our.
Build and release job.
So the job logs.
That's not mandatory, but it's good to have all our log for our project in one place.
So use the same log group name.
And see software.
Give some nice name and say create, build project.
Okay, So another job is also ready.
All right, so we have our V profile build job that runs the core analysis.
We profile build artifact that that builds the artifact and stores in the S3 bucket.
Build and release job that's going to generate the artifact for the deploying to deploy on Bienstock
software testing job that is going to run the software test suit.