Now let's create a pipeline and put all these things together.
So let's go to Pipeline.
You can edit the existing pipeline if you want and update the jobs over there.
Okay, so you can say edit.
And you can update the same pipeline if you want.
But I'll create a separate pipeline for this.
Because the name is V Profile C Pipeline.
We can't edit that name, so we're going to create a separate pipeline, rename it as v profile hyphen
c c d hyphen pipeline.
So it's going to create a new role.
Again, if you want to make it unique, just add a number there.
Now.
Let's go next.
Source provider code comment.
Our repository.
And the branch said hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
Let's keep cloud watch events to detect a new commit.
Next build.
Could build.
So first we'll select our build and release job, and then we'll update this pipeline and add all the
other jobs together.
Go next.
Deploy providers.
So Bienstock.
Application name and the environment name.
So as we already created our being stack environment and so in the same region.
So it will also show the name and the environment name.
We can select that go next.
Create pipeline.
As soon as I create the pipeline, I have to say stop execution right now.
Put some comment quickly.
Stop.
Already started disabled transition.
So already went.
Okay, it's stopping.
Okay.
It's still in progress.
It's not stopping.
But I have disabled the transition to for the deployment.
I don't want it to deploy it right now.
So if it triggered automatically just to disable transmission and then you can transition and then you
can later enable the transmission.
Okay.
Now, instead of waiting for that job to stop, we will edit this pipeline and we'll stitch all the
jobs together now.
So let's go to edit.
So before we are building.
I would like to run a sonar analysis of code analysis stage.
At a new stage at the action.
It also is a code analysis.
Provider code build.
Input Artifact.
Source Artifact.
So download the source code.
Project Name.
So this is our project which is doing code analysis.
Any output artefact we want to give?
No, just done.
Okay.
After this.
Another job.
The previous job from our CI pipeline, which is going to build.
And store the artifacts.
So let's give that name and stage.
Add action.
We give the same name.
Provider could build.
Input Artifact Source Artifact.
Project name.
So this is the job the build job from was CI pipeline.
Let's select that.
Output artifact will give us build artifact.
So this is the name that we can select in the next job, which is going to deploy the artifact to S3
bucket.
That is also done.
And then add a stage to deploy the artifact to S3 bucket.
So let me just deploy 2x3.
Add action deployed to three same name action provider.
Amazon is three.
Input artifact as build artifact.
Bucket name, same as we selected in the CI pipeline.
We profile artifact storage extract before deploy.
And done.
Okay.
This job is also completed.
So let's check once again.
Fetch the source code, do code analysis then job to build and store.
And this is going to store to the S3 bucket.
Next, we have a build job.
So this job is going to deploy the artifact.
The next job will deploy the artifact to the bean stack.
Edit this job and build artifact.
Let's give a name.
Build artifact to be.
And say, Done here.
And that is going to deploy the artifact to the stack.
You have to edit this.
Hear input, artifact, build artifact to been.
So the previous job, which is generating the artifact, will be with this name.
So it's going to fetch that as an input artifact and deploy to Bienstock.
Okay, so let's say done.
This is done.
The last job is going to be running the software testing.
So let's add a stage.
Mm.
Software testing.
Let's copy that.
Add action.
Software testing action provider code build.
Input artifact is going to be the source code that we fetch.
And this one is going to fetch the Selenium Auto script branch.
Project name software testing.
This is the build job that we created already.
And that should be it.
Let's say dun dun.
Steer clear of the naming convention.
Initially to go with.
You can use the same naming convention that I am using.
Then later, when you change and make sure you're referring it in the same in the pipeline.
So our pipeline is created.
Let's finally save this save.
Okay, let's check again.
So it's going to fetch the source code.
Branch city hyphenated US code analysis will run.
Build and store a build job which we will use to store the artifact.
Deployed to a store is going to store the artifact to the bucket.
One more build job.
Which will build the artifact so we can deploy it on Bean's tax or next job is to deploy two elastic
bins.
Tag.
And then finally, a software testing job.
This is also a code build job which is going to run our software testing.
Now it's time to test it finally.
So let's say release change.
Click on release.
And by the time this is happening, we'll also add our soon as notifications a new pipeline.
So we have to select the notification year also.
Not here.
Let's go to pipelines.
Let's select our pipeline.
Yeah, they are.
Notify manage notification rules.
Create notification rule.
So we'll see notification.
D pipeline hyphen notification.
Look if we profile.
Okay.
In detail notification.
We want a full notification and you can select all the all the events.
If you don't need any, just unselect them.
Target.
So we already have a target.
V Profile Pipeline notification.
Submit.
Okay.
That's nice.
Let's check our pipeline.
What's happening?
We are in the code analysis job now.
We can see the progress.
We can see the details.
Phase details.
It's in a build stage.
Let's check the build logs.
It's downloading dependency and it should download from code artefact.
While it's already running Sonar scanner.
Scroll up.
Up.
Again your previous logs.
This is all coming from cloud watch.
So you can really go to cloud watch and you can see it from there also.
Okay.
This usually hangs the browser.
They're finally got it.
So, yes, it's downloading the artifact from code.
Artifact.
Let's close this.
This just keeps hanging the browser.
I'll go to phase details.
Okay.
It's going to take some time.
Let's go to our pipeline back.
Pipelines.
It's in progress.
So let's keep this view and it's going to take a longer time.
By the time I'm going to pause my screen and come back when it's done.
Okay.
We are at deploy to study that is completed successfully in the build job is running.
If you have disabled the transition, then make sure you enable the transition.
Otherwise the deployment job will not trigger and will not have a deployment on bienstock environment.
So make sure you enable the transition.