So we see the deploy to be stacked job also completed successfully now after a few minutes and we can
really go to our bean stack environment.
And that's the URL.
Recent event Like a new application version.
Let's check the application versions.
That's the new version.
It got deployed.
Let's check whether it's really working or not.
So we have the URL.
Click on it.
So yes, that's working.
Let's try to login.
The login works.
The ideas connection will be also verified.
Okay.
I have to enable the sticky session.
Configuration.
Okay, so that's the issue with our V profile application.
We have to put the sticky session enabled.
So configuration load balancer.
US in the health check.
Edit and.
Sticky session policy enabled.
If your single instance this is not going to be a problem, but when you have multiple instance, we
have to do this apply.
Okay.
Sticky session enabled.
Now let's try log in once again.
Let's refresh.
So software testing job is also going to do the same thing.
It's going to log in.
So we have to make sure this sticky session we have you have to enable before the software testing job
completes.
Okay, it's working and we hope our software testing job also finds that.
Let's check in the detail of software testing job.
What's happening?
Let's scroll till the end.
Whoops.
Okay, good.
It's just still sleeping, which is very good.
Because after this it's going to do the test as we did.
Same thing.
It's going to open a browser, do a login, take a screenshot and put it in the S3 bucket.
So let's wait for a few more minutes.
Let's go back to our pipeline.
After a few minutes, the software testing job failed.
I checked in the details and it's because I have given.
And let's go to these details.
Okay.
In the build stage, I have given the wrong URL.
I have not updated the URL, so I'm going to go back to this job.
Build project.
Software testing.
Edit build spec file.
And we'll change the right URL.
That's the URL.
Let's copy that.
Okay, Let me verify once again, you all.
The URL slash login username password is good.
Let's update this file.
And we go to Pipeline.
And we go to our failed job and we can retry it.
Let's retry.
So we have a sleep also there, 360 seconds.
So it's going to also wait for 360 seconds before it actually executes.
So I will pause my screen and come back when this is done.
Okay, so this job completed successfully.
Let's see the output.
So there's a lot of logs.
Let's go down.
Yeah, that's a success.
But really, it's not so much visible over here.
The output will be in the S3 bucket.
So we can find the screenshot when it log in.
It's going to take two screenshots.
So if this is really a success, which you're able to see those screenshots, successful log in screenshot.
So let's go to a three bucket.
So this was the target S3 bucket for the job.
And there is a directory.
Actually, it's a zip file.
Let's download it.
Okay, let's open this.
Okay.
You see a directory called screenshots over there.
Open it and you see two screenshots.
Let's see, what do they contain?
And there we go.
So it was a successful login.
So selenium test suit got executed successfully, successfully tested our site.
And everything checks out fine.
We can also see that in our bienstock.
The link is live.
We can log in and we can test it much further.
All right.
So that was a success, right?
Same thing.
The selenium test suit really tested.
All right.
So we have completed everything in this project.
It's time for clean up.
So here we really need to do some cleanup because it's been stack and it has to be two instances.
So either you can delete this environment altogether or you can change the auto scaling group size set.
You can set the size to zero so it will just delete your easy two instances.
But then you also have ideas.
Now you can shut down the ideas.
You can stop the ideas instance, if you will.
But the story charges will be still there.
We are using 20 GB, but if you have anything else so total to no more than 30 GB is out of free to
right?
So you can delete it or if you can, if you want, you can just shut it down.
So I'm going to delete it now.
So that is going to take some time to delete and easy to instances will also get deleted from the bean
stack.
And we really don't need to delete the pipeline.
It's not going to charge us anything.
It will only charge when we run it.
And anyways, we are in the free tier, so no charges really.
Okay, so then let's conclude with our architectural design.
So we test, we make a code change, the entire pipeline gets triggered, code commit triggers the sonar
code, build job, download any dependency from code artifact, then a code build job.
It needs a dependency.
It downloads from our code artifact stores the output to the three bucket.
A deploy service is going to deploy an artifact to a bienstock, which is connected to IEDs.
And selenium tested will get executed from another code build job and the output will be stored to S3
bucket.
You've seen the screenshots also.
So I hope you like this video.
You enjoyed the project and learned a lot.
So keep practicing.
I will see you in the next video.
Thank you very much for watching.