Welcome to the next project.
The name of this project is complete Provisioning with Ansible.
This project is a continuation of the previous project, the project where we did Ansible for eight
years.
It's continuation of that project.
So in that project A was.
VPC setup we have done by using Ansible.
In this project On that VPC, we are going to set up our V profile application stack.
So our project is lift and shift.
In that project.
We have set up some bunch of EC two instances and on that we have provisioned V profile stack and all
the services, my SQL mem cache, rabbit, MQ, Tomcat, all those things we are going to automatically
set up by using Ansible.
So you can say this project is a combination of two other projects, but this will be completely automated.
So let's see when, where, how.
Okay, let's see the scenario and what are the problems?
Okay, let's see.
You have an operations team, and this team will do the regular deployment and set up commonly.
You can also call this team as sys admin team or systems engineer team, so they'll be in charge of
managing all the operating systems in your infrastructure, cloud setup, virtual machine setup and
all the changes and they will get regular request of provisioning or making changes to the infrastructure.
Today we're living in a time of agile.
Everything needs to be agile quick.
And also we have a lot of disposable environment pre prod environments which are really disposable and
such kind of request comes very regularly.
So the team will get request to set up the complete infrastructure.
Which is complex.
There are so many moving parts.
You'll have different services, you will have network, you'll have security, you'll have high availability.
So setting up that entire stack is really complex, time consuming work.
Moreover, if you want to do it again and again, it's not repeatable.
Right.
I'm talking about, you know, humanly speaking.
Doing the same thing again and again.
And also making regular changes, making regular changes.
It's difficult to track if the changes are happening manually or like through a human, of course.
So those things are really difficult to track.
And when there's human intervention, there is always chance of making mistakes which can lead to no
highly time.
Also managing all those things is a time consuming work.
You need people, a lot of people, a lot of operations engineer to manage all those things your cloud
infrastructure, your services, your operating system, and making regular changes to them.
Again, keep in mind, in today's time, we need to be more agile.
So instead of human doing it again and again.
We need to have a configuration management system of our entire infrastructure.
So an automation framework, a tool that can manage all the configuration of our infrastructure automatically.
So we're talking about automatic setup.
If you have a new provisioning or any changes, you're going to do it automatically.
So no or really less chance of making human errors.
Also, everything will be centralized, so any changes that happens will be centralized.
And if you have that as a code so you can version control it, so you have infrastructure as a code.
And when you have a code to manage your infrastructure, it's repeatable.
We can execute it as many as time we want.
Also, it's reusable.
So you can reuse this infrastructure as a code across your projects.
We already talked about the statistics of cloud automation.
Now, automation is not just cool thing to do.
It really adds business value.
And more than 70% of IT companies are telling that they are having 10% more revenue growth.
84% of them are telling.
They have really lowered the operations cost.
81% are telling that they have become more innovative.
Now, that's very important.
When you hand over your work to a tool to a machine.
Then you have more time to find more innovative solutions to your problem.
You become more agile.
So 84% of the I.T organization are saying that they have become more agile, which is need of the hour.
So in this project, we're going to use Ansible for configuration management.
And our entire stack will be set up on a cloud platform.
We're here talking about complete provisioning, VPC security group instances when the stack is ready.
We are going to set up services on two instances.
My SQL mem cache, Rabbit, MQ, Tomcat Engine X, all those services for V profile project.
Also with the load balancer.
So the entire execution is threefold.
First, we're going to set up a VPC, which we already did in our previous project.
So we have the code from the previous project and Sybil for us in that project.
So we're going to pull that code from our repository execute, which is going to set up the entire VPC
stack.
That's one next.
We're going to provision easy two instances load balancer and security group.
Easy two instances for our V profile stack or all the V profiles project services, my SQL mem cache
rabbit Q don't get an engine so just easy.
Two instances.
Next, we are going to see how we will provision the entire V profile stack.
So the easy two instances that got created on them.
We're going to install services, configure and, and do the entire setup.
Really, we're going to build artifact, set up my SQL mem cache, rabbit, MQ, Tomcat and engine X.
Now we'll see the architectural design.
We have three architectural design in this project, one for VPC that you have already seen.
Second for two instances, third for provisioning V profile stack.
So let's see it.
Okay, This designer is for our VPC set up, so we have playbook for setting up VPC from our previous
project.
Which will have variables, configuration and list of modules which is going to use Python both to make
a connection to a cloud account.
Create VPC in that VPC will have subnets distributed in multiple zones.
We'll have public subnets.
With an Internet gateway connection.
We'll have private subnets.
Connecting with the round table that's going to forward the request to the NAD Gateway.
And also the Bastion host, which is inside a security group.
So this is the same design from the previous project.
We're going to pull the code, execute the playbook, and we'll set up this stack.
So that's first execution, second execution, the second execution playbook, which is going to access
our easy to service.
Which will have variables that got created in the previous project and also a lot of modules.
Again, it's going to use Python to make an API connection to our account and the VPC that we created
in the previous execution.
We will have a public subnet in that.
We'll have an application load balancer.
So we'll create an application load balancer in public subnet.
In private subnet.
We're going to have c two instances for our V profile services, the Tomcat, Rabbit, MQ, MySQL,
all of that.
And it will be distributed in two private zones.
And it is easy to instance, will also have security groups.
So security group will also get created.
And our instances will be divided into or distributed into two private subnets.
Also, there is a bastion host from the previous setup.
Also, not to mention there will be key payers also that we are going to create.
So this is the second execution.
Now, once we have our infrastructure ready.
We can provision our services.
So a third execution now in the third execution will have playbooks, which is going to set up our V
stack provision of services.
So we'll have the inventory file.
This will get created automatically in the second execution where we launch these two instances.
So it's going to use those inventory file and all the modules.
So this is no API execution.
Python is going to use such connection as a switch to the easy two instances that we created in the
previous execution.
My SQL setup.
So again, my SQL ec2 instance will be in a private subnet of the VPC.
So we provision my SQL service, then mem cache service, then rabbit MQ service and Tomcat service
and finally engine service.
We're also going to create a load balancer in the second execution.
So instances will be already mapped.
As soon as your engine service comes up, the instance will become healthy and you can access it from
the load balancer.
So again forced VPC stack setup.
Second instances and load balancer setup.
Third fee profile stack provisioning.
All right.
So we have a lot of things to do.
Let's get started.
So this is what you're going to do.
And in this order, we get into a plus account, we're going to create an easy to instance to run our
Ansible playbook.
Will install Ansible and bot on that.
We'll set up an easy to role for Ansible.
We should already have this role from our previous project, Ansible for us so we can use the same thing.
If you have not deleted the ansible control machine so you can use the same, you don't need to launch
another issue for instance.
In any case, we fetch the source code from our project.
Previous project Ansible for us, which has the source code to set up VPC, we'll execute that VPC playbook
which will set up the VPC stack.
Then we'll write the playbooks to launch an easy to instance load balancer, security group and few
other things.
We have like key pairs for our V profile stack.
We'll get into.
We profile VPC after this third execution where we want to access the private instances in private subnet
is not possible from our ansible control machine because ansible control machine will be in a default
VPC or we profile VPC at two different network.
So we will not be able to connect to private instances in our private subnets.
So we need to get into the VPC.
We profile VPC and there are a few ways either you can use Bastion Host or you can launch the controller
in the in the V profile VPC in the public subnet.
We can do that.
So the few ways we'll see both ways launching the controller in the we profile VPC and also we can use
the Bastion host also.
Then it's going to be your choice.
Once we are in the VPC, our easy for instance is in the VPC controller is in the VPC.
Then we'll write playbooks to set up our V profile stack here to remember.
Ansible is going to do SSH too easy, for instance to install those services to access the operating
system so it's not possible from the default VPC to log in to the V Pro to get into we profile VPC.
We can do VPC peering though.
Okay.
But that's again too much for now.
So we'll see simpler approach in this area.
Let's get started now.