Okay, let's get started.
I am in my Intel ID source code from the VPC setup project, so we have the VPC setup playbook there.
Variables that we used previously.
And output underscore vars, which will be very useful in this project execution.
So we had a VPC setup playbook.
Bastion host set up playbook.
And we are continuously putting it in our GitHub.
You know, repository.
What will do will not touch this code, will create a separate branch, will name it as a V profile
stack.
So we created a new branch.
Let's fetch that.
All right.
And we switch to that branch and let's start making changes somehow.
So, Bastian, set up variables.
I'm going to take this.
Variables and we'll put it in a VPC set of variables.
So we'll merge both the variables file.
So regions already region is already mentioned.
So let's remove that.
Dustin Vase.
Since it's there, let's remove this bastion set file.
You don't need this.
Now we'll create a common Playbook site which will call these two Playbook VP's setup and Bastion Setup
Playbook.