Now we'll launch an easy to instance, install Ansible in that and fetch this code and execute.
So let's launch instance again.
I'm in Ohio region.
And I'll go with Open to 20.
D2 Micro should be fine.
And let's provision it with Ansible.
But also where to install will install it after it comes up.
Mm.
Controller.
I'm going to select the same security group.
Now.
I already have.
And the same login key.
Instance, is running.
I will update the security group.
To allow connection from my IP if it changed.
Yes, it changed.
And let's log into this instance.
Instance is up.
We logged in.
Let's check the Ansible version.
To be good.
Now, other two things we're going to install bottle and we're going to also attach item policy so this
instance can access ADA services.
So we'll install python three, hyphen bottle, three python three hyphen bottle code, which anyways
gets installed as a dependency, then python three hyphen bottle.
Let's install.
Okay, that's done.
Let's attach an item roll.
If you don't have it all, if you delete it, then recreate the IM role.
Which has full access.
To all the services.
Let's attach that.
I am role to our instance.
Now let's fetch our source code.
Get clone and let's get the repository URL.
So you should have also the repository that you created.
In previous projects you can use that or either you can use our project repository there.
Also, we have all this.
If you have not created a repository, then whatever code that you have written in the previous project,
you can just copy to the control machine.
You can use CB.
Let's get into the repository.
And we'll see the branch.
So we just created a branch that we will check out to that branch.
Kid, Check out the profile stack.
Right.
So we have Sitewide playbook that is going to in turn call VPC, set up Playbook and Bastion instance,
set up playbook.
It will need variables from the vast directory.
So we have the variables and this output vars.
If you want we can delete.
It will be no new file now to generate a new file anyways, if the file exists, can override that file.