Okay, so let's do the execution.
Ansible hyphen playbook ci dot AML.
So it's creating everything.
VPC all our subnets.
Internet Gateway Route table for Internet Gateway.
Now it's creating the net gateway, which will take some time.
So I'm going to pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
So VPC set up, but when we're creating Bastion host, it failed.
That's because we have removed the Bastion host variables file but we did not make the change in the
Bastion instance yaml.
There.
It's important.
It's trying to include that variables file which does not exist.
Instead of that, we have the VPC variable file that we have to import.
So let's do it again from our ID.
That's an instance.
Not that we need VPC.
Underscore Setup.
VPC.
Underscore.
Set up.
Let's save it.
Committed.
Completed vars file in Bastion.
And let's push the change.
Okay, let's fetch it.
Okay, let's try the execution once again.
So we already set up all subnets.
Everything is good.
So it's just going to say, okay.
And this looks good.
Now it's importing.
It has imported the variables file.
Created security group, for Bastion instance, and it has stopped launching the Bastion host.
Yeah, worse.
We pick out set up variable.
If you have not updated your my IP over here, make sure you change that and you can reapply the change
if you want.
Okay, we should have output vars file and we have all the information, all the IDs of VPC, subnet,
internet gateway, everything.
We should be a very vital information for our next execution.
So our first execution completed, we should have VPC with all the details.
Second execution.
We are going to write a playbook to set up our easy two instances load balancer and security group for
our V profile stack.