So let's get to our intelligent.
So we'll create a new playbook now.
New file limit as we pro hyphen easy to hyphen stack.
Dr. Wymer, This should be good.
Okay, so all the Google settings set up, we profile stack name of the play, getting executed on local
host connection, local gather facts know or you can give false.
Now list of task First we'll include our variables file.
So we include our VPC output, underscore VARs and the existing file that we have.
And the file that we have over here has changed now.
So we should also come at it from here, push it to GitHub and fetch it in our intelligent.
Or if that's too much, let's let's just copy all that.
And just open, intelligent.
I'll put words and just overwrite it.
Also the public IP.
Also, we have changed.
Write my IP so we can override these settings as well.
Save.
Let's commit.
Let's push it.
So you have to make sure both the repositories are saying if you want to ignore some file over here,
you can ignore it.
You can use git ignored.
And we'll do that in a moment because we are going to create key pair.
And I don't want that key pair to be uploading to GitHub.
We have a conflict.
It's saying this file will be overridden by the setting that you have made, and we are fine with that.
So no problem.
Let's just commit that.
We just committed.
You have said the gate conflict global username and email.
Let's it.
Okay.
And then I'm going to pull it.
And.
Yes, Majid.
I'm fine with that message.
Now all the changes are in sync.
Let's continue our work.
So including variables.
Right.
So we'll also we're also going to launch a lot of two instances for my SQL rabbit MQ Tomcat.
All the instances and those instances needs my ID, We will provide that again through a variable file.
So we'll create one more variable file.
We'll see in New.
File.
The limit is the pro stack setup.
That should be fine.
It's a text file.
To find the ID, we can go to this site.
One to to find we're going to use Ubuntu.
So to find Ubuntu army we can go to the site cloud images, ubuntu dot com locator and we're looking
for ubuntu 18 so we can give the 1 to 18 or we can give the code name of this bionic 1 to 18 is called
bionic.
We are doing it in the region us east to.
So let's find that.
Yes us ist to vm ebs sd based OC.
This should be good.
There's also a chance that our playbook doesn't find that.
Amy.
Maybe we're given a wrong Ahmed.
Or maybe this is an old Ahmed.
So if we get into that situation, we'll come back, we'll find any other Amy, and we'll use them.
So let's create a set of variables for them now.
So for all the instances, we'll use the same Amy Engine x Amy.
So yes, we're using save my ID for all the instances, okay.
Where there's name change.
But then you have it in variables file.
If you wish to change, you can change the image.
But a stack is focusing on ubuntu.
So make sure it's open to.
Let's see if this file.
Now we import or include these variables file in our playbook.
So hereafter, if we need any variables for our V profile instance setup, we'll use this variables
file.
We'll also need a key to log into our instances.
So let's create a key pair.
Easy to underscore.
Key module we are creating in the region that we specified in the variables file and we're going to
store the output.
Then we'll store the output of the output that it returns into a text file, the PEM file we're going
to create.
Yeah.
So register that output and variable dot key private key.
We're storing it into this file.
Only when.
Its values change.
So when the key is created, then only it's going to save it into the file.
And that will save only when this condition is true.
When the pro key underscore out dot changed, right?
So if this returns true, if this creates a key, then only this is going to save the key.
There are few changes we need to do again.
So variables file vpc, hyphen output underscore vars.
Let's copy that.
And our variables.
Volume is different, output underscore versus.
So either you can change this or you can change that.
So I'm going to change the name of this file.
Rename it with this name.
The Factor.
Do re factor.
Okay, let's get into that.
This seems good.
Unavailable file it is importing is the plus tax setup, which is this one.
We are referring to a variable called US region.
And let's check that where the region is defined there or not, It's not defined.
So we can define it over here.
Or if you want, we can also import VPC set up playbook.
So in VPC set up, not playbooks or in VPC set up variables file, we have the region defined.
So let's include this variable file as well.
Now, if you're thinking why so many variables file, why not put everything in one file?
Well, you know, it will be easy for us to access the variables if they are distributed in different
files.
So VPC setup variables are in this file stack set up variables in other file output is in other file.
Now any of these, we don't need these all these variables to be imported in our playbook.
So we just need this region variable and we can just put it into.
Oh, here.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Region Is this US East too?
Okay, let's save all this.
Let's also save this file.
Close this.
We need this now.
So a playbook that is importing two variables file.
We have them.
We need variables.
Those variables are present on those in those files.
So we.
Good?
Let's commit it.
Let's push it.
Okay, it's pushed.
Now, if you have different codes that you may end up into a lot of conflict, don't you need to waste
your time in solving those conflict?
Let's delete the repository and clone it once again.
If you get into conflicts.
Yet, Branch.
So we'll check out to this branch.
We profile stack.
Just to be sure.
If you want, you can execute the sidecar playbook once again.
Check your VPC.
Check your bastion host.
If everything is good, we can move ahead.
Now, I created some new data.
We updated the VPC output file.
We created key for the Bastion host.
Which got saved.
So our repository did change.
It got drifted.
So we can push our code from here to GitHub.
Except we are not going to push the key the to Bastion, key, dot, PEM or any file for that matter.
So we'll create a get ignored file.
Since the repository you create a container file don't get ignored.
It should be hidden.
And you mentioned the files that you don't want to commit, especially PEM files.
So we're going to say start Pem.
And a IT ad dot.
Get.
Comet hyphen m.
And let's push it.
Okay.
It's synced with our remote repository.
Let's also fetch the changes from here.
To say it is to file updated so we have get ignored file.
And this file.
The output output file then got updated.
And if you see we don't have the key here, right.
The login key didn't come.
Let's check from GitHub also.
So there's no penfill see that.
So such kind of important things like login key or even if you want to know the output of a file output
of your playbooks or any confidential information you should really ignore.
Because when you set up a stack, it will generate a lot of valuable information that can prove very
valuable to people who want to exploit it.
So keep that in mind when you're working in projects.
Also, we'll test our playbook, which is going to create key pair for a V profile stack.
Okay.
I think we made a made a mistake VPC hyphen VPC output words.
That's not good.
Let's go to Intel AG.
Yeah.
The name of the file is VPC hyphen output underscore vars.
Save it.
Let's come at it.
Let's try once again.
No, I think region is also not defined.
Probably that happened when we're committing things.
Okay.
Finally.
So it's good.
We caught the error in the very beginning before we when we launched the stack, before you put too
many things in our playbook, too many tasks.
It's better you put some task execute so it will validate your variables, file variables, name and
everything.
And I recommend it may be looking a little painful, but I recommend you do it through version control,
because when you're working in a project, you'll be working in a team.
So making code changes on the machine, either on your local machine or on, or only on the control
machine.
This data will be on that particular machine.
It will not be sync with individuals who are working in your team.
So do it through version control.
Push the change to the version, control.
Then fetch it and then execute.
Also know if you use ID, it becomes easier for you to see the YAML syntax and for that matter any syntax,
JSON or any bash scripts or python script.
Okay.
After this, the flow of the playbook will be like this.
The objective of this playbook is to create our easy two instances for we profile stack.
But the flow will be like this.
First, we'll create security group for load balancer.
Then we'll create security group for E two instances.
Then we'll launch easy to instance.
Then we'll launch load balancer.
And also we'll add our engineers, for instance, under the load balancer, and also we'll store all
the private IPS, for instance, into another variable file which can be reused later.