So next thing you know is creating load balancer security group.
No, because the model is to underscore group name of the load balancer security group sum description
region variable coming from our variable file vpc ID also coming from our variable file.
Yeah.
There.
Region and the VP side.
Okay, let's mention the rules.
So load balancer security group, you're going to allow Port 80 from anywhere.
Okay, so list of rules.
First item protocol TCP from Port 82.8 and allowed from anywhere.
And of course, if you store the output into a variable.
Let's see if it's in the same line as the model.
Yes.
Okay, One more security group for V profile is two instances.
Again, same model, easy to group name Description Region VPC ID.
I'm going to give one option over here.
Birch underscore rules.
No.
The reason I'm giving this option is when you execute this playbook, it will create security.
When you execute this playbook, once again, it will once again update the rules.
Even if the rules are the same.
So by default, it's not important.
So this rule, this option purge, underscore rules.
No will make it potent.
So if the port numbers, if all the rules are same, then it is not going to do it once again, it's
not going to delete the rules and recreate them.
So let's give the rules.
Okay, So 88.80 allowed from Load Balancer Security Group.
So we're creating load balancer security group.
We store.
The variable over there, the output.
And in that we have the key group ID.
So I'm going to say allow Port 80 from the load Balancer security group.
Okay.
There we have CIDR IP because you have to mention IP address here.
Here we have to mention group ID.
So option is group ID and the group ID from where you want to allow.
And under rule 22 allowed from Bastion Security group ID while Bastion security Group ID is nowhere.
I've just given that variable, but we have to either define that variable or we have to automatically
store it when we execute the Bastion playbook.
So if we can put this into this file.
We need to give the idea of this.
How do we get this idea?
It's very simple.
You can execute the playbook once again.
You can check it also from a console if you want.
But I will execute.
Bastion instance will.
Okay.
Does not print anything.
Let's update this.
Now, again, I'm not going to make any updates from here.
We'll do it from ID.
And so far, whatever is done, you can just save it and committed.
And let's pull all the changes first.
Okay, let's go back to our ID again.
Not my bastion instance y yaml file.
I'm going to.
I'm storing the output of everything k, but I'm not storing it into any variable that.
So if you want to store it into the same file, I don't want to create one more variables file for this
all the output.
I want to keep it into the same file vpc output vars file.
So we'll use here.
Not copy module, but another module block in file.
So we are going to update this file its variables file with this module block in file.
You mentioned the path of the file.
Back up.
Yes.
If you want to take the backup, you can say backup.
BLOCK And so it's going to add a block or update a block, Insert a block, and the block is just block
of text, right?
So this is the text.
And security group ID.
Gerri, is your story here?
Also there.
Indentation.
That's the biggest problem in Ansible.
How should I say yaml?
Okay, because it's very easy to miss these things.
So let's commit.
Let's push the change.
Okay, Let's fetch the change.
And let's do the execution now.
Okay.
That made some change.
Let's check that.
Check out variables.
Fine.
So you'll see in the output file.
Bastion security group ID.
Yet again.
This change is in the control machine.
We are going to push it back to GitHub.
Nancy Bush.
Okay, that's done.
So make sure you pull the changes here so we don't have conflict.
Okay, we're getting an error, and that's because of the backup file name.
So it takes backup if given that option, takes the backup of that file.
Yes.
And there is this at the rate time and.
This.
Tilda Okay, so this is creating the problem.
It is saying the wrong invalid part.
So let's let's remove that file.
We don't need it anyways.
We can change its name, but let's remove it.
We don't need it.
Really.
I guess we're going to say guitar, right?
So it also removes from the index that's committed.
I guess every time I do get pushed, I have to enter the username and password to save that time.
You can do search login with GitHub.
But for now, I'll skip it.
Okay, let's go to ID.
Let's fetch all the changes.
Seems like it's done.
Let's check.
No, not here.
There.
Yeah.
Good.
And then we can refer that variable.
All right.
So we profile stack instances can be only accessed from the bastion host.
So we have to log into the Bastion host from there.
We have to log into instances which are in private subnet.
And for that reason, we have given that Rule 22 allowed from Bastion Security Group ID.
Okay.
Now we have to update one more rule in the same security group ID, the same security group.
All our instances will be in one same security group and they will be interacting with each other,
Tomcat, accessing my SQL and accessing my SQL.
So we need to give a rule all traffic.
It is all traffic is allowed internally in the security group, same security group.
And for that we have to update the security group rule.
Okay, so we are add another task, easy to group, same security group as we are creating here.
Same secret group, similar description You can give region VPC ID rules.
No.
Now this ad's very much important.
No meaning over here, because we are now going to add rules, protocol, all group ID, its own group
ID, which is we create a security group, store the output.
So basically we're updating same security group and we're saying all traffic is allowed from itself.
If you have not given this option, then it will remove all the previous rules and add this rule so
it will remove these rules also.
So make sure that option is there for rules.
No.
So it will keep existing rule as it is and add the new rule.
Time to test this.
So let's save Comet.
Okay, Let's just check once again.
Indentation.
Seems good.
As of now, let's find out.
Get pull.
Okay, now, this time we'll execute the Playbook approach.
See two Previously, when we executed this, it created the key pair.
Now it's going to keep the key pair as it is and create the security groups.
Unsupported parameters for module rule.
Okay.
So I have given an option called us rule.
It's actually rules.
So there's a mistake.
So I'll fix it.
It's here.
Typographical error.
Very common things.
She read the error and you will find out.
Well, the mistake is.
Okay.
Now let's get bold and try once again.
Okay, so it's done, but with some weird output, it's giving warning ran out of time for the security
group.
Let's validate that.
The security group.
Action.
Let's check our security group.
The LP security group should allow a team from anywhere.
We profile Stack's security group.
They should allow aid from the load balancer.
All traffic from Stack is G.
That is correct by itself.
And allowing 22 from Bastion hosts G.
This looks good.
Okay.
So as of now, we're good and we are covered.
And it's just a warning, not an error, but may cause some problem later.
So we'll see that later.