Okay, now, next thing.
Now we have security group, we have keeper.
Now it's time to launch a reset instance and also create load balancer for engine X instance.
Okay, so we'll create one engine X, one application, Tomcat, one mem cache one rabbit can one my
SQL.
If you want multiples, you can mention it multiple times and you can mention the other private subnet.
But to keep it low cost, we'll just launch one one single, single instance.
So again, same as the Bastion host.
Easy module.
The key that we have created region instance type data to micro image engine X underscore amika.
That is coming from our.
It's variables file, right.
And we are not so sure.
We may even need to update this image file.
We'll see that at the time of execution where it is.
Yes.
Wait.
Time of 300 seconds.
Instance tags.
So as many tags I give out here.
Exactly.
Same tag I'm going to give in count tags, exact count to one.
So it will not launch the instance again and again.
As I explained this in the previous project, when you execute the playbook, it will count whether
this tag exists or not.
One time, if it exist, it will not launch the instance.
If it does not exist, then only it will launch the instance.
That will make our task important.
Group ID We are going to put in the security group that we created.
Right there that we mentioning over here.
If they're restoring the output, we create the security group for V profile stack.
We store the output and then we're using it over here, VPC, subnet ID.
Now we're going to place it in our VPC private subnet.
So we mentioned the variable private sub one ID, and that is in our output file.
Yeah, we'll put all our instances in this subnet if you're launching multiple engine X or multiple
Tomcat.
Then you mention the other subnet ID.
So the high available architecture and we stored the output into this variable.
So it's good if you write all this code by yourself.
But even if you don't want to write, we have all this in our source code repository on GitHub in the
Ansible branch.
You can check that and you can use those playbooks also if you want, but I still recommend you write
all this task.
So you'll get issues, you'll get indentation error, you'll fix it.
So that's Engine X, Web zero one.
We're giving Tiger also as Web zero one similar way we'll launch other instances.
Tomcat.
Trading Tomcat app zero one Similar thing.
What changes is the tag name?
And subnet is also same.
So the only thing that changes is the tag name and the output where we're are registering this.
Can't, ma'am.
Cash.
Again.
Same thing.
Only the tag changes.
Of course, the Army variable is also changing, but you know, the value is same.
Store the output.
Ten rabbit MQ.
EMI dag and the output variable different.
Final instance, my SQL.
DAC db zero one.
My SQL.
My The output variable.
So we are storing the output of every execution, every task.
Let's print one of them.
So because we're going to use them later.
So let's use a debug module.
Receive our.
So let's print this DB zero one and we'll see what is the output that comes because we need to get the
ID and private IPS from that.
So we'll print it and we'll see what is the output so we can get the right key.
See this and let's commit it.
Look, we can expect some failure because of the wrong Ahmed, but we'll find that out.
So let's execute our playbook.
I would like to stop in the middle and talk about a bug that we've been witnessing with security group.
If you are getting this error while you're creating the security group.
So this was a bug that made security group not important.
The fix is we can upgrade it to 2.9. ten.
Or even that warning that we were getting while we're creating security group.
That is because of a bug and it was really widespread.
So how can we upgrade to Ansible?
2.9. ten because if you say apt install ansible on ubuntu, it's going to download 2.9.9.
That's the latest version.
Currently at this time October 2020.
You may be lucky when you execute this and you may get 2.9. ten, which is good.
You will not have this problem, but if you have older than 2.9. ten, then you need to uninstall your
ansible and install latest ansible with PIP and I'll show you how you can do that.
So first simply install ansible, the existing ansible.
You have to say apt remove.
And civil.
I have already uninstalled it so I don't have it.
Then you can install Ansible with PIP that will give you the latest version, but you need to have PIP
so you can have the first install.
Pip.
You have to say sudo apt.
Install python three hyphen pip.
And just install it.
Once you have PIP installed, you can then use it.
You can say sudo.
Three.
Install ansible.
That should give you the latest version of ansible.
So you see there two dot 10.1.
Now, once this is done, if you still you're running the Ansible command and using command not found,
then a logout and login.
If you're not given sudo it means to call it in your home directory.
So you need to log out and log in.
Yeah.
Then you can check the version.
Ansible hyphen, hyphen version.
2.1.2.
Okay.
So that's the update.
Now, you can continue watching the video.
Okay.
So as we are already discussing about the Army ID, but you don't get a specific error about that.
If you mention a wrong ID or the instance type, you select a T to micro and that is not supported by
the image that you're using.
There is a conflict.
You'll get error like this.
So let's change the Ahmed.
Let's change it to latest one.
Let's see.
What is the latest, Amy?
ID?
So again, you can find the Omid from the site, but if you really need the latest instance, you can
just say launch instance.
In the quick start, you can find the Omid.
Okay there.
So let's copy that.
Let's go to our ID.
Well, let's update it.
Now EMI ID conflicts are a very common problem when you're using Ansible and it may give you different
different errors which may be more confusing.
So check if your ID is correct.
Okay, now let's test it.
So will this latest changes.
And let's do the execution.
Trading seems like it's now creating or launching these two incidents.
Let's go to a management console and check.
Okay, There's one instance coming up.
Web zero one.
So you saw that there were that was an image problem.
The T two micro instance was not supporting that image, but we're getting very different error.
Okay, So we'll wait for a few minutes until all the instances are up and running.
All right.
All the instances are created if you see over here.
And they should be all in the same security group.
The pro stack security group with the login key.
We key.
How if we see the output, we have printed the output of DB zero one out the variable that we store.
And from this, if you want to get the instance ID, we can go to tag instance tags tagged instances
under that you have Now this is the list.
So the first element in the list you can have the ID.
It's a list.
So zero dot ID or you want to get the private IP or we don't have public DNS.
This is a private instance, so we do not have a public IP or you want to get the region or you want
to get the tags.