Next step is we're going to create elastic load balancer.
We'll add engine X instance under that.
It will be not in service because we don't have any service running on Engine X instance, but we'll
add it for our third phase.
And while we do that, we'll also do a few more things.
We're going to take the private IP of all the instances and create a host file.
Okay, so let's go to our ID.
I guess, after creating the instances.
I want to really now also print the instance ID I want to show because in the next tasks I'm going to
add the IDs, the IP address into a file.
So DB zero one underscore out right Under that you have tagged instances.
Tagged instances and it's a list.
And we just need the first element in the list dot.
The instance.
Now just have ID.
Okay, This is just for printing purpose, just to show, you know, such kind of information.
We're going to store in a file.
So this is how we're creating load balancer.
We have a module called Local Action, and we can local action means it's going to get executed locally
and we can give a module name.
Module.
That's the module name of our load balancer.
Region, state, present instance IDs so you can add the instance IDs.
It's in a list format, so you can add a number of instance IDs if you want to add our engine X instance.
So web zero one underscore out.
Variable that we are storing.
Here Web zero one underscore out.
That's for engineers dot tagged underscore instance zero in square racket dot ID as we are doing it
over here.
Suppose instance it is.
If we say true, then it will remove the instances that we have not defined in this list.
So under this load balancer, if you have existing instances, those instances will be removed and only
the instances that we're mentioning over here will be added.
Security group.
The security group we created for the load balancer.
That's the variable subnets.
So this load balancer will get created in public subnet and we're giving the ID of the three public
subnet and which is coming from our output file.
And listeners, you can give a list of listeners.
We just have one listener we're going to listen on.
Port 80 HTTP Protocol.