Next thing.
What I'm going to do is.
The IP addresses.
Of all the instances that we created, the private IP, we are going to store it into a file.
So this task blocking file model we are using, we are going to create a file.
This will be our next execution.
For that, we are preparing variables already and we're going to create a directory provision at HYPHEN
Stack Group underscore virus inside data file host IP where we'll have IP address of all the instances.
The private IP is also we need to create these directories, so let's do that.
So we created provision hyphens tag inside that group underscore vars.
Next task we are going to copy our key that we created for our instances to this directory.
Provision Stack will copy it over there.
In this victory, you're going to write all the playbook to provision our services engine X, Tomcat,
rabbit, MQ, mem, cache, MySQL, all the services we're going to provision.
And for that we're going to write Playbook in this directory.
Next task is to prepare our inventory file.
So we're going to use block in file module.
We're going to prepare inventory file again, provision hyphen stack directory with the name inventory
hyphen vibro.
The BLOCK will be the name of the host.
Web 0101 RFC 0101 DB zero and Control Machine, which is really the local IP.
So ansible underscored host equal to the private IP.
So like that we prepare the host entry and then we're preparing also groups web server group app server
group.
DB server group, all these groups and also for the control machine.
Also, we are preparing a patent group and all these groups will be the child group.
Of course the username and password.
So stack underscore instance the parent group colon vars and we give the ansible underscore user one
two and the private login key.
And that's how we can automatically prepare our inventory file as we provision the instance.
So we get the IP address also automatically from this variables.
So we don't have to create inventory file manually for our next phase.
I'm going to save this file now and I'm going to update one more thing in VPC set up playbook.
Where we create these variables files automatically.
I also want to put the region over there.
So this variable file will also have the region variable automatically when you execute this VPC setup
playbook.
So we then don't have to manually mention our variables.
Mention the region into this file because this file gets updated every time you execute the VPC setup
playbook.
So it will overwrite if you don't have the region if you manually mentioned it.
All right, then it's time to do the rest of the things and finish our second phase.
So let's commit.
The changes are pushed.
Let's fetch our file.
Let's log in.
We got logged out.
Okay, It's done.
Now let's do the execution.
CS.
This file does not exist.
We have created the directory but it is not going to keep track of the directory.
So we have to create some empty file in this.
And let's again commit it.
All right.
So the execution completed successfully, and we should have new files now.
We should see that file.
Host IP.
So there we go.
We have the private IP of all the instances in a variable format.
We should also have the login key copied.
Provision stack directory.
And also the inventory file, which is very, very important.
So the next playbook that we're going to write, we're going to use this groups, these hosts.
And we created the inventory file automatically by using a register to store the output and then use
the keys from that and get the IP address and also getting the ID.
All right.
So a second phase execution completed.
We'll verify everything once again.
We have all the instances.
We should also have a load balancer.
There's this instance, Web zero one.
It will be out of service because the Internet service is not yet running over there.
We're going to do that in the third phase.