After this.
Before we move to the third phase, we will copy all this valuable information to our repository.
So let's get ad dot, get commit.
If your name.
And we'll push it.
Don't forget to fetch it in your ID.
All the changes.
Okay, So you'll see the host types, the groupers, you have the host types, then you have inventory
file.
Again, keeping all this in a private repository, it will be much better and safe.
Now, before we go to the third phase, if you would like to delete your stack, you can go ahead.
You can delete all the instances if you want, and we can provision it later by using the same playbooks.
So you can delete all the instances, you can keep controller for a while and you can shut it down.
You can delete all the instances, terminate them.
Once that is done, you can go to VPC.
And you can delete your VPC will be very easy to delete your VPC.
But first you have to delete the Nat Gateway Force.
Delete the Nat Gateway.
Wait for some time once the status is deleted.
Release the elastic IP.
Can release the elastic IP.
Once that is done, you can just go to your VPC.
You select your VPC and you can say Delete VPC.
When you delete VPC, it will delete subnet, root table and everything that is associated with it,
not the NAT gateway.
So you have to delete the Nat Gateway first.
If you wish, you can clean all this and then you can continue in the third phase where you can run
the playbook, set up the stack once again and continue with the third face execution.
Okay, If you're done here, join me in the third phase.