Welcome to the introductory session of TerraForm.
This is not a new project, but first we'll learn the basics of TerraForm and then we'll see how we
can use TerraForm for our project implementation.
If you already know TerraForm, then you can directly skip to the project video.
But if you're new to TerraForm, then you can continue with this video.
So let's get started.
Okay, so what really TerraForm is there are so many automation tools in the market.
TerraForm is infrastructure as a code so we can code IT infrastructure.
So we set up infrastructure on cloud computing environment like Google Cloud Azure, so you can manage
your infrastructure from TerraForm through code.
We can define the infrastructure state.
If you talk about a state or for instance, or for instance, security group load balancers, bienstock
or any such service you're using on a platform, you can define its state.
And TerraForm will make sure that your system's your infrastructure is in the same state.
So how does it compare with automation tool like Ansible, Puppet or Chef?
If you talk about these tools, these are configuration management tools for systems, mostly OS related
tasks.
They'll define the state of the machine to be specific, state of the operating system, what packages
should be installed, what vision, what configuration file we can use Ansible as and other automation
tool also to do cloud automation.
But these tools don't manage the state of the infrastructure.
We can see we can automate cloud with Ansible, but we can't maintain its state.
It doesn't maintain any state.
Everything is in a YAML file.
TerraForm, on the other hand, automates the infrastructure itself and also maintain its state.
Like any cloud provider, E.W. has Google Cloud, Azure Digital Ocean.
Now TerraForm, combining together with automation tools like Ansible can give you complete automation.
So once your infrastructure is set up and if you're provisioning easy to instances, launching easy
two instances with TerraForm, you'd like to provision it with some software packages you can use Ansible
with that, or even puppet or even chef.
Otherwise, normal batch scripting is also fine with TerraForm or even PowerShell scripting.
You don't need to know any programming language to use TerraForm.
You have come so far.
You have no you have done so many projects, you know, Ansible, you know, infrastructure, you know,
cloud computing.
It's just a matter of learning the syntax of TerraForm.
Once you know the TerraForm syntax and the basic execution, then you can use the TerraForm documentation
and write your complete automation or infrastructure state.
TerraForm does not have any programming language.
It has its own syntax domain specific language.
DSL, which is similar to JSON.
Very easy to understand.
And on top of that, you have great documentation.
Remember in Davos.
We need to automate everything we do.
We know how to automate systems with Ansible.
We can do also cloud automation.
With Ansible, we can do Cascade on Jenkins, we can do CSC on us.
But when it comes to the infrastructure itself, I find TerraForm is one of the best tools today in
the market to maintain the state of your cloud infrastructure and also to automate it.
So you have a centralized configuration management of your cloud infrastructure.
That sounds pretty awesome.
So what do you need?
Well, installing TerraForm is very easy.
There's a binary file.
You can just download it.
You have it for Linux Windows on Mac as well.
So you can just download the binary and you can store it in your path.
You can put in an environment variable in windows or you can export it in Linux or in Windows.
You can also do Choco install TerraForm.
That is also better.
So first exercise.
First exercise.
What we're going to do is launching easy to instance with TerraForm script, very basic.
So we need a native plus account.
We need an IAM user with access keys and we'll have a TerraForm file to launch our instance.
And then once we have that file, we're just going to say, Run!
TerraForm.
And TerraForm will launch our instance.
So this is the exercise we'll write.
Instance DOT to file.
TerraForm File ends with DF.
Kemp.
We're going to execute it, launch the instance, then we'll make some changes to those instances,
and then we're going to apply TerraForm again.
And we'll see how TerraForm maintains the state.
If your system, for instance, is not in the state as defined in your file, then it's going to reapply
the changes.
Then what are you waiting for?
Let's get started with TerraForm.
First will download a terraform.
On our Windows machine, we're going to execute TerraForm from Windows Machine.
If you want, you can execute it from MacBook Linux anywhere.
So you'll go to downloads in TerraForm and select your operating system of your choice.
You can go with Windows 64 bit.
It's going to download a zip file for you which you can extract and put it in your location like C Drive
Linux.
If you have just download it, put it into your local bin.
Extract this into your local bin and you should have terraform and then you have Mac OS and Windows.
The easiest way is actually to install it from Choco.
You can just open your PowerShell.
All right.
That's the most easiest way you can just say I have to open it as an administrator.
Paul Schell.
She.
And I can see just Choko install terraform.
I don't need to download the binary and extract it.
This is the easiest way.
Or if you want to do it this way, you can just download it, extract it.
You need to extract it to some location.
You can go to your C drive.
Maybe you can do it somewhere in the C drive.
I can create a folder.
Let's say TerraForm.
And you can extract it over there.
So I now have TerraForm Directory in the C Drive and this TerraForm Extractor.
Now we need to set this into systems variable so you can just search for environment variable.
You can edit environment variable.
Environment variable.
Right for my particular user, I can just edit the path and I can just add a new entry.
And I can just see.
Okay, so terraform.
Then I can directly start accessing TerraForm from the command line.
So.
Choose your way either download it binary and put the environment variable or the best way is just install
terraform.
In any case, you should have terraform.
Once you have TerraForm, we can start doing some automation, but I would like to set authentication
first.
We need authentication once you can define it as access key and secret key.
So we're using eight.
So we're going to use IAM user access key in secret key to access ADA services.
But the problem is then we have to define it in the data from file, which is not at all safe.
So install a CLI.
And set your access key on line.
So if you have done previous project, you should already have a CLI.
If you don't have your windows machine, just say choko, install a blue collar.
So say choko, install a plus c ally if you're on windows.
If your MacBook might be a MacBook, then you can just do your book ask install.
Yeah.
Once you have your blue collar installed, then just do a configure.
And set up your access key and secret key.
So we need an user.
We need a user.
So we'll go to a management console.
You go to Imam.
Yeah.
Let's create a user.
Mm.
Tera admin or This one is fine.
Write when.
Programmatic access.
So we're really going to do a lot of things with this user.
We need administrator access.
We're going to access a lot of services.
Let's let's download the credentials.
Okay.
I have my credentials now.
I'm going to copy paste that.
Now, again, I keep reminding to you in every project, do not share your credentials with everyone.
I'm showing you because I have to show.
But anyways, I'm going to delete it once this video is done.
So for now, I'm going to be in a higher region, so I will select that region.
And output format.
JSON should be fine.
Anyways.
We are not going to use a WC.
TerraForm is going to use the credentials of a WC ally.
We should have TerraForm now already installed.
Right.
So TerraForm is there.
We have a client's credential and now we can get start and writing our write our first TerraForm file.
So I'm going to use Sublime text, the simplest ID or editor, but first I'll create some directory.
So in my F drive I'll create a directory terraform hyphen scripts.
And then.
In that I'll create exercise one.
So first exercise.
Okay, great.
I'll open my sublime text editor and we'll start writing the code.
So I'm going to say Open folder and TerraForm scripts.
It should be good.
Yeah.
Exercise one.
Let's write our first file new file, and we will name it as.
My underscore instance dot t f or you can say first instance.
Again, TerraForm is used by so many cloud providers.
You can use it to automate so many cloud providers infrastructure.
So first you have to mention the provider provider.
So we're going to use ADA.
So I'm going to say provider is a plus in double quotes, and then you give the curly brace opening
and closing.
This is important in TerraForm, so there's no indentation here.
There's opening and closing curly braces.
You have to just keep, you know, take care of that apart from that.
Things are very declarative.
Now you can define a region over here.
Region equal to that's the region.
And you can give the region name.
So us is to my region name and you can also define here axis key.
Equal to and your access key.
And also you can define secret key.
This is your IM user access key and secret key, you see.
All right.
But there is always chance of, you know, exposing this, right?
Putting it on public repository.
So don't do this.
If you have already given credentials in our system by using a C ally, and that's much better and much
safer.
So you mentioned the provider, and next thing we are going to define the resource that we're going
to use.
So we have to say resource.
And you give the resource name.
E w.
S underscore instance is the resource to create to access a fabulous instance.
So this is a resource type and then we can give resource a name.
So I can give like intro.
You can give any resource name and then open and close your calibrates.
And in between these two calibrates you give the attributes like EMI is one attribute where you can
give the EMI ID.
So let's find some EMI ID.
That's.
Go easy to.
Launch instance.
And I will go with Amazon Linux.
Okay.
That's the image you will select.
Let's see the amid.
No space there.
And other things like instance type, instance, underscore type.
So we need to to micro.
Other things like availability zone, if you want to mention just just for sake of it.
Okay.
Key Name Login.
Key and key underscore name.
Now we don't have a login key.
If you want, we can create it and then mention it.
I will do that first.
We'll do that manually and then we'll see how we can also create key automatically.
Okay, so let's create a keeper.
I will name it as Dove.
Yeah, just some name.
Dokey.
So I will say my key is dove hyphen key, which the private key is already I have downloaded now.
Right.
Security group.
Security group also will create it now and will give the name of the security group ID, but later we'll
create it automatically.
So let's create a security group.
We'll see.
Dove hyphen sg.
And will give some rule 22 from my IP and C create security group.
Okay.
Copy the security group ID.
So VPC.
Underscore security underscore group underscore I is equal to.
And square bracket.
It's going to be in a list format.
So let's get the sick.
Copy.
The security group ID.
All these attributes are mentioned in TerraForm documentation.
Very well, which I'm going to show you.
But first, let's finish this tax.
And the tag is going to be in a hash format.
Indentations are not mandatory, but it's better you do it.
So you code looks good.
Dove instance.
Okay, so let's save this file now.
Let's go to get back.
So I'm going to have drive.
You have to terraform.
Exercise one.
All right, so that's our script.
Okay.
First thing, what you do is you run the command, terraform in it.
Now you can do this through PowerShell Command, Prompt terminal, anywhere you want.
I just find it from good batch.
Little convenient so I can version control it also quickly from here if I want.
So I'm just going to run TerraForm in it and this is going to check my provider that is eight and it's
going to download the plugins for us in the current working directory.
Yeah.
There you go.
If you do a less hyphen, you'll find a dot terraform directory.
I don't directory in that.
You can check.
You should have plug ins.
Before we really execute, we are going to do some validation for code will say TerraForm validate,
which will syntactically check our code and will give you some errors if there are.
Okay, so I'm going to make some syntax error.
The double code is removed.
And let's do TerraForm Validate.
You see, I'm getting an error over there because I've missed the double quotes over there.
The value of key underscore name is a string, but I have just given just like that without any double
quotes.
So that's a syntax error.
Syntax error.
Now I can see that all of you missed some options.
If there is any syntax error, it's not going to check any remote resources, just going to do a syntax
check.
This is success.
So that's the benefit of validating.
Right.
There's also one more option you can use after this FMT format, so it will format your TerraForm code
or should I say rewrite in a in its what it sees as canonical format and style.
Right.
So nothing really, you know?
No, it's just going to change the format, the style, like, you know, space and all those things.
First instance for us didn't do anything.
You see that?
It's all equal to that line now.
Yeah, you can see that.
That's the format Fmt.
So it makes your code more readable.
I recommend you run TerraForm FMT before you actually do an execution.
So we did TerraForm in it.
TerraForm Validate.
TerraForm for FMT.
Now TerraForm Plan.
Plan is not going to do anything.
It's just going to show you that.
Well, what will be the execution?
It's just going to give you, like, a preview.
What will happen if you apply this?
Okay, So it's going to show you this plus means the addition TerraForm will perform the following action.
So it's going to this instance is going to launch and there are all the attributes like this is the
my ID is taking the instance type and other thing which we'll get after we apply this.
Right.
If you're good with all those things, you can see TerraForm apply.
If TerraForm is deleting anything, it will also tell you that you know what it is really going to delete
or delete and recreate.
So terraform apply finally.
And then you say Yes.
Now I've given you so many commands, you can directly jump and start and jump and write TerraForm apply.
Yeah, but it's better to first validate, have proper format, right?
And then check your plan, what it's going to do, and then do the actual execution in a proper way.
Okay, so it's launching easy.
For instance, let's go and check.
Now you see there, it's launching incidents and it has given the right tag as well.
Name of instance.
Right.
Security group, which would have taken down security group and also the key.
Keep it.
Name?
Dove Key.
Okay, That's good.
It's in a running state.
Let's see what's happening here.
It says it completed successfully.
Kemp.
Okay, now we'll make a little change.
Very simple change.
We'll just change tag or we'll add extra tag and we'll see what happens.
Give a tag called us project.
Duff.
Okay.
I'm going to see you.
And.
Good.
You can do it through Sublime also if you want.
Okay.
I made the change.
All right, let's see.
Yeah.
Extra things.
I have added extra tag.
Let's do TerraForm.
Validate.
Okay, good.
It's a success TerraForm Fmt format.
Okay, Let's see if it changed anything.
You see that?
Aligned the equal to theirs.
Right.
It was not like this.
Yeah, but now it's a line That's.
That's what FMT does.
TerraForm Plan.
They always recommend you run a plan before you apply anything.
Okay, because there are a lot of benefits with TerraForm, but one very, you know, huge drawback
or should I don't want to say drawback but you know, if you if you're not careful and you made some
changes, it can also delete your resource and recreate it.
It could be very dangerous.
Think about this instance.
You made some changes and it's going to delete the instance ideas instance and recreate it to apply
the changes.
You lose all your data, right?
So always do terraform a plan and see what it is going to do.
It's going to do one change.
No additions, zero destroy.
So we are safe.
Let's do terraform apply.
And I'll say, yes, apply it.
All right.
That made the changes.
You can check from the console refresh.
Let's go to tags.
Come on.
Tags with our tags.
Dags.
Project.
You see new tag.
So TerraForm really maintains the state of your infrastructure.
If you do less here from where you executed TerraForm, there are files that are form of state file
if you see this file.
It's all the content.
How about your easy to instance?
Right amid availability zone CPU core count.
So the current state of your ESI two instance is all over here.
In JSON format.
Right.
So it compares the this state with your remote state.
If there are any differences, it will apply the differences.
Okay.
And this also terraform TFS state backup file.
Right?
When I say TerraForm maintain state, I mean to say this, it really maintains the state in a file.
Later we'll also see how we can keep keep this state file in a centralized location like an S3 bucket.
Okay.
That solve in this exercise, we'll do one final thing you're going to destroy.
We can set terraform, destroy to delete our resource.
So TerraForm Destroy is going to read your current state.
You have an instance and it will say, Yes, I will destroy that.
Are you okay with that?
And I will say, Yes, I'm okay.
Destroy c one to destroy.
Okay, so let's summarize.
We have written an easy to institute instant study of file.
We launched the instance.
We made some changes and we applied the changes.
So we have instance dot file is one file for now, which has the instance information.
And also the provider, Oedipus Cam.
So there are some apply.
Remember before you before you apply TerraForm do TerraForm plan so you can see what is getting ADD
and what is getting removed.
So once you're good with the plan, then you can say TerraForm apply.
We shall apply all your changes.
Maintain the state.
Once you're done with the exercise, you can say TerraForm, destroy, and it will destroy what you
created.
That's all in this exercise.
We'll then move to the next exercise.