In this section, we are going to talk about variables.
We'll see how to define variables, how to use it.
So you'll really see the TerraForm way of consuming variables.
So variables, as we know, helps us move critical or confidential data out of our script.
Also, if there are some values that changes based on your environment, on your project, you can define
them as variable.
So you don't need to make much change in your code.
You can just change the value of variables or if you're again reusing it.
You want to reuse your code for different, different environment, different, different project.
So you can define things like army tags keeper, these things as variables in our instance, Dr. File,
that we're going to write.
So we are here right now.
We have an instance of file, right?
We have provided information and we have the resource information.
So we have things like region that may change based on where we execute our TerraForm scripts.
There are things like RMI in this instance type.
These are the things that varies based on different situations.
So from here we'll go here.
So we'll take providers out.
We'll have a providers dot file where we'll define the provider.
Which is actually accessing region.
The value of region variable is going to be var dot region.
So it's a variable and variables we define in another file.
So they have let's say we have vase dot of file where we'll define variable.
That's how you define variable in TerraForm variable variable name in curly braces use a default and
the value.
So it means the default value of a underscore region is us hyphen west hyphen one and that you are referring
in the providers dot to file var dot region.
So that's dot file.
We have the variable region and its value is us hyphen west hyphen one.
If you're going to define the access key and secret key, you make sure you define it in different file
terraform dot vars file, but you can totally skip that because as I told you, do not put your access
key and secret key in your scripts, in your code.
And then we'll have instance Dr. File, where as of now we're not defining variable, but we'll change
that as well.
In a very different way like this.
So now was the ATF file have more variables.
Access key secret key region and also one more interesting variable variable AMIS.
This variable is of format is of type map, like a dictionary, like a hash.
So if you want to access this based on your region, what's the value of your region?
We can define the values.
So if you want to access this image, you're going to say amis dot us hyphen, west hyphen one, and
you will get that particular am-I.
This call is map variable.
So if you see in your instance dot file now for AMA, we have var dot amis.
So that's the variable.
And then in square bracket, we are giving our dot region inside that image.
It will look for a key name, this region.
So region value currently is US West one so US West one value is EMI and this particular ID, this will
be very helpful if you're executing your TerraForm scripts for different different regions or based
on the region, it will pick up the right amp ID.
So let's see what we're going to do in this exercise.
The Internet providers dot file vassarotti file where we'll mention all the variables, instance dot
of file, which is going to access all the variables.
We'll apply the changes, of course, before validating from the first we'll validate and then we'll
apply the changes.
And then we'll make some more changes to the instance to see it's state and then we'll reapply the changes.
So let's get started with the exercise.
Okay, so let's go with access to let's create a directory new folder.
Let me just exercise to.
First, we'll create our variables file.
So let's say new file.
See this with the name verse dot DF.
First variable will define is the region.
So we'll say gaps or if you want, you can use small also, but that looks good.
Region default equal to.
So I'm doing my exercise in this particular region or higher region.
Also, let's mention zone variable.
This is zone one.
Default to.
Okay, So that's simply the variable and its value.
Now we'll define one another kind of variable, which is of type map variable amis, and it's a value.
First of all, it's type.
ES Oh I forgot an equal to their.
Map like a dictionary.
And then we'll set default.
So I'll save my us east to region is there.
I would like to have its value as the my ID and take it from our first instance file.
Make sure your image is correct apt to your region.
Let me switch to some different region.
North Virginia.
I'll find some of my ID here.
I'll say launch instance.
Take this Amazon Linux, this side.
So not Virginia's US East one.
So we'll see.
US hyphen East hyphen one.
And you can like that give all the regions that you generally use equal to their.
Let's see how our instance file is going to refer to that.
But before that we'll also write provider's dot file.
And for this Dr. Phil will have just as much provider ADA plus region, var dot region.
And that should be the that should be a variable name.
Region its values us east to.
Let's see if this file.
All right, Now let's finally write our instance file.
I'm just cute.
The name is Instant Start def.
So as a resource instance name I'm going to give to my resource.
Is this an army?
Okay, so this is going to be like this.
Var dot amis.
The variable that you have there.
In square bracket.
You're going to say var dot region.
Now you can pass the region name directly like us is to one, but we're already using it as a variable.
So it's going to automatically pick up from there.
That this is going to be us is to.
Right.
And based on use history, too, it's going to pick up that Amy.
Let's give the other details.
Instance type two Micro.
If you want, you can define that as also variable availability zone.
We are doing var dot zone one.
Can zone one values us east to a.
Rest of the other things I'll copy just from the previous.
Resource.
This looks good.
Time to validate all these things.
So let's go to our Get Bash.
You go to the exercise to.
Forced to reform in it the new directory you will need to reform in it.
And we have an error.
Okay, so this is syntactically wrong.
So interphone will very clearly tell you where the error is.
Line number 11 in this file var start file default.
There should be actually an equal to and the value.
Let's fix that.
Default.
Equal to and let's see if this.
And let's test it once again.
Okay, that is done.
Let's do a TerraForm validate.
That is also a success.
TerraForm Fmt.
To format it properly.
So let's see what it do.
Carrot instances.
Yes, it looks good.
Time to check the plan.
TerraForm Plan.
So there are sometimes issues that will not get caught in the TerraForm value because it will just do
the syntax check.
Those things you can also catch in TerraForm Plan.
And sometimes it happens.
That doesn't catch in TerraForm Plan.
Also, when you apply that time, you get to know the problem, but those will be mostly logical errors.
So it's going to add one instance.
Same thing.
But this time we just using the variables terraform apply.
Ask a question.
Say yes.
Okay, That should be done.
And we have a new instance of instance.
Okay.
Now let's show you one thing.
We will create a new key pair.
Mm.
New hyphen, dove.
And now I'm going to mention that key.
Nike new hyphen dove.
Just ne hyphen dove.
We have not given the key.
Let me see if this.
Yeah.
Make sure you have given the right name, you new hyphen out.
That's good.
Okay.
Let's see what happens if we apply that.
But before that, we're going to plan it, we're not going to apply it, etc..
Form, plan.
Of course you can do validate.
So we're changing the key here.
Is it possible to change the public in this instance?
Like just like that?
Forget about TerraForm, but even manually through console or through clan, it's not possible.
The only way is you have to destroy that instance and create a new instance.
Right.
So changing things that are very simple in the TerraForm scripts file, but make sure you run a plan.
You see, it's going to destroy that instance, one to destroy and one to add.
If you scroll up, you will see the minus and you will see the plus or minus and plus both and CS must
be replaced.
This instance must be replaced.
So be careful on this part.
I am not going to apply that change.
I'm going to just now run, TerraForm, Destroy.
We are done in this part, in this section.
Yes, we are done in this section did destroy it.
So keep cleaning your resources.
In every exercise you do.
Otherwise, you'll have unnecessary things running.
Okay, so it's done here.
Let's move on to the next section.