In this section, we're going to talk about TerraForm Provisioning, what you can do in TerraForm to
provision the task once your operating system is up.
We used to have provisioning to do things like building image.
With Packer.
So when you're building the image, you really need to provision all the things you need to install
software's push files, you need to do all those things so you can use provisioning for that purpose.
Or in general.
Also you want to provision an instance with some packages, some files.
You can do that.
You can upload some files like artifact.
You can use a remote exec option in provisioning to execute task remotely on any instance.
So you just launch the instance, you can say remote exec yum, install or APT install some package
or even cocoa install if it's a windows machine.
You can also use provisionals like Ansible Puppet or Chef Puppet and chef.
You have the out of the box feature in this.
It will set up a puppet client or chef client.
In Ansible, you don't have client master relationships, so you can just use your Ansible playbook
and run your ansible playbooks with just remote exec.
To do provisioning.
We need to give connection details like how will we provision will do access to a Linux machine when
arm to Windows machine and we'll open PowerShell or bash Shell in Linux and we'll execute our command.
So TerraForm also needs detail for that.
If you want to do a search or not, you need to provide details.
So sample this.
You want to push a file, you can use provisional file resource source you the source file destination
where you want to push.
So source file obviously existing in your machine destination is going to be the easy to instance directory.
In order to do that, TerraForm needs the connection details so we can provide that connection.
And this is going to be the same.
BLOCK We're going to give a connection detail.
So it's a Linux machine, so you can say type, search, user username, password, and you can give
the password the variable you define.
And if it's a new machine, you are going to do, log in with the key, obviously, so you can provide
the key also instead of password.
And in windows side, you have the same thing you want to do.
Now you want to push a file, you can use the same resource file, but connection is going to be different
type item, user username and the password will be the password.
So in order to push a file, you need to provide the connection detail based on the operating system.
You have more probationers.
File is just one that we have seen here previously.
Pushing a file with your other provisions like remote exec.
You want to run some command?
So let's say with file proof, more file resource, you push your script and with remote execute and
execute that script.
Or you can execute any command.
Local exec is to execute task locally from where you are running TerraForm.
So these are the general provisions, but we have more provisions.
You can use Puppet as a provision where it will install a puppet agent on the remote machine.
And based on the operating system, it can use a search or binary chef provision that we have.
So it's going to install chef client.
And again, based on the operating system, it can use as a search or wine item to install that client.
If you're going to use Ansible, then you know how simple it is to run an Ansible playbook.
You can use a remote exec or local exec, local exec to force to get the IP address, and then you can
say Ansible playbook and you can give the playbook name.
So it's very easy to read with Ansible.
Really.
There are a few other things that we need in order to run our provisioning.
So in variables you can define things like the private key file path and the public key file path.
So we're going to generate keys first locally and by TerraForm, we're going to push the public key
to our cloud account.
So in order to use these file names in our instance file, we can define variables so we can very easily
access them.
Also the username for the connection.
So we can create the key pair.
Locally, we can run like a search kitchen.
We'll generate the key pair and then we'll push the public key to our account.
So for that we're going to say resource plus underscore, key, underscore, pair.
That's the resource name, that's the resource type.
And this is the resource name.
You can give any resource name.
I've given down hyphen key here.
You give the keenum, the private Keenum or just the Keenum of key and this is the name of the key that
will be there in the cloud account.
You can see that.
The public key that we want to upload to a plus account.
So public underscore key equal to file.
So you have to give the content of the public key.
And instead of giving the content, you can use a function in TerraForm called this file function.
You say file and you give a file path.
It will open that file or read that file content, and that content can be stored into this variable.
So this resource is going to create a public key on our account, right?
Private key will be still with us because we generated it locally.
Then we can refer this key in our instance resource so we can see instance instance, name, RMI, instance
type, availability, zone key underscore name.
We are giving a plus, underscore key underscore pair.
That's the resource type which is over here that we have defined dot dove hyphen key dot key underscore
name.
So A.W. underscore key underscore dot dove hyphen key dot key name which will return this dove key.
So we create the key pair here and then we refer it in our to instance like this or easy to resource
like this.
So new things that you have seen now is one is the resource key pair a file function in TerraForm that
can read a file and then how to access a resource from other resource.
All right.
We want to access this, Dulcie.
This value so we can access the key underscore name properties.
So we have to give the resource type, dot, resource name, dot the attribute or the property, and
that will return the value of key based on the same concept.
Let's see one more resource definition.
So we want to push a file.
So it's a provisional file source file web dot search, which is a shell script destination.
So we want to push this shell script and we have to mention the connection detail.
Okay, so the connection detail is user var dot user.
We have a variable there, private key.
So we're not going to give password.
We just provision an instance with a new key.
So we need to give the key, but the content of the key.
So private underscore key equal to five function and the file name, which is again a variable here.
And these variables are defined in the variable file, right?
So variable private underscore key underscore path, that's the file name.
So it's going to open up that file and.
But in the content of the private keys, it's going to use this private key and this user via dot user
is defined here to login to easy to instance and push this file.
The important thing here is you have to define the host.
So the resource which gets created, that in-situ instance gets created.
We will have the public IP of it.
We can say self dot, public IP or the private IP, whatever connection you prefer based on where you
are executing TerraForm, you can get the IP.
And it's going to use that IP, that username and key to login and push this file.
Kept coming back.
Going back.
We create the key public key enables account launch the instance.
Then with file provisioning, we're going to push the file.
There are connection details.
Variables are mentioned in the variables file.
Now we push the shelf script.
Now we want to execute it so we can use a remote exec.
So we can see a provisional remote exec.
And then in the places in line equal to square bracket in a list format, we're going to give a list
of commands.
And the first command, I'm saying give execute permission to my shell script and then pseudo part of
the Shell script, which will execute the script.
So it will hear three steps.
First launch instance with the key, create the key, launch the instance.
Second, push the shell script with local exec sorry with file provision.
Third remote exec and execute your script.
Okay.
Let's check out exercise again.
So we're going to generate key payer first screen locally.
Then we'll write a script which can do some task installing packages and stuff.
We like provide a file.
When we mention a provider, we'll write Vasco file.
We'll mention all our variables.
We let instance dot to file.
We'll create the key pair in this key in this private upload the public key in this and launch the instance.
That's a keeper resource plus instance resource will mention in this and provision will mention.
So we have one provision that as file, we're going to push our shell script there and then remote exec
provisioning which will execute our Shell script.
And then we're going to apply the changes.
Let's see this exercise now.
So this is going to be extreme.
Let's create a directory.
In this access three directory will create key pair.
So let's go to that directory.
So I'll say search hyphen kitchen.
Said dove key.
So I'll just say for Stacy's kitchen.
It will ask me the file name and here I can give it dove key in the current directory I will create.
I guess I should have a public key and a private key.
We see there.
That's our private key and that's our public key.
It's okay.
We don't need to open it.
We'll create the variables file first.
So we're going to define three variables again, Region Zone and AMIS.
And later, we're going to update it with few more variables.
But that's all for now.
There's three variables.
For now, of course, the private cloud providers are.
Just the region in the providers provider region variable, which is going to be us, is to one.
That variable is defined here.
We'll also write a shell script.
We will see a new file.
And we named the script as Web dot search.
So we're going to provision our instance with this script.
So we're going to install three packages.
We're going to provision Amazon Linux so we can use them to install software's start and enable extra
DVD service.
Then it's going to download a template like an artifact which has its HTML content, unzip it, copy
all the content to the HTML and restart the service.
So we'll provision our instance with this script.
Let's see that.
See the software providers dot.
Finally, let's create our instance data file.
And this will mention our instance detail.
First, we're going to create the key pair.
So the re source is E.
S underscore key underscore pair.
And let's cue some name.
I say dove key.
Dove hyphen key.
So keep in mind, this is just the name of the reserve resource.
We can use it to refer to it in our next task or our next next resource.
This will not be the name of the key.
And to prove that I'm going to give a key name different, like it's a key underscore name.
And I said, Duckie, no hyphen.
So you will see the key on the plus gets created with this name and not this name.
This is just the reference name.
I guess the public key that you want to upload.
So going to say public underscore key equal to.
So to give the content of the public key.
Right.
So ideally it should be like this in double code we should give.
All this content.
All right.
We should be giving this.
Right?
But that's too much.
All right.
So instead of doing that, we'll write a function.
There is a function called a file function, which will just read the file.
And we give the name of the file Dove Kee Dot pub.
Should be exactly same name.
All right.
So it's going to open that file and we don't need to put the entire content that should upload the public
key.
Now the insurance resource, same as the previous exercises.
The instance name will give different dove hyphen instance.
All right.
So the EMI, which will be coming from the variables file map variable instance type availability zone
again, variable coming from variables file.
The key name.
So key underscore name.
Now we really know, like right here and we can just directly say dove key over here.
And we can give like, dove key.
We can do that.
Not Dfki Duff.
Yeah, but I'll show you how you can access a particular.
Attribute a parameter from a resource to do that.
You give the resource type that you're using.
Dot the resource name that you have given to that resource.
Like I have given dev hyphen key here.
Dot.
The attribute name.
Which is going to return us this.
I will say it would be really simple if we just give dove cure there.
Right?
But that's the name we have given.
Maybe if it's a variable, then what?
All right.
Or even if you want to like that, refer a resource from one resource to other resource.
Any attribute you want to refer, then you should know how to do it.
I know those standard things.
Security group ID tag.
That should be it.
Save it.
Now, that should provision our instance, but we just don't want to provision the instance.
So we don't just want to launch the instance.
You want to really provision it with our shell script.
Right.
To do that again.
You have to be in the same resource block area block instance, resource block, da instance, like
you're giving EMI instance type.
Same way here.
You have to give the detail of provision so you can see a provision for.
And a provisional.
We are using this file provisional, which is used to upload files.
And we have to give source.
So we have a shell script in the same directory.
So we're just going to give the name.
You can give the absolute path also.
Destination.
So I would like to push it at the temp location.
That should push this script, but it needs the connection detail.
How is it going to connect to that?
Easy to instance?
So we are going to give the connection, detail, connection.
User.
So we already know the user.
We can put this into the variables file.
We can create another variable over here.
So Amazon Linux, easy to hyphen user, that's the user, right?
And we can just use that variable.
Let's see this file.
So we'll say var dot user.
Var dot user.
The capital user.
Key.
Private.
Underscore.
Key again, the content of the private key.
So you can use the file function and you can give.
Dove key.
The name of the key or again, you can put this also as a variable, but let's skip that for now.
Okay.
Also, one more thing.
Host self dot.
Public underscore IP.
So that's a way to tell TerraForm that use the public IP of the instance and use this user and key to
login.
Also, I would like to do the remote exec once this file the script is pushed.
I would like to do a remote exec.
And execute my script.
So.
We're going to use a provisional, we call it as a remote hyphen exec.
And this provision can execute commands on the remote machine, on a receiver instance that will be
launching.
So we can mention the list of commands should be in this format in line equal to and in a list format.
And you can keep giving your commands.
Line by line.
So I'm going to say first, make my script executable.
C h.
Mod u plus x.
And the part of our script.
And then finally executed.
Now.
Now, there are really so many curly braces and we need to be careful at this part.
So let's check once again that curly brace.
Right.
And it's a resource instance resource.
Start over here and it should complete there.
In between that you have.
Distance properties.
Provisional polls close there and remote exit opens and closes.
Their connection opens and closes there.
Seems good.
Let's save this and let's test it.
First thing terraform in it.
Okay.
It's a list, comma separated.
Right.
So we have to give a comma there.
Let's see that control less.
Okay, terraforming.
It is done.
Let's do a terraform.
Validate.
It would validate our syntax.
Wow, that's nice.
It's a success.
Let's say TerraForm FM to format it.
And let's see the instant starter file.
Properly formatted.
Very good.
TerraForm.
Plan.
Okay to add to to add the two things are getting add added.
One is the instance and the other is the key.
And you can see the public key content also.
Yeah.
Let's do a terraform.
Apply.
Yes.
Kat's Keeper is getting created.
Oh, the public is getting uploaded.
And instance is getting created.
Okay, This instance security group should allow 22 from our IP.
Can't see the security group that we have selected.
Otherwise the provision will not be able to do anything.
So we said 22 from my IP.
I think that's good.
That's fine.
So it completed successfully.
So let's check that.
Okay.
Let's go to keep Air Force.
So you'll see Dove key.
Okay.
That is the name of the key.
So if you go to our instance, start your file.
We have given key name, key, underscore, name, dove key.
So that's the name of the key.
Not dove hyphen key.
This is the name of a resource which we use it to refer in our other resources.
Like here we have used it.
Okay, so let's go back to the console.
Our instance should be up and running.
That's our instance.
All right.
The latest instance.
Let's refresh.
Yeah, that's our instance.
And you should have the verb service enabled.
Let's allow Port 80 from my IP so I can access it.
Bought it from my IP.
Yeah.
Let's get its IP address.
And yes, you see, it's provisioned with a website.
The Web service is really running.
Okay, that is good.
A few points I want to note.
But to bring to your attention really is the Web dot asset shell script.
So you're going to get it anyways through from the source code.
All these exercises.
But if you're copying it into some Windows editor and from there you copy it into.
A text file with name like that.
Right.
So there may be some invisible special character which you will not be able to see.
So I recommend you copy to a normal notepad with the windows, normal notepad, and then put then put
it in your ID when, where you want.
If that is also troublesome, then you can just from the git bash, you can just say vim and give the
name of your script.
Right.
And then put the content, type the content.
Otherwise there could be some special character which would be very difficult for you to find out and
you will keep getting errors.
And then that is all in this section.
Let's delete our instance, TerraForm Destroy.
So not only our instance, our key will also get deleted.
Yeah.
You see there.
I will not delete it for a moment.
I will show you the TerraForm State file.
Yeah.
So all the content is in the TerraForm State file, right?
And you're going to see the next session if you want to print anything out, like private type your
public IP.
It's going to be printing it from this TerraForm State file.
And so we can access our resources and we can print them.
Okay, Let's destroy it now.
You know, okay, my resources are deleted and that should be all in this section.
Wrap this up and join me in the next section.