Now get printing out the information and also we can store information from our TerraForm State.
So when we execute TerraForm Apply, it returns a lot of output and that is getting stored into TerraForm
out of state file.
And we can access information from that file itself directly.
We can say we can go to the underscore instance resource, the resource name dot public IP, and we
can find the public IP.
We can use an output block to print this also.
So output resources to print content and we can print out attributes that are already saved.
We can also use local exec to save such information into another file.
We want to see if IP addresses or IDs.
We can store it into a text file.
So output.
Instance, so you can give the name of your resource, whatever you want and value.
You can give the.
Part of the attribute that you're looking for.
So resource type, dot resource name, dot the attribute name.
The element is this enables underscore, instance, dot server dot public underscore IP.
My C plus underscore instance is the resource type.
Resource name is the server.
So as we give any resource name, right?
So like that, it's just an example server and attribute name inside that public underscore IP.
If you know how to access that and you can store that information to a text file also by using a local
executioner.
We have seen remote exec in the previous section.
Local exec will execute command locally.
So we say, for example, command equal to echo.
Echo is for printing, right?
So you can say print all this content, redact the output to this text file.
So let's then try that.
Okay, so I have here three exercises, so I already have data in the exercise three.
I will just copy all the data to exercise four so I don't have to write all that thing again.
And you also don't need to do that because we're going to see only one thing in this printing output.
So let's open our sublime editor.
You shouldn't have case for.
Let's close all that.
Okay, so let's say I want to print the private IP or the public IP, whatever you want to print.
So we'll go out of this resource block and we'll use this proof output.
And you can give any energy name.
So I'm going to say public.
IP.
Value.
So let's get our resource type.
Ms..
Dot the resource name.
It just dealt in hyphen instance.
And the attribute in that.
Now we can find all the attribute from documentation, which I'm going to run you through in some time.
For now, if you want to access the public IP, you can just see public underscore IP.
Also, if you want to print the private Tiberius, copy that one more time, we'll see private IP.
Private.
Maybe.
And they attribute.
Private IP.
Okay, let's save this and let's execute.
Now, it's the same code from our previous exercise.
So it has the provisioning also everything.
So you should have all the data.
Same from the exercise three.
Okay.
I saved it.
Let's go to our banquet bash.
Let's terraform in it.
TerraForm.
Plan.
In the plan.
Also, you can see the attributes.
All right.
So two resorts are going to get ADD, right?
Added.
So you see the resources you can see there, right?
Private underscore, DNS, private underscore, IP, public underscore DNS, public underscore, IP.
Right now, it's nothing because the instance is not created.
But for a resource before you output, before you put that output block, you can say TerraForm plan
and you can find which attribute you want and then you can put it in the print.
Okay, so let's see.
Apply now.
The execution completed, you see the output private IP in the private IP of the instance and the public
IP.
Only that much in this section.
I'll see you in the next section.
Before that, make sure you destroy.