This section is about back end.
So far we have seen in all our exercises that TerraForm maintains the state, but the state is really
local.
What I mean by that is it's in my machine.
If I'm working in a team and we're using the same code to maintain the state, then I may have a different
state of the infrastructure.
If someone makes a change, they'll have a different state of the infrastructure.
The state should be in sync.
So terraform of state file should be same across all the execution.
So for that we need to put the TerraForm State file into a remote location.
The best place to use is S3 bucket, or should I say the easiest place to use is the S3 bucket.
But there are a few other things.
It's going to be a very simple session, but also very, very important session if you're working in
a team.
Otherwise, there's no point in maintaining the state of your infrastructure.
So I just have the excise five, which is same as excise six, except we're going to maintain state.
So we're going to maintain the state in S3 bucket.
So we need to create S3 bucket.
Let's first put our state information.
Backend dot to file name.
I guess all you have to do is terraform.
And in that you have to give back.
In the name of the back end service you're going to use.
S3 In S3 we have attribute bucket.
We have to give the bucket name that we'll create key name.
The directory inside that bucket and the region.
If you want, you can fetch this information from variables as well.
But let's just first create a bucket.
Let's go to three.
Let's create bucket.
We name it as Terra.
Hyphen state.
Hyphen dove.
Okay.
If it says already exists, then try with adding some number.
That was a unique name.
Okay, so tera hyphen state hyphen dove in this we will create a folder, you name it as terra form.
Okay, so let's copy this bucket name.
It's a bucket.
TerraForm.
Slash back end.
So in this file the states should be mentioned region.
So my bucket is in this region, US east too.
So I'll mention that name.
Let's save this file.
And let's now execute this.
Exercise five.
TerraForm in it.
So as soon as you give TerraForm in it, you see it's a successfully configured back end SX three.
All right.
Okay, let's set that up.
Form a validate.
Data form format.
The reform plan.
All right.
And finally, terraform apply.
Okay.
The resources are created.
And we have terraform of state file.
This is from the previous.
Exercise.
Even if you did, it doesn't matter.
Let's go to S3 now.
TerraForm.
You see the file back in there?
Let's click on it and let's see open or you can download it.
See the TerraForm State file.
So now the state is remote.
Now same repository used access file.
That's our repository is used by another member of my team.
We'll also have the same state he or she makes any changes.
The TerraForm State file gets updated in the pocket.
All right.
And same can be sent to the other individuals repository.
So now this will really complete your terraform.
State concept maintaining TerraForm maintains the state of the infrastructure.
Yes, but when you maintain it at a centralized location, that will actually give you the real benefit
of TerraForm State.
That's all in this section.
Let's delete our resource.
And I'll see you there in the next section.