As I told you in the introductory session, that TerraForm is used by many, many different providers.
So you can use many providers like Google Cloud Azure, or not only Cloud.
There are few other things also that TerraForm supports.
It has many providers.
So if you scroll down here, you can say registry dot, terraform, dot IO come to the site.
These are featured provided the main providers ADA, Ada Azure.
Google Cloud.
Kubernetes.
Oracle Cloud.
Alibaba Cloud.
So let's go to a house.
Documentation.
So all the resources that you want to use to maintain your infrastructure are available here on the
left hand side.
And if you see a lot of services and services like EC2, so we used to already write so easy to and
in this section you have the resources plus EMI copy EMI to take snapshot.
The one that we used was this underscore instance.
Let's click on this so you can see example usage.
You should really scroll down to see better example.
Okay there.
Now there is a resource for plus VPC.
My VPC and give the CIDR block.
And this resource will create a VPC.
You want to create a subnet in the VPC eight underscore subnet subnet V in this VPC.
And so we are referring to this VPC that we created.
Then there is some networks interface that is getting created.
So there are really multiple resources in one file here.
And for instance, the one that we used.
Right.
So we mentioned Ahmed.
Instance type, the network interface you want to connect to.
So you're right, In this exercise, we are going to see multiple resources and the good way is really
to distribute them into different files.
If you see a key pair.
See that we use that public key and we have not given the entire key.
We use the file function.
I'll also show you functions.
So you can see arguments, attributes that you can pass to a resource.
So in this exercise, we're going to create VPC.
We're going to create security groups and we're going to launch instance in the VPC that we created.
And also we're going to use the security group that we have created.
So let's see our resources one by one.
First, VPC.
So I'm going to close that.
I can make a search from here.
I can do this VPC.
And you have the VPC resource.
He underscored VPC.
So we're going to use this resource to create our VPC, underscore subnet resource to create our subnet
so we can see it easily example and you can also see the arguments and the attributes that you can pass
in that.
When you create a subnet, you have to mention the VPC ID, right?
So that should be the format.
And the value should be a VPC ID.
So we're going to create three public subnet and three private subnet by using this resource.
We'll also create Internet gateway.
So there you have a plus underscore Internet gateway.
And that's how you can create an Internet gateway.
Round table a underscore root underscore table there.
So you can create a table like that.
So you really don't need to remember all these things.
Everything is there in this documentation and the arguments and the attributes that you can pass.
Also, there's a round table association.
So how we're going to associate our subnet with the round table.
So we say the resource name, we give the subnet ID and we give the round table ID.
So these are the resources we're going to use in our VPC dot file.
So let's create our next exercise now.
Okay, so in my sublime text editor, I'm going to say new folder.
Excite six.
First thing we'll do is we'll create the providers dot to file.
Providers dot DFA.
Let's see that.
We create variables file because we're going to refer to some variables.
So we'll have the region variable zone variable.
We'll have images.
User variable, also the public key name.
So that should be our key.
Dovecot Pub and Dove key will copy the same key from the Access five.
Or we can just regenerate it.
In any case, let's just delete the existing key that we have.
Okay, it's not there, but just validate if you're not destroyed it, the key should be there.
It's not there anymore.
So let's also copy our key.
From exercise just to exercise six.
Jeff, we have the key here now, the private key and the public key.
Okay, now let's create the resource file for VPC.
We leave it as VPC.
HTF.
Oops.
Control.
Dot f.
Now give it a W, Send us your VPC resource, the name of the VP.
The resource will be def CIDR block instance Tenancy default Enable DNS support true.
Enable DNS hostname true.
And the tag.
So these are the properties.
Again, you can get that from the documentation or sorry the attribute we call it attribute here.
Then we're going to create the subnet.
It does underscore subnet.
Subnet name First public subnet will create vpc ID.
Now we are referring to plus underscore VPC.
That resource, that name dot Dove.
Dot ID.
So once this resource gets created, it will have an attribute called ID and that we can refer it here.
So this subnet will get created under this VPC.
With cider block this map map public IP on launch.
True.
So if you launch instances in this subnet, it will have a public IP availability zone.
We will change that.
We will define our variables.
We have zone one like that.
We'll define zone two.
Zone three.
So I'll copy this.
Be it.
Okay, so we'll see.
Zone two is us is to be.
Zone three is US East to sea.
Make sure you confirm the zone name from your account in easy to dashboard.
You can check that.
Let's save the file.
So we'll see here for dot zone one.
That dot zone one.
Like that we're going to create.
Five more subnets.
So the public subnet two things that is that are different subsector block.
And that zone will change it to var dot zone to.
And then the tag.
That's second subnet.
Third subnet.
Again, same resource.
CIDR block changes zone is different.
And of course the tag.
So we're saying these are three public subnet.
Now we have three private subnet also.
Private subnet, one sided changes zone.
It's going to be in zone one.
Subnet two again CIDR changes and Zone two.
Total private subnet sider changes and zone three.
So you can really check from the documentation as well as underscore subnet and you can check the arguments
that you can pass availability zone or availability zone ID, you can pass CIDR block mapped public
IP on launch.
So what you need, you can fetch that VPC ID and as per your requirement, you can put it in your resources.
Next, we'll create Internet gateway.
So that's the resource type resource name VPC ID that set Internet Gateway gets created in the VPC.
So we have to join our public subnet with the Internet gateway.
So we have to create the route table so we can check the resources of the route table.
Underscore.
Route.
Underscore Table.
Hi.
So resource name, resource type, resource name, give the VPC ID and then inside that you have root.
So you have to say if the traffic is destined to this, then it can forward it to this particular gateway.
And also you can give tag by using this information, we'll create our resource.
So we're creating a roundtable named this.
VPC ID we're referring and we are saying IP address that wants to go.
The packet that wants to go to any IP addresses can be routed to the Internet gateway.
Case is a gateway we have creating over here, Right.
Dot dove hyphen GW dot ID.
So that should be good for the roundtable.
But we also need the roundtable association.
We have to associate our public subnet with this roundtable.
So we have the Resource Roundtable Association.
And we it's very simple.
You just mentioned the subnet ID and the route table ID, So if we have to really give it three times
because you have three subnets.
So round table association resource name Subnet ID the subnet that you've created previously.
Roundtable ID the Roundtable ID that we have created previously.
So this is for public subnet one.
This is for public subnet two.
This is for public subnet three.
So these three public subnet will be attached to a route table and route table route all the traffic
to the Internet gateway.
And there we have created the Internet gateway also.
Okay, so this should create a VPC.
Let's save this and let's test it.
TerraForm in it first thing.
Okay, that's done.
Let's do terraform.
Validate.
That's a success.
And let's do TerraForm format so we have it properly formatted.
Okay, let's check its plan to reform plan.
Gates has planned to add 12 resources.
And what are you waiting for?
Let's do it.
TerraForm apply.
Okay that completed successfully.
So 12 resources is updated.
And if we wish, we can really go to the console and we can check ourself.
You can go to VPC.
A.
B.
C.
Their dove VPC.
All right.
The cider.
That's so nice.
Details.
DNS hostname enable DNS resolutions enabled.
Should have six subnets.
There we go.
Three public.
Three private.
Should have the Internet gateway.
Dove Internet Gateway Roundtable.
For public subnet and we should see our three public subnet associated over here.
And also the route which points to the Internet gateway.
If you wish, you can create the NAT Gateway, but we are going to do anyways that in the project.
Okay.
The next resource that we are going to create is Security group.
So let's go to the documentation plus underscore, security, underscore group.
This should be in the VPC section there.
It's in the VPC section, not the C section, because security group really is the part of your VPC.
You have the example.
Resource, the resource name VPC, I'd have to mention ingress and egress.
So inbound traffic and outbound traffic mostly we keep outbound as open to everyone, so traffic from
our instance can go out on any port, on any IP address, but traffic which is coming in ingress there,
we can put some restriction.
So from port here, four, 432, port 443 protocol TCP site block So you can mention.
The IP address or the range or here.
To allow your traffic from that port.
So we'll create a security group because we're going to launch an instance and we need a security group
for it now.
So let's go to our sublime, and now I'm going to create a different file.
I'm not going to create it in the VPC file, create a different file and name it as SEQ.
Group dot F.
Oops.
Not there.
Okay, So that is the resource security group, the name of the resource VPC ID.
So we are referring it from our this VPC.
So we can refer it like that.
You can create things in different, different files.
TerraForm will find it and we'll put it in a proper order.
So you see, it has to create a security group and there's a VPC ID here.
It knows that it has to create the VPC first.
So you don't need to worry about the order.
But if you want to, you can specify order that also we're going to see in the project.
But here, the terror from intelligence should be fine.
So the name.
Let's change it to.
Dove Stack, S.G. Egress outbound traffic.
I'm going to say for all the ports, traffic can go anywhere on any IP address ingress, although I'm
going to say 22 allowed from I'm going to say my IP here, but I'll put a variable better var dot my
IP and I'll define that variable in my var file.
Edible.
And I'll find my IP and put it out there.
And let me see if this also the security group.
And let's test it.
TerraForm.
Apply, Or should I say first plan can have included a new resource.
So it's refreshing.
The state is checking the state of VPC.
It's good.
So it's not going to touch it again.
And all the subnets and route table, it's just refreshing.
The state.
It's checking there in the same state.
That is good.
Except I need to add one resource.
Everything else is good.
It is saying and that's the security group.
And let's say apply.
Oh, you know what?
You can keep adding your resource and keep testing it by saying plan.
If this is good, then you can go ahead and keep adding resources.
And finally, you can apply the state.
Also from the previous section.
Remember, back end maintaining back end is very important.
So create a back end, file something like that and put your back end as three bucket.
Okay.
So the security group created.
Next, we will launch instance in using that security group and also putting in the VPC that we created.
Before that, I will now start mentioning the back end state.
Same bucket.
I'm using just the film.
I'm changing.
We save this.
Also for the provisioning.
I will need the Shell script, so I will copy the Shell script from the previous exercise.
I already have my keys.
Now I can write my instance dart file.
Okay.
So what we did in our previous exercise, plus a few more things.
So we create a key player, key named Dove Key.
And we have the public key variable there, which is actually this public key.
Let's confirm that once variables Bob underscore key Dovecote pub That's right.
Underscore instance resource dev hyphen will see web that's the resource name will give a mid it will
pick up instance type subnet ID.
So underscore subnet dot dev hyphen pub hyphen one dot id.
So this is from this vpc dot file.
I dove hyphen pub hyphen one dot id is going to return the subnet ID of this particular subnet that
gets created.
Keenan We are saying a loss underscore key payer dove hyphen key there dot key underscore name.
So it returns dove key.
So it's going to use this key security group ID eight plus underscore security underscore group dot
dove underscore stack underscore is G.
Again, that resource name is from our security group file.
Yeah.
Dot ID is going to return the security group ID and then some tag.
Volume.
Also, we are putting EBS volume.
It's going to be an extra EBS volume.
So some name of the resource availability zone.
We have to change this to var dot zone one.
Now.
Our instance is getting created in zone one.
Right this.
Subnet public one subnet in the VPC section if you see this is in zone one.
So the EBS volume should be also in the same zone.
Right.
In this case, this this variable comes very handy.
So you can use the same variable.
All right.
So we create a volume there with three GB of size.
And another resource.
E underscore volume.
Underscore attachment.
We attach our volume.
Volume D.
All right.
That is coming from there.
In the instance, I'd.
Which is going to come from our instance.
And finally, output public IP.
That's the name and the public IP from our attributes.
So we're actually using everything from first to fifth exercise.
Everything in the six text size plus many more things like VPC security group.
So you are you're actually witnessing multiple resources distributed into multiple files and how to
bring them together.
Bringing two resource together.
Remember?
Resource type resource name dot and the attribute name to ID or kin and whatever is the attribute.
Right.
That's how you club in two resources together or you refer one resource from the other resource.
Right?
Multiple resource.
You need a few more things with this like elastic IP, you can just check the documentation, how to
create elastic IP and then attach the elastic IP, right?
Like we created EBS volume and then we attached.
And like in VPC, we created route tables.
All right.
And then we have attached the round table associate round table.
So like that we create a resource.
You associate a resource.
All right.
And for reference, we use this way.
Okay, let's finally test this.
First, we have to set TerraForm Plan.
Now, first, the validate.
The syntax should be validated.
If you have validation error because you're not referring the right names.
Okay, So let's check that and let's fix that there.
If we see we have referring a loss underscore instance, dot dove.
So what's the name of a resource dove hyphen web?
And over here we have given dove, hyphen dove.
So let's fix that.
They're also there.
Let's find.
We have dove.
Dove anywhere.
It's not there.
Good.
Okay, let's check once again.
Now, Right.
It's a success now.
Okay, Let's do an FMRI format because it's really a lot of things, man.
It gets formatted very nicely.
I love this format option from TerraForm.
It just makes the code very readable.
Okay.
TerraForm Plan.
So.
We have included backend, but we have not initialized it, so we have to set TerraForm in it.
So the backend will be initialized because so far we were maintaining state locally we updated.
So we're going to say yes.
Do you want to copy existing state?
Yes.
Copy.
So in the middle also you can include the state, right?
But then you have to say TerraForm in it.
TerraForm Plan.
Okay.
Everything seems to be good.
Let's finally now apply it.
Okay.
That completed successfully.
Let's just check it.
You already checked our VPC.
Let's check our C two instance now.
Okay.
That's so easy.
For instance.
It should be a separate security group that we created.
Yes.
And also with an extra volume.
Of three job sites and it's attached.
It's attached.
We're able to attach because it's in the same zone as our instances.
Our instance is in US east to a so as our volume should be also in us is to a.
Yes, dear.
Finally, once you are done verifying everything, just destroy.
Your resources.
It's easy to create, easy to destroy.
I love this.
All right.
So that should give you quite a good experience on how to use TerraForm to do your cloud automation
and how you can maintain the state as well.
Feel free to check your documentation and try a few extra things like load balancers ideas or elastic
cache or rabbit.
Q In the project video, I will show you how you can set up the entire stack.
We profile as the project that we did, we profile refactoring or re architecture where we used ideas
being stack elastic cache, active MQ, and all those sources that we used in those in that project.
We are going to automate that entire stack with TerraForm and also will maintain it state through TerraForm
that will see in the project video.
That's all in the introductory session of TerraForm.
Thank you very much.
I'll see you in the project video.