Welcome to the next project in the DevOps Project series.
The name of this project is Kubernetes, set up on local and cloud.
We're going to see different ways of setting up Kubernetes cluster, starting from our local machine
or laptop to a cloud, a local test environment, and a production grade environment also.
Okay, so let's say this is your scenario.
You have already containerized your application.
You have used Docker or any other container runtime environment and you have created your container
images.
Now it's time to test it on a Kubernetes cluster.
And you would like to test it locally and also on the cloud.
So we're going to see also set up local cloud both.
I'll get tools that we're going to use for is Mini Cube, which will be used to set up a single Node
Kubernetes cluster locally on our laptop by using Oracle VM VirtualBox.
Then we're going to use Q ATM to set up a multi node cluster.
We can use Cube ATM to set up production grade cluster, local local data centers or also cloud anywhere.
You just need some set of compute machine Linux operating systems so you can have physical machines,
virtual machines, instances on the cloud.
Next, we're going to use cops.
Cops is a tool to set up a production grid.
Cuban This cluster on a cloud and also now it supports Google Cloud.
It also has a beta version that supports VMware, vSphere environment, and one of the most famous Kubernetes
clusters set up tool for us.
It has its own service, ECUs.
We're going to see how we can set up a Kubernetes cluster on x.
X is a service from us, so you just need to run some simple commands and it will have for you a production
grade Kubernetes cluster.
In my view, it's the easiest way to have a very efficient Kubernetes cluster powered by A.
S.
Okay, So our objectives are very simple.
We need to set up a cluster and we need to test the Kubernetes cluster local and on the cloud.
So let's dig in and achieve our goals.