First will go through some companies cluster documentation, which are official Cuban is documentation.
So let's check them out.
Okay, I'm on Kubernetes, dot IO.
Let's check the documentation.
Getting started.
Learning environment.
We start with this first.
Learning communities with Mini Cube.
So it is to run Kubernetes cluster locally, meaning Kube runs a single node in this cluster.
So all the Cuban is control plane services and the node services will be running on just one virtual
machine.
And there are some features to it installing many cube.
So there are different ways of installing mini cube.
We are going to install it on Windows machine by using chocolate.
Once we have mini cube, we can just say mini Cube start.
It's going to take a moment, pull the image and bring up a VM.
Once our component is cluster is up, we can test it with some deployment.
And we can expose the services for deployment.
We can see the pots running.
You can see the URL and we can access it from the browser.
This is just for some local testing environment, just for a little fun and a quick hands on Kubernetes
cluster.
So first we'll do this, then we'll switch for production environments.
Installing Kubernetes with a deployment tools.
So we'll use Q radium cops.
Q sprays new.
It uses ansible.
We're going to see first Q radium, then we're going to see cops, and finally we'll be seeing X.
So it is a little longer setup.
So many steps you have to execute.
I have all those steps in some bash scripts and we're going to use Vagrant to provision multi node Kubernetes
cluster by using cube idiom automatically.
So we'll automate the automation.
Q Idiom is an automation tool to set up Kubernetes cluster, but there are really a lot of steps, and
we can automate those steps also.
Once we do that.
We'll see.
Cuban This cluster set up by using cops.
We're going to use a cloud platform and set up a Kubernetes cluster.
So we need to set up some tools.
We're going to launch a VM for that and we'll run through the setup and cost will the longest setup
that we have.
But it will give you amazing control on your Kubernetes cluster.
We are also going to see finally Amazon Echo's Elastic Kubernetes Service, which is the easiest production
great Kubernetes cluster that you can spin and manage.
So let's get started.
First, we'll do the mini cube.