You can clone the source code.
V Profile Project Source Code.
So I'm going to clone the source code.
If you have it already cloned, just get into the repository and do get pull so you get the latest changes.
Let's see if you already have it.
Just do a good poll inside that.
So get all the latest changes.
We are already up to date.
We just cloned it.
We are going to use a branch Kubernetes.
Hyphen setup up.
So you have different directories over here.
First, we're going to do Mini Cube, so let's get into mini Cube.
And that is a simple piece of document.
First, you need to install chocolatey from prerequisite video.
You should already have chocolatey on your system if you don't have run this command and have chocolate
installed.
Once you have chocolate install from PowerShell, close the PowerShell open up again.
Open PowerShell with administrator.
We will copy this command to set up chocolaty.
In case if you're getting error over here, like restricted or not allowed, then turn off your antivirus
for a moment and run this command.
You should have the latest version of chocolaty on your system.
Once you have done this, close PowerShell.
And start again with admin privilege.
Next, we're going to run this command Choko install mini cube, which will install the mini cube to
your tool and Kubernetes hyphen cli, which is the command line tool to connect to the Kubernetes cluster.
Okay, Now I have latest version of Mini Cube and Kubernetes.
See a light tool.
I can close this now and I can use my GED bash, which is much more convenient.
Jack.
Mini Cube.
Hyphen hyphen help.
If you still don't see me in command, then close.
Get back and start again.
So we are going to say Mini Cube start, which is going to start a local cooper in this cluster and
then we'll check its status.
So many cube start.
It's going to take some time because it's going to download an image and then bring up a VM on Oracle
VM VirtualBox.
It is done.
The Cuban is cluster is up.
You can see a VM.
So you can check Mini cube Cube CTL get nodes.
And you should see your one node, which is master node.
So Kube CTL, which we installed through chocolaty, is using a file which is in your home directory.
Dot cube configured this part cube config file.
So that's the cube config file.
You have the cluster detail over here.
Cube config file is used by the Cube CTL command.
So the server detail, the name of the cluster.
This is the cluster detail.
Down here.
You have users.
Meaning you and client cert client key for the user and then context.
Context marries the user with the cluster.
So you say in context cluster the name of the cluster mini cube, which is this one.
User, McHugh.
So that's the mini cube user.
With the credentials to login.
So when I see Cube CTL get nodes, it is using that cube config file to access our cluster.
Now let's run a few more tests.
So let's go to Kubernetes documentation.
Learning environment.
Meaning you.
All right.
So we just did this mini cube cluster is up.
And now we can test by running cubes.
It'll create deployment.
So this command created a deployment named Halo Mini Cube.
It has fetch and image from Google Container, Registry Cube, CTL, Get Pod, and you should see a
pod running from the deployment cube.
It'll get deploy.
So this deploy is running this pod.
Okay, let's expose it so it creates a service which we can then access.
It'll expose deployment, deployment, name, hyphen, hyphen type, node port on port 88 to check the
URL of our deployment of our service.
Run this command and you should get a URL so we can access.
Our application at this URL.
And you should get this and that.
Just test that your mini cube cluster is up and running.
You're able to create pod deployment and expose service for it.
So in our next project, we are going to host a Java application on Kubernetes cluster.
In this project, we are just seeing the setup by using different different tools.
So one mini cube is done.
Now let's wrap it up.
Q Ctrl get CVC will force delete our service.
Q It'll delete.
C.
That's a service.
Q It'll get deploy.
Q It'll delete.
Deploy.
Hello, Hyphen Mini.
Q So delete the deployment and it's going to delete your pod as well.
Now let's stop the mini cube cluster.
Mini cube.
Stop.
And then finally you can say mini cube delete.
And you should have not.
No VM over here.
So that's good.
Hansen.
On a Kubernetes cluster.