Now let's shift our attention to production grade Cuba and this cluster.
By using Cuba idiom.
First, we need to install QB Adam.
So I recommend you read this documentation.
So we will set up Q bidding cluster on virtual machines.
We'll have 312 VMs, one master and two worker nodes.
Here are supported operating system list, the RAM they need and the CPU.
And we need to do some initial setup or a prerequisite before we install Q Radium and other tools first.
You have to do more probe and load these modules to make sure this option is set to one.
And don't worry, I have all this automated.
In Shell script, which we're going to see in a moment.
To set that value to one, you have to update this file with this entry.
So you can just run this command so this file gets updated and then you run CTL hyphen hyphen system
sys this you have to do on all the nodes master and worker together.
You can set up COVID cluster by using cube EDM and you can use Docker Engine or any other container
runtime environment.
You're going to use Docker engine.
So you need to install the Docker runtime environment.
A standard Docker installation is from the Docker documentation.
Once you have Docker installed after doing all the setup, then you're going to install Cube Cube let
and cube steel.
So command to install Cube, CTL, Cube, EDM and Cube led.
And this he has to do on all the nodes.
If you are not using Docker and some other container runtime environment, then you need to make some
C group driver up.
But we're going to skip that.
Once you're done with this, you can restart the cube lit.
So this common step you need to do in all the work or not once you're done with this.
We have to run some command on the master node, which will generate some instructions.
And with these instructions we can use to run on work or not.
So work or not can join the master node.
The command on the master node will be cue Adam in it with some options.
We have to specify the POD network and the API server ID.
Once we learn this cube in cube idiom init command, it is going to generate some other commands in
the output logs which then can be executed on the worker node.
So you will see output something similar to like this when you are in cube in cube idiom and it command
on the master node.
And finally, you will get this in the output.
Commands to create a cube config file and then a command queue idiom join, which will be executing
on the worker node, which will connect a worker node to the master node.
But in order to join the worker node to the master node, you need a network.
So kubuntu supports multiple networking models.
You can click on this link.
And based on the requirement, people will use any of the plugin we're going to use Vive Net.
So let's directly scroll down to view net.
Integrating Kubernetes and measures via CNI plugin.
It's very easy to integrate commodities via the add on.
Click on this link.
And you should get a command still apply.
It's going to download some Kubernetes definition file and set up a network for your pod to interact
with each other.
And that should be you should have a communist cluster by using Cuba idiom.
Let's go through the steps once again and we'll start after that.
I'll get forced, will have M.A. and worker node will log into them.
If you're going to do predictive sites on all the node, somewhat pro and systems, it'll come on.
Then you're going to install Docker engine on all the nodes, worker and master node.
We're going to install Cube, Cube lit and Cube CTL on all the nodes.
Then specific to we're going to log into Master Node, we're going to run Cube in it with some options
which will generate.
A command cube CTL node Join qubits or Cube Idiom Node Join.
We're going to save this command and we'll log into the worker node and we'll execute that command which
will join our worker node to master Node.
We have some script to save our cube config file.
Once we have that, we can log in as an ubuntu user or any normal user and run cube ctrl get node command
to see list of all our nodes.
After this, our Kubernetes cluster should be up and running and would be ready to use.
So let's get started.
I know there are a lot of steps to execute, but don't worry, I have most of it automated for you through
Vagrant.
So we're going to run the entire setup on virtual machines on our local system.
You can use same scripts to set up queue is to set up Kubernetes cluster by using queue atm on anywhere
on easy two instances or VM anywhere or even physical machines.
Okay, so let me open the source code.
So we're in Cuba.
So we have a vagrant file.
We're going to use this vibrant file to launch three VMs.
One is Kubernetes master.
We're going to name it as Cube master.
It's going to be two GB of RAM.
It will have a static IP.
Operating system is open to bindings 64.
Open to 18.
Instead of having a vibrant VM, if you choose to have a A++ e, c for instance, you can use that as
well.
When this VM comes up, it's going to execute a Shell script.
This is that Shell script.
So first is a variable set master IP, which is its own IP.
It's going to do the prerequisite command.
It's going to run, not prop command, it's going to load this module and it's going to create.
This file with this content.
Then run CTRL system Command.
If you're using a center machine, then it's going to script will detect that, find that out and execute
command.
To install and set up Docker engine on a red hat machine.
So basic commands as you see in the documentation.
Docker documentation to set up Docker engine.
So these command are going to set up Docker engine.
And then restart Docker engine.
If you're not using Red Hat machine, then it will execute this command.
And this will be good for open to machine.
Again, same command from the Docker documentation to install Docker engine.
Once you have Docker engine, you restart the Docker engine.
Okay, next step is to install Cube, Cube lit and Cube CTL.
So it's going to set up a repository, enable a repository, and this file document is a repository.
So we have to set SELinux to permissive mode.
And we are also going to do that permanently.
So we're going to change a select enforcing to SELinux permissive in the SELinux config file.
Then we're going to install cube lit cube EDM and cube Ctrl against the Yam command.
So this is for RedHat Machine.
Once you have that, I'm also stopping the firewall.
If you have a12 machine, then it will execute these commands.
To install cube lit cube EDM and Cube City and stopping the fireball.
Once you have that, then it is going to run the cube idiom init command.
This is the main command.
We're seeing hyphen hyphen, pod, hyphen Network, CIDR.
We're giving this IP range.
So this is going to be a support network.
We also have to give this option hyphen f and EPA server advertise Address the address of the master
node.
And all the output will be redirected to this file.
Q Bottom out dot log.
This file will have the commands which can be executed on the worker node, which we're going to do
automatically.
It's going to wait for 360 seconds and execute the script.
Set hyphen cube conflict message.
Let's see the script.
The script is very simple.
It's going to.
Copy the Q.
The admin dot com conf file.
This is going to be the cube config file.
To the user's home location Kube config.
It's going to give permission to that file ownership of the user.
These are the command if you're doing it for any user.
But these are the commands for vagrant users specifically.
So you would have a cube config file.
Then you can run cube ctrl command from the master node.
So once the script is executed, it's going to run a command cube.
It'll apply and apply these definition files.
This is going to create the weave net network.
Then it's going to halt for 60 seconds.
It's doing that to this file, the log file, which was generated by cubed a minute command.
All right.
And from this file, you're going to find out the cube idiom, Joint Command.
And we're going to put it into this script.
And this script will be executed on the worker node automatically.
So all automatic.
So this is the script that will get executed.
Main script that will get executed on the master node.
Q Monster, if you don't want to do it on Vagrant VM, if you want to do it on easy, for instance,
just launch.
Easy for instance, copy the script over there, make changes on the IP addresses, run the script.
You do make a few more changes.
I have written this script specifically to run on Vagrant VM.
But by making few changes, you can run anywhere.
But anyways, we're going to use cops to set up Kubernetes Cluster and AWS.
So you can do this on the VMs.
Okay.
Once the master node is up, it's going to bring up the worker node.
So one, two.
Bionic 64.
IP address two GB RAM.
You can set this to one GB.
Also, there should be fine.
So after the VM comes up, it's going to execute the script.
Script cube node.
One hyphen in a dot search.
That's the script.
So the script first half is similar.
It's going to run the pre request side, the CTL LZ mod install Docker engine based on the operating
system.
Similar thing.
Disable SELinux, disable firewall.
And then install a cube lit cube idiom and cube CTL, same as the worker node, and it will finally
run this script.
Joint command.
So this script will get generated automatically.
But I have a sample over here.
So the script will have a command automatically created from the script.
Okay there.
This command is generating the script automatically.
So it will have the command to join, so the script will get executed, will join the worker node to
the master node.
This will be over.
This is a sample from a previous execution.
Once that is done, the worker node will be joined to the master node.
Now No.
Two almost similar Cubano to any such.
Prerequisites.
Unless mod still install docker engine based on the operating system.
Said Kubernetes Repository Install Cube lit.
Cube Admin Cube Ctl.
And then finally running the script.
Which will join this worker node also to the master node.
See, all you to do is just get into the van near the vagrant file.
The same directory say vagrant up and wait for few minutes.
In your Kubernetes cluster with Cube, it will be up and running.
Let's test this.
If you any time wish to run all these commands manually, you can just copy paste them.
On the shell.
You just need to take care.
You're going to run master command on master node and node command on the node.
So I'm saying vagrant up.
You forced.
The M.A. is coming up and we'll execute our script.
So after waiting some time, the cluster is up, the VMs are up.
We not we don't know for sure whether the cluster is up or not.
So let's log in and find out.
Fragrant as such.
Cube master, This is where the cube config file is stored.
We're in.
Let's clear the screen.
Q I still get notes.
And we see everything ready.
So we have the cube master, which is ready.
We're only on Cube Master, Node one and Node two.
So it's a three node.
And this cluster you should have in your home directory cube config file.
You can use this file, copy it in your local machine and you can use Cube Ctrl from your machine as
well.
This file is generated when we run the companies cluster.
When the medium command, we run and then feed our script, it gets it got copied to the home directory.
We have also copied it to the root user home directory.
Skip config file there as well.
So from root is user.
Also you can run cube CTL get nodes.
And that works.
Okay, now let's run our usual test.
It'll create cluster.
Mean, we should have given a different name.
Let's give one more.
Hello.
Hyphen Cuba idiom.
That's the name of a deployment.
And we'll expose it.
Hello, Hyphen.
Q Adam.
On board ADHD.
That's fine.
Okay, so we should have a pod which was created from.
This deployment.
And we should also have this service.
So the new report is 32748.
You can see much in detail.
It'll get poured.
It's a cube.
It'll describe a pod.
And we'll check our pod on which node it is running.
So you see that it's running on cubed, not two.
So when you describe your part, it will give you detailed information and you can find out, find out
where it is running.
And we have exposed the port.
32748.
Let's test it.
Let's open our browser.
So I'll access it on board 3 to 7 four eight as the service has exposed on this port.
Right.
So you get the page.
That's awesome.
Now, that was about Node two, but, you know, we have a network and we can connect our pod from any
worker node or even master node.
So let's try 56.3.
That's cube node one.
That is also working.
And we'll also try the M.A. 56.2.
Now it's also working.
So we have successfully verified our Cube Kubernetes cluster, which we created from Cube EDM.
And as in this video we are just talking about setup, that should be all for cube EDM.
Let's hard you can heart or if you want, you can even destroy your VMs.
You should have three VMs.
Cube Master Cube Node one.
Cube Node two.
I'm going to destroy it because I don't need it now.
Okay, so we're done here with cube idiom.
Let's now shift our attention to cops.
That we're going to do completely on a.
So let's see what we're going to do.