To set up Kubernetes cluster with cars.
We need to have.
We need to do some prerequisites.
The first, you need to have a domain where we're going to use.
Use it for Cuba and its DNS records.
So like I have a domain from GoDaddy groovy dot in.
So you should also have if you gone through the prerequisites video.
We need a Linux VM we can use with current VM, but I'm going to use EC2 instance.
If you wish to use your current VM, you can do that.
This VM will be only to set up the cops.
Kube Ctl ssh keys and a clean.
So this will be our base machine to launch the Kubernetes cluster with cops.
This will be not part of the code in this cluster and this VM.
We are going to install COPS Cube CTL, which is going to generate SSH keys and we're going to install
a, w, C, and also a configurable clean.
You us account.
We need an S3 bucket and I am user for a CLI.
We're going to need route 53 hosted zone which will be our subdomain.
So after creating the hostage zone, we are going to give its entry.
We'll get the NSS servers, name server URLs.
We're going to give it's entry in our domain.
I'm going to use GoDaddy and I'm going to create for DNS records and record, which is going to point
out to a subdomain to name server from eight plus Route 53.
So domain on GoDaddy, subdomain on Amazon Route 53.
Okay, so let's do the prerequisites first.
I'm on my management console, I'm on EC2 service.
I'm going to launch an easy to instance.
And I'm going to use Ubuntu Server 20.
T2 Micro should be fine.
Our default.
This is for our cops setup.
I'm going to name it as a cops.
Just cops.
We need a simple security group for this.
We're just going to do a search to it.
Support 22 allowed from my IP.
And will create a key.
Mm.
Cops key.
Let's launch the instance.
By the time this is getting launched, let's do some other things on that.
We need like an S3 bucket and we also need to create an IAM user.
And also Route 53 hosted zone.
So let's go to S3 bucket.
Let's create a bucket.
This bucket going is going to store the state of cops.
So we're going to maintain the cops state in an S3 bucket.
And if you do that, then we can run our COPS command from anywhere as long as we pointed to our S3
bucket.
So let's name it as v profile hyphen cops hyphen state.
And I'm going to say create.
Okay.
If you have a bucket now, let's create an I am user.
This will be for a CLI.
I'm going to name this user as cops admin Programatic access.
I'm going to give it administrator access because it's going to access various service like VPC.
It's going to create auto scaling group Route 53.
If you want, we can selectively select all those permission, even S3 bucket, and we can give that
or we can just give administrator access.
But then we have to be very careful with the access keys.
I'm going to download the credentials.
Okay, Now let's go to Amazon Route 53.
We're going to create a hosted zone.
Mm.
V profile.
Now.
I should see Cube.
Repro.
Okay.
That is going to be my subdomain.
It's going to be a publicly hosted zone create hosted zone.
Oh, of course.
I have to give the complete domain name.
Also graphy dot n so my domain is graphy dot n.
So I'm saying q v dot groovy dot in.
And I'm going to create a hostage zone now.
So close that terror.
Okay.
When we do that, we should get the server's URL.
And we can add this entry in our domain.
Registrar.
I'm going to do that in my GoDaddy account.
So log into your registrar provider.
I'm on my GoDaddy account and I'm going to add four names.
Record name, server, host.
Said all students own name Q Vpro.
Points to the NZT server.
So we have for any server.
I'm going to take that one first.
Save it like that.
I'll add entry for the other three.
And that should be it.
I have four new records over here for my sub domain that points to the name server of Amazon Route 53.
Okay, we're done here.
Okay, so now we have a user and a three bucket.
That's our three bucket.
And easy to instance.
Now we'll log into our receipt instance and we'll set up everything.
So first I will generate the SSH key, which will be used by the cops.
So the public key will be pushed to all our instances.
You just generate the key, that's all.
Next we will install a CLI.
So I'm going to run first apt update
apt install a c ally.
After having my IWC lie, I'm going to configure it as configure.
It's going to ask the access key and secret key, which I already have downloaded.
Region.
We are using a higher region.
So the code is us east to.
Output.
I would like to have it in JSON format if I need to.
S c l i configured now.
We need Kube, ctl and cops.
So from the company's documentation, install and set up Cube CTL.
You can just copy this command.
Which will download Cube Ctrl.
So we should have now a little binary.
We are going to give it executable permission and then we're going to move it to use our local bin.
So if you move it over there, then we can access it from anywhere.
Cube, CTL.
Hyphen hyphen vision.
I don't think there is a version, but there is hyphen hyphen help.
Yes.
And still is installed.
Now final tool to install is the cops.
Installing cooperatives with cops.
Linux.
You copy that command?
That should download as a cop's binary.
Okay, that's there.
Let's give it to executable permission.
And that's off of your name, so I'm going to move it.
To use our local bin with name cops.
Let's check it.
Cops hyphen hyphen help.
And copse is also set because now we can run, the cops come on and create our cluster.
But before that I would like to verify my domain.
So I will do an s lookup hyphen type.
Nice and my domain cube with pro dot graphy dot in.
And yeah, that results to the for name server.
Okay.
Now I'm going to run a cops command which will create the queries cluster.
And this is a little longer command.
So let's try and understand it.
The same time command is cops create cluster.
That's the command and we need to pass a lot of arguments.
First is the name of our cluster, which will give the same as our domain.
So I type that and you type your domain.
I'm going to say space a backward slash and hit enter so I can keep entering the command in the next
line.
Next I'm going to say hyphen hyphen state.
Equal to s three colon, slash slash.
The bucket name which we created in the prerequisites then hyphen hyphen zones.
Equal to.
US is to a comma.
US is to be two zones.
So I'm going to mention two worker nodes.
These two worker nodes will be distributed in these two zones.
So space backward slash eight enter hyphen hyphen node hyphen count equal to two.
If you wish, you can give more than that.
But for the practice purpose, it should be fine.
And then it's.
Then it's size, hyphen, hyphen, node, hyphen size.
Is equal to TW three dot small.
Yes.
This is not going to be free.
It is not going to be t three micro.
You can try with t three micro.
It works.
But when we run our workloads, when we run our parts containers, then it will become slow and even
hang.
So be careful with that.
Hyphen hyphen master.
Hyphen size.
Masterson is also 33.
D3 dot I'm going to give here.
DT three.
Medium Yes.
Because Master will run many other parts for our different services, for our scheduler at CD, controller
manager for all that.
It will run pods and we will be later running our workload also.
So I'm giving at3 medium.
You can try with T three small as well, but do not use t three micro.
It won't work.
It will be dead slow and even will not even create many times.
Hyphen hyphen.
DNS hyphen zone.
So that's our zone name.
Subdomain and the domain space backward slash it enter and now hyphen hyphen node hyphen volume.
Hyphen size.
Equal to eight.
Now, if you do not specify this volume size, I'm saying it means eight GB for the worker nodes.
If you do not specify, it is going to create a very large volume and you can see a lot of bills later.
Hyphen hyphen Master hyphen volume.
Hyphen size is equal to eight.
Make sure you definitely give this, otherwise it for a it is going to create huge volumes 120 GB of
three volumes.
So keep it to eight.
That's minimum.
Now this command is not going to create the cluster.
Yes, it is going to create configuration for the cluster and store it in this S3 bucket.
So let's hit enter.
So it created the cluster and it stored the information in the S3 bucket.
Right.
So, Control.
See, I'm not running once again.
This Now you need to run this command Cops Update cluster.
Hyphen f and yes, hyphen f and I mean copy that.
And with this, you also need to give the bucket.
Every time you run the cops command, you need to specify the bucket.
Otherwise it won't work.
So whenever you make any change to your cops configuration, you say cops have data and will apply the
changes.
So we just created configuration for a fresh cluster and we say update cluster.
It will read from the S3 bucket and apply all those things.
And this is going to take some time.
So I'm going to pause my video and come back when this is up.
After issuing this command.
Wait for, like 15 minutes.
At least.
And after that, we can verify our notes.
Okay.
After waiting for like 15 minutes now I'm going to run this command.
Cops validate cluster and hyphen F and state bucket pot.
If everything is good.
It will say your cluster is ready.
Now, that was cops command.
Now you have QCT installed.
And when you create this cluster with cops, cops will create a file for the Kube CTL command.
That file path will be in your home directory dot cube directory.
Inside that there is a config file.
This is the file for cube CTL.
We will talk about this file in detail.
In upcoming lectures.
But this file is used by CTL to connect to the cluster so you can skip Ctrl get nodes.
And you see a master node and you see to worker node.
Now, if you are excited to look from a console, you can check that also.
Let's go to our console.
Okay.
You should see in the console one master node and two worker nodes and look at their size and check
the zone.
So one worker is in two way.
Another worker is in two.
B and Master is in two A.
Now, this is created by auto scaling group.
So if you come to auto scaling group.
So you should see three auto scaling group.
One for master.
One for one worker.
And therefore another worker.
Now for.
Two worker to different auto scaling group.
That is because they are in two different zones.
Now all this is managed by cops.
Cops will do all this.
Along with this you should have a VPC also set up.
So it will be on a separate VPC.
So you go to your VPC and you should see a separate VPC.
Also Route 53.
In your home state zone, you will see new records that are created API.
Q Bibliography in this point to the master node IP.
Then you have internal that points to the master node private IP.
You can see more detail about this node.
We have separate cube conflict cube Seattle session where I have talked about these commands in detail,
but this is enough for now.
To set up the cluster.
Now, if you want, you can go ahead and delete the cluster whenever you need.
You can create them.
Keep in mind, don't if you keep it running.
I will charge you for that because the instance size is bigger.
T three.
Small and medium.
So if you are not using it, delete the cluster.
Command is simple.
Instead of cops validate, you have to just say cops delete.
Hyphen.
Yes.
And they should delete the cluster.
Okay, My bad.
We also have to give the name of the cluster here because it should know which cluster it is.
Deleting hyphen if a name equal to.
And that's not.
That's not the cluster name.
Yeah, they're hyphen fnm equal to the name of the cluster bucket and at the end hyphen hyphen.
Yes.
Hit enter and they should start deleting the cluster.
And this will take some time.
Because it will go through the VPC sort of scaling group DNS record, everything IAM roles, many things
it has created.
So it's going to delete all of them and it takes some time.
Once the cluster is deleted is going to give you back your shell.
Do not try to delete this cluster manually.
There are many things.
If you really want to do it manually, then you have to start from auto scaling Group delete.
Auto Scaling Group Delete VPC.
Clear DNS Records.
And do that only inverse situation where you are not able to run cops cluster command.
Now if you want to create it once again, it's just those two commands.
Don't remove your prerequisite, Keep your bucket, keep your hosted zone, keep your domain, everything.
Then all you need to do is just run these two commands.
Cops create cluster and cops update cluster and your cluster is back.
Once this is deleted, we are going to shut down our cops.
Easy, for instance.
Okay, my cluster is deleted.
Now I can power off this cop's VM.
I can just pseudo power off certain spelling.
Or you can just go to the CD console and just shut down your cups here.
And as I said, whenever you want your cluster back powered on your cops VM login.
Cops create cluster, cops update cluster and putting all the commands in the resource section.
That is all in this video.
I will see you in the next one.