Amazon.
IKEA's elastic Kubernetes service.
So you see in shops, we have to do a lot of prerequisites.
Then we run the cops come on and we have the cluster.
Then we have to use COPS command to manage that cluster.
Compute resource X is directly a managed service from us, and it's very easy to create a Kubernetes
cluster with this.
And that, too, for production.
So let's check the user guide.
You can read about it.
What is X?
In this section, we're just going to see how to create the Kubernetes cluster on X.
So we'll see.
Getting started with X.
So there are two ways to create X cluster.
One is through Sealy.
One is through console.
CLA is the easiest one.
You just need to issue of some long command and the cluster will be up and running.
The console way is a long way.
So you have to first install a ally and you have to run some commands to configure CLI.
Commands to run Kube Ctl on Mac OS or on Windows.
And then once you're done with those things, you can create an AI role for your X cluster.
Steps are given over here.
I'm running quickly over here because we're going to do it much faster through clean.
Guess first thing you have to do in before creating the cluster is you have to create a VPC.
And that can be done here through cloud formation template.
There.
You can copy that and you can launch that template, which will create a stack with all the VPC, private
subnet, public subnet, all those things.
Once your VPC is ready, then you can go to finally X service.
And you can launch your cluster by selecting your VPC.
And then inside that you have to create worker nodes.
So there are really a lot of steps to do.
The much faster way is through x steel.
You need a blue collar x steel tool.
You just you just configure it with the access credentials once you have it.
So once you have the X, still see a lie.
With right credential, you can just exit and create cluster and you give all the information and it
will create a multi node Kubernetes cluster for you.
I have a much simpler step for this.
We are going to launch a Vagrant VM, which is going to set up the tools that we need for EC2.
Then we're going to run this EC2 command and we'll have our.
Kubernetes cluster on X.
So once you have once we are done, we should see a cluster over here.
Right now, there's nothing.
Okay, So let's get started.
We're going to go to our source code.
You should be in this branch covered in this hyphen set up.
Get into exe directory.
Here you have a vibrant file which is going to execute first a script X Tools Setup search.
Accessing it from my sublime text editor X.
So that's the background file.
It's a simple VM.
Ubuntu will get created and it will execute the script.
X Tools hyphen Setup search.
The script, the Shell script is just going to set up.
It was silly.
And.
Exactly.
So based on your operating system, if you have used any Red Hat machine, it's going to install these
tools, zip and unzip.
If it's open to machine, it's going to say apt install, zip and zip.
Once you have zip and on zip.
It's going to use this URL to download a CLA.
This is a CLA version too.
So don't do a apt install it.
Let me give you version one.
We need version two.
So from this URL you can download it.
Then it's going to unzip it and there will be a script install script which will get executed and that
is going to set up a SEAL version two.
Once you have a publicly.
It's going to download binary of CTL.
From that URL.
So it will be downloaded in temp directory and then it will be moved to your local bin.
And you can run the command to check the vision.
Then we're going to download Cube.
Give it executable permission and move it to your cell local bin.
So we are having three tools with this script.
C fly.
ECUs Ctl and Cube Ctl.
Once our VM is up after executing all the scripts, we'll log into the VM and we are going to execute
the script x cluster hyphen setup message.
We are declaring some variables over here.
The cluster name that you're are going to give if you wish, you can change that region.
So I'm going to Ohio, so I'm going to select my region as Ohio US East to.
Node name.
So it's going to.
So you don't have a master over here.
The service itself is the master.
You have the worker node, which we just call it as node.
So we're going to give some name to it.
I'll just give Linux hyphen nodes and a key.
This will be the public key name.
So we have to create a key payer with this name.
So let's go to S.E. to make sure you're in the same region.
Quebecers.
Create keeper.
Okay, so that key will be used.
You can use this key to log in to your worker node.
Then this command will get executed.
If your credentials are set.
We have to run a double click to install a double SQL and we have to run a plus configure.
That's mentioned over there.
After that.
It is going to run this command.
If this is successful, your key is verified.
Then this command will get executed.
X, it'll create cluster the name of the cluster version, region node group name nodes.
How many nodes we going to with two two worker nodes, node minimum one and maximum four.
This is the auto scaling group size.
Node type 3t3 Micro.
There's no t two micro here.
Node volume size eight GB we are giving.
And such access as such public key hyphen hyphen managed.
If this is all successful, I'll script is going to print cluster created successfully.
Else we're going to get a failed message.
So all we need to do bring up the VM login and execute the script.
So let's do that.
Let's do vagrant up.
Okay, Now the provisioning has started.
It's executing our script to set up our three tools.
E w c Ally Cube, Ctl and X Ctl.
Now Cavium is up.
Let's log into it and search.
Okay, let's check our three tools.
E w.
S hyphen hyphen version.
It like to.
IKEA's Seattle version.
Story in is also there and then Kub Steel version.
Our three tools are set.
First, we need to do a configure.
Access key and secret key.
So let's create an IM user.
You can use existing IM user that you used for cops.
If you have deleted it, create a new user.
So I'm going to create a new user.
I will limit as x admin programmatic access.
Attach policy administrator access.
Go next.
Download credentials.
Or I can just copy paste from here itself.
Copy the access key.
Okay.
A blue collar is set.
Let's go to slash vagrant directory.
And we have the cluster set up script.
IKEA's cluster set up research.
If you wish to change some variable names, you can change it.
It's going to set these variables.
And on the command it lists get caller identity.
If this is successful, we will be running the command which will create the x cluster.
Okay, so let's run the script.
Okay, that's working.
Already started deploying the cluster.
Okay.
This can turn out to be very expensive if you run it for a very long time, because it is also going
to set up VPC with NAT gateways.
Distributed among multiple zones.
So once you are done.
Checking it, testing it, then deleted also.
Let's go to X and let's see what's happening there.
What's.
Refresh this?
Nothing yet.
Let's go and check VPC.
Okay.
You should see a new VPC.
This is created by our exit.
Come on.
Should see multiple subnets.
Six subnets.
Three public and three private.
Let's check the nerd gateway.
In that gateway is getting created.
So it's going to wait until this Nat Gateway is not up once VPC up with the NAT Gateway, the VPC stable,
then it's going to start launching our cluster and that VPC.
So I'm going to pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
It's long time and still the cluster is creating.
But we can see now the cluster creation has started.
At least we profile X cluster.
Right.
So this acts like your master notes.
You don't have a master node.
After some time you will see in the compute node here, the worker node group will be there and we have
said to worker nodes.
So we'll see two compute nodes over here.
This is all done through a cloud formation template.
So if you go to cloud formation.
Should see a cloud formation template there.
The events.
So was creating your nerd gateway.
And that is completed.
It's two shows in progress.
Resources.
C two group control plane X cluster.
So if not with exit command, then you have to do this yourself.
You have to get the cloud formation template, upload it and create the stack.
And that requires you to create two cloud formation stack, one for VPC and one for the x cluster.
And you have to take care of creating the roles and few other things.
So a lot of steps, really.
So.
Doing it through X.
CTL is the easiest and the fastest way.
All right.
So it says EEGs cluster in this region is ready.
Let's check it.
So you should see to cloud formation template here.
One is for the cluster, the VPC, and then the other one is for the node group.
Let's go to X.
Fresh and it is active.
Click on it.
Compute and you should see Linux nodes to desired.
So this is running easy to instance.
As same as we are running it through cops.
There's an option also to use for Target.
And if you wish, you can add here more node group you can add forget also if you want.
App server.
End Point is also there.
Okay, let's check the cube config file.
Should be in the home directory of migrant user.
Yes, there's a cube config file.
Let's run it.
You'll get notes.
So you should see the two worker notes.
You'll not see the master node, and then you can run all your test.
You can launch pod deployment services, any other object on the Kubernetes cluster.
It's going to be work.
Same as it works for any other Kubernetes cluster with Cube, CTL Command.
So you see with one simple script that's running this command.
We have a production grid.
Kubernetes cluster up and running.
And also not to mention with VPC.
If you are done testing over here, you can delete the cluster.
You should not keep it running because there's also not Gateway Linux nodes.
These two instances and this can turn out to be expensive.
So we'll delete the cluster with the cube Ctrl delete cluster.
So the name of our cluster we profile X cluster.
It's basted tender and it's going to take some time.
It's going to create, delete, VPC notes, everything.
So wait until it's completely deleted.
If you get any error, you can very easily go to cloud formation templates and delete the stacks.
That can be also done and that should be all in this video.
Thank you very much for watching.
I will see you in the next one.