Welcome to the introductory session of cloud formation.
What we do with cloud formation, well, we automate and maintain the state of our cloud resources.
Sounds similar or familiar.
If you have gone through TerraForm Project videos or if you already know TerraForm, then yes, it may
sound similar.
And both the both both the tools have similarity in most cases, except for one big difference.
Cloud formation is specific to a yes, it's an A service, whereas TerraForm supports many other cloud
providers.
There are so many blogs that compares the difference between cloud formation and terraform, and you
can check them in if you need help in making the decision.
But as for me, if you want to automate and maintain the cloud infrastructure and you need a native
service to do that, then you can go with cloud formation.
But if you want more than eight of us, you want some other providers also.
Then you can go with TerraForm.
Let's understand terminologies in cloud formation.
Templates.
Templates are really the text files, or you can see the scripts of cloud formation, but they are really
not scripts.
Any programming language, you can write them either in YAML or JSON format.
So cloud formation will read this template as an input and the output will be the resource that it will
create and maintain.
You describe the state of your infrastructure in these text files.
Templates they are called.
So if you're comfortable with JSON, you can go with JSON.
If you're comfortable with YAML, you can go with YAML.
I recommend YAML because it's much easier to read and write yaml.
So what templates does is it creates and maintains the stack.
So you want to create any resource or maintain any resource on it.
As you write, template file and cloud formation will read that and create a stack for you.
If you want to make any change to a resource like, for example, security group rules change.
So you update your template and then you update your stack.
So you stack will read your change template.
And make the changes or create or update your stack.
Stat is basically a single unit of multiple resources or even it could be a single resource as well.
Like you want to create easy to instance S3 bucket idea, so you can put all that in your template which
will create a stack for you.
And so you can see input is the template and output is the stack.
Change set.
I want to highlight very initially because when you maintain the state of your infrastructure through
template, you can very easily make changes.
You can update your stack by updating your template.
Before you roll out, that changes.
You can call for a change so that you can generate a change set.
So change that will detect the difference between what you what was the state and what you meant and
will show you the impact.
What impact will happen if you make all these changes.
This is very, very important thing for life systems, for productions.
For example, if you have an ideas and you're renaming an ideas, which is very easy to do in the template
file, it's a text file, you can very easily change the name, right?
But when you roll out that change in ideas, it's going to create a new, for instance, and delete
the old ones.
So it will delete your data.
If you have gone through a TerraForm plan, it's similar to that You plan first, you show the change
set, how it's going to impact.
If you're good with it, then you roll out.
Hours.
The result will be data loss.
Okay, now let's understand the template anatomy.
Now that's everything really of cloud formation.
You really need to learn the template.
So it supports Jason and Jamaal both.
Let's see for Jason.
Okay so that's in Jason format.
First thing you have is a template format version.
This is what you have to describe.
This is not mandatory, this is optional or all of them are optional except resource resource is the
only mandatory section in your template version is optional.
Description.
You can give some description about your template.
It's going to be a string metadata, some more information about your template parameters if you want
some input parameter.
When the user is creating the stack like key pair or select a security group, you can mention that
mappings.
So it will be the mapping of key value pairs store like a dictionary in python or a hash table or a
lookup table.
In TerraForm we create a variable of type map, so it's similar to that.
So based on condition, you can pick up the right value talking about conditions, that's the next thing.
Conditions.
You can specify a condition and based on the condition is true, it can create the stack or make some
other decision.
Transforms are good for serverless application where you can specify the version of a SAM Resources,
the only mandatory property over here where you define the resources easy to instance or load balancer
or S3 and their properties output.
If you want to print something out once your template is created or while it is creating.
So these are the section and accept resources.
All of them are optional and mostly we just give a little description and resources and if you want
we can print something.
And of course the parameters, these are regularly used things.
Same thing in a YAML format.
Much easier to read.
And easier to write also.
Okay.
Talking about resources, the most important thing and this is what actually makes your real stack in
JSON format.
So resource value in JSON format is again, a dictionary.
You give a logical ID, this will not be the name of your resource, but you know it's a reference in
your template.
This is not going to be the name of the resource that you create if you're creating an easy to instance,
logical ID.
If you go over here like example instance, so the instance name will not be example instance.
It is just a logical idea to refer in your template.
So you see a resource and then you can say like for example, some name over here and then you set type
resource type inside.
That resource type will be easy, for instance, or S3 bucket the services that you want to use and
then properties offered like for S3 bucket, any key that you want to create, any encryption that you
want to enable.
And that is in YAML format.
And we are going to use the YAML format only you see much easier to read and much easier to write resources
with some examples.
So I want to launch an easy to instance.
I'm going to say resources and it's case sensitive.
Our capital, the resources.
Then you give a logical ID, whatever name you want to give, type A colon, colon E to colon, colon
instance, and then properties.
So properties like image instance, type availability zone, VPC, security group keeper, all those
will be the properties and it's all available in the documentation.
It has all the great documentation as always for its services.
Cloud formation documents are also documentations are also very good.
The both in JSON and YAML format.
If you see YAML looks much better.
Let's take a look at the documentation, some sample from ADA plus documentation of cloud formation.
So it is documentation cloud formation, User guide.
You can find your resource like what you see right now is elastic IP.
So I'm going to scroll this up.
So you can read about it.
What this resource is for syntax.
You can see this is in JSON format and that's in YAML format properties domain instance ID and you can
see all the properties and their values that you can give.
Instance ID type is a string.
Is it required?
No, that's not mandatory.
Right.
So all the details are given tags and what it's going to return return value for reference.
Examples.
I directly jump to the examples, for example, in JSON format, an example in YAML format.
So like this, you can scroll through all the resources that you want.
So I'm checking for ec2.
You can check for other things.
X x elastic cache.
All of this.
So wouldn't be a big trouble to write really cloud formation templates.
One more example.
S3 bucket so resources a logical lady like my I'm giving like my S3 bucket type.
Eight.
Colon.
Colon x3.
Colon bucket.
You can get that from the documentation for your resource properties and you can find all the properties
in the documentation and what value you can give.
He and I'm giving bucket name some bucket name access control, publicly read web configuration values
and other dictionaries of web configuration, then indentation index document and the document.
So this resource is going to create a bucket name chamomile, public REIT access, and it's going to
put this file for the website configuration.
Let's see one more example for security group resource or logical ID type.
Again, get this security group.
Resource name from the documentation properties and you can find all the properties like group description.
You can give its values a string.
Group name its values also string security group ingress ingress value IP protocol TCP from port the
port number two port, the two port number CIDR IP, and you can give the IP address.
I know you're thinking it looks more similar to TerraForm.
And so if you have if you have some hands on one of the tool or even if your hands on Ansible, you
can learn these very easily.
So I think that much introduction should be fine.
Let's jump into our ID and start writing some code.