All right, I'm in my management console.
And I will go to cloud formation service.
So a blood clot formation model and provision all your cloud infrastructure so you can check the getting
started guide.
You can also watch some video over there to understand how it works.
But anyways, we're covering that.
So this stack, that's that's the result of your template, right?
So when you say create stack, you have to mention the template.
You can say your template is ready and you can upload your template.
You can also put your template in S3 bucket and you can mention the endpoint of the bucket.
So I'll pick up your template from there.
What we'll do is we're going to write template on our machine, on our computer, on our laptop by using
ID or any text editor, and you will just upload it from here.
We'll just choose file, we'll upload our template there.
Also some sample template to try.
If you initially want to see how it works, you can select some sample template like Clam Stack, Ruby
on Rails WordPress blog.
And that is for single.
You have multi AC also for Windows, a few templates.
You can try to understand how it really works.
Now you can create a template in designer.
It's more of drag and drop, but I really don't prefer that.
I think writing the template in YAML format is much, much easier than doing that drag and drop.
Okay, So we will write our template and we'll upload that template.
So let me open my sublime text editor.
Fossil create a directory somewhere in the F try.
I'll create a directory.
I'll call it a cloud.
I'll call it a C formation.
Underscore basics.
Okay, let's open this inner sublime text editor.
Open folder.
After I see formation basics.
Okay, let's write our first template.
I'm going to say new file.
Save it with name.
First hyphen.
Example.
Dot y html.
If you wish to use here your intelligence, you can try that.
But we're going to write very simple, simple, basic templates and intelligence.
Also have plugins for cloud formation.
So it's going to give you a quick suggestion.
It's not so good when you're initially learning any technology, any any program or you're learning
any template.
It's good to first understand the basics and write everything from the scratch without any help.
Once you have that basic.
Then you can take all the help.
So I'm going to say resources.
That's the only mandatory section.
Resources are capital, colon.
I'll give a logical ID, I'll see my instance.
Colon.
And type.
So I want to launch easy to instance, right?
So I'm going to access e, w s, colon.
Colon, e, c to colon.
Colon.
Instance.
And the resource will, of course, have the properties in the same line.
You're going to see properties.
People there and the properties instance type.
I will see.
RT two dot Micro.
Okay.
Image ID.
Let's get that.
So let's try and launch an instance manually and find my ID, Amazon Linux.
Amazon Linux too.
Should be fine.
Let's pick up that image ID.
Okay.
Only I give this much.
I'm going to save this template and let's go to cloud formation.
Now, cloud formation stack and a template is ready or I'll cancel and do it once again.
Create stack.
Template is ready.
Upload a template file.
I'm going to choose file.
Find your template and just upload it.
Now it is an option to view in designer, if you want to check that.
So that's the designer.
Right here.
You can even validate your template.
You can click on this checkmark.
It will validate your template if it's good.
It seems template is valid and it's gone.
Okay, for a minute.
So if you're good with your validation, you can just say create stack from here itself.
It's going to take you back, actually.
So we'll see next.
Okay.
Will you stack a name on the first hyphen?
Stack.
No parameters.
You're not given any parameters.
If you give any parameters, it can list over here next.
If you'd like to give some tag, some role you want to give some advance option, we'll just take everything.
Default go next.
Last review section.
If you're good with everything, just say create stack.
Or you can say create change set.
Let's directly go with create stack first.
Okay, so that lands up in the event page over here.
It says Create in progress.
That's a forced event.
You can keep refreshing this to find out the events.
Creating progress.
Resource creation initiated.
User initiated.
So it's going to take take a moment to launch an instance and now it's completed its create complete.
You can check the stack info.
Stack ID is there.
You can see the template that created this resource.
Or this stack.
If you're printing any output, you can see that in the output section.
But really, let's just see, for instance, whether it's launched or not.
We see one running instance there.
Refresh.
There is an instance running, but it does not have any tag anything.
So now what we'll do is.
We will update our stack.
So that's a stack and there's an update button.
So we'll make change to a template.
Or we can write another template.
We'll say update.
Because our instance does not have any tag.
I want to give a tag now.
So let's go to our sublime text and I'll create another file.
I will name it as.
Update.
Update example.
That should be fine.
Okay.
I'll copy everything from the first template.
And I will give tags.
So you can give tags.
You can see just tags, colon.
And you can give a list of tags like hyphen key.
So I'll see name and value.
I will say my.
For instance.
For my first instance.
Let's see if this.
Okay.
Now let's update our existing stack with a new template.
So you can say use current template, the same template.
You can make change or you can say replace current template.
I want to replace.
I want to upload another template, which is this one.
You can go next if you want.
You can view and design it and validate if there is any syntax error, it will highlight that.
I'll just say.
Next.
And.
Okay.
Let's go update, Jack.
It's making an update.
Updating progress, it says.
It's going to take a moment.
Now in a few seconds, is update completed?
Let's see our instance letter refresh and you see that.
Now you to be careful in this part.
Maybe while you're updating a stack, it may delete your resource and recreate it so it's better you
check change set that we'll see in the next video.
You.
After you're done with this, just delete your stack.
You can say delete stack from here.
Delete stack.
When you say delete stack, it will delete your resources also.
Of course.
You see that shutting down and it will get terminated.
You can check events.
I recommend you wait till it deletes everything.
Sometimes because of some issues the delete feels.
And it sees now delete completely.
If you're done here, then move to the next video.