Cloud formation has some built in functions which can turn out to be very useful.
You're going to see one simple example of a function that cloud formation provide.
But from the documentation, you can check some intrinsic function.
We'll see example of how to use a function in this video.
So we're going to go with a simple function.
Join.
Join is a function for string.
It will join a list, a comma separated list into a string.
Some examples we can go.
Okay, this is JSON format.
This is YAML format.
First how to call a function.
So exclamation and the function name join.
And joint function will need to argument one is a string and second is going to be the list list of
strings.
So it's going to join this list of string together with colon.
Okay, let's try that.
We'll use it in our tag, for instance.
Tag.
So let's write.
A new file.
Save it.
The name of functions.
Dot y.
M.
L.
So we'll use our template from update example.
So here we have given a value directly, a string.
Now, instead of that, I'm going to replace that with the join function, which will return a string.
So exclamation and the function name.
Join.
Space and in square bracket, we have to pass two values.
So I'm going to say I'm going to use this as a string hyphen.
Comma and I will give.
I have to give a list.
So I'll see my comma instance comma from.
Come on, Cloud.
Formation.
Very, very simple example.
So this should return me a string separate by comma.
And that will be the name.
Of my instance in the tag.
Let's see if this and let's try this.
Go to cloud formation.
Let's create stack template is ready.
Upload our template.
Choose file.
Functions.
Next.
Enter stack name.
Just give name s function.
Underscore.
Join.
Next.
I can't give underscore.
The hyphen.
Okay.
Taking all defaults.
And just to create stack.
I guess the insurance should get created.
Let's check.
And it's the old instance.
Yeah.
You see there in the tags, it has joined my list into a string separate by hyphen.
Now, if you go to Tag's really, you have the nametag that we have given.
But when you create a resource with cloud formation, it will also add some extra tags.
Which is very, very useful.
So you can see this the resource is really created by cloud formation and it has the logical ID there.
And also has the stack ID, so it's easy for you to filter and really, you know, go and find the stack
and you can make changes from there instead of making manual changes here.
So that is good.
That's what I wanted to show you in this video.
Stack is completed.
Now, we we're done with this.
You can delete the stack.
So that's how you can really call a function, exclamation and the function name and the value that
you pass.
You're going to see a few more functions in our upcoming videos.
So if you're done here, wrap up your stack and join me in the next video.