In this video, we're going to see about change set.
One of the most important thing I feel for life or production systems.
When you have a stack life up and running and you want to make change, you really need to see what
this change is going to or how this change is going to affect your existing resources.
So we'll create an easy to instance and then we're going to make some changes to it and we'll see from
the change set how does it affect.
So it's create a new file save we'll call it as.
Change hyphen set.
Dot y wireman.
So I'll just copy the previous resource.
Okay, First we'll just create instance with this template and then we'll make changes to it.
And it creates Jack.
Tablet is ready.
Upload our template.
Chin said.
And we'll see next.
Brexit testing Change set.
Now when you creating it first time change, it doesn't make sense.
There's not going to be any much change.
It's a fresh stack, but you can still see create change set.
But first, we'll create the stack.
Then we'll make the change.
Let's wait for a moment so it becomes stable.
Okay, Create.
Completed.
Now let's update the template.
And upload it again.
So first I will just change a tag.
I will.
Change from name this to.
Does it change one?
See this?
And let's update our template.
Update replace or should I say use current template replace will upload it back once again.
Upload template choose file.
Same template, but there are differences now.
And let's go next.
Her next.
Next.
Okay here.
It's going to wait for a moment.
So it's really checking there.
So it's comparing your template with the existing resource.
And it found there is the action is going to be modify.
You can see a view change set to see it in detail changes.
So there will be a modify.
So this is fine.
It's going to be modifying it input.
We are not really providing any input like parameters or anything.
Templates, you can see the templates.
Jay are the Jason changes.
Okay.
This should be fine.
If you're good with this, you will say execute.
Okay, so the update completed and it has modified it.
Let's make one more try.
You can test that with also instance type.
When you check with instance type, it's going to shut down your instance and then bring it back.
Too small.
Let's see if this.
And let's go back.
Update.
Replace upload.
So I made a change to the instance type.
You really don't need to do this because this is chargeable.
It's not due to micro.
But I'm just going to run it for less than an hour.
So that should be fine.
Still it modified.
We'll change that.
So there's really modification camp.
If you're good with this, then you can say execute or you can say delete.
I would like to delete this change set.
All right.
So I don't want to make any changes.
I'm good with the existing thing.
Okay, let's try to do something more.
I will change the Ahmed.
Now, that's not possible, right?
How can you change an image of an instance?
Right.
It's going to delete it.
But maybe you did it by mistake, right?
Or you meant to make some change, and you didn't think thoroughly about it.
That it's an immutable change.
Like changing an army.
Is not possible, Right?
So we know very easy, for instance, very well.
So we know about that.
But things like sometimes, you know, we using some service like ideas or elastic cache or active amp
or any any such service where we make some change and that may result in the data loss.
So change that will help we will be will be very helpful in such cases.
So let's try this.
Update replace upload template new template.
Now this template contains the new image ID.
Let's see what happens.
Next.
Okay.
Let's see.
Okay, it says modify, but if you see here replacement true.
Okay.
That means it's going to definitely delete it and recreate it.
And so you need to be checking here.
All right.
Okay.
If you're good with this, you can execute or you can delete.
I'm not good with this.
I don't want to terminate replace my instance.
Maybe that will cause me data loss.
So I'll say delete this change.
Like this.
This change set can help you and save from big disasters.
All right, If you're done here, just delete your stack and join me in the next video.