So we have seen join intrinsic function previously.
In this video, we're going to see an intrinsic function ref.
As the name suggests.
Ref It refers something like you create a security group and then you want to refer that security group
while you're creating to instance.
So you want to refer an existing resource or a parameter while you're creating or making change to your
existing resource.
Then you can use a ref function.
Some examples.
Let's see.
So this is an example creating an elastic IP.
So logical ID is my IP here type easy to elastic IP properties.
So we want to here join this elastic or associate elastic IP.
Do an instance that you already have created, or we mentioned it in the same template.
So we can say Ref, we call this function and we give the logical ID of the resource.
We're going to do such kind of things in the next video.
In this video we'll see a very simple example of ref intrinsic function.
So I'll create a new file.
I've been named as a ref hyphen function dot AML.
I will use this.
So there's one function already, one interesting function.
Join over here and you can pass an argument like this in square bracket, but you can also pass in vertically
a proper YAML format.
John, delete this.
So first argument that I'm going to pass to Ref is join with the space.
And the next argument is a list.
Again, more arguments.
So I will join.
My v profile or my just instance in.
And here I will use the function.
So I don't have any other existing logical ID in this template.
So I'm going to use this plus colon.
Colon.
Region.
So as in this template, I don't have any other logical idea to refer.
So I'm referring an existing parameter.
This is a pseudo parameter.
You have some list of pseudo parameters.
Like account ID notification.
An.
No value.
Partition region.
So wherever this template will get executed, where the stack will get created so that region value
will be returned.
There are a few others.
Stack id stack name u.
R.
L suffix.
Okay, let's go ahead.
See if this.
And let's create a cloud formation stack.
I'm doing it in Mumbai region.
Let's create stack.
Upload my template.
The rare function.
Go next.
Let's wait for a moment.
And there is a failure rollback.
So if the template creation if the stack creation fails.
It will roll back your changes automatically.
You can see the error.
It says Wrong army ID This army does not exist.
This army is from.
Oregon region and of course in Mumbai region, the Ahmed will be different.
So let's find.
And why I'd.
Let's copy that.
Let's update that in our template.
Save it.
Let's go back.
So a rollback is completed.
But you should still see this tag.
It should have not created any resource.
So I'm going to delete this tag.
Stacks gone.
Let's create a new stack.
Let's wait for a moment.
Yes, it is.
Create complete.
Let's check our instance.
The Mumbai region and its name and you see there.
So we are referring to a parameter pseudo parameter.
So it automatically got the region ID there.
In next example where we also going to create security group.
We'll see how we can refer like this security group for an easy to instance.
So if you're done here, delete your stack.
And join me in the next video.