In this video, we're going to see how to create a security group and easy, for instance, from the
same template file.
We're talking about multiple resources.
If you have multiple resources, we also may need to refer them.
Like if you're creating security group, I want to refer it into my e C, for instance.
First, we'll see how to create a security group so you can check in the documentation template, reference
resources and property reference.
You can find your resource.
Let's go to AC to security group is part of AC two.
There you have AC two and you have a lot of properties in easy to.
Let's expand this a little bit.
Let's find security group.
The security group.
You can click on it.
And you can reduce this.
And as I generally do, just I just go to the example so you can go to the example JSON or YAML.
We're going YAML so they're not.
And this is an easy copy button also there, so you can copy if you want.
But I'll do that later.
First, I will create a file.
I'm going to call it as multi resource dot y html.
So if you generally create easy, for instance from the console, you create easy to instance first.
And while you're creating easy, the instance you create or select your security group.
If you like that order, you can do the same order in the template.
Cloud formation is smart enough to understand how to order your resource.
So I will take a previous example from functions.
Let's take that.
So I'll keep it as it is.
And I'm going to give a property for security group.
Security groups give you multiple security group.
It's a list so you can give in hyphen and elements in the list.
So I want to refer.
And if you're thinking we have not yet created security group, that's fine.
We can create it after this.
I mean, we can mention the security group after the instance.
The order here is not important.
So I'm going to say refer to.
V profile.
SG which I have not yet created, but then I'll make sure I will give the same logical ID when I'm creating
the security group.
I will make sure I'm going to create it in the same line.
So I will give the same name as I've given over here.
The logical ID.
And the rest who make our life easy.
We can copy it directly from here.
I'm going to just copy it from there.
Till the end.
Take care of the indentation.
You see the properties going out.
So let's bring it in.
I will say allow I'll add to rule as such and HDP.
From my IP, I'll say that's a description.
Because I'm not mentioning VPC ID, that's not mandatory.
If you don't mention it's going to take the default VPC security group Ingress inbound rule Security
group egress, outbound rule.
Again, list of rules.
It's a hyphen IP protocol, TCP hat from anywhere.
That's fine.
I will also add one more rule.
I just copy this.
DHCP LC 2020 22 to 2 allowed from only my IP, my IP slash 30 slash 32.
Ingress and egress is not important.
If we don't give this, it's because this is 88 allowed from.
So, you know we won't be able to do such right.
We have to probably see then such rule also.
Anyways, I'm not giving outbound rule if you don't give it's going to all anyways have all traffic
can go anywhere.
Okay, let's save this and let's check again.
So instance will get created.
Ahmed, We need to take care of the Ahmed.
So I will check the Ahmed.
I will launch an instance.
And let's go with.
Open to this time.
Okay, So I'm going to create my cloud formation stack in Mumbai region.
So I'm fetching Ahmed from Mumbai region.
Okay, This is fine.
Save it.
And let's create our stack now.
Let's go to Cloud formation Stack and Mumbai region.
Create stack.
Upload a template.
Multi resource.
That's the one.
You can see in designer.
Let's see how it looks in the designer.
You see that there's a V profile security group and there is an arrow which says really that it is referring
to the security group.
Let's validate our template.
Template is valid.
And let's create it.
Next.
That's entered our name.
I'll give multi resource.
Now let's take everything.
Default.
Create stack.
Okay.
You see, the first thing it's doing, it's creating security group, right?
We have given it in a different order.
We give an easy to instance force and we're smart enough to understand that we need security group first
because it's referring it.
Let's go to our digital dashboard.
Let's go to security group.
And you should see the security group.
Inbound rule 80 allowed from anywhere, 22 allowed from my IP outbound rules we have not mentioned so
at any way sticks this default rule.
Okay.
Let's check out instance.
It should be having the same security group.
Yes, There.
Let's see the tags.
And that's a nametag, which is obviously it is showing there.
And the stack ID is well.
Okay, So this template was or this video was about a referring.
A logical ID in a multi resource template.
So we have multiple resources, we have incidents and we have the security group.
You also learn one more thing.
Order of creation will be handled by cloud formation.
We can specify it in any order, but sometimes there are chances that its order may go wrong and we
will get errors for that.
We can handle also that we'll see those things in project.
We'll see how we can create dependencies between resources for the order.
Okay, this creation is completed anyways.
We have verified everything.
We can delete it.
Delete stack.
Delete in progress.
So wrap up your stack over here and join me in the next video.