So far we have seen just one section in our template anatomy, but we have other sections like mapping.
In this video we'll be talking about mapping.
We'll take an example for that and we'll also see some new pseudo parameters.
So let's go to working with templates.
Template Anatomy.
And mappings.
Let's click on that.
Now what is mapping is just like a dictionary and you want to fetch some value.
You have to give the key name and you can create multiple levels inside.
And once you declare a mapping variable, you can use a finding map intrinsic function to find values
from your keys.
So example should make more sense.
So let's scroll down, let's see examples.
So that's the section mappings.
Like we have resources, we have also mapping section.
Inside that you give a name.
This is mapping for am-I.
So we are saying for this region, if you're doing it in this region, you can say finding map function
for this particular region and it's going to return the value, which is this.
Mapping is mostly used for this particular example, Amis.
As we have seen so far, we're jumping between regions and we are getting a problem of having different,
different army IDs.
So if you want a cloud formation template for UDC to instance, to be working on every region without
making any changes, then you can use mapping to store the image IDs.
So let's create a new template now.
We'll call it as mappings.
And also we're going to do some pseudo parameters.
Dot y.
M.
L.
So let's copy the mappings.
I'll make some changes.
I will give this name as a my region map and I will keep these regions and to this I will change it
to EMI.
Okay.
Now I'm going to go to these regions and find the idea of Amazon Linux to.
I'm in US East one.
I will get Amazon Linux from ID from here.
Let me put that over here.
I will also have it for us.
Easter to us East.
To.
To go to us is to.
That's convenient.
US West one.
So we don't have us.
West one Let's put here the US.
West one.
And I'm going to stop here.
I'll remove these things.
If you're going to use more region, then mention all the region and the image ID that you're going
to use from that region.
For now, I'll only keep this much.
Next, the easy to instance.
So we have to give that in the resources.
Okay, let's take that from the previous example.
Here.
The image is hard coded.
Now I'm going to refer from here my Amy from the mappings.
And for that I have to use the function.
Find in map.
And we have to pass three values for this.
We have to pass the name of the mapping.
We have to pass the key from that mapping.
What we are referring to in that the sub key of it.
It should give you the right, Amy.
So how do I do?
Now you can do it in this format.
You can pass all the argument in a list format.
So I'm going to say my region map the name.
First I have to pass, then then the key inside that, which is actually a region name.
But then I have to hardcoded, right.
Instead of that I can use.
Pseudo parameter E.
S colon, colon region.
So wherever I create this template, it will have the region code, right?
And instead of giving hard coding it, it will automatically pick up the region name.
And from that region name, I would like to give the next key, which is my basically.
So based on the region that I create, it's going to go to that key.
And then inside that AMI the sub key of it and it's going to pick up the my ID, the rest of it, I'll
create save our security group going to do the security group as well.
So security group here.
Can will copy it from the previous.
Template.
Care to take care of the indentation?
And yeah, all the logical IDs are in the same line.
Okay, this seems good.
Let's save this.
And I'm going to create my cloud formation template from or my stack from any of the three region.
So let's go.
Okay, so I'm in Ohio region US East too, and we have created a mapping of RMI for this region.
And I will go to Ohio region or the instances.
Okay, Let's create the stack.
Create stack.
Upload template.
Choose file.
Mapping and pseudo.
Let's go next.
See mapping.
That's just a map example.
Next.
And create stack.
Okay, So it's creating the security group first, as usual.
Now it's creating the instance.
Okay, let's go to the instance.
Refresh.
Okay.
It's creating it.
So it found its image ID automatically from mappings.
I scroll down to see my ID.
So that's the last 7912 in US history to us is to yes, you see that.
So finding map has found the right ID for us based on our region.
Region.
Also we are selecting automatically based on where the template is getting, where the stack is getting
created.
If you're only curious to log in to an instance that are getting launched, we're going to do that in
the next video where we'll select the key payer.
We're going to see what are parameters, how to use them.
And for an example, we're going to take key pair and also instance type as the input parameter from
the user.
If you're done here, you can delete the stack.
And you can join me in the next video.