So from a template anatomy, we have already used a resources.
And we have used also mappings.
Now, in this video we're going to talk about parameters.
While you're creating cloud formation stack, you see parameters option there.
We'll see in this video how we can give user power of entering some parameters so we can use two parameters,
key pair and the instance type.
So let's go to template anatomy parameters.
Defining parameter in a template.
So the parameters, the section logical ID type string, there are few other types.
We'll see that also default.
You can set a default value.
If user does not provide anything, it's going to take that default value.
So for example here to to micro the instance type.
You can give the allowed value in a list format.
So if you give this parameter allowed values and you give the list of allowed values, you'll get a
dropdown over there.
Let's see the other properties.
Allowed values, an array containing a list of values which will create a dropdown constraint description.
Default.
Default can give description maximum length.
Maximum value.
Minimum length.
You can mention all that.
No echo.
If you're taking secret data like passwords, you would like to not print that when the user is typing,
so you can put a no echo there.
Type.
So there are different types.
You have string, you can take numbers, an input list, it's an array of integer or floats.
Eight specific parameters type.
You can also point user to an ADA parameter like, for example, existing key pair.
So you can list it.
So let's see the specific parameters type.
So we're going to create keeper list.
So instance ID, so it's going to list all the instance ID available.
Keep it.
If you use this, then the user will get the list of existing keys.
And for that, we really need to create a key.
So let's go to our.
Console.
I'm in Ashland region.
And I'll prepare a few things before I create the stack.
First, I'll go to the key pair and let's create some key.
I will name it as the profile hyphen key.
Then format and I will say create keep here.
So Bob, Public Key is downloaded and I'll give user the list of the keys.
Let's create a few more key.
I will see.
Ewart Key.
That's fine too.
Should be fine.
So we can get the list of these two keys.
Now let's write our template.
We'll name it as input parameters.
Dot y html.
Okay.
I'll copy everything from the previous template.
As it is.
And just about this, I'll put parameters.
So I'll go to the documentation.
And take an example from here.
This one.
List of instance type.
Let's put that.
And I'll keep it as it is.
I want to if you want to add more list like I.
Let's do one more.
Let's see.
RT to dot small.
Let's also give.
T two dot medium.
Okay, that's one parameter.
We'll get a dropdown list there.
Let's create one more parameter.
And we'll see a key name.
And that's the logical ID You can give anything.
I'll give some description.
And I want the list of all the available keys so I can set type.
School, the documentation parameters.
So now the clot formation is going to access the existing parameter.
We'll show all the list of keys available in that particular region.
Also, I would like to refer these things in my instance profile and my instance resource.
So instance type.
Now I'm going to refer the ref.
And.
Let's get the logical ID instance type parameter.
Also the key.
So.
Key name.
And referring it to.
That's the logical idea of given the same logical, very similar name.
But it's a this is a logical idea and this is a property, for the instance, two different things.
Okay, I will give one more parameter, which I'll put it in the tag.
It's a simple one.
Just name of service description string.
So a user will see this and user, if want, can make change also to this and I'll refer this in the
tag.
Name.
So instead of using this, join.
I would say ref.
To.
Name of service.
And everything else I'll keep as it is.
For mapping.
I am creating instance in Ireland region, so I have to give that region also over here.
So you were you West one.
Okay, let's launch instance and get an Ahmed for Amazon Linux.
EU West one.
Let's create entry for that.
You hyphen west hyphen one.
Hear my.
This seems good.
And let's go over once again parameters.
I have three parameters name of service, instance type, parameter and key name.
They are all three different parameters.
This is just going to give a description.
So if user wants, user can change that.
Also, while creating instance type parameter, again, it's stuff type string, but we have given allowed
value, so we'll get a dropdown list of our entries.
Key name.
This will also give a dropdown list, but this will check the existing parameter.
Camp.
So here parameters are predefined by us.
Here parameters are defined by us.
Then we are mapping.
Based on our region name.
It's going to pick up the mapping.
And in the instance we are referring to all the parameters that we have defined.
Instance type Key name.
And in the name of service.
And then we have the security group that you are referring here, which is seen from the previous video.
Okay, let's do this.
So let's go to cloud formation.
Create stack.
Upload my template.
Choose file.
Input parameter.
Okay, let's go next.
Right now we have the parameter.
Let's let's give a name first.
Input hyphen parameters for an example.
Okay, now you have the parameters dropdown list.
See that little micro too small we can select.
It's what we have defined in our template.
Key name.
This place is fetching for us.
Right.
So we have two key.
I'm going to say I'm going to select this key name of service.
If I want, I can make change.
Otherwise it will keep.
Empty.
There will not be anything.
So let's give some name input hyphen parameter.
For an example.
The spelling mistake.
So three different parameters go next.
Next.
And secrets Stack.
It's creating everything.
Let's check.
So we have the instance, and that's the first parameter that you're seeing over here.
To micro, that was also the parameter and the key.
Let's check the key.
B profile key.
So all these three parameters were taken successfully, all these three parameters of a different style.
Cloud formation stack should be completed by now.
Yes, it's completed.
Let's quickly reiterate what we did.
We started now using parameters, which is optional but can turn out to be very beneficial.
There are examples over here in the documentation which is easy to pick up.
So in our template we have taken three.
We have given three parameters, one which is string parameter that user can type, other parameter
which creates a dropdown list of our defined values.
Third parameter key name.
This is going to create again, dropdown list.
Which aid will fetch the properties parameters for us.
And then we refer it in our e c to instance by using a function and we give the logical idea of the
parameter.
So if you're done doing this, you can delete your stack.
And join me in the next video where we're going to see how to print outputs.