After creating our cloud formation stack, there is a section of outputs where you can see any output
that is given by the stack when it was creating or after it created.
Outputs can be used for two purposes one to print and second to export the values in other cloud formation
template.
When you're using nested stack, this can turn out to be very vital information.
So let's see some example.
I'll just go down.
There is the syntax output.
You give a logical ID description value that you want to print or export.
If you do export, you can export the value which can be referred by the next template in a nested cloud
formation stack.
And I scroll down a little bit.
Okay, here we have two outputs.
This is the logical ID description value.
Value is the one that really is the output.
First, your value is intrinsic function get at.
Get attribute function will get the attribute of a logical ID.
Here is an example given backup load balancer.
So there is a there is a logical ID in a template named as this inside that you have an attribute dot
DNS name or like fetching an IP address of an instance.
So you the instance logical ID, dot public IP or private IP.
So combining output with get attribute function can fetch you write values what you're looking for.
You can also give condition.
So that's one output.
And this is going to be fetching attribute for the value other output is.
Value is referencing a logical idea.
So you see value in two styles here.
One is getting the attribute and one is actually getting the reference of the logical ID.
Let's see this by an example.
I'm going to take everything from the previous template and just paste it here.
And I'm going to put the new section.
Outputs.
Colon.
It gives some logical ID and say print some info.
Okay, I'm interested in values.
I'm just going to say value.
So I would like to fetch the value of the instance that I'm creating.
And I want its public DNS name to be printed.
So I have to get the attribute of this logical resource.
So I'm going to copy that.
And I will see.
Exclamation get at.
This function you pass to values.
First is the logical ID.
And the second is the attribute.
So how do I know the attribute?
Well, there are a lot of attributes, right?
Or the properties?
Actually, they are the properties.
So in the template reference, you can find your.
Resource forced.
So we want public DNS name so for easy to so easy to.
And we using the AC two instance there.
Okay, So in this here itself, you have most of the.
Properties.
But if you scroll down, you'll get the list.
So I'm looking for public DNS names so I can find in the file public.
DNS, their public DNS name.
So that's how I can find the attribute.
And so like that, any other thing that you want you can get.
All right, let's save that.
And let's create the cloud formation stack.
Okay.
All right.
I'm in Ireland region.
I'm creating the stack.
Choose file.
Print output.
Okay, Next.
Output hyphen example.
I'll keep two to micro.
I'll select my key.
We profile key.
And I'll give some output example.
Let's go next.
And next.
And create stack.
Once the stat creation is complete, you can come in the output section and you can see the output.
Okay, so the stack created successfully.
Let's check in the output.
And you see there the key.
Print some info and the value is the instance public DNS name.
So you've seen one use case of the output, which is just printing.
Also, I want you to check the intrinsic function get attribute.
That we have used to fetch the attribute.
You can see some examples there.
Well, it's pretty simple.
Get attribute logical id dot the attribute name.
Craig that from that entire template.
Here we're using the get attribute so ref and get attributes.
There is a little difference.
Get attributes going to get the attribute.
When you say href, you are referring to a logical ID and get attribute.
We give the logical dot the attribute name, so we are looking for the value of that attribute.
Okay, so that's simple.
It is output logical ID value and you can give any value.
We are fetching the attribute value for logical ID, which is public DNS name.
So if you're down here.
Delete your stack.
Once it's deleted.
Join me in the next video.