Okay, so template anatomy we have already seen now resources, which is mandatory.
You have seen mappings.
We have seen parameters and we have seen outputs.
In this video, we're going to talk about metadata.
This is helpful, especially when you're using easy to instance and there is in it.
Scripts which are really helper script that can initialize your instance or you can see provision easy
to instance with some data like you want to install packages, push some file, start the service.
So there is a now.
See if an inmate is going to be held per script which will execute your.
Metadata that you have mentioned.
So let's see the syntax.
That's Jason.
That's YAML.
This is mostly supported for the Linux machine.
There is also support for Windows machine, but there are some dependencies.
As it says, all metadata types for Linux system.
Its support metadata is for Windows with conditions that are described.
So we're seeing Linux system.
So it will be convenient.
So when you declare your resource, of instance logical lady, the type you can give metadata.
Cloud formation in it.
So you have a lot of things over here.
You have config.
Packages.
So the list of packages that you want to install, groups that you want to create or destroy users sources.
Files that you want to push.
Commands that you want to execute, just raw command shell commands that you can mention, right.
Services, any service that you want to make sure it's up and running.
Right.
So let's see an example.
That is better commands, test commands.
So it will execute this command environment variable.
It is setting.
Current working directory will be home directory.
Again, few more commands.
Similar things.
He commands.
There are also a few more examples.
Ignore errors.
You can ignore the errors.
You can run some test also.
Files if you want to push some file.
So file that's JSON files, part of the file content and you start your content from here to here.
So it's going to create this file with this data and can also set the permission ownership and the group.
For example, for groups you can create groups like this can specify the group ID as well.
Packages.
You do install some package by using rpm e pl you can give.
The repository.
Ah the package link to download Yum.
You can use the package manager and you can say I want to DPD, php, WordPress or you also have Ruby
gems.
You can install Ruby gems.
Like chef.
This is for my windows.
Services.
You want to make sure a particular service is up and running, like service as you see in it, you give
a name of a service like Engine X enable to ensure running true, so it will start and enable the service.
And you can also point out the configuration file if you want, and also the source.
Like that.
Other services is some PHP service or send mail service.
And that's Windows example.
Sources can turn out to be useful when you want to use when you want to clone the source code from GitHub.
Are also these S3 bucket.
So it's going to download your data from the S3 bucket.
Users if you want to create user.
And this user with this group, this is the user ID home directory.
So it's giving really a lot of support.
You for for basic service setup, you don't need to use any automation tool like Ansible or anything
or even your bad scripts or Python scripts.
You can use metadata, you can use the init helper script and it can provision everything for you as
much as it can do and any ways it had.
It has all the support for command, so you can just run commands as well.
So let's take an example now.
And let's name it us in it.
Dot Jamil.
Okay.
We'll take everything from the previous template, which was print output pasted there.
Okay, so my instance does a logical lady just after the type I'm going to say.
Metadata.
Okay, I'll cop it from here.
I will say here config.
And then I can give all that package.
I could just.
Packages and groups, users, commands, files.
I can mention all those configs.
So this is just one config key.
If you want multiple configs, you can create config set.
Like I'm saying, this is one single config key.
Which has packages and I can create an insert that I can have groups, users.
Files that I want to push or create.
Commands that I want to run.
So let's say I want to run this configuration.
So this is one config set like that.
You can create multiple config set and you can decide the order also.
Let's check that from documentation.
So config, single config key and then you can give all your packages, groups, resource sources,
files, command services.
So that is for one single, but you can create multiple config set.
Also like in this example you have config sets and ascending.
You say this is first config, second config.
So config one.
So this is one config, this is second config.
You can give any name you want.
So based on the requirement, you can then say config sets and you can give the order in which order
you want to call this config.
So we'll just have one single config going to install some package, you're going to create some files
and run some commands.
Mignolet that.
So Amazon Linux, we can use yum yum.
And I want to install package PHP.
And I want to install hpdi.
And I want to w get.
Unzip and get with no special options.
After that.
I would also like to execute some commands.
So the same list, same line as the packages, I'm going to say commands.
And I want to see test.
Okay, so I have written a command which is going to download.
And its HTML template from 28. com and unzip it and then copy all the content from that to dub dub HTML.
I would also like to create some files.
So you say files.
So file.
I'm going to see this file path colon content sub, which is an intrinsic function which just says,
you know, this is the value of the content.
So an HTML file, some HTML content there, then also services CSV in it.
It should be indented.
Let's check if it's in the same line as the files.
Yes, it is, but files is not in the same line as the commands.
So we have to bring the right indentation for the services.
Okay, let's check everything once again.
Packages.
So config.
You have packages.
Commands.
Files given services and you can give other things like users groups.
Now this is the metadata that I created, but I also have to call this metadata.
So you need script is a helper script that can call this metadata and run it.
So when my instance comes up, I want to execute some commands so we can use user data.
So let's mention some user data.
This user data will mention the CFN in it helper script path and the config that it has to execute.
So we are going to see the property user.
Data.
So we want to pass the user data and base 64 format so we can use a function based 64 function, intrinsic
function.
And there's also one more way we've been using this method ref, but you can also call function like
this.
You can see FN double quotes.
Bass, 64.
So when we are calling it in the next line, when you're intending it, then this is how we call the
function or otherwise you can use a ref also.
And to that, I'm going to insert that.
I'm going to call one more function sub, which is going to present this string to the basics and convert
it into base 64.
So this is going to be the user data.
We're going to invoke the bash shell.
We're going to update a WCF and bootstrap.
So this is the helper script and this is the part of the C CFA, any helper script.
And we call this this, this binary file.
Hyphen v and we give the stack name, hyphen, hyphen stack.
Now you don't need to give the stack name.
You can use this method.
Like this is like reference.
One more way of doing a reference like we say ref and we give the logical id like that.
So this is going to return the logical id hyphen and resource and you give the logical ID web server
directly can give, and that's the logical ID for us.
For instance, web server.
Hyphen region and this is going to anyways get the region for you.
So this should execute your any data.
So once the instance comes up, this command gets executed and your init data will get executed.
After this, whether it completed successfully or not.
That also you can verify.
So you can again call the c f and signal binary.
Hyphen.
E It's going to return the exit code dollar question mark.
So if this completed successfully, the dollar question mark value will be zero in the script.
And if it fails, then it's going to be having non zero.
So it's going to send this exit code to our stack.
Okay.
Now, if if it gets a non zero, then we can see our cloud formation stack failing.
So this is going to execute the data and this is going to send the information in exit code.
So if you sense zero, it's a successful if it's if it sends non zero, it's a failure.
And you can your stack can then roll back.
This should be fine.
Security group and then print data attribute web server, public DNS name.
So we get an output public DNS name.
We can then click the link and from the browser we can see other whether our website is up or not.
So we should see a website from two paycom.
Jim So which are downloading and extracting it.
And we should also see this file.
Hello dot HTML.
So let's save this and let's try this.
I'm in Ireland region and I also have in my template mentioned.
The EU West one amity.
So I can use it in Ireland region.
It's going to launch that EMI.
And it will.
Let's go next.
Let's cue the stack name Dest in it metadata.
Key.
I'll select the profile key name of the service.
Testing in IT data.
I also say Jim.
So.
Risk taking all defaults, let's say create stag and we'll leave.
Wait for a moment.
Once the stack is up, we should get the public DNS name.
You can click on it and we can see the website live.
Okay, so it completed successfully.
Let me click on outputs.
So we see the public DNS name.
Let's click on that to show the website.
There we go.
Jim So fitness, so that's the template.
We download it from to plate dot com, right?
We mentioned that in our template.
Yes, we download it and then we have extracted it, unzipped it.
All right.
And then we copied all the content to var HTML.
Oops.
Yeah.
After that, we also create this file.
So we should also see this file and skip that part.
Slash yellow dot HTML.
So much HTML content, you can really give anything.
So just testing just the proof that the file got created that content.
Right.
So.
So that's metadata in it.
Script how to call.
Now we are defining the metadata and then we are calling it.
Right.
If you're thinking that, why not like, directly give it over here, Write all the commands over here
in the user data.
Well, we can do that.
But then if anything fails over there, we cannot pass the signal with C and signal and we see if any
in it we can call it and then see if and signal we can pass the exit code to the cloud formation stack.
If anything fails, then cloud formation stack will show you a failure and it can also roll back.
So that's the benefits of using an IT metadata and in its script.
Okay, So if you're done testing this, then you can delete the stack.
And that should be all in this video.
I will see you in the next one.