Let's dig in.
I am logged into my account.
I'm in North Virginia region.
And I also have a certificate which I'll be using.
For deep connection on load balancer.
I have mentioned the previous site video how to create this certificate and do its validation from your
domain provider.
I have a good idea.
Domain graphy dot n and I have seen some validation.
In this dense zones.
Okay, let's go back to loss console.
I'll go to easy to service.
First thing that we'll do is we'll create a security groups.
First, we'll create security group for our load balancer.
So let's go to security groups.
See create security group.
Let's give a name.
Let's give some description.
And let's add the rules.
And let's add inbound rules.
Inbound rules, not outbound rules.
You are not going to touch outbound rules.
It should be always like this.
All traffic should go anywhere.
This will be for all the security groups that we will be creating.
Outbound rules should be like this.
We will be editing always inbound rules.
So first rule we will add is.
HDP bought 80 allowed from any IPV four.
And then again, you can just go here for 80.
Any IPV six.
Now some Internet service providers are giving IPV six.
So you should also use this rule to allow anywhere from IPV six for it is for initial purpose.
But our main goal is to use HTTPS 443 port.
So we will be accessing our website securely.
HTTPS connection on Port 443.
Let's see any IPV four again.
Any IPV six.
Later, once we set up the secure connection, we can remove this port at both the rules.
But for now we'll just create it.
C Create a security group.
Next, we'll create security group for our Tomcat instance.
We profile hyphen app hyphen SG.
Let's add a rule.
So our Tomcat service will be running on Port 88.
So let's go to that port.
And we'll allow traffic only from our load balancer.
So here we'll select the security group of the load balancer.
We'll give some description about traffic from LP.
And let's see if this.
One more security group.
This security group will be for our backend services.
Robert McHugh, Mom Cash and my SQL.
So we limit we profile hyphen backend.
She.
And let's add rule.
So we'll be running a MySQL service over here.
So let's select.
My SQL 3306 port allowed only from our application Security group.
Let's give a description.
We have two other sources that will be running in the security group.
Mom, cash and rabbit MQ.
Metcash will be running on port one one, two, one, one, and grab it.
McHugh will be running on board five, six, seven two.
If you're not so sure about it.
Let's check the source code.
Our application properties or application configuration file will definitely have the port number of
our backend services.
Let's open our source code.
If you're going to use branch left in shift.
I saw.
See?
Mean.
Resources application dot properties file.
So my SQL on Port 3306.
Gash on port.
One one, 211 rabbit McCue on board.
Five, six, seven two.
So we'll add these two rules as well.
One.
One, two, one, one.
Allowed from our security group application Security group.
And put five, six, seven two again from application security group.
So Tomcat, which is an application security group, can connect.
To all banking services on these boats.
Let's also give some description.
And now let's see this.
Okay.
We need to make one more change in our security group, in our back end security group.
We have three services.
And these services will be also interacting with each other.
So we are going to give a rule over here all traffic.
From itself.
Its own security group ID.
That's the final rule.
Let's save it.
And in any case, if you make any mistake in adding the rule, we can come back and make the changes.
Now we will create a log key pair.
Which will use to log into our C two instances.
So go to key peers.
Create keeper.
Let's give a name V profile prod.
Key.
I'm going to use git bash for login, so I will use PEM format.
If you're going to use putty then use PKI format.
If you want to import your own key, you can do that.
But we'll see these kinds of security approach in other projects.