Now we will launch easy two instances with user data.
We'll have some batch script to provision our services.
So let's go to EC2 instances.
Instance section.
Let's foresee the user user data script that we'll be using for provisioning our EC two instances.
User data script is in our source code, so you can clone the source code.
If you already have it, you can just do get pull.
Okay.
Let's get into a repository and we are going to shift to a branch named S hyphen lift and shift shift.
Okay, let's clear the screen.
You have a user data directory over here and you will see some bunch of shell scripts.
These are the same shell scripts that we used in our previous project when we provision our instances
with Vagrant.
So first we'll provision our backend services, rabbit, MQ, Mem cache and MySQL.
Let's see these scripts through our sublime text editor.
So force will provision my SQL.
So it's the same script that we used in previous project.
We are installing dependencies and my web server.
But my SQL will be running on CentOS seven instance.
So we're installing my my DB hyphen server package.
We start n enable it, we clone the source code and then we initialize our database.
We do some security changes and we create database named accounts.
We create a user admin with password admin.
One, two, three.
You can change the password if you want, but then make sure you make changes to application properties
file.
And we of course initialize our database with schemas.
And then finally we restart my service and we take care of our firewall rule.
So we'll have firewalls, a two level one, the security group, the second and the operating system.
So let's provision a MySQL easy to instance with this user data script first.
Okay, so let's go to instances launch instance.
We will give a name.
We profile.
Hyphen db zero one will add one more tag.
We'll say add tag.
Project.
The profile.
Let's come down.
Now we need Center seven instance for this.
So we need to click on Browse more Amis and go to a marketplace.
Make sure you click on it.
Marketplace and Type CentOS seven.
Find your Amy Center seven.
That one.
Let's select that.
Let's click on continue here.
Okay, so am I selected instance type tw to micro should be fine for this one.
Let's select the key pair v profile prod key that we created earlier.
This will be used to log into our instance.
In network settings, select existing security group, and we will select the security group that we
already created.
The profile backend SG database goes in the back end security group.
Advance details.
Scroll down and we need to add the user data script here.
So let's get our user data script.
So I'm going to copy all this.
Make sure you select everything.
Do not miss the beginning.
And let's face it here.
And let's click on launch instance.
It is successfully launched.
Instance, let's click on the instance ID.
And that's our instance.
It is in pending state.
And even if it's in a running state, it is going to take some time.
To come stable because it will be executing the user data script, which will kick in in a few seconds.
So after a few minutes I will try to log into this instance.
We need to go to the security group.
We're going to do SSH to this AC instance.
And we need to allow.
Port 22.
Or we can just select search from here.
Or we can just say for 22 from my IP so I can do a search to this instance, which is in the security
group.
So I'll take its public IP.
I will open my kid bash.
I have the key downloaded in the downloads directory.
And we have the user center's center seven instance.
Get the IP address.
Log in.
And we are in that's login is the root user.
Let's clear the screen.
If you want to see user data from here, you can do cool.
And you can use this URL.
So it will show you the user data script.
Let's check if it has provisioned.
Over my SQL Service system.
CTL Status Manager DB.
The service is still not up and running.
It could be because it's already provisioning the services.
It's already executing our commands.
Let's check the process.
And if you see the process, which is installing my server now.
So it's going to take a minute.
Let's pause the video for some time.
Okay, So after waiting five, 10 minutes more.
Let's check.
Let's log in now.
Let's check the service, first of all.
System serial status.
Maria DB And the service is active.
Let's log into the DB, my SQL hyphen, u root and the password.
Okay.
Let's check the databases.
The database is created.
This accounts database we have.
Let's use it.
Sort.
Use it.
Use accounts.
Show tables.
All right, This is good.
Let's exit from here.
So we have successfully provisioned our MySQL easy to instance with user data.
Now it's time to provision our other backend services.
Next will provision mem cache.
Jim, Come on.
So we'll be using Center seven easy instance.
So let's launch an instance.
Name tag v Profile hyphen MK zero one.
Additional tag.
Same project we profile.
Let's go to Marketplace.
And find CentOS seven.
Center seven select.
Continue.
Instance type again to micro is fine using the login key.
We profile Iraqi.
Network settings Select existing Security group.
We profile backend security group member cash also goes in back and security group.
Advance details.
Scroll down.
User Data.
Let's take our user data script.
And be stood here.
And launch instance.
Click on the instance ID.
It's in pending state.
It's going to come up in some time.
Okay.
Now, instead of waiting for this instance to be provisioned completely, we will also provision Robert.
Q And then we'll verify both.
So let's check the user data for Rabbit MQ.
Which is again installing dependency.
Downloading rabbit MQ rpm, downloading its key, installing rabbit MQ rpm start and enable rabbit MQ
service.
Make some configuration change.
Add rabbit MQ user called test with passport test and set it administrator tag and then finally restart
rapid MQ service.
Okay, so let's go to console.
Launch instances.
See, we think tag we profile hyphen or q01 additional tag project.
We profile.
Let's find the center seven.
EMI.
Marketplace.
Center seven.
Select.
Continue.
Instance type once again t to micro key pair.
Same key V profile prod key.
Select existing security group and rabbit MQ also goes in the back end security group.
Advance details.
Scroll down.
And let's get our rabbit Q script.
And pasted there.
Launch instance.
Let's click on View All instances.
You need to sometime refresh this page.
Click on this refresh button.
Now, we'll wait for some time and I'm going to pause my screen and come back when the provisioning
is completed.
I am back from my coffee break and now I will validate these two instances.
So let's access Metcash first.
We are in.
Let's become the route user.
Let's validate the user data.
So cash service should be up and running.
Let's validate that cash to.
And it's running.
It's also check if it's running on right board.
This is good.
Let's exit from here.
Let's also check rabbit MQ.
We are in.
Let's check the user data script.
Let's see the status of rabbit MQ server.
And it's up and running.
So our back and stack is up and running.
Rabbit MQ mem cache and database.
The next thing is we will update private IP of these three instances in Route 53 private DNS zones.
Let's narrow down their IP addresses.
Let's copy DB zero one private IP.
Mukesh Cash.
Robert MQ.
Okay.
Now let's go to Route 53, service, Route 53.
And here we create a hosted zone.
This will be private.
So we can give any domain name.
Let's give a V profile dot in.
Let's give some description.
Let's select the region.
North Virginia.
Their US East one.
Select the default VPC.
And see create holstered zone.
So Hostess zone is created.
Let's create records now.
Create record.
Simple routing.
Next.
Define simple record.
So forced.
DB zero one.
Point.
An IP address.
And let's give the IP address.
Define.
One more.
Endpoint will be an IP address again.
Define simple record.
Robert McHugh.
So we defined the record, let's say create records now.
So it's a simple area code name to IP mapping.
Which will be used by our Tomcat.
AC For instance, in our application properties file, we will mention these names rather than mentioning
IP addresses.
So even if we replace the backend servers and we we give the same name.
Then we really don't need to make any change in our application server.
Okay, let's launch.
What?
Don't get easy to instance now.
So user data script we have.
This one which is for centaurus.
And we also have tomcat underscore ubuntu dot search, which is very very simple because in open repository
we can directly install tomcat eight by using apt installed tomcat eight.
And anyways, we are building the source code locally in our laptop and then we're going to push the
artifact to the Tomcat instance through S3 bucket.
So this is a much simpler approach and we will use 1 to 18 I for that.
Let's see.
Launch instance.
Dag we profile hyphen app.
Zero one.
Additional tag.
Project we profile and we will need ubuntu 18 for this one.
Ubuntu 18 I say.
So let's click on ubuntu here.
And we'll go for open to.
18.
Now, as per a user data script, we are using Tomcat eight.
If you go for open to 18, open to 20 or higher, then you need to install Tomcat nine so you can switch
it to Tomcat nine or better.
Just keep open to 18 and use the same user data script.
So once again, Tomcat 801 to 18.
Okay.
One moment.
I selected the wrong army.
I have to go with this one.
Open to server 18.
Not the deep learning open to server 18 SSD volume type.
Let's come down to to micro will keep it login key same.
Security group.
Now, this is not going to go in back end.
This will be in V Profile App Security Group.
And this allows port 88 from the load balancer.
So this will be connected to the load balancer.
Advance details.
Let's come down.
Let's get our script.
We stood there and say, Launch instance.
Click on View all instances.
And refresh this.
So this is in pending state.
It will come in running state and then it will provisional script.
So that is all in this video.
In the next video, we will see how to build the artifact on our laptop and deploy it to the Tomcat
server.
We have zero one.
So launch all these instances, wait for a few minutes and join me in the next lecture.