We will validate application server after some time.
By the time we'll build our artifact.
And we'll build it locally on our laptop.
And for this we need to install some tool.
We need JDC and MAVEN to be installed in our computer.
So if you have Windows machine you can use chocolaty to install JDK eight and Maven.
If you have macOS, you can use blue cask.
I will open my PowerShell.
Open as administrator.
So we need to install GDG and MAVEN.
If you follow the prerequisites video, you would have already installed it.
You can check MV and hyphen version.
You can check java hyphen version.
So if you see here in MAVEN version, if you see Java version higher than 1.8, then you have to uninstall
Maven and uninstall JDK and then you install it again.
Choko on install Maven.
You run that command and then you run JDK eight hyphen y.
If you see a Java version, which is not same as 1.8 here.
But if you already see this, this is good.
And if you have uninstalled it or if you have not installed it, just say again.
Kyoko install JDK eight iPhone VI.
First adjudicate you have to install.
And then Joko install.
Maven.
So if you have uninstalled it or if you don't see Maven and JDK, then you can use Choco Command.
For macOS user, you can use Blue Command.
Okay, so we have the dependency.
Time to build our artifact.
Let's go to our repository.
And let's go to CRC Main Resources.
And we should have application properties file here.
We will update this file.
So we have DB zero one the host name of database.
It is db 01. v profile dot in.
Now.
As per our route 50 3dna Zones Entries mc01 dot v profile dot n and Rabbit m q dot v profile dot n.
All the other things are common.
3306 Port four Database Username password 11211.4 mem cash 5672.4 Rabbit MQ test username and tested
database.
If you made any change to the user data script while provisioning, you have to make changes over here
as well.
So let's see.
Even quit.
Let's clear the screen.
So in a Route 53 state zone, let's validate it once again.
We profile dot in.
VB 01. v profile dot in MK 01.0. n r MQ 01. v profile dot points to write IP addresses validated once
again.
If we are good with these entries, we can build our source code to an artifact.
So let's go to the top level directory in a repository where we have bombed out XML file and here we'll
issue the command mv and install.
Which will generate our artifact in some time.
Now, again, this process is also going to take some time.
And I have fast forwarded the video and here we are.
Let's clear the screen.
The build was a success.
We have a target directory and we have our artifact v profile.
Hyphen v two dot var.
We'll store this artefact in an S3 bucket and on Tomcat server will download this artifact from the
same S3 bucket.
And we'll upload our artifact to S3 bucket from a command line.
So we need to install a CLI.
And again, you can open your PowerShell if you're in Windows.
If you're using MacBook Mac, PC Mac OS, then you can use your blue cast and install a clean.
Choko install a silly.
So by the time this is happening, we'll create an IM user.
Which will use for the authentication for CLA.
Let's go to Imam.
Users add user and let's give a user name and see if we profile one SW three hyphen admin.
Programmatic access.
Attach existing policy and we will give as three full access.
Be careful with this policy.
This is going to give you access to all the S3 bucket.
So do not lose access.
Key and secret key of this user.
Do not expose it anywhere.
Let's download the credentials file.
After this setup is done.
Anyways, I'm going to delete this access key and secret key so I don't mind showing it to you.
But you don't do not expose it to anybody else.
I'm talking about your own access key.
As I told you, I'm going to delete this user and this access key.
Secret key, of course.
So I don't mind showing it to you.
But you be careful with your own keys.
Let's check A.W. Seelye.
It's installed.
Let's configure it publicly.
So I already have some access key and secret key saved.
I'm going to overwrite them.
We are using region US East one.
Format, Jason.
And is configured.
I will put in a three bucket now a, ss3 and B, keep the name s v profile hyphen.
Artifact hyphen storage.
A bucket is created.
Let me go to my source code repository.
Target directory there.
And I will copy my artifact S3 copy, which is v profile hyphen v two dot var in the strip bucket that
I created.
With that same name.
And this is done.
A w.
S three ls.
And the artifact is copied to S3 bucket.
In order to download this artifact in our Tomcat.
Easy, for instance.
We will create a role.
So let's go to Imam.
Let's go to roles.
Let's create a role.
Should be used by easy to.
Bombshell three for Lexis.
Next.
Skid Row.
Name of profile.
Hyphen Artifact.
Hyphen Storage.
Hyphen roll.
Create role.
Let's go to Easy, for instance, AB zero one action.
Settings modify.
I am role and let's select our role.
V Profile Artifact Storage role.
Oh, there's a typo.
Anyways, it will work.
Let's see if this.
Now our application server app zero one has authentication to access S3 bucket by using that role.
And it's time to log into App zero one.
Username Ubuntu and the IP address.
Oh, of course.
We need to allow Port 22 in the security group.
22 from my IP so I can do such.
Okay, let's do it once again.
And we are in that's logging as the route user.
Let's check Tomcat service.
Tomcat eight.
It's running.
Let's go to var lib.
Tomcat eight.
Here we'll see.
Web apps directory.
We will delete this root directory, but before that we'll stop Tomcat eight service.
And we remove root directory which will have the default application.
And we will download our artifact from S3 bucket now.
For that we will need a c ly to be installed here as well.
So we are going to run apt install a w.
S cli.
Okay, UCLA is installed and I don't need to do a configure.
I'm going to just use the attached role.
So let's list our S3 bucket.
It's name V profile hyphen Artifact hyphen storage.
And it's the artifact.
Let's download it.
S3 copy.
Slash v profile v to dot var and we will download it in the temp directory for now.
And that was so quick.
Let's go to the team directory.
And we see our artifact here.
Let's copy our artifact to user lib.
Sorry.
It's var lib tomcat eight web apps with the name root dot var.
So that becomes then our default application.
Let's copy that.
And let's now start Tomcat eight service.
Okay, let's check.
Var lib tomcat eight web apps directory and it has extracted.
The rule directory.
Let's get into that.
And you'll have enough in D.C., have classes.
And there you have application properties file.
With the right changes.
If you would like to validate a network connectivity, you can install Telnet.
Then it is already installed.
And you can just do telnet.
Let's do it.
Four db 01. v profile dot in port 3306.
If you are able to connect, the network is validated.
Yeah.
So that's making a connection you see there connected.
So it's resolving into right IP address.
Like that.
You can test MSC zero one on Port 11211 Rabbit Q and Port 5672.
Use this while you're doing troubleshooting when your application is not able to connect to backend
services.
Check the host the IP support numbers that it is using to connect to back end service telnet.
To that validate whether we are able to connect back in services or not.