Your application server is also up and running back and services are up and running.
Now it's time to set up a load balancer.
So let's go to S.E. to.
And we'll go to load balancers.
We are going to create application load balancer.
So first we need to create a target group.
So let's go to target groups and create a target group.
For instance, we're going to add, etc. instance, you name the target group V profile app hyphen,
the G Port 8080 Tomcat running on Port 88 and see VPC.
The health check will be slash log in.
Advanced health check.
So for health check, also, we have to override the port 8080.
Healthy threshold.
Let's reduce it to two or three.
Available.
Instance select.
Our application server Tomcat.
And say include a spending below.
And they create target group.
Target group is created.
Let's go to load balancers.
Let's click on Create Load Balancer.
And we will be selecting application load balancer.
That's what we need for HTTP and HTTPS traffic.
Let's say create.
Load balancer name v profile fraud ill be internet facing because we want to expose it on the internet.
Zones.
We have to select all the zones here.
Now this will make your load balancer also highly available.
So minimum two availability zones you have to select for high availability.
So if you're not going to select all the zones, you have to make sure you select at least two.
And out of that two, one should be the same availability zone where you have your Tomcat, AC, for
instance.
Or else just select all of them.
Security group.
We will be selecting the load balancer security group that we created earlier.
And it can allow traffic on 84 for three from anywhere.
Listener.
So our intention is to have a DPS listener.
We'll say add listener.
We will select here as DPS.
And we'll keep it for four three and we'll select the target group.
But also let's keep 84 now for validation.
Later we can remove this.
So eight and four for three, both forwarding the traffic to the same target group.
Now when you select here HTTPS, you have to mention the certificate.
So we already created certificate in the prerequisites ACM certificate.
You have to select that certificate here.
If your certificate does not appear over here, make sure you are in the right region and your certificate
is validated.
If you have any further doubts on certificates, check the prerequisites.
Video where we created the certificate.
Okay.
I think this is all.
Let's click on Create Load Balancer.
View load balancer.
So it's in provisioning state.
It will come up in some time.
By the time we will take its end point.
We copy it from here.
Description.
This is better.
It's copy the endpoint of this load balancer and we'll go to our domain provider.
I have GoDaddy domain groovy dot n and I will add a C name record here.
Select C name Record host.
We will give V profile.
App and we'll see it points to this endpoint.
So you see.
So we profile app dot goofy dot in will be our URL with https of course.
So it's still in the provisioning state.
Okay.
In a few minutes, it became active.
And now let's validate http s slash slash V profile app dot.
Graphy dot in.
And that is pointing to the end point.
Of the load balancer and load balancer has routed the request to Tomcat.
This page is coming from Tomcat.
Let's log in admin, underscore VPI password admin.
Underscore VPI.
Successful login.
That means my SQL Server connection is there.
Let's check rabbit and queue whilst generating queue.
Go back.
Let's check Mom cash.
Click on all users.
Let's select a user.
The data is inserted in cash.
Nice.
Yeah.
Now, the data is from cash.
And that was a successful set up of our application workload on cloud.