We have one more pending thing, we talked about auto scaling group.
And we will set up auto scaling group for our application server Tomcat ec2 instance.
So let's go back to ec2 instance console.
First thing we need to do is we need to create the AMI of this instance, so let's say action, instance
state, oh sorry, image and create image.
Give it a name, the vprofile-app-image.
And you can give some description.
And I will say create image.
This is going to take some time.
The AMI is getting created by the time we can create the launch configuration for the auto scaling group.
So let's go to launch configuration.
Create launch configuration.
Say vprofile-app-LC we will select our AMI, even if your AMI is not ready, you can just selecte it
from here.
But I recommend you wait till the AMI is available, instannce typ, based on a requirement.
So we want to keep it under free tier, so we will just use t2.micro
IAM role
We want our instance to have an IAM role that we have created so our instance can download artifacts
from their.
Enable ec2 instance detailed monitoring within cloud watch, yes.
We don't need any advance details, same EBS volume should be fine, security group, of course,
we have high vprofile app security group.
Log-in key.
We have the key over here, I acknowledge and create launch configuration, so launch configuration is created,
let's create auto scaling group.
So create auto scaling group name of the auto scaling group, vprofile-app-ASG.
.
Let's select the launch.
We switch to launch configuration using launch configuration, so let's select our launch configuration.
And go next, same VPC, we will select all the subnets.
So, our instance, can  be launched in any of the zones, go next, enable load balancing.
Of course we have an application load balancer and will select the target groups, so our instance, will
be automatically updated in this target group.
And we will do health check on the load balancer.
We, as in the application auto scaling group is going to do health check on load balancer, for instance,
is unhealthy.
It will launch a replacement.
And this should be good, let's go next, capacity you can decide 2 and maximum 8.
Based on our requirement, We we don't have that much requirement, we'll just keep two to one.
Scaling policies, so if you just want to maintain the number of instances, this should be fine.
But if you want to automatically scale out and scale in and you can use tracking, scaling policy.
So I will keep this I will say CPU utilization, target value 50 percent.
So if my CPU urilization crosses more than 50 percent, then it will add instances.
If it goes less than that, it will delete instances and it can go maximum 2 I have given if you want,
we can increase this capacity.
Let's say maximum.
Desired one.
Minimum one and maximum 4.
If you don't want our instance to be get terminated automatically, so we should put this checkmark
on.
For instance, will not get terminate automatically.
So in case if you're troubleshooting, you want to download the logs, you want to see what's the problem
with the instance, you should enable this.
But I recommend you stream the logs of your ec2 distance to cloud watch logs or any other service and
don't have any static data or any dynamic data.
Sorry.
On your Ec2 instance, I am not going put that checkmark on.
Let's go next.
Add notification.
So if you want, we can send notification.
to our SNS topic.
If instance is getting launched, terminated, fail to launch or fail to terminate all those events, notification
will receive email address.
Any tags, so we will see name the vprofile app, that's our tag.
And we can also give any other tag, if you want, like project vprofile.
Owner can give our name or team's name, go next.
Verify everything and finally say create scaling group.
So autoscaling group will create instance automatically, we already have an instance under our load balancer
load balancer in the target group, app01, the one that we created first.
But from this, we have created this one.
From this, we created the AMI, we don't need it now, so if you want, we can even terminate this.
So I'm going to say instance state, terminate.
So it's saying we cannot terminate, and that is because the termination protection is enabled, we
have to disable that first.
Instance setting, change termination protection.
And I will say disable this.
So I can safely terminate this instance.
Make sure you selected the right instance.
And terminate.
So new instance that was created by the auto scaling group should be already in our target group automatically.
See, it's currently unhealthy.
So we wait for some time and it becomes healthy automatically.
It took time to bring up the application by Tomcat, so it was showing unhealthy for a few seconds and
now it's healthy.