Let's again do the validation.
https://vprofileapp.groophy.in
And that's working. If you have come this far, then really good job, so you now as a user.
Access your app through a URL that points to the load balancer endpoint with https connection,
you access your application load balancer endpoint the certificate is in ACM, Amazon certificate manager
application load balancer is in a security group that allows only 443 https traffic
Which then forwards the request to Tomcat ec2 instance on port 8080, which is in another Security Group.
For the backends servers that had access with name.
It's private IP mapping is given in the private dns zone, our backend servers are in one security
group, Memcache, Rabbitt MQ and MySQL.
And now, whenever we want, we can upload a new artifact to S3 bucket and download it to our target
instances.
Now, that's not such an efficient way of deploying artifact, the right way of deploying artifact.
We going to learn in CICD projects, which will be completely automated. If you wish to create auto
scaling group for memcache.
Robert MQ, database.
You can do that, it's very easy to do.
You can just select your instance action, instance setting.
Attached to auto scaling group.
And you can give a new auto scaling group name over here, but there are really better ways to do these
things in AWS. Instead of using auto scaling group and ec2o instances, we can use some PASS &
SAAS services, which we are going to see in the next project.
We are going to refactor our application stack so from ec2o instances from virtual machines will
start migrating to AWS managed services.
And that is all in this project.
Thank you for watching.
I will see you in the next project.
Keep practicing.