Welcome to the project.
Name of this project is continuous integration on us.
If you have gone through continuous integration project of Jenkins and tools, then you know there is
an extra overhead of managing Jenkins server, Nexus server and so on a cube server.
In this project we are going to use some of the very cool services where we can set up continuous integration
very easily, very quickly and we don't need to manage servers.
I know that's pretty cool.
So first let's understand continuous integration and how you can achieve it by using services.
So this is the scenario.
Let's say you have a product development and Agile SDLC is in motion.
So bunch of smart developers in an Agile team will regularly make code changes.
So there'll be multiple code changes every day.
And all this code needs to be tested because this is what actually is building your product.
So this code needs to be regularly built and tested.
So usually in an enterprise there will be a separate build and release team who will be doing this job
of building, testing and releasing the code.
Or if it's a small industry, then they'll be it will be developers responsibility to merge and integrate
this code.
So yes, there are regular code changes, also called commits or pull requests.
Developers will be dependent on build and release team, usually to test the code and move it to the
next level in the release cycle, but not so frequently.
The code will be tested if there are any bugs or error.
It will be known late due to these bugs and errors in the code.
Keep accumulating.
And let's say these got accumulated.
The problem goes more deeper.
Now developers need to rework to fix these bugs and errors, which is time consuming process and teams
would be already approaching the deadline.
So product owners really need to test the code as fast as it's building.
But that's not possible because the build and release team is doing a manual process.
And also there are approvals and ticketing system in place which delays the process more further.
So a solution to this problem is regular build and test for every comet.
So as soon as there is a code change, the code needs to be built and tested at the same time.
But if the process is manual, this will not be possible.
So you need to have an automated build and release process.
And whenever there is a build and test of the code, the developer should get notified automatically.
So if there is a build failure, if the code is not passing your quality gates or if there is any bug,
any kind of error, the developers will be stopped doing whatever they're doing and force they'll fix
the code.
So if you have such kind of automation framework in place which will regularly build and test the code
for every commit, then you're also removing dependency of developers from build and release team.
This process is itself called a continuous integration process, and there are various ways of setting
it.
We can use continuous integration server or we can even use cloud services.
Now if you're willing to set up continuous integration server.
To set up a continuous integration process, then we know there will be an extra overhead of managing
those servers.
There will be regular maintenance of the servers and you need extra time and effort to do it.
If you don't want extra overhead of managing continuous integration server and remove all the operational
overhead with it and we can use some very cool services to set up the continuous integration pipeline.
So we'll set up a continuous integration pipeline on us.
The first benefits, of course, we get is short.
MTR mean time to repair will be shorter.
It's going to be agile.
We're going to have no human intervention in this.
If there is any fault that can be isolated very quickly.
And if we are setting up on it by using cloud services, then there is no operational overhead.
So we get all the benefits of continuous integration without any operational overhead.
If we do it on cloud.
Okay, So let's see the sources that we are going to use to set up this continuous integration pipeline,
starting with Code Commit, which will be a version control system or version control system repository,
remote repository.
The next service will be using is code artifact.
Maven is going to download dependency from code artifact repository.
Good build to run our build process.
So we are going to run.
Maven Bill.
We're also going to run code analysis, sonar, cube analysis.
So to run code analysis and to run the build process, we'll use a code build service.
It could deploy service we'll use to deploy our artifact.
And in this project, we're going to deploy our artifact to S3 bucket.
So we are not going to set up Solar Cube server, but there is a Cerner Cerner Cloud, which is a cloud
based solar cube server, you can see.
So we'll just create an account on Sony Cloud and we're going to push all our result from code build
to Cerner Cloud.
Check style for code analysis will be using.
And finally, code pipeline, which is going to integrate all these jobs together.
Okay, so let's achieve our goals.
Before that, we'll see the architecture of continuous integration pipeline.
So first our developer are going to make code changes by using their ID like Intel J or whatever they're
using.
There'll be a git repository connected to it.
And for that local git repository, the remote repository will be.
Our code comet.
And whenever there is a code commit, the pipeline will get trigger.
First the code get pushed to a code commit, which will be like GitHub for us over here in the US.
So as soon as there is a new commit, the next job will trigger, which is a code build job.
But it is going to run sonar scanner and do code analysis.
It will also run check style from this job.
For any dependency, it is going to download it from a code artifact.
And then.
This job will also upload the reports to SoundCloud and get the result, which then will trigger another
code build job.
And this will be building artifact.
In this job, we're going to build our artifact, version it and store it.
On S3 bucket and also if there is any dependencies required for MAVEN build, it will be again downloaded
from code artifact service.
So it's a pretty simple architectural diagram.
Have a look once again.
Pause the video if you want.
I will run through the play once again.
Okay, let's see the flow of execution now.
First, we'll set up everything on blue, so you log into a plus account.
We're going to go to code, commit service, and we're going to take some action.
We'll create code commit repository.
We'll create an I am user with code commit policy, which will have privilege to access this code commit
repository.
And locally in our machine, we are going to generate such keys.
We are going to do search based login to this code repository.
We'll exchange the keys with the IAM user that we created.
So we set up the authentication to our code repository.
Then we'll take source code from GitHub, download in our local machine and then we're going to switch
to code commit repository.
So you'll also learn how to switch between two git repositories with all the commits, all the history.
Next, we'll go to Code Artefact service.
In this service, you're going to create a repository which is going to store MAVEN dependencies.
And for this also we need an another IAM user.
Which can access code artifact repository.
We're going to install a CLI on our local machine and we'll configure it with a plus item access key
and secret key.
We'll run a command that is going to give us a token.
For authentication.
Then we are going to update settings, XML file with the repository detail with the code artifact Repository
detail.
We'll update that XML file so it can fetch dependency from code artifact.
Okay, Now we'll start setting up the build job.
The first build job will be setting up is going to be for sonar analysis.
So we're going to create an account on sonar cloud.
We're going to generate a token over there.
And this information of sonar token and Project Key and all the sonar details we're going to store in
some parameter stores.
So we don't need to specify them in the build job directly.
Or build job is going to get those parameters from some parameter store.
Will create a build job.
I would build job.
When we create, we get a role and we're going to update this role with some parameters to access.
So our code job code build job can access some parameter stores.
Then we'll create a notification.
You can do it for SMS notification or Slack.
We're going to do in this project as soon as notification.
Then we'll set up a build project which is going to build the artefact and deploy to S3 bucket.
Begin to update our XML file with artifact versions with timestamps.
So automatically our artifact will be version with a timestamp with the current timestamp.
So what are properties required for this build project like code artifact information?
We're going to store all that properties in some parameter store again.
And this code build job.
What we're going to create will also need access to parameter store.
So we're going to update the roll code, build roll.
Once we have all this ready, then we're going to finally connect everything with Pipeline plus code.
Pipeline code, commit job test code, job, which will be our sonar code analysis job and the build
job, which will build the artifact and upload to S3 bucket.
And then finally, we'll test our pipeline.
We'll make a code change and we'll see how automatically this pipeline triggers.
And we get a well tested artifact in S3 bucket.