Okay, time for action now.
Let's get into a console.
Okay.
I'm in my management console and I'm going to first go to the service code Commit.
In the left side, you see all the services Anyways that we need are here.
Code commit code, artifact code, build code, deploy code pipeline so you can use an axis, all these
services from one single pane.
Okay.
If you go to some other region, like, for example, if you go to North California, not California
region does not have code, artifact service and few other.
So if you don't see code artifact, check your region.
Probably you're in a region that does not have code artifact service.
I'm in North Virginia.
For this project, you can use any region of your choice.
But just make sure there is a code artifact service over there.
Let's go to code commit repository and we'll say create repository here.
We'll give Repository a name, we will name it as V profile hyphen repo, or I'll say we profile hyphen
code hyphen repo.
You can give some description over there and few tags.
If you'd like to enable Amazon Code Guru for Java project, you can put a checkmark over there so it
will improve your code quality.
It will give you it will do code analysis and give you the result, which is a very convenient service.
So directly developers instead of building and then doing code analysis, they can test it automatically
with code guru service as well.
Okay, I'm going to create this repository.
And you can access this repository by using HTTPS connection and SSH connection.
As DPS comes with username and password and there is always a risk of exposing your password.
So search is a preferred method and will use this method.
So there are steps how you can configure it.
We're going to follow this.
But in order to do that, we also need an I am user.
So I will go to IAM service.
So an IAM user that you're going to create will have access to a service.
So let's go to user add user.
And let's give a username.
Mm v profile hyphen Code hyphen admin.
So for the time being, we'll just see Programatic access.
But we are not going to use access keys anyways.
We're going to use SSH credentials.
Attach policy.
So if you want, you can directly give code, commit full access, but that will give access to all
the code repository.
So we want specific, we only need for the repository that we created.
So we'll create policy.
Will choose the service.
Code commit.
You can fine tune all kinds of actions that this policy can take.
List.
Reid I'll just give all I can just select a word here also, because I'm going to be very specific.
I'm talking about only my code repository that I created resources.
We'll talk about the specific resource.
Add an.
Region.
So our repository is in US East one.
And the repository name.
So we'll get a repository name.
We profile hyphen code hyphen repo.
So I'm being very specific.
I'm saying this repository in this region.
If you want to put some conditions, you can do that.
But we are going to skip this one and we'll say review policy.
We'll give this policy a name.
So I'm going to say we profile code admin repository, full access.
That's quite a long name.
We can even give a better description.
And they create policy.
And it would scan for this.
We profile.
I have a code admin repository, full access, so I'm going to select my policy.
And I can just check it once again if I want.
You can see all the actions.
I'm going to go back to this place where we are creating user.
From here.
We click on Create Policy.
We already have a policy now.
So refresh this once again and paste your policy name.
So you can see the policy selected.
Go next.
You can use some tag if you want.
And to create user.
Okay, so a user get created with the policy.
And I'm going to close this again.
Go to your user.
Security credentials.
So we really don't need access can secret key.
So you can either make it inactive or better just delete these keys.
We don't need it.
We need six keys for a code commit.
So we have to upload ssh public key.
So a gendered squeeze from our local machine.
So let's open gate bash to generate keys.
We are going to issue the command key gen.
And we'll keep it at that location, but with a different name.
Well, let me test for pro hyphen code.
Commit.
Underscore underscore rc.
I will keep created with this name.
Once the keys are created, let's go to our directory and you can see they're the private key.
They're the public key.
So let's catch the public key.
Let's copy it.
And let's store it.
Let's see, upload as a public key.
Be stood there, make sure there are no extra space or anything just to upload.
And you will get an such key ID over here.
Now we'll create a config file, a search config file.
I see in place.
Let's create a config file which as such will use.
So when we use the code commit service at that time, it's going to use the in the config file that
will be mentioned.
If it's code commit is the host name, then use this access key, this username and this key to login.
So there you have.
So if the host is.
Good code comment.
Then the username changed that to the user.
To copy this user such key ID.
Mention it there and the file name that we created.
So let's verify the file name once again.
And that's the file name.
So for you, I will create.
You will create this config file in the repository.
You can check in a branch sai hyphen, a w s and you can find this config file which you can use.
See if this.
We also have to make sure that our config file permission should be 600.
In Linux, this will be mandatory.
Okay, Now let's make a test with our credentials.
Run this command search space.
This URL hit enter.
And it says you have successfully authenticated our search.
So our authentication is really working for troubleshooting purpose.
If there's something not working, you can use an hyphen v option.
And you can see much in detail what is being used, what user, all that you can see for troubleshooting
purposes.
Okay, now I can really clone my repository.
Also, let's test it.
I'll go to the temp directory.
So repository clone URL and we'll use zoo URL.
There's just a test.
We're going to do it a little different.
But just run a test like this.
Get clone.
So this will also validate whether your user has privilege on this repository or not.
Yes.
If you're able to successfully clone this, then that means a user that you used in user that also has
privilege to access this repository.
Once you have cloned, then you can put the data and commit it back.
But we're going to do a little different.
We already have a code repository from GitHub that we clone.
We're going to transition that code repository from GitHub to code commit.
So I will go to my f drive.
If you don't have the source code, you can clone it.
If your done previous project, you should already have cloned it.
Okay.
Like I already have it, so I'm going to switch.
To my repository.
And this is a git repository.
Yes.
And but the remote repository over here is.
GitHub.
So what are data that we push?
It gets sync to GitHub remote repository.
Instead of this, we will be having our code commit repository.
So let's do the transition.
So first just run the command, get branch hyphen, L, list all your branches and check out to the
branch that you want to use that you want to push to code commit.
First I'm going to check out the master branch.
Okay, then I'm going to run this command.
Which list all the branches.
It does not get the branch that has head and the master name.
And we're going to use the cut command and field three, which will just give us.
The branch name, right.
So we can very easily.
Get the branch name.
I'm going to send all this output to a file temp if you wish to do it like this automatically.
Otherwise you can just run git, check out command as many branches you have that you can run or you
can do it like this quickly, automatically.
I just named those branches.
I guess I have all the branches in ten branches file and I'm now going to run it on a for loop.
For.
I in?
Tactics kit.
Do a CO dollar I and you can just first print it whether it's really printing the right branch name.
Yes.
Now, instead of doing an echo and printing it, we are going to do get.
Check out Dollar I.
Really a quick way to check out all the branches.
If you have many branches, then it will be stupid to run.
Get check out that many times.
Just do some automation and get over with it.
Okay.
We did get check out to all the branches.
Let's run it.
Branch hyphen.
See that these branches are all check out.
I checked out.
Next, if you have some tags in your repository, you can say get fetch, hyphen, hyphen tags.
Once you are good with this, then we are going to remove the remote repository which is currently GitHub
origin.
Get remote item origin.
And we will add our code commit repository, git remote, add origin and the URL.
So let's get that search review URL.
Closeness is such.
And just hit enter.
Now you can check in your config, file it config file Leicester Remote repositories.
Now code comment.
That's nice.
Now let's push all our changes.
Get push origin, hyphen, hyphen all.
All these branches are now on code repository.
If you have any tag, you can push all your tags as well.
Git push hyphen hyphen tags.
You'll absolutely have some tags.
Once that is done, let's check.
Let's go to repository.
Must check a repository and.
Come on.
Yeah.
Okay, great.
Branch is the master branch.
Yeah, it's the master branch.
Yes.
And we should have our CI hyphen plus branch.
There.
Okay, So in this branch, you have some files and files.
You'll see more files over here.
One is a search config file and a few other files over here.
Okay.
So you can use this for the search config.
Other files we have will come to it in a moment.
Now let's switch your attention to code artifact.