Getting started.
So now we'll create a repository in code artefact, which will be used by our build job maven, build
job or MAVEN, build your download dependencies from here.
So we'll create repository.
Okay, let's give the name as v profile hyphen maven hyphen repo and give some description.
So public upstream repository.
I want to have Maven Central store.
So from here it's going to download the dependency and keep it.
And we profile Maven repo repository.
Let's go next.
Yes.
You want to create it for this account.
You have to select a domain and it will give a domain name.
So we'll give a domain name as I'm going to give it as visual path.
And this should be good.
Let's go.
Next.
So you see the external connection.
It is telling.
Domain.
It is going to use this visual path.
It will have a Maven central store repository.
We just connected to this group repository.
So we really created our repository.
Oh, not yet.
Let's click on Create Repository.
Okay, let's go to click on Repository and you should see two repositories now.
This is what is going to store the dependencies.
So you can click on it and you can see how you can connect to it.
There is a view connection, instruction.
Select package manager MVPs.
And so if you're going to use package manager MVPs and if you're going to run like MVPs and install
right, we will need dependencies.
So what you need to do, you need to run this command which is going to give you a token.
We have to use an IAM user and we feed the information in settings dot XML file.
Mr. Information.
So we'll do all this.
We already have settings dot xml file with the details.
We're going to just make the changes over there.
But before that, we need to export this variable, which actually is going to run a command, a base
code artifact, get authorization token.
And this command has to be run with a user privilege IM user.
So we're going to now create an I am user for this.
So let's go back to IM console user.
Say add user and we'll limit as we profile hyphen code artifact.
Hyphen admin.
Programmatic access will need for this one.
Policy.
So I'll just say code artefact.
So for this one, you can also create your own policy.
But to keep it simple for this one, I'm going to use code artifact admin access policy.
Or you can create your own policy and you can only target your own repository.
So Aaron should be your own code artifact repository.
But for now, I'll just keep it.
It managed policy.
Let's go next.
Look, I'll download the credentials.
Now you need to have a CLI in your system because we going to run that export command.
And we're going to run this command on our local machine.
So we need a blue collar for this.
So from previous project, if you have not installed a blue seal, then I recommend you install them.
So you can do it through PowerShell.
PowerShell width.
We have to open with admin run as administrator.
And you can use Choko install command.
If you have not installed it, install it now.
I already have it installed so I'm not going to run it again.
So you can run a configure.
And set up the credentials that you have just downloaded.
So from my credentials file, I'm going to overwrite the existing credentials.
Well, anyways, I'm going to delete this user, so I don't mind showing it to you now, but it's quite
very dangerous if you expose this credentials.
So make sure you give you a right region.
US East one is right for me, so I'll keep it as it is output for my JSON.
Okay, once you have this setup.
Will copy this command and run it.
Which should give us a token and return.
Hey, cool Dollar.
Let me see.
Does it have value or not?
And there's a token.
So we're going to store this token.
Some parameter store from where our code job is going to get it.
But now it's time.
Before we do that.
Now it's time to change our settings.
Dot XML file.
So let's go to our repository.
And switch to.
Sci hyphenate s.
So you'll see a settings dot XML file over here.
So we have to make some changes over here.
So we'll keep username as it goes over there.
And there is a variable which we are going to define from some parameters to, as I told you to login
and.
You are over here repository URL.
So we are going to change that.
Copy that.
And let's face it over there.
For Miller.
So the name domain name here changed the domain name.
To the domain name that you have used.
I have used domain name as visual path.
You can really get the details from here also if you want to.
And change this URL as well and make sure to give that a forward slash after that URL.
Okay.
This should be good over here.
Let's save and quit this.
We will also update our XML file with the URL.
You can keep the idea name same.
It really does not matter here.
Let's just save this.
And we are going to make the chief commit the changes.
Get at dot, get comet hyphen, m, c updated poem and settings with code artifact details.
Okay.
And then we'll push it.
This is going to go all the way to our repository.
Oh.
Get push.
Origin si hyphen.
E.
W.
S.
This should have been updated in our code repository.
I would also like to show one more setting over here to you.
So in that XML file, we have also given one more setting.
In this particular branch, we have the setting.
We are setting up a variable timestamp so it will automatically get the timestamp in this format and
this will be used to version our artifact.
Okay.
So these two lines there.
Which will be useful in the build project.