Okay, So now we're going to set up a code analysis job, which is going to do some honor code analysis
in code build.
And for that, we need a sonar cloud account.
So you go to SoundCloud dot IO from your browser and you can log in with your gate credentials if you
want GitHub credential or Bitbucket with any of these four, you can create an account.
I already have an account with GitHub.
So once you log in with your GitHub or any credentials, once you sign up with this, you will come
over here.
So it will look almost similar to so on the cube server that we have used in continuous integration.
Jenkins project.
But this is cloud based.
So first thing we'll do over here is we're going to generate a token.
So your user go to my account.
Security.
And give it token name v Profile hyphen Sonar hyphen Cloud.
C generate.
So you'll get a token.
Save it somewhere safe.
For the time being, I'm going to keep it in my sticky notes.
Okay.
Now from this plus symbol see analyze new project.
So when you sign up, you should already have an organization name that you have created over here and
you can see all the repository from your organization.
But we are just testing it.
We're not going to scan all these repositories.
I'll say create project manually.
Okay, so choose the organization.
And let's give a project key like we give sonar key sonar project key.
Similar to that, we'll give it over here, we'll name it as V profile hyphen repo.
That's all I'll keep the name.
I can only go with public because I have a free account.
If you have a paid account, you can go with private also set up.
Okay.
By now, we should have some details.
Let me put them into sticky note.
That's the token.
Project name we have is v profile hyphen repo.
The sooner cloud URL is https Colon slash slash sooner cloud dot io.
The organization I'm using is dev ops at ID Club.
That's the name of my organization that I've used in the Cerner Cloud.
There you can see and we profile repo.
So we need this for details and we're going to store this information into a parameter store.
So let's go back to our database console.