They can done with this.
And we'll search for the service.
Some systems manager service.
A very easy way to set up or store variables over here.
This secret manager, which is quite expensive, so as you can try that also, but I'm going to go with
systems manager parameter store.
Here will store these variables.
Okay, so let's create parameter.
Forced will create this organization.
Name and value string.
Okay, string text and we'll just you the name of the organization.
Just that.
And let's create parameter.
Next parameter will give the host.
That will be our sonar cloud.
You are all.
Okay, So let's create that also.
Script.
Next parameter name of the project.
Which we have given us a v profile hyphen repo.
Create.
One more parameter.
This will be our sonar token, the token that we have generated.
And this value.
I don't want to be taxed.
Oh, sorry.
Not string value.
Just secure string.
So it will encrypt the value that I put over here because I don't want to show this value to everyone.
Maybe for that reason I will just encrypt it.
Make sure there is not any extra space or anything and just say create parameter.
So we have four parameters.
Will also create one more parameter.
And this parameter is for our code artifact token.
So we have executed Cly cli command, which has given us this variable.
We exported this variable and we're going to copy this.
And we named the parameter as code artifact hyphen token.
Again, this is a token, so I'm going to say secure string and paste the value there.
And to create parameter.
All right.
So currently I have these parameters.
Four for Sony Cloud integration and one is for code artifact.