Okay, now is the time to create the build project.
So.
Let's go to build project.
You can go from here.
You can just say build and you can say build project or you can just search for the service code.
Build from there.
Code build.
Okay.
Your first job, first billed job will be to do code analysis on our code analysis.
So let's create a project.
Create, build project.
It's like we're creating Jenkins job similar to that.
So we'll name this job as we profile hyphen build.
Source code comet, our repository.
You can see the repository over here.
Branch.
We are going to use a CI hyphenated plus branch.
And scroll down operating system.
We are going to run a maven command so open to should be fine.
Runtime Environment Default Standard Image 3.0.
Okay, let's scroll down.
So this is going to create a service role.
And just to make it unique, I'll put some numbers over here, like 12.
And we'll later update this roll so it can access the parameter store that we have saved.
Okay, But first, let's create it.
Okay, so we have to use a build spec file.
So you can use a build spec file from version control, but we're going to say insert build, come on
and switch to editor.
And this is where we're going to copy our build spec file content.
So build spec file is in our source code.
In sci hyphenate plus branch.
You have a files directory in that you have sonar build spec file.
You can just get it and copy its content.
Now let's select all bastard.
We'll go through this build spec file in a moment.
So we'll just read it from here itself.
.0.2 environment variable from parameter store that we have saved.
So we are going to set up here five variables and its value.
We are going to give from the parameter store that we have set phases in install phase.
We are installing JDBC and we have a command.
We are going to copy our settings dot XML file to slash root, dot M to settings dot xml.
So setting dot XML anyways has to be in this place.
So we're using a copy command to copy that file settings dot XML is already in our source code which
will be moved to this place, which will have the information about our code artifact repository.
Then we have pre build phase.
We're running commands, we're running APT update, we're installing check style and GQ with W Command,
We're downloading Maven here.
We extract Maven.
We create a link for MAVEN.
Then we download sonar scanner.
We unzip the sonar scanner.
We export the pot for for sonar.
And then the build commands.
Of course, in the build phase commands, we have MAVEN test, we're going to run check style, MAVEN
check style and MAVEN sonar with all the parameters that we are passing.
So in our login data, log in.
That one.
And so all the parameters that we are saving over here, all the variables that we are saving over here,
we using it.
Then we wait for 5 seconds and there is a command which is going to store the result and result dot
JSON file.
We get this file.
And with an e condition, we check the status, the quality gate passes.
This job will be returning an exit code zero all or else it will return non zero.
So basically this is going to fail the job if your quality gates are not passing.
Okay, so we are good with this, so we need to make few changes though the parameters value from some
parameter store.
So host value we can just give directly host.
It's already there for login.
That's really the owner token.
So let's give us it's value as sonar token or whatever named of variable that you have saved it with
the sonar token with organization name variable, we have given us organization itself.
So we can keep it as it is project.
We have given variables project.
Code artefact or token.
We have saved it as code artifact hyphen token that variable.
So as you have used the variable name in the parameter store, so you have to give it with the same
name.
So it's going to access the parameter store and store all the variable these values.
And let's check again.
I think should be good.
We have not yet set any quality gates.
We'll set it later.
Okay, let's crawl down.
And I'm not going to store any artifact from here.
Cloud watch logs.
I will put a checkmark on there.
I'll give a group name.
We profile hyphen and Virginia hyphen sooner.
Or in Virginia.
Build, I will say.
Build.
Logs.
Stream name.
I'll say sooner.
Build job.
So we can see the output streaming really from here.
That should be all in this job, let's say.
Create, build, project.
Okay, before we run and test it, we have to update.
The role that we have used over here, and we have to give the privilege so it can access some parameters
to our.
Okay, so you can find the name from Edit Environment section.
You can find the road name there.
That's the road name.
Let's copy that and say cancel here.
Yes, of course.
Discard.
We'll go to I am service.
We'll go to role section.
We'll find that role.
There is that role.
Let's edit that role.
We have to give some policy.
We're going to say attach policy.
So we'll create our own policy.
I choose the service.
And some.
Actually, it should be with the name system manager.
So to manage the service action.
Okay, so in list we need describe parameters in a read.
We will need this describe document parameters.
Indeed.
Again, get parameters, get parameter history and get parameter get parameters.
Both get parameters by depth.
If you have created parameter store one inside another.
So you have to give this.
And that should be it.
No.
Right.
No tagging.
You can give Aaron if you want, but let's keep it that much for now and let's say review policy.
For resources.
You can give a specific urn, but I'm going to say any in this account and review policy.
Prosecute this policy and name v profile hyphen.
Sooner.
Parameters.
Axis.
That's quite a long name.
I'll put Same in the description.
Create policy.
Okay, The policy is created.
I have to go back to rules, actually.
Get the name.
It's like the role attach policies.
Honor some.
I have given the profile soner parameter access the checkmark attach policy.
Okay, so we updated that.
Now, this role will have the privilege to access some parameters to.
Which this villager will need.
Now, let's make a test.
Let's click on Start build.
And this is going to do the code scanning branch I'll keep same.
Start build.
This is going to take some time.
Let's go to phase details.
Switch to build log.
If you are done seeing the phase because build log will really hang your browser sometimes.
As of now, things are going fine.
Okay, install phase is going on.
That successful pre build phase is going on.
Rebuild, completed build started a view from the build log you see from the code artefact it is downloading
the dependencies.
Oh, and this is there.
Yeah.
From code artefact.
Okay.
I missed it again.
So it's very difficult to scroll up and scroll in over here.
Even I tried all the browsers Edge, Chrome, Firefox.
This is always very slow.
Yeah.
You see there?
Then you miss it again.
Okay.
We got a few other logs.
So if we go to our code artefact, let's go to another tab code artifact repository.
Maitland Central.
And you should see here the dependency maven dependency getting stored.
So it's storing the dependency over here.
From here it is providing to your build job, to the build job.
And you have like so many dependencies, right?
And it will keep updating it.
Okay, this is anyways hanging.
I'll go to court.
Build your from here build project.
It's still in progress.
So this is going to take some time, at least initially.
First time.
It takes a very long time.
Fees details.
So I'm going to pause the screen and come back once this is finished.
I'll agree that completed successfully.
That was pretty awesome.
Let's see the result.
So this is a sonar code analysis job, so it should have published result in sonar cloud.
So go to sonar cloud, go to your projects and you can see your project over there.
It has 92 bugs for vulnerabilities and blah, blah, blah.
If we want, we can set quality gates on this.
So I can see quality gates.
I can go to quality gates and I can create my own quality gate.
I will say we profile quality gates.
That name.
Save it.
And let's add a condition.
And I'm going to see an oral code and let's set it for bugs.
I will see value anything that is greater than 50.
So let's first fail.
Try to feel this job.
Okay, we'll give like 50.
We know that currently we have 92 bucks.
Condition.
So we have one rule in this quality.
GATES Let's go to our project.
And for our project, we're going to set up this quality gates.
Quality get in the administration instead of default, we're going to use our own quality gates.
Okay, this is nice.
So this quality gate is going to fail your job.
If your box are greater than 50 and let's test it.
It's a code build.
To test it.
We need to run this job again.
And you will see at the finalizing state or the completed state, it's going to fail the job.
So let's say.
Go to the build and let's start build.
Let's run it once again.
I will take all those defaults and we'll just start build.
Fees details.
Okay, So I'm going to pause my screen and come back once this is done.
Okay, so this is completed with a failure, of course.
So if you see in the build phase, it has error executing while this command is running.
So that this clearly shows the quality gate has failed.
Let's tweak our quality gates back.
So you can change the rule or I'll just go back to the default sona rule.
And we can test and test run the job and test it once again.
But we'll do it later with the pipeline.
I have given the name of this job as the profile build, I should have given V profile code analysis.
But that's just the naming convention for a description in that we can't change the name now, but we
can change the description.
So now our analysis.
So on our code analysis, we'll give that in the description update configuration.