Okay.
Now time to create our next job, which is going to build the artifact.
So let's go to build a project.
Mm.
We profile hyphen, build hyphen artifact.
So score our repository branch.
C.
Hyphen a.
W.
S.
It's going to be almost similar.
Build spec file will be different.
Amazon Linux open to will use.
Standard image, standard 3.0.
This is going to create a service role.
And this also we have to update so it can access the parameter store.
This job needs the parameter of a code artefact token.
At one token access, it needs its code artifact token.
So for that, we need to update this role later.
Okay, build commands, insert, build command, switch to Ed and let's see our source code.
So I build spec file in the source code.
Let's add files and here you have build, underscore, build spec file.
So you copy all this content.
Select all based.
Okay.
Parameter store variable code Artifact auth token will give it value as code artifact hyphen token.
The variable that we created in parameter store.
So that's only one thing we need to change over here.
Install.
We need JDBC settings data XML file gets copied, Prebuilt command we are installing.
Let's see it from here.
This is better view.
A little bigger view.
Right.
So installing JDK there we are copying settings dot xml file from our source code to dot m two directory
into directory.
Then apt update and we install JQ, we install apache maven extract it, create a link for it, and
then we run the command MV and clean install hyphens.
Skip test.
So I don't want to run unit test and code analysis over here.
So I'm just going to say skip test and artifacts file and the file, you have to give the list of the
files.
So any file that ends with not valid directory in the target directory, any file that ends with DOT,
where will be our artifact and our artifact will have a timestamp as well.
We have updated or a prompt XML file.
So artifact will even have a timestamp.
And that we'll finally upload it to the SD bucket.
So.
Everything copied over here.
So here we are not saying anything.
Log group name.
So I'll select the same log group that I selected for the previous project.
Logs.
So they have the same group for the screen name.
I will just say billed job.
To create build project.
Okay.
Last one thing in this job.
Bailout effect job.
Edit.
Environment will copy the role name.
And we'll go to Imam.
Rules.
The search for a role.
Nope.
Not found.
Oh, I think I need to refresh this.
Yeah.
There it is.
Attach policy.
We already have a policy created.
We'll use that.
That was for solar.
We created the same policy we need.
This policy gives permission to access the same parameter store.
Let's attach this policy.
And we should be good.
Cancel this.
Okay, time to test this job as well.
Let's say start, build.
Single build.
Same branch.
They start build.
But it has started to phase details and this will also take some time.
I'll pause my screen by the time and we'll come back once this is done.
Okay, so this job completed successfully.
Can completed.