Now we have to do one more thing.
We have to set up notification as well.
Before we set up our pipeline, I would also like to set up notification with that and we'll use SNS.
So we will go to SNS service.
Okay, So first we'll go to topics and we'll create topic.
And let's give topic a name.
We'll say V, profile hyphen, pipeline and hyphen notification.
And they just create topic first.
Once this is created, we'll create a subscription for this topic.
And we will use email.
You can use other things as Q as Lambda IDPs.
I'll use email here and I'll give the email address that I'm going to use to receive my notifications.
Could be a group email for developers or a monitoring team.
So I'll say create subscription.
And it is pending confirmation.
So I have to go to my inbox, look for an email from this notification, and I have to say confirm subscription.
Okay, So in my inbox, I got this mail.
I say confirm subscription.
That's all.
Let's refresh this.
It's confirmed.
Now.
I can use this.
I will use this on subscription or sorry.
The topic the topic name to send the notification for my build progress.
Let's come back to the code build service and finally, we're going to connect everything together with
the pipeline.
And yes, we have to upload the artifact to S3 bucket that also will do after after we create our pipeline.
So I'm going to go to Pipeline and say create pipeline.
Let's give a name.
We profile hyphen sci hyphen pipeline.
A continuous integration pipeline.
Let it create a role.
And just go next.
Source provider code commit.
Our repository.
And the branch C hyphenate us.
And this we set.
So whenever there is a new comet cloud watch, events will detect that and trigger the pipeline.
Or you can use a core pipeline also, this will check periodically, same like we did in Jenkins.
But this is the one that is recommended cloud watch events.
Let's go next build provider.
The code bill is our bill provider.
We'll give the project name.
So first I will add this project.
We profile build project only this project, and then we'll update with other projects.
Go next.
Deployer.
I'm going to use a SW three.
And this will set later.
We'll just skip the stage.
Skip?
And the great pipeline.
Okay.
The pipeline already has started.
I will say stop execution.
Stop and wait.
Okay.
That started this one as well.
It's trying to stop the build process.
You can continue it.
Also.
It's not a problem, but I'm going to add a few more jobs over here.
Added the pipeline.
First will integrate our test job, the code analysis.
I'll just give the name as test.
Add actions group.
Action name.
So honor hyphen Code.
Hyphen Analysis.
Action Provider.
Code Build.
Project.
Name e profile build single build and see done.
Now input artifact.
I have to specify the input artifact.
The source code.
The input artifact.
Go ten.
And see done.
Okay, so pulls the code tested and runs the build job to generate the artifact.
Next stage we're going to add is we're going to deploy the artifact to S3 bucket.
So we'll give add stage name as deploy.
Edit Add action group.
Action name will say deploy to SE three action provider.
Amazon SE three.
Input artifact that gets generated from the build artifact.
So build job is going to generate the artifacts.
So that's going to be the input artifact on this job.
And we have to set a bucket also.
So let's create an S3 bucket.
Create bucket.
So I'll give name as V profile.
And give some number.
V Profile 12.
Build hyphen Artifact.
Make sure you create it in the same region.
Create.
My search for the bucket that we just created.
And in that we'll also create a folder, we'll name it as we profile, or we'll just name it as Pipeline.
If an artifact.
Create a folder.
Copy its name first.
Create folder.
No.
Sorry.
Save.
Okay, let's go to Code Pipeline.
You have to cancel the job and again, create the action C add action group.
Action name deployed to.
Three.
Action provider.
Amazon is three.
Build artifact for input artifacts.
So our build job generates the artifact that's going to be input for this, and the output will be sent
to the bucket.
Inside this directory.
And we'll also say extract, file before deploy or artifact as part of XML file or artifact will have
build timestamp also, and it will be a zip file.
So it's going to extract that zip file and then put it into this directory.
Now let's say done.
And is it done here?
And see if the pipeline.
Care.
So.
One is the source code.
Second is the test.
Third is the build job and the fourth is deploying artifact to S3 bucket.
Okay, one more last thing pending.
We have to set the notification.
So let's go to settings.
Notifications.
Create notification rule.
So you want to give basic information.
You want to give full information again, based on your choice.
Let's give this notification a name.
We profile hyphen, c hyphen.
Pipeline.
Notification.
And what action.
So if the job is failed, if it has started, it has succeeded.
Or we can just see all and you can just remove what you don't need.
And let's go to Target says topic.
We'll keep this topic.
We'll choose our topic that we created and say submit.
Okay, this is set.
Notification is set.
Now let's go to our pipeline.
And it's showtime.
Let's click on a release change.
Release.
So fetch the cord.
And it's going to run test.
So I will pause my screen now and come back when this is completed.
Okay.
After a few minutes, this is completed.
The test job completed.
Successfully billed.
Job completed successfully, and it has deployed the artifact to S3 bucket.
Let's go and check the bucket.
In the directory.
And we see the artifact with the timestamp.