Okay.
You can run one more test by committing the code.
So if the developer makes a code, change to the repository.
It should automatically detect that and trigger the pipeline.
Let's test that also.
So let's open.
Get back.
You can use the ID as the developer.
Users like Intel AG.
And this is the code comet.
Yes.
And let's make some changes.
So let's open read me dot MD file.
And just please extra hash.
So we're not making any serious code change, but we are making change to some file which should be
detected.
Get ad dot.
Get comet hyphen M.
Testing code pipeline.
And time to push.
So get push.
Origin ci hyphen.
E.
W.
S on this branch.
If there is any comment then it should be detected by events, cloud watch events and that should trigger
the pipeline.
Let's check it.
Okay.
Nothing yet.
Let's refresh the screen.
All right.
You see that?
That started?
It's in progress.
So you had to wait a few more minutes for this to complete.
And then you can see the artifact in the S3 bucket.
Now let's reiterate what we did.
So as like a developer makes a code change and commits in the git repository.
The pipeline should get triggered.
So latest source code will be fetched in the pipeline.
Then our code build job, which is running sonar code analysis, will get triggered.
It will download any dependency from code artifact.
And we'll also check for quality gates.
If that completed successfully, it is going to run the build job, which is going to generate the artifact.
Any dependency will be downloaded again from code artefact.
And the resulting artifact will be stored into S3 bucket.
So this is a continuous integration pipeline.
So no, no need of managing Jenkins server, Nexus server.
So on the Cube server, we're using all cloud based solutions.
So people, I recommend you not to delete these jobs, not to delete this pipeline because anyways,
they are not chargeable.
They're only chargeable when you run it.
And if you are free to your account anyways, you'll not be charged for many, many bills.
Just check the free tier service.
How many hours of free years are allowed in code build?
And I think you have enough number.
So do not delete this pipeline because we are going to use this pipeline in our next projects where
we're going to extend this to continuous delivery pipeline.
I hope you have enjoyed this and learned a lot.
Thank you very much for watching this project video.
I will see you in the next one.