I'm on my management console.
I have an instance named Cops.
I have done all the prerequisites for cops.
So now just with two commands, I'm going to launch the Kubernetes cluster.
Now I recommend you to pause the video and do all the prerequisites for cops and launch the COVID cluster.
You can check out Kubernetes, set up project, and do exactly the same setup as we did in that project
for COPS.
I'm going to log in to this node now with the cops.
With this command, I'm going to create Kubernetes cluster configuration.
First name of my cluster is the Blue Cube, and that's the S3 bucket where I'm storing information.
These are two zones, what we're using to work our nodes.
Size.
Two two micro.
Master size two to micro and my DNS zone name.
I'll hit enter.
Now with cops Update Cluster Command.
I'm going to launch my Kubernetes cluster.
And that is going to take some time.
By the time we are waiting, we'll go to GitHub Repository will keep all our Kubernetes definition file
in the repository.
So I'm going to create a new repository here named us Kubernetes.
Our Ice Cube app.
I will keep it public.
Create a repository.
I'm going to clone this repository on my intel ID.
I will say get from version control.
And let's give the URL.
I will keep it in my F drive C clone.
There is a Kubernetes plugin Intel.
We can use that.
Let's go to Settings.
Plugins.
And we'll find out there itself, Kubernetes.
Let's click on install.
Let's see.
Okay.
Okay, Let's check the health of our cluster.
Cops validate cluster.
Hyphen.
Yes.
Shouldn't be here.
Okay, so it's good.
We have two nodes and one master node.