Now, before we start writing definition files for our parts, we have to create a volume for our DB
port so it can store the MySQL data which gets stored in var lib my SQL into EBS volume.
So let's create an EBS volume.
It was easy to create volume availability zone.
I have selected us east to a.
Size just three GB.
That should be fine.
Volume type GB two and we got the volume ID.
We're going to take a note of it.
For the time being.
I'm going to put it in my sticky notes.
Now we have to make sure when we run our DB port it should be running on a node which is in the same
zone, same availability zone, and we can make that through node selector option in our definition
file.
Node selector works with labels, so we're going to create our own label.
Keep ctrl get notes.
Hyphen hyphen.
Show hyphen.
Labels.
So we should see the available labels.
They are existing labels.
If you want, we can use them.
But we'll create our own label.
Keep Ctrl get nodes.
Let's get the node name.
Keep Ctrl.
Describe Node.
And let me check this node.
It's in which zone?
So I can grab with us hyphen.
East hyphen two.
Okay this is in US east to a.
So this node should be good to run our DB part, but we'll label both the nodes.
So it'll label nodes.
Will select a node name and will give a label called a zone equal to.
US is to a.
Let's label our other node with the US East to be.
Now I have selected only these two zones.
If you want, you can describe this other node and check in which zone it is.
Okay, so I have given two labels.
We are done with our setup and the prerequisite that was required to run our project.
Now we'll start writing the definition files.