While writing the definition file.
If you feel that you want to see all the definition file before you make a decision, then search for
a branch cube app in our repository.
We have a directory here, Kubernetes.
In this.
We have a pro hyphen app.
And here we have all the definition files.
So if you want to check DB deployment definition file, you can check it.
We're going to write it from the scratch in our and we're going to keep it in a different repository.
You can put it in your own repository, like I'm going to put it in a different repository that I have
already cloned on my intel.
It's a fresh this.
There's no data in it for now.
There's some more information that we need to collect.
Let's get that first.
So in Containerization project, we have containers in our view profile application and we need the
we need the image part.
So I'm on my Docker hub account.
I'll get into my organization.
We have repositories.
We're going to use these two images.
We profile app and we profile DB.
We're not going to use Engine X image.
We'll be spinning up an elastic load balancer automatically instead of that.
We profile D.B.?
Jack Beaven is there.
We'll be using that tag.
The profile app.
We went Tag.
This v profile app image was created.
From this branch.
Containerisation.
Now that Docker Docker branch.
Dr. Branch.
Don't.
Fine.
App.
Doka finds.
This is the Docker file that created a V profile app image, and we have copied an artifact inside that
this artifact was generated.
And it has application properties file from our source code.
Resources.
Application dot properties file.
So when container comes off from this image, it will have this application properties file, it will
look for the back end services with this name with pro db username, root password, Vibro db pass and
that for mem cache and that one for rabbit MQ and rabbit mkv.
You also have the username guest guest and the password guest also note down the port numbers.
These are very important information to collect before we create our definition files because we need
to define these information so our application can access the back end services.
There are two sensitive information over here.
One is the database password and one is the rabbit MQ password.
And it wouldn't be ideal to put to put these passwords into text format.
So first we have to encrypt this password with secret.
And then from our pod definition, we can access these encrypted passwords.
Not really encrypted, but encoded.