So let's write our first definition file, which will be of creating a secret.
So I'm going to say file.
We'll name it as.
App hyphen.
Secret dot y html.
So it still shows why.
Amel Because still does not know its a Kubernetes definition file, but we have the plugin.
As long as soon as we give first two lines, it will understand that a component is definition file.
So first API version.
If you're going to use secret objects.
Wasn't his v one kind.
Secret.
You see, as soon as I do that now you see the Cuban symbol over there.
And now we can get this data very easily.
Metadata hit enter.
So we're going to give a name to the secret.
We limit this app hyphen.
Secret Secret.
It's a type.
Oh, back.
Data, not date data.
So we'll create two variables over here, one named as DB POS.
This is just to give the name in the PA definition file so you can give anything our MQ hyphen pass.
Okay.
Now we are going to first encode the values of our passwords and then we're going to mention it over
here.
So from our application properties file, the pro db pass should be the password.
Let's encode this first.
Okay, so first let's encode our password for the pro db Pro db pass.
It's the password.
I'm going to pipe it with base 64.
So you get an encoded value there, which can be used in our definition file for secret.
So I'm going to copy that.
You stood there.
Robin MQ password is guest.
So let's encode that as well.
And let's copy that.
No, this should be good.
I'm going to save this.
And I'm also committed.
The images Committee's secret asset, Comet.
Before we read our other definition file, let's just quickly run a test.
Let's push it to our version control.
It goes to a remote repository.
We're going to fetch it.
In our cop's view, it's a git clone.
We see that in our remote repository.
I'm going to copy this and clone it.
Yes.
Let's get into Cuba.
So we should have the secret here.
Let's create it.
Cube CTL.
Create hyphen f.
Secret created.
Still get secret.
Q it'll describe secret.
To see the detail information and you should see now.
We really don't see the value as long as we don't decode them.
I just say it's five bite size and this is of ten bites of size.
So this is safely stored in our Kubernetes cluster, and this really prevents the accidental exposure
of your passwords.
But if your definition file is still public or accessible by many people, they can really see that
it's encoded with base64 and they can easily decode it with base64.
So this is more about best practice in handling secrets.