Okay, now we'll write our DB definition file.
So.
Going to see.
Fine.
The below DB deployment via email.
This is fine.
This is good.
So we're going to run our DB with deployment apps.
Slash V one is the API version for IT kind deployment.
It will use some metadata like name of course, the pro DB.
Labels.
App Colon, the pro DB.
This label is going to be for our service definition file.
So we're going to create a service of type cluster IP.
And our service is going to route the request to any part that has this label.
I'm talking specifically about the database service.
Now let's give the specifications spec.
So I'll say selector if I already have some part.
With this label app with Pro DB, then that will be already considered in this deployment definition
file.
This is not a mandatory setting for now, but if you want, you can give or you can ignore as well.
Replicas, I'm going to say just one.
We just need one DB.
We are not doing any clustering here.
Template.
Now, by definition, metadata.
Labels.
App Colon, Apple TV.
So the part will have this label specification about the part.
Let's give the containers detail.
Containers.
Name the probe and image.
So we're going to use the image from our Containerization project.
Nats, we profile app we profile back again.
We profile DB.
And tag.
We have only won there.
We won.
Ports.
So our service runs on Port 3306.
So I'm going to say name of my service V Pro db hyphen port.
That's the name we'll give to our port.
Container Port three three is zero six.
Some environment variable to read the MySQL db password.
We have stored it in the secret.
So we have to access it from the secret.
The name of our variable.
Is my school underscore route underscore password.
So we have to set value for this variable and we're going to get the value from.
Secret key reference.
Name of the secret.
So we created a secret with the name app Hyphen secret.
Their apparent secret that one.
And from that we are going to say DB pass.
The key is going to be db hyphen pos.
So the value will be fetched from this DB pass variable and will be assigned into this variable in the
port in the container.
If you have created a volume and I want my DB port to be running in the same zone where we have created
the volume.
Okay, so now we give the node selected information.
This will be going in the same line as the containers node selector, not node name.
Node selector.
We have given label.
Zone.
US hyphen East.
Hyphen to a.
So not running in this zone.
We have given a label to this already.
Okay, so you still get nodes, hyphen hyphen.
Sure.
Hyphen labels and they're zone us east to be zone US east to a.
So we created our EBS volume in this zone and for this node which is in in this zone we are given a
label.
So our pod will run only on the node which is in the same zone which has this label.
Okay, Now let's give the volumes, detail volumes.
Name will save a pro hyphen db hyphen data.
It's an elastic block store.
Volume.
We have already taken note of the volume ID.
So this volume will be attached, will give the file system type.
So it should also format it with extension for.
Okay.
Except there'll be one problem now.
You'll not be able to spot.
Will not be able to attach to this EBS volume.
And that's because in cooperatives, we have to give a tag to the volume that we want to attach.
And I will show you what tag we need to give to the EBS volume.
You can do it through command line or you can do it through console also.
So let's go do it through console easily.
So let's go to EBS Volume.
So we are in this same region.
See, that's the volume.
You can match it with the volume ID?
Yes, that's the volume.
And we have to give one tag over here.
So then only your part will be able to attach to this volume or note is going to attach the volume.
Otherwise you'll get permission denied errors.
So the tag is Kubernetes cluster.
And your cluster name.
So my cluster name is V Cube dot graphy dot n.
So whatever name you have given to your Kubernetes cluster, you have to give the same name over here.
So while creating the Kubernetes cluster command, we give Hyphen F a name.
That's the name of your cluster.
So give that.
If you don't give this, then you will not be able to map and you can see it's throwing you permission
denied errors.
So this should be good.
Okay, Now we're going to say map this volume to the pod.
So we have to say volume mounts.
Mount Bath.
I want to mount it at their lib.
My school name repro hyphen db hyphen data.
This is the name of the volume that we are creating over here.
So the volume gets created over here and gets mounted over here.
Now, you may also get one more error if you just roll this out.
And the data will be coming.
Sorry, the error will be coming from the pod.
You can see Cube CTL logs and the pod name.
You can see log in the pod telling that volume or storage is not free or it's not empty.
There's already data when we format it with extension.
It's going to create a directory over there called Lost plus found.
That's what happens in Linux.
And if the volume mounts is finding that there's already a data, then it will not mount it.
So you have to pass an argument.
You can pass arguments to your pod or your containers.
You can see args.
So you have to pass this argument.
Ignore hyphen db hyphen directory.
Equal to lost.
Plus found.
So that directory, if it's there, it's going to ignore it and it will attach the volume.
Okay, let's go through the definition file once again.
Deployment.
That's the label match Label replica one Template labels spec.
So it can also alert you for some issues.
All right.
This is about the label.
This is good.
Image Path Volume Mount Option Port 3306 My root password note selector seems good.
Let's save it.
Committed.
DB part.
And let's push it.
I want to make a test on it because there's so many things in this.
So get pulled.
Yeah.
Okay, let's test it.
Cube CTL create hyphen F with pro db deployment.
It is deployment created.
Let's see if it'll get deploy.
It'll get bored.
And the real information should come from this board.
Q It'll describe poor if there is any issue while creating the poor or mounting the volume.
We should find it here.
It's still at pulling image state.
Look, if you're getting an error warning, back off, restarting fail, it's trying to restart the
container for some reason.
Cube still get bored.
Let's see the logs of this part.
Keep Seattle logs.
Okay.
And there is some issue with this option.
Let's check it.
Yeah, of course it should be hyphen hyphen.
Ignore.
Of.
See that?
That's committed.
So it's saying that it's an invalid argument like that.
Okay, let's try once again.
Okay.
I'm going to delete this.
Keep Ctrl, get deploy.
Keep ctrl delete deploy the pro db.
Let's fetch the latest changes.
Get pull.
Okay.
There is a new comet we can see.
Should be good now.
It'll create hyphen f.
Yeah.
Let's check Cuba.
It'll get bored.
Keep still.
Describe pod.
Still creating the container.
Let's find out whether it's done or not.
Now it seems done.
Attach volume succeeded container image created Container started container should be healthy now.
Okay.
So I recommend first you test this.
Now, after this, you're going to create all the deployment definition files and spin all of them together.
Let's go then.