Okay.
We have to create a service for this DB so our application pod can access it.
So I'm going to say DB hyphen C, IP cluster IP.
We are not going to expose it to the outside world.
It's going to only for the internal traffic API version.
Colon v one.
For the kind service.
Okay, so you give this to line and you say, controller, save it, and it will just show that it's
a Kubernetes and then you'll get all the help in writing your definition.
File metadata name will give the pro DB.
Now, this name is important.
Now all our service definition files will be based on our application properties file for our application.
DB v pro db.
That should be the name of the service and port number 3306.
So it should accept the request.
The server should accept the request on 3306 and send it to our DB port.
Okay, let's give the specifications.
So ports, of course.
Port number 3306.
All right.
Target port.
Now we can give the port number, but we have also given name to our port.
Right.
So we can just say a pro db hyphen port V pro db hyphen port.
Protocol.
Dxb Capital DXB So it's going to accept the request from 3306 and then should send the request to the
backend port on 3306 and the back end part.
What should be the back end selector?
App Colon, the pro DB That should be the label of your pod.
Their template label app with pro TB.
So you should give the same label over here.
Okay, let's see if this.