Okay, that's fine.
Let's continue with our next.
Port definition file or deployment definition file, which is for mem cache.
So I'm going to say MSI j deployment dot y html.
Okay.
This is also this is a simple deployment definition file.
Label app, Wipro MSI.
Selector webroot pro app msi replica one single template and the port information.
So we have this label for our port app Colon, Wipro, MSI container name Wipro MSI image mem d So this
is not customised.
This official Docker image from Docker Hub Official image from Docker Hub.
And we already have that port exposed at 11211.
So we're going to mention that port.
There's a simple definition file.
Let's create a service definition file for this.
We'll see.
MCI hyphen c IP dot women.
I just say, remember, don't ask again.
Hoagie Kind Service Name Vpro Cache zero one.
Again, this name should be the same as we see in the application properties file.
So yourselves.
The service will be running with this name and we'll be listening on request.
One, one, two, one, one.
One, one, two, one one and forwarding it to the pro msi hyphen port, which is.
The sport.
One, one, two, one, one.
So accept the request on 112, one one for the request on one.
One, two, one, one.
Where the selector, where the label is.
That.
Now, this one.
Starting this one, The pro M.S., That's your pot label.
Right type cluster IP.
Again, I have to mention that over here as well.
Type.
Cluster IP in the DB definition file also.