Next, Robert McHugh.
Kind deployment.
Name Viper MQ zero one as the label.
Same label for the selectors replica one.
And this will be the label of our pod.
Specification Container Name Wipro MQ zero one Image Rabbit MQ.
So if you don't have a customized image for this and we don't need it again, this is an official image
from Docker Hub.
Port.
15672.
That's the name of the port.
Now we have to set two environment variable over here.
One is for the rabbit MQ user and rabbit MQ.
Second is for the rabbit MQ password.
So we're going to say.
E.
And V.
First.
Naeem.
Rabbit.
MQ.
Underscore default.
Underscore pass.
This is the variable as per the official documentation of rabbit image.
On Docker hub.
So that's the variable you have to assign the value.
And we have already encoded this value in the secret.
So we're going to say value from secret key reference.
Key is item Q hyphen pass the name of the secret.
Also you have to give name.
App hyphen secret.
This is coming from this app.
Secret Arabic Pass.
Secret Name.
App.
Hyphen.
Secret.
Also the username.
The username.
We can just give just like that.
So you're going to say name rabbit mq underscore default underscore user.
And value not from just a value is.
Guest.
Guest username and guest password.
Password We have kept in the secret.
Okay, cluster I p for this rabbit MQ so I'm going to see item Q hyphen cip, dot y html.
Support 15672 Target Port.
Wipro.
MQ hyphen port.
Abraham, You haven't put that on the board.
Selector app.
Wipro MQ.
Their label app Wipro MQ.
So you should match these things.