Now our main hero Tom application.
So.
File.
Pro App Deployment Definition dot HTML.
Okay so the default things kind deployment apps we want version.
Replica one.
Match label template, and that's the label of our pod.
Specification about this.
Container's name Vpro app.
That's the name I'll give.
Image.
And we have a customized image for this on the Docker hub.
That one.
V Profile.
V Profile App.
Tag v one.
And that's the capital over there.
If you want, you can use my same image, but I still recommend you go to the Containerization project
and have your own images because you can use this image.
These are public.
There's no problem with it.
Container Port v Pro app hyphen port.
That's the name I'll give.
That's the.
Nima, I have to give the fort first.
Yeah.
Sometime This act.
Weird name.
If a pro app hyphen port.
This is fine.
So all our deployment has one single container in them.
But in this are going to have multiple containers in this pod one our normal container or main process
which will be created from this image.
And the other two I'm going to give in it container and it containers name in it hyphen my DB.
I want the DB container to be created first and then it should create this pod.
And for that, I'm going to have a shell script executed from.
The Xbox.
Okay.
That's an image box, I think.
Yeah.
That's right.
Busy box.
Okay, that's cool.
It's also showing us the images from Docker Hub.
That's so nice.
So I want this container to be created from this image and should run this command for me.
Okay, so the command is so in it container.
So it will come first and one when this container work is completed, then it will launch this container.
So this container will be halted as long as this container does not finish its work.
And its work is to really check the DB port.
Or should I say DB service?
So we are running a bash until loop and we're doing nest lookup vibro DB.
So as long as it does not return true, this loop will be continuously running.
And while it's running we are printing a code waiting for my DB slip 2 seconds.
So we're doing this printing and we're executing sleep two command, so it's going to sleep for 2 seconds.
So every 2 seconds is going to run and look of the bro.
DB If it does not return true, it does not result to any value.
That means it's false and it will keep on running.
Okay, so I'm creating a dependency over here.
And this example is directly from the Kubernetes documentation.
So whenever you have dependencies like that you can link by init containers.
Okay.
Also, one more dependency will create.
Same thing for the Prakash one.
So we'll also wait for the web Prakash and service to come up.
So it's going to fetch the busy box image.
Run a container and run this command on that container.
When its job is completed, when this command completes successfully, the containers will be dead and
then our main container will be launched.
Yeah.
Let's see if this and let's create the service definition file for this.
And we would like to have a load balancer before this app hyphen service, dot y.
E html.
Okay, so I'm going to say API version.
We one of kind.
Service.
Receive this.
Oops.
I have not gotten colon there yet.
Let me see if this now.
Okay.
Now I can get easy options.
Metadata.
Name the Pro app hyphen service.
Spec.
Put.
Port number 80.
I'm just going to write it on default http port Target, Port V Pro App hyphen port.
That's the port 88.
Five one.
Port.
Port 80.
Protocol TCP.
And this line will have selector.
No, not here.
Sorry.
There.
Selector.
App Colon, the pro app type is going to be load balancer, so it's going to launch an elastic load
balancer.
Okay.