Okay.
Let's check.
We have a secret file, DB cluster IP cache.
Cluster IP and cache Deployment Rabbit MQ Cluster IP Rabbit.
MQ Deployment.
Okay.
I think we're good.
Let's commit.
That's it for Profile app services.
Commit.
And let's push it.
Okay, Let's fetch it now.
Okay.
We have pulled all the changes.
Let's do it now.
So Ctrl create hyphen F and I'm just going to say dot, so it's going to read all the definition files.
I don't need to do one by one.
Okay.
A few errors we got.
It's a secret already exist.
We probably already exist.
And that's the cluster IP which we created and we deployment.
So these three things you already created previously for testing.
So that's really not an error for us.
We could have done apply instead of create.
So if it already exists, you don't get any error.
And that should be fine.
Let's check now.
Keeps you till get deploy.
Okay.
The pro app is still not up.
I think it's waiting for it back in port part.
Oh, it's still up.
Already up?
Yeah, it's up.
Everything is up.
Keep Ctrl, get SBC.
Get load balancer endpoint.
Let's copy that and let's test it.
Okay.
It's not yet up.
That's because I think.
And a load balancer would be still doing the health check.
Yeah.
Okay, health check is happening.
Okay.
It's in service now.
No, it took a while because our application takes some time to come up.
Let's log in and try admin, underscore VP, admin, underscore VP.
So we're getting the page from Tomcat application.
This is good.
Let's try log in.
If this works, then DB will be also verified.
Yes, we're in.
So we're also able to connect to the DB port.
Let's check it out.
MQ.
I would MQ initiated all users for mem cache.
Let's fetch user.
Back.
All right.
All the services are verified.
So from containerisation of a project, now we are running our containerized application on production
grid, Kubernetes cluster.