We have an end point and we can also put this into our GoDaddy or we can also use a Route 53.
Let's go to Route 53.
We'll put the key name entry.
Let's go to hostage zones.
That's our whole zone.
Let's create a record.
Simple record.
Okay, we'll see.
I will see.
Like this blog endpoint will select our load balancer.
It's in Ohio.
US is to Ohio.
Yeah, that's the one.
Record.
It's seen a record was taken as a record.
Okay, let's keep it as it is.
Blog dot cubed or graphy dot rn.
Define simple record.
Let's create records.
Okay.
Let's test it with this URL.
Yeah, that's working.
That's awesome.
You know what?
I'll create an account this time.
Create an account?
Username Cube Master Cube at Monster.com.
Some fake email address there.
To password.
It has to be think a digit.
Sign up.
Yes, we're able to also sign up.
This looks pretty neat.
So yes, we have successfully deployed our application to Kubernetes cluster.
By using these simple definition files.
We already have all the definition files in the branch.
Q branch.
So if you want, we can check that out before writing it, so you'll have an idea before writing it.
So Kubernetes in that you have pro hyphen app and all the definitions files are here, so you can just
fetch it and you can just say cubes, it'll create hyphen f dot and you know, it will just launch the
entire stack.
And I recommend you go through all the options and write your own definition files.
And that's pretty neat.
And it's time for the cleanup now.
So let's clean up everything.
Well, if you want to delete your application, you can just skip ctrl from the same directory.
Okay.
Very high definition file can skip ctrl delete hyphen f dot.
That should be done in in a few seconds.
And when you're done with your practice, you just delete the Kubernetes cluster with cops, delete
command, and it will anyway, is delete everything inside that, including the load balancer.
So I'm going to say cops delete cluster.
So it's going to wait for some time.
And, you know, by the time it will keep attempting re attempting the deletion, once you cluster is
deleted, you can stop your cops instance.
All right.
Keep all your dependencies and then, you know, you can launch your cluster anytime you want by running.
Cops create cluster command.
All right.
So that was all in this project.
I hope you have learned a lot.
Thank you very much for watching.
I will see you in the next one.