Hello and welcome.
Welcome to the next project in the Davos Project series.
The name of this project is Continuous Delivery with Jenkins and Tools.
So if you have the continuous integration project, this is just an extension of that project.
Continuous delivery force will understand what is continuous delivery, what are the problems that it
solve.
And then you will set up the continuous delivery pipeline.
Okay.
So this is the scenario.
There there is a product development happening with Agile, SDLC.
So all these developers are making regular code changes and building the product.
And in an agile SDLC developer will make regular code changes.
And all these code changes which gets merged with your remote repositories needs to be build tested
and also needs to be deployed to servers for further software testing or performance testing or load
testing.
So before even it gets promoted to the production, there are so many tests that happens first on the
code that happens in the continuous integration pipeline and then after delivering the code to the servers,
more tests, tests are conducted.
So once the code is packaged into an artifact, it will be deployed to servers, maybe staging servers,
and then there will be more test conducted like software testing, integration testing, load testing,
performance testing.
And if this test reports checks out, fine, then only you get approval to deploy your changes to production.
Now we have to understand we are working in an agile environment.
There will be frequent code changes and all these changes needs to be deployed to different, different
servers, which is called US delivery and which will be very time consuming if this process is manual.
And moreover, the ops team will not be able to cope with such frequent changes.
They will not be able to deploy it so frequently if the process is manual.
And moreover, here comes a lot of dependencies.
The developer will be dependent on build and release team.
Those teams will be dependent on operations team and the interaction between these teams will be happening
through ticketing system or through emails and some fancy tools also.
But my point is, there are too much of dependencies, too many tools involved, which actually delays
the process of delivery.
So a developer, as fast as they're developing the code, not at the same speed or not at the same pace,
the code is delivered to the server.
One thing is for sure in this fast moving world, whenever there is a code change, this code needs
to be built, tested, deployed and then tested more further before you deploy to production system.
And if this has to be done for every commit, every pull request, then this process needs to be automated
process.
And whatever you build your test or deploy or for every place, there should be a notification, every
task, completion or failure.
There should be notification if something fails.
The product owner who saw is the responsible developer or a tester will get into it and fix those problems.
Even operations team.
So if there is any bug in a code that can be isolated very quickly and developers can work on making
the code change, making all the fix and patches, and then this automated process can repeat again.
So completely automated build, test, deploy, test, deploy tests.
This entire process is called this continuous delivery process.
And mind you hear, the word delivery really means delivering it till preproduction.
So your artifact is really ready now to deploy to production.
We have not deployed to production.
We are still waiting for the approval.
We have delivered it to all the pre prod environment and even tested it and we are ready to deploy it
on production.
We just need the approval.
That's what is continuous delivery process and we'll understand it much better by doing it.
Some common benefits about continuous deliveries.
You can resolve any issue quickly.
So you don't wait and accumulate the bugs and errors in the code.
If there is any problem, a code fix will be done.
Automated process will deploy to everywhere and will make the test quickly so mean.
Time to repair will be very short.
It will be very well agile and no human intervention or very, very less human intervention.
No human intervention is better, actually.
So you try to achieve with your continuous delivery pipeline, no human intervention.
In such cases when you're running your pipeline and if you happen to have any bug or any error in your
pipeline or in the code, it can be isolated very quickly and you can fix it.
Okay.
Now let's see the tools that we are going to use.
So the tools are first we will be using Jenkins as a continuous integration and continuous delivery
server.
Next repository from where we'll download Maven dependency and upload our artifact.
Next Sona Cube server sona cube scanner for code analysis and sona cube server to check the quality
gates maven which will be used in Jenkins to build our artifact our Java artifact repository, where
we will have our source code and our pipeline code as well.
Slack for notifications.
Docker to build our Docker images.
So we will copy our artifact, our Java artefact in a Docker image.
Publish the Docker image to Amazon ACR.
So here, the final product in our continuous integration will be a Docker image.
We build it in the Jenkins and push it to Amazon easier elastic container registry x where we will be
hosting our Docker containers.
A.W. Seelye, which will run from Jenkins fetch the latest image from Amazon ACR and deployed on.
Ethics cluster.
Let's take a look at all these tools in a flow.
So developer will be using get.
To make changes to the code committed and push it to GitHub, which will also have our Jenkins pipeline
code.
Jenkins will fetch the latest code whenever there is a comet.
Using Maven will run a unit test textile for code analysis, then sonar scanner again for code analysis.
Upload the result to sonar cube server.
Check for quality gates if everything is good.
That build the Docker image, which will have the Java artefact in it.
This Docker image will be a tomcat docker image with our artifact in that which will be pushed or published
to Amazon ACR.
Then we will use a C command from Jenkins Pipeline, which will deploy.
Our latest image to Amazon X cluster.
So Amazon X will fetch the latest image from ACR and run it on x cluster.
Take a look once again at this flu.
Okay.
The objectives.
So we want fault isolation quickly.
We want short MDR.
We want fast turnaround time.
So if there is any new request and a new code change, it can be built quickly by the developer and
can be also delivered very quickly.
So that's what fast turnaround time means here.
And less disruptive.
Once everything is automated, you have in that continuous delivery pipeline.
Then there are very less chance of making human error.
No human error actually in the pipeline is going on.
So it's going to be less disruptive.
All right, so let's achieve our goals.
Okay.
Now we'll see the architecture of continuous delivery pipeline and also the flow of execution, how
we're going to execute this entire project.
Okay.
So this is the design.
So first thing developer makes a code change once you have a continuous delivery pipeline set up.
Then this entire process will execute automatically.
So the law makes a code change into a remote repository.
We are using we are going to use GitHub.
So as soon as there is a new commit in GitHub.
Jenkins server or automation server is going to fetch the latest changes automatically build it, run
some test, unit test or code analysis all the kinds of tests and give the information to.
The developer on Slack.
Oh, what are they using?
We're going to use Slack for notification.
Then the next job in the pipeline will get executed, which is actually going to package the artifact
version it and store it on some remote repository.
Remote software repository like Nexus Sonata.
If you're going to use Nexus sonar type repository, once that is done, a notification is sent.
The next job then gets triggered automatically, which is going to deploy the artifact to staging environment.
Once it is deployed to a staging environment, there will be a few more tests conducted integration,
test load tests, any software testing.
So there will be a software testers, test scripts.
We are going to execute that from a Windows server, which is going to check our staging environment
for any bugs, any errors.
If everything is good.
Then again, the notification will be sent.
The artifact can then be stored to somewhere else for production, deployment or like S3 or you can
keep it in excess repository also.
And this will be a very well tested artifact.
Now same artifact.
You can deploy it on production.
Now, in continuous delivery, we don't automatically deploy to production.
In continuous delivery, we are done till here and we wait for the approval.
We have the artifact stored now, which is well tested, deployed and again tested.
We're waiting for the approval.
Once we have the approval, we are going to trigger a job which is going to do deployment to production
environment, and a few more tests will be conducted.
So it will be a manual trigger.
All right, now let's see the flow of execution, all the steps that we are going to perform in order
to complete this project, in case whenever you are lost while doing the project, you don't know what
or where we are currently.
You can anytime watch this and understand where exactly you are.
So starting with updating GitHub webhook with the new Jenkins IP.
After doing the continuous integration project on Jenkins, you would have stopped Jenkins server and
now you power it on again.
It's public IP will change in our GitHub repository.
We have given the public IP of Jenkins for the webhook, so we need to update that.
We need to change it to the newer IP so our pipeline gets executed automatically whenever we make a
code change.
Now since we will be deploying Docker containers on X cluster first we need to prepare the Docker images
and that gets prepared through Docker files that are already Docker files and we provide repository.
We're going to copy it from there and put it in our own repository.
We will be seeing the deployment on a staging environment and production environment, and for that
we will create two separate Jenkins file in the source code in the repository.
In place.
We need to do a few things.
Of course we need to create an IAM user, which Jenkins will use to access ACR repository.
We also need to create the ACL repository where Jenkins will store the Docker images.
In Jenkins we log into the dashboard and we need to install some plug ins, Amazon, ACR, Docker plugin,
Docker, build and publish plug in pipeline steps.
These are the plugins that we need to install.
There's also one more plug in credentials which gets installed when you install this plugin as a dependency.
So you'll need to mention that the Jenkins is going to build the Docker images.
So we will be installing Docker engine on the Jenkins.
So Docker engine is the tool in the Jenkins that will build the docker images.
It will use CLI.
So when we deploy our docker images to x cluster, we will be running a sqlite commands.
So we install a cloud as well.
After all this preparation, we are going to write the code in the Jenkins file to build the Docker
image and publish it to a CCR.
Once our image is published to our.
We will need x elastic container service to run our Docker container from our Docker image.
So we need to create an X, so we have to create x cluster in that we create task definition.
And then we create a service.
This service is going to create the Docker container for us.
It's going to fetch the image from ACR and run the container.
It will also provide us load balancer and few other things that we will be seeing.
Once our X cluster and service is set up.
We will write the code in the Jenkins file to deploy our Docker image to X cluster.
Now, so far, this one is for the staging environment.
Once we deploy our Docker container on staging easiest cluster, we need to deploy to production environment.
Of course, in real time there will be testing, there'll be software testing.
Once everything is approved then you can deploy the container to the production environment.
So we'll just repeat the same step eight and nine for production.
Easiest cluster.
Then we will see steps or process.
How do we promote our Docker container to production environment?
So these are all the steps or stages that we will be executing in order to complete this project.
Take a look once again and join me in the next lecture.