Welcome.
This project is basically the continuation of continuous integration project, which we did on Jenkins.
So you should have all these three instances from that project.
Just power them on.
If you deleted them, you need to recreate.
You need to do the complete continuous integration project that is the prerequisite site for this project.
Once you power on, make sure you update the security group rules to allow it to access from your IP.
So on Jenkins Security Group Rule 88 from anywhere 22 from your IP on a Nexus 22 from your IP 81 from
your IP and a Sony server 22 from your IP and 80 from your IP.
Once you update that, your update all your new IP is.
Get the Jenkins server public IP.
Copy that.
Go to your GitHub repository, the same repository that we used in Continuous Integration Project.
Go to its settings.
The books.
Edit.
It might ask you the password to enter the password and login.
Update the Jenkins IP carefully.
There.
And let's see.
Update Webhook.
And let's go to the recent deliveries.
And let's try.
To deliver this.
Okay.
That's a success.
So the book is working.
Next.
We need to prepare our code.
We need to add Docker files and we need to arrange the Jenkins file for staging and production environment
in our source code.
So let's go to Vpro file project repository.
So go to our project repository at this link.
And you need to select the branch docker from here.
Make sure you switch to the branch docker, not anything else but Docker.
Click on this dropdown and we'll say download zip file.
And that's the save it in our downloads.
Okay.
In the downloads.
Let's extract it.
You extract all.
Extract.
Okay.
So you see that folder inside that you should have same folder once again, same name, and then you
have the Docker file.
So you need to copy this folder in the source code.
Okay.
In the source code, I mean to say the same repository that we used in continuous integration project.
So if you deleted that from your system, then you clone it once again.
I did it in this f drive this directory, same as previously I did in previous project.
You can clone it same place or do it somewhere else.
If you deleted it.
If you already have it, it's fine.
So let me clear the screen.
Once again, this is your repository that you created in continuous integration project, not mine.
So I will go to this directory.
Okay.
So we are in the main branch.
We will switch to CI hyphen jenkins.
So you need to be in this branch.
Sy hyphen Jenkins.
And then you switch.
On create, create and switch.
Sorry.
Git checkout and will secede hyphen Jenkins.
A new branch we are creating from the CI branch and we are switching to that branch.
And we'll copy the Docker files here.
So let's go.
It's a copy.
The Docker files.
And go to your repository where you have cloned it.
Make sure you already checked out to CCD.
Jenkins branch.
Okay.
And then you copy it.
So I'll say just paste it.
Just control we.
So we will read the Docker files when we write the code.
For now, we're just preparing the source code.
So that's the first thing you need to do is copy the Docker file into your repository.
And it's there.
Okay.
Next thing is, you have to create two folders here.
Stage pipeline and prod pipeline.
Okay.
Let's clear the screen.
And you copy this Jenkins file to stage pipeline and also to prod the pipeline.
I'm doing it from command line.
If you want, you can do it from the file Explorer also.
And we do not need this Jenkins file, which is in the root directory.
So I'm going to say git arm Jenkins file git item, not just our.
So better do it through command line.
Okay.
Now, why did I do this?
Well, for we will have two pipelines at the end of this project.
We'll have a staging pipeline and we'll have a production pipeline.
So a staging pipeline will use Jenkins file from staging pipeline directory.
And for production pipeline, we'll use Jenkins file from production pipeline directory.
And I think that's self explanatory.
Okay.
Now before we make the comment, code structure is ready.
By the way, we'll make the changes to the Jenkins file in upcoming lectures, but our structure is
ready.
And before I push it back to my git repository, I will validate this config file.
Just do a cat dot git config file.
Open this file, read this file and see jenkins branch mean it's going to merge it to see a jenkins
branch.
That is good.
If you see here anything like cursed branch Cecil Jenkins branch and you see merge it to see a Jenkins
branch if it's a different branch name here compared to here, then open this file and delete that entry.
If you don't see it, it is good.
Now we'll say git add dot.
Whoops, let's take git add dot.
Get.
Commit hyphen m.
Let's say preparing see secede branch.
Okay.
Time to push, get push origin.
So we have a new branch, right?
So we mentioned the origin ci seed hyphen Jenkins.
A new branch is created on the GitHub repository.
Let's go there.
Let's refresh.
We should see New Branch.
Cassidy Jenkins.
Yeah.
And we have the Docker file, we have these two directories.
They contain their own Jenkins file, which will be updating later.
Okay.
That's all we need to do really in this lecture.
If you want to do it with other ways, you can do that.
But you just need to have the Docker files from the profile repositories and these two directories with
their own Jenkins file.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.