In this lecture, we will be creating an IAM user that Jenkins will use to access a s services like
ACR and X.
Forced will create iam user second will create easier repository elastic container repository.
So let's go to iam service.
I click on users.
And see add users.
I will limit, as Sy said, Jenkins.
Access key.
You can give whatever name you want for this user.
Just make sure you put a checkmark and access key.
Next, attach existing policies directly.
So we need to add here a few policy.
One is the EC two container registry.
Full access, that one.
So this user can access the ACR repository.
The second one is going to be ex.
This is the service which will run our container.
And Jenkins from Jenkins.
It will be happening.
So Jenkins will run.
It will be running a sea fly to deploy the container to easiest service.
So we need to give full access here.
Next.
Get once again, make sure these two policies are selected while creating this user.
Create user.
And I'm going to say download CSV file which will store which will have the credentials access key and
secret key.
We will need this in the next lecture.
I will keep this tab as it is so I can just copy it from here.
Also make sure you do not share this credentials with anybody.
Do not post these credentials in Q&A.
I have seen some people posting their credentials on Q&A.
They will be instantly hacked by hackers or grabbed by the hackers and they'll misuse it.
So make sure you do not post your credentials on the Q&A or anywhere for that matter.
Okay.
Let's go to the next service.
Are.
Plastic Container Registry.
So elastic container registry service is pretty simple.
It just stores your Docker images so you can store here.
You can make it public, you can make it private.
And just take a look, go through it, read it.
If you have never used ACR, it's pretty simple, but take a look.
Read this, understand what is ACR?
Like that.
There are many.
Not many, but quite few.
Repositories services available from Azure.
You have from Google, you have you have Docker Hub on Nexus.
Also, you can create a repository, Docker repository, your own local Docker repository, but will
be using ACR.
So let's say get started and we'll keep it private.
We don't want publicly accessible repository and repository name.
Let's give it a name.
Yeah, that is fine.
We profile app IMG.
That's the name I have given.
You can keep the same name, but make sure what you give.
You remember it because you're going to come here and copy this one.
Scroll down.
We're not going to do anything.
That's it.
Just give the name, create a repository.
It's that simple.
And this is the UI.
Okay.
I will come to this.
When we write our code, we need this URL.
So that is all in this lecture.
Join me in the next one where we set up Jenkins to run our Docker pipeline code.