In this lecture we will be doing multiple things on Jenkins.
First install necessary plugins.
Second store enables credentials on it.
Third installing Docker engine in Jenkins.
So it's pretty simple things just go to Jenkins.
IP 80.
That's log in.
Okay.
We need to make sure this pipeline works because we will be extending this pipeline from continuous
integration to continuous delivery.
We'll come to this job, but first we have to install some plug ins.
So let's go to manage plugins.
Available.
Okay.
One by one, starting with.
Docker pipeline.
Put a checkmark.
Then darker build and publish cloud based Docker build and publish that one.
And we have ACR.
PCR, Amazon, ACR, this one.
And Pipeline.
Calling it steps that one.
Yeah.
You need to search it like that.
Pipeline, colon steps.
These are the four plugins we will use.
There's also one more plug in a plus credentials that gets installed as a dependency for this Amazon
Echo and the pipeline UW Steps plugin.
Okay, let's install this.
Okay.
Well, I don't see the credentials plugin getting installed as cloud V0 plus credential.
Let's wait for it to complete and then we'll check.
Okay.
This is install.
Let's go back to the top page.
Manage Jenkins, manage plugins.
Lets come again to manage plugins.
I want to see whether it has credentials plugin again.
Not able to search.
That means it's already installed.
We can check it in the install.
E.
S credentials.
A.W. Sdhc.
This is good and available SDK.
Okay.
I think it's already installed.
If it's not installed, we will not be able to find one option that will see now.
So go to manage.
Jenkins will store the access key and secret key in Jenkins.
So go to manage credentials.
This will be used by our pipeline.
Jenkins global credentials and see add credentials.
In the kind you should see credentials so that plug in card installed.
Select that and let's give a name.
I will say it is creds.
ID and in the description also I'm giving same and I'll give the access key and secret key.
I have not closed this window so far, so copy the access key.
Be stood there.
And then the secret key.
Now you're going to see my secret key, which is very, very bad.
But anyways, I am going to delete this user once this recording is completed, so I don't mind you
seeing it.
Okay.
There.
Please specify the secret access key.
That's what I did.
Okay.
What's going on here?
I see.
Yes, that's correct.
Mm hmm.
Okay, let's create it.
Let's see.
You're not saving it.
E.W. Scripps.
That's the credential name.
We will be using it in our pipeline code.
The next thing, the third thing is going through the command line and installing Docker engine.
So let's do an search to the Jenkins server.
As a search hyphen, I downloads.
We profile high.
Pam That's my logging key one to at the rate IP address.
Yes.
Okay.
We're in.
Just be the root user.
So the hyphen.
I become the root user.
Run apt update person in person.
APT install a US client.
So that's what we'll install first.
And after this completes, we will install docker engine.
Okay.
By the time it is installing.
Let's go to Google.
And search for docker installation step on ubuntu docker install ubuntu go to the documentation docs
dot dot dot com.
Do not go anywhere.
These commands installation steps are changing a lot, many, many times.
That's why I have stopped putting them into the resource section.
So go to the documentation, find the steps and install it.
Okay.
So first is apt update.
We already did that.
So we're going to install these dependencies first.
Okay.
Make sure this is right.
1 to 20.
Okay.
Me.
Clear the screen and shift.
Insert paste it.
Install these dependencies.
They're already installed.
Nice.
Okay to run these two commands.
One is creating this directory.
And next is downloading this GPG key for docker repository.
Okay.
Next is this big echo command, which is going to create the repository file.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
All right.
That's it.
APT update and install docker engine.
Yeah.
So I'm not telling you.
This is the command.
This is the command and this is the command because I don't know, it may change maybe in the next month.
Who knows?
So.
Make sure you go to the documentation, find the commands and install Docker engine.
Okay.
While this is installing.
So.
Jenkins, we are going to write the code in the Jenkins to build the Docker image.
Docker image is built by Docker commands, so you need to have Docker engine installed in Jenkins so
Jenkins can run the Docker commands and build your Docker images.
And there is one problem though.
Docker commands can be run only by the Docker, by the root user and the user who are in the Docker
group.
I'll show you what I mean.
I'm going to switch to Jenkins user from here.
Yeah.
So I'm currently Jenkins user and I'm going to run the command docker images and you see I get this
error got permission denied.
Okay.
Exit from the route user.
You can obviously run the cow.
Any Docker.
Come on.
Right.
So what you have to do is you have to add user mode.
Hyphen A, capital G, you have to add.
Jenkins user in the Docker group.
So I say Docker.
Jenkins So Jenkins user will be added into the Docker group with this command and you can see it.
Jenkins.
See that it's in the docket group now.
Now, that is not it.
Either you restart the Jenkins service system, CTL restart.
Jenkins.
Ah.
You reboot Jenkins.
So I will say system.
It'll restart.
Jenkins But while running the build job.
Docker Build job if you are getting the same error in the Jenkins, then check whether this Jenkins
user is in the Docker group and if you see it's still there.
Then the next step I would suggest is just reboot Jenkins server because maybe the restart did not work,
so you might need to reboot it.
Okay, now final thing, it's time to test our continuous integration pipeline from the previous project.
It should be working because we are going to continue from here.
Yeah, I got logged out.
Uh huh.
I think it's still not ready, so it takes some time.
After restarting Jenkins.
Okay.
I have purposefully failed the pipeline.
If you remember from continuous integration project, I made a mistake so I get a notification, right?
So I'm going to go back to my repository here in the GitHub itself.
Yeah.
Not one.
And we are.
We have used this branch.
See, hyphen Jenkins.
Mary.
We check the Jenkins file.
Yeah.
So I made this change, right?
So the pipeline fails.
I'm going to fix that.
I'm going to say edit.
And I will just remove that and replace it with the actual command and even and.
Let's.
Committed, fixed.
Maven.
Come on.
Com.
It changes.
Okay.
Now let's go back.
To our pipeline and it should automatically trigger it because there is a webhook.
Now we have also updated the webhook IP Jenkins IP.
Right.
So it should automatically trigger the pipeline.
It should complete it.
If this is failing, make sure you fix the problems.
Make sure your next steps and so on are cube.
All are up and running.
Right.
Test the pipeline.
It should be a working pipeline.
So then only we can continue with the next lecture, we can continue with the project.
So I'm going to pause the video and wait until this completes.
All right.
My pipeline completed successfully.
I made all the necessary changes.
Let's see.
In the next lecture, if we are able to build the Docker image and upload it to Amazon easier.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.