All right.
So in this video, the actual fun will happen.
We are going to write the code to build the Docker image and upload it to Amazon ACR.
Let's go through the code first.
Let's look at the code for Docker file.
So let me log out from Jenkins here.
So I go to my repository.
To my repository, not be profile repository.
And I'm in the branch.
KD hyphen Jenkins.
Check.
Get status.
Everything is good.
Make sure you're in this branch.
KD hyphen Jenkins and zip code dot.
You should open your voice code.
Okay.
First, let's go through the Docker file.
So Docker files dropdown, this Docker file for app DB and web in app.
So we are going to build the Tomcat application image.
So there is a simple Docker file.
If you are building the artifact in the Jenkins itself, you can use this Docker file to copy the artifact
to the container, but we will go with multi stage Docker Files dropdown, multi stage Docker file and
that's our Docker file.
Let's go through it.
So first we are building it from an open JDK image.
This is the build image.
So we have two images here.
This is the build image which will build the artifact and this is where we are going to copy our artifact.
The second image.
So open JDK image version eight.
Installing Maven there and cloning the source code from Vpro file repository.
Now you can run this Docker file in the same source code.
You can copy the source code in this image and run the install command.
But just to keep things simple and clean for this project, I'm mentioning the step to clone it from
Vpro file repository in real time you may need to just copy.
Your source code this all the source code into the image and rename uninstall.
You can do it through a volume option.
You can use copy option or add option also.
But let's keep this like that.
Clone the source code from Vpro file repository.
Get into that directory and run an install which should generate the artifact.
Now the second image, Tomcat image.
This is what we will be publishing.
It's based on Tomcat image.
So we remove the default Tomcat application from this image and we copy from build image from this build
image.
Right.
We are copying the artifact.
Act one which will be in this part we profile v to dot var into us our local tomcat eight sorry tomcat
web apps route dot var with the name route dot var.
So that becomes the default application.
Expose it on port 88 command to search dot run.
So when we say Docker run, it's going to run this command and host our artifact and that is the only
image we will be building in this project.
So now we have to write the pipeline code.
So stage pipeline, go to stage pipeline.
Jenkins file we are to make sure.
From here.
We run the stage.
We have a stage where we build this Docker file and push it to ACR.
Okay.
First, we will be setting up three variables that will be using in our code.
Registry Credential.
App Registry.
V Profile Registry.
These are just variable.
You can give any name, but we will be using this variable in the code down.
So if you give a different variable, make sure you give the same in the code.
So let's fix this one.
Okay.
So I copied the default value from my file.
So registry credential variables.
So the credential scripts that we have added, so it should be in this format you have to say are.
Colon the region.
Name us hyphen east hyphen one.
Which let me check the region code.
Oh, sorry.
It's us.
Hyphen West, hyphen one.
Glad I checked it.
So make sure you give you a right region code.
US West one.
Colon eight scripts.
Now, this is the credential name that we did add in the Jenkins and Jenkins credential.
You see eight scripts, whatever name I did add there.
That will be the value of that.
E.W. Scripps OC, but not the CW.
You have to do it in this format.
ACR Colon Region Code.
Colon The Credential Name Next Variable App Registry.
This is the ACR registry.
Let's go to ACR.
And let's copy this.
Get this.
You are a.
And let's paste it here.
Okay.
So that's kind of like, you know, the name of your repository or Docker image.
So if it's not Docker Hub, right?
If it's not an official image, the image name will be always like this account name, slash the image
name.
And so you see it in that format, right?
That's your account slash image name.
Then we profile registry variable.
Here we are going to give the URL which is like this HTTP, colon, slash, slash and paste to the same
thing that you copy.
Just remove at the end.
Can't you see the difference?
That's the URL of your repository and that's your image name.
Okay.
Oh hey, the maven kept it same as from the previous one.
MV And Q Okay, now these three variables will be using in our codes.
You'll understand how this works.
So let's come down and create a stage to build the Docker Docker image with the Docker file.
Okay.
So I'm going to see stage.
I'll give you a name and test build.
AAP image.
Open and close curly brace.
Steps.
I guess this is how we'll be building it.
There are actually multiple ways we'll be using the script method script.
Open, close, curly brace.
Giving a variable here darker image is equal to and this is where we'll be giving the command.
Now this variable, you'll understand why I have given it in a moment.
This will be used when we push the image.
So we have installed a plugin, docker plugin, dot build.
It has the function build.
Parenthesis and we need to pass here arguments.
One is your image, name, colon image name, colon tag and then part of your Docker file.
So the image name.
You have given a variable here app registry in that one.
Let's copy that.
They're wasted and we need to give a build tag.
So I'm going to use the variable here.
I'm going to concatenate plus.
Double quotes.
Colon.
And let me give a space here and here.
And I'll use the variable build underscore it.
If you remember, we use this variable in continuous integration.
Also not wait, I'm going to use build.
Number two, this will give us the build number, right?
So it will tag the image with this build number whenever we run it.
And then the second argument, comma, is the part of your Docker file.
So our Docker file is here.
Docker.
Hyphen files.
Slash app.
Slash slash.
Multi stage.
Forward slash.
Oh, I need to put that into double quotes.
Okay.
So part of this Docker file I've mentioned over there.
I can give space here.
I would just look for any, you know, syntax error and fix it if you have.
And let's do the next stage, which is going to upload this build image to ACR.
Okay.
I've just typed it, so it's pretty simple.
Upload image steps script, same as it docker dot width registry.
Like here we use docker build here Docker with registry.
You mentioned the registry information.
We profile registry.
That's the variable.
Right.
I did go.
We profile registry.
And that's one argument.
Second argument is registry credentials.
So we pass the credentials and we pass the URL.
So it will log into that registry and then docker image dot push.
This Docker image is this variable.
So it will store all the information over here.
From that you can access the push function, push method and push your Docker image, which was built
here.
And while you are doing that, we are going to give the build number as the tag.
And also tag is latest.
We'll be always deploying the latest tag, but we'll also have version of all the previous images that
was built.
So it's basically the same image with two different tags.
That's all latest and build number.
So validate if everything is good.
Let's just save it then.
And then we will go to this comet and push.
Comet and push.
Let's see.
Docker build and publish to ACR.
Control less check mark there.
It's a new branch.
Would you like to publish this new branch?
Yes.
So already this branch.
Let's go and go to Jenkins.
Okay.
Now we will create a new pipeline.
We will not use this one.
It has the CIA, Jenkins branch.
We will create a new pipeline.
We'll call it as we profile CCD Pipeline Docker.
So click on Pipeline.
Okay.
All right.
GitHub hooked trigger for Git ACM polling.
So next time we make a comment, it triggers the pipeline from ACM pipeline script from Sxm.
ACM is git.
And repository URL.
Let's get the URL.
This is Earl.
Now, we already have the credentials saved here.
In Jenkins.
So we can just select that GitHub login.
Kim Branch.
Make sure you switch the branch to secede.
Hyphen Jenkins.
And the Jenkins file path.
We have removed that path.
We have it in this part stage pipeline slash Jenkins file.
Right.
Secede branch.
Their stage pipeline.
Jenkins file.
Right.
2 minutes ago.
This is what we committed.
Okay.
That's it.
Save.
And Sybil now.
So I'll pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
All right.
That is complete.
It's a success.
You can read the logs.
You can see you see pushing the Docker image.
And let's go to C.R..
All right, refresh this.
Let's click on our image name and you should see there, right, the image tag one and latest one is
the build number.
Right here.
Right.
That build number.
So that it has given as a tag and also it has given us a latest tag.
Right?
So now the ops team can fetch this image and deploy to clusters, Kubernetes cluster or E-Series or
Beanstalk or wherever they want.
But that also next step, we will see how we are going to deploy it on X cluster.
All right.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.