Okay.
So we have built our image and stored it on SDR Elastic Container Registry.
So our image is ready to be deployed, but where are we going to deploy it now?
If you already know Docker, then you must know there are varieties of solutions available out there
where we can run our Docker container.
First of all, just the Docker engine.
We can just install a Docker engine anywhere on a VM, easy to instance, or a physical machine, and
we can deploy our Docker container to this Docker engine so it could be any server.
The other.
The most popular option today is Kubernetes.
And mostly used for production purpose.
We will be seeing about Kubernetes deployment in later projects.
But Kubernetes is itself.
He's an ecosystem and it is supported by many platforms.
You can run Kubernetes standalone.
That means you can create your own VMs or or physical machine and set up a Kubernetes cluster on that,
your own Kubernetes.
Or you can use cloud solutions like X, x elastic Kubernetes service or Azure Kubernetes service or
Google Kubernetes engine OpenShift.
There are actually many.
I'm just showing you a few over here.
The most popular one, but initially for testing purpose.
Before we move to the production environment, we can use this amazing container service.
It was X.
It's pretty simple.
You create the easiest cluster and you create the information of your container and it just runs for
you.
It provides you load balancer also.
Now it is used for production purpose also.
But since Kubernetes has superseded everything in container, well, today.
So most of the people use Kubernetes.
As I said, we'll be talking about Kubernetes deployment later in this project.
We will be using X and now we will take our container image, which is an ACR and deploy it on x cluster.
So first we need to create the easiest cluster.
Okay, so this is what we will be achieving in few lectures.
So developer makes a code change in GitHub.
Which will be fetched by Jenkins.
So we have a pipeline which gets triggered.
So it's going to fetch the code and run the unit test run check steel analysis.
Do code analysis with sonar cube server.
Sorry with sonar cube scanner and upload the result to the cube server.
Check for the quality gate.
Then build the Docker image with our artifact in that and upload it to Amazon ACR.
We have done till here.
Next we will be using X Deploy plugin in our pipeline and deploy our Docker image to Amazon x.
Amazon x will fetch the Docker image from Amazon ACR.
And once this pipeline completes successfully, we'll also see how how do we promote it for the production
environment as well.
So now the next step will be to set up Amazon X cluster.
So let's get into that.
Okay.
So I'm in my console, not California region, which I'm using my Jenkins Nexus Sonar Cube, all are
in North California region.
So make sure you are in the same region where your Jenkins is.
So search for X.
Elastic Continuous Service.
Let's click on that.
So if you have never used e-cigs, don't worry.
It's pretty simple.
But I still recommend you to watch this video and read this to just get a better understanding of what
is X.
But if you just follow me also, that is also fine.
Basically X is to run our docker container.
Simple as that.
So let's click on Get Started.
First thing is we need to create X cluster, so we will be having staging and production environment.
We create the cluster first for staging environment.
So they create cluster.
Let's give Cluster a name.
I've given the staging.
And choose this all the subnets.
Now this gives you a serverless environment with far gate, so you really don't need to create any two
instances.
If you want.
You can use easy two instances as well.
So Amazon X will create a cluster of easy two instance for you, which will be powered by the auto scaling
group.
But I do not recommend it for now.
Forget is simple.
It's cheaper.
It follows the serverless models.
So you don't need to manage any servers, any easy.
Two instances, nothing.
Everything is managed by us.
So let's keep that forget.
In the monitoring, we'll say use container insight.
So when you deploy your Docker container, what are the logs is coming out of that container?
We can see that.
And this is again powered by cloud watch tags.
So let's give a tag.
Name tag.
I will give same pro staging.
Let's create this.
So this will take time to provision your cluster.
So let it complete and then proceed.
I will pause my screen and resume when the cluster creation completes.
My cluster is created.
Let's click on it.
All right.
So here you will see a few section.
You have services which is used to expose your container to the outside world or for inter communication
also.
And it also provides a load balancer.
It also manages your containers.
So it's like.
Auto scaling group for the container that we used.
We see our auto scaling group similar thing, but for containers for easiest container task will be
the containers that will be running like we have easy two instances where we run our services here.
We will be having tasks so we can run tasks directly, but we will be creating task definitions.
So click over here and go to task definitions.
So we'll not directly run our containers.
We will create task definition and service will use this task definition to create the container or
manage the container.
So let's click on create new task definition.
So I will say V Pro App Stage task.
I know the names are getting longer, but if you name it properly, it will be easy for you to identify
your resource and troubleshoot if you get into any problems.
So give proper names container name.
So we'll give container name as well.
Pro App Keep the same as I'm keeping the pro app and here the URL of the registry from where it will
fetch.
So let's go to our ACR registry where we have uploaded.
E.C. are.
Yeah.
So on this ECI, we uploaded our docker image.
We'll mention that same URL here.
Copy that, you or I, and just paste it here.
Container port now withdrew app container or Docker container built on Tomcat runs on port 88.
So specify that Port 88.
Night is all here.
Come down and just go to next.
So app environment will be using a target will keep it as it is.
And one CPU and memory.
Let's see if we can go down.
We can go to GP.
Yeah.
That is the minimum.
We can go here container size.
We'll skip that one, not mention any container size storage will keep optional.
And let's go to tag.
And let's keep this tag as it is.
Let's go to next.
So review whatever you selected for AT&T your you or I you everything memory size.
If you're good just click on create.
This will also take some time.
So I'm going to pause my screen and screen and return when it is completed.
Okay.
So task definition is created.
We have the cluster now, we will be creating the surface.
So let's go to the cluster.
Let's click on a cluster.
So we have task definition and we just created it.
Now we'll create a service which will use that task definition and create tasks or containers for us.
So let's click on deploy here.
In the services, click on deploy.
Let me close this to notification here.
So let's see one by one.
So cap capacity provider strategy will go with launch type.
So we don't want to mention any strategy.
We'll keep it simple.
Just we're saying just forget.
Do what you want.
I'm just giving you my container.
Just run it for me.
It's like that.
So deployment configuration, we are creating a service, so let's stick to that service.
We can directly create task.
Also, you don't if you don't want to use service, you can directly run your containers.
But we will be using service which creates a load balancer also for us.
So let's keep service and let's select the family here.
You will see your task definition.
Select that.
And so with name.
So we'll say repro app stage SVC.
And decide task will keep it one to just run one container and let's come to networking.
Now here we will see create our own security group and we'll give name as super app stage SG.
And a seam in the description.
Make sure you give the description.
Add in bound rule.
Now there's only two options.
The protocol is HTTP.
HTTPS will be selecting A and it automatically selects the port number 80.
We want port 88.
Actually, this is the security group for our task.
So load balancer will route the request to the task and the task or container runs on port 88.
We will be changing this after this is completed, but for now we'll say 80 from anywhere.
Now let's come down.
Load balancing option.
So we need a load balancer.
So we'll say select application load balancer.
Create a new load balancer.
Load balancer name will say be.
The Pro app stage you'll be.
Okay.
Choose container to load balancer.
So Port 88 keep it as it is.
Listener Port 80 This is the port number of the load balancer.
So Load Balancer will listen on port 80 and root the request to the container on Port 8080.
Target group.
DG.
So again, make sure keep the naming convention because we will be creating a production cluster also.
So we should be able to differentiate between the two names.
Protocol HTTP.
So target group will be basically group of containers.
Group of task.
Health check will be slash login for us our v profile application as we have seen previously also when
we deployed IT response on slash login.
So it is going to do the health check at slash login.
Health check.
Grace period.
Late 30 seconds.
Check the health every 30 seconds.
So Target group will check a container.
It will check on the URL slash login and it is going to check every 30 seconds.
If everything is good, the container stays.
But if it is unhealthy, then it will.
The service will delete our container and create a new container.
A port number here.
Make sure it's 80.
Okay.
Now let's deploy.
This will take some time.
And by the time we will do a few changes, Target Group is going to do health check on Port eight.
We have to change it to Port 8080 and we have to also update the security group to listen on Port 88.
So let's go to S.E. to.
Goss target group, security group.
All of these are in D.C., too.
So let's go to S.E. to come down.
Let's go to target groups.
Okay.
So that is our target group you see there.
Click on that.
And let's go to health checks.
There.
Click on edit.
Advanced Health Check.
All right.
Put 80, 80.
Now, this is specific to our profile application, the container license on Port 88.
So we have to make sure the target group also do the health check on Port 88.
So make that change and say, see?
Also we go to the security group.
And we should find a security group here.
There.
That's our security group.
You see that naming?
I've named it properly, so I'm able to easily identify it.
Inbound related.
Inbound Rule.
And we'll add here rule report 8080.
Lessons on any IPv4 and.
E.T., E.T..
Listens on any IPV six.
Again, this is specific to our V profile application, right?
It listens on port 88.
So that's why we need to make these changes save all.
Okay.
Let's go back to X.
So this will also take some time to create.
Let's wait for some time and come back.
Once this is done, I will pause my screen and resume later.
It is, it has been deployed successfully.
So that is all in this lecture.
Join me in the next lecture where we will verify this and then make sure we deploy our container from
Jenkins automatically to our pipeline.
So wrap this up and join me in the next one.