Okay.
So my cluster is good.
My service has created some task.
See, this is the service.
Let's click on that.
You will see it has the load balancer information here in networking.
We'll have the load balancer information load balancer.
And this is this is the URL of the load balancer.
Let's click on this button and you should see.
That our container is running on x cluster.
So it has fetched the image from Amazon ACR and has executed the task which runs out of container.
So let's go back.
So go back to the pro staging cluster in the tasks you should see.
That's our container.
So that task is actually a container.
Click on that.
Okay.
So there's all our container information here.
That's the container name runtime, the URI from where it is fetching the image.
If you click on the logs, you can see the logs of the container answer container log.
All that.
So this is good, but we don't need to do this manually.
We did the setup though manually, but the next deployment, whenever the next image is pushed to the
AECEA will make sure our pipeline deploys that new image to the easiest cluster.
So let's go to Jenkins.
So I shut down my Jenkins all these instances and have powered them on so that IP changed.
First, I will be changing the webhook in GitHub with the new IP.
So I'll go to GitHub.
And go to my repository.
Settings.
And we will go to WebEx.
That's a rare book.
Edit.
Okay.
I need to enter the password.
So I will update that with the new Jenkins IP.
Let me get Jenkins IP.
Okay.
What's the update, Webhook?
Let's go to recent delivery and make a test.
Can we deliver?
Well, that is already done, right?
It was like 0.19 seconds ago.
Anyways, let's deliver it once again and it is successful.
Okay.
So before I move ahead, I will test this pipeline once again.
If this is successful, then we will add the steps in our pipeline to deploy our container to X.
So let's build now.
Okay.
This is all good.
Now, if you remember, we did two things while we were setting up our Jenkins, the post installation
and all.
We installed a few plug ins.
We have set up credentials.
Manage credentials that one E.W. Scripps we have set that which has the access secret key and it has
the policy to access the X cluster and we will need that.
Then also, if you remember, we installed a ClA, we will be using a CLI command in our pipeline to
update our x cluster so it will fetch the latest image.
So what I just did, I just ran the pipeline and I should have the latest image.
And that's a repository.
So it has the image ID with tag two and the latest.
This gets updated every time I run my pipeline, so we need to run an s cli command which will say hey
x, just update the latest image.
So the service is going to inform the task to fetch the latest image and it will redeploy.
So this old container will get deleted.
This container will get deleted in a new container will get created with the latest image.
So let's go to our VTS code.
That's our Jenkins file.
I hope this is the latest code.
In order to verify, I'll open the gate.
Bash.
I'll go to the repository and get pull CDF project get report.
Okay.
That one.
Let's do a.
Pull.
Is to make sure everything is.
It's correct.
This is good.
So everything is in sync so we can add the code and push it back to GitHub before we write the code.
We will add two variables over here which we'll use in our code.
The one I'm giving it as cluster equal to the name of the cluster.
So let's get the name of our cluster.
Okay, so pro staging.
That's the name of a cluster.
Let's copy that.
In double or single code.
Just put it cluster equal to that and we'll use one more variable called service and we'll give the
service name here.
So that is our service name.
You can make sure you copy the service name.
And pasted here.
So these are two variables, cluster and solvers that we'll be using.
Let's go down.
Okay.
Here.
This is the stage to upload the image.
And just after that, we'll create a stage.
Which you will see deploy to x staging.
And obviously open and close curly brace will have all steps.
Now, this will be a shell command.
So it's going to be pretty simple steps.
And but this shell command should execute with the credentials.
So we have to say this.
With his credentials, the credential name and the region.
Now mine is not California, which is US West one, so make sure you give the correct region over here
and open and close curly brace and then the shell command is such in the single code.
Give the click command, which is this.
Okay.
Now it's pretty simple eight plus X Updates so it is telling the service to update hyphen font cluster
the cluster variable that we have set hyphen F in service, the service variable, the service that
we have set and the first new deployments, it's going to forcefully delete the old container and deploy
the new container with the latest image.
It's kind of redeploy, just delete the old one and deploy the newer one.
So when it deploys the newer one, obviously it's going to fetch the latest image for that.
So that's how we are doing the deployment.
So let's test it.
Let's see.
Control less.
And let's see.
Commit and push.
Let's give the commit message.
Deploy to X control less.
That checkmark.
I'll get thinking.
Okay.
That's done.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Okay.
A new build has triggered already.
New pipeline.
So I'll pause my screen and resume when this is completed.
Okay.
One more stage.
They're deployed to X staging that is completed successfully.
Let's look at the logs.
It's come down.
The constructing a credential setting and you see that that is our a plus shell command.
It will see a command sorry and returns a whole lot of JSON information about your clusters, x servers,
task and everything.
All the information.
Let's go to x.
And let's see what has really happened.
So you see something here?
Two by one.
Let's go to tasks.
Okay.
So the old one is still there.
It's 21 minutes old and this one is 12 seconds old.
This is the latest one and the task is still in the pending state is not yet completed.
So it's going to take some time.
To do the complete setup, complete deployment.
So let's go to VS Code.
Okay.
So this is the source code right now.
Whenever a developer makes any change to their code, this entire pipeline you see gets triggered and
completes.
Once it is deployed, then the other test can be executed.
The software testers can test it if everything is good.
The Cuban approval, then we can deploy it to the production environment.
Now deploying to production environment will keep it similar.
It will be similar, but except we will talk about the real time way of doing the deployment, how staging
and production pipelines are separate and when the production gets triggered or how it should get triggered.
That will see in the next lecture.
By the time you run the build a few more times, test your pipeline, wrap this up and join me in the
next lecture.
We'll talk about production deployment there.