In this lecture, we will see how to promote this to production environment.
Now for production environment, we'll create a separate production X cluster.
So let's do that first.
We'll create a new cluster.
We will also create a new Jenkins pipeline for production environment.
And then we will see how staging and production pipelines are connected.
Or maybe they are not connected.
We'll find that out.
Okay.
So let's go to clusters.
And let's create a production cluster which will be similar to this.
I just name it as the real prod.
We'll keep.
Seems certain.
VPC Forget and we'll just say create.
Okay.
My cluster is created.
Let's click on that and I will create a new task definition.
For the production.
Create new task definition.
Similar information.
The prod task, I will say.
Container name Vpro app.
And the same UI which we used in staging.
Now we would like to promote the same image and not a different image.
So we'll give the same image.
You all container port 8080.
Just come down and let's go next.
Forget will keep it as it is.
Memory will reduce to two GB again.
It's come down.
And let's go next.
You everything and they create.
Your task definition created to close this notification, let's go to the cluster service clusters.
Prod.
And so this will say deploy.
Will they launch type?
He forget service.
Family.
Let's select our task definition.
So his name.
The Pro app prod cc.
Networking.
Will they create new security group?
We'll give security group a name.
Again.
Make sure you add the prod.
So we will be editing the security group.
So you should be able to identify with its name.
Load balancer option.
Load Balancer.
Type Application Load Balancer.
Create new load balancer.
It's come down.
Target group name.
Should a college GDP.
Health check pot slash login.
A grace period.
30 seconds.
This is just similar as we created for staging.
Except the name is different.
In real time.
Also this will be similar, except you will be having more GB to your container's multiple containers.
But we want to keep things under three tier or very minimum on billing so we're creating similar to
staging.
So in real time also it will be similar to staging, except it will be bigger in size.
All right, let's go deploy.
Yeah.
It's not working, obviously.
Security group.
I did not add any rule whatsoever.
So I need to see add rule to DPI and we'll see just from anywhere.
And then we'll click on deploy.
Yeah.
Now that works.
Okay.
That is going to take some time by the time.
Let's go to our voice code or our code and write a new pipeline for production.
First I'm in my git batch, I'm in the repository, I'll get repository.
That's where I have my repository and I'm going to create a new branch here.
Git checkout, hyphen b prod.
Now this will be a separate branch in real time.
Also, you'll have a separate branch for production.
Its name could be prod or main or master.
It could be anything.
The name that I'm giving is so you can understand and identify that this is for the production purpose.
But the name of the branch could be anything.
So I'm saying git checkout, hyphen b prod.
It's going to create a new branch from the CSA Jenkins branch.
All right.
And the Jenkins file we will be using will be from the pipeline directory.
So let's open the VTS code.
Margaret, you also need to push this new branch.
Now we can do it from VTS code also.
So if we go to.
So source control.
It's already saying, you know, this is the broad branch, right.
That is saying you should publish this branch, let's publish it.
So this goes to GitHub.
Okay.
You're going to GitHub.
Let's go to a repository and you see that it is broad that has a recent push there.
So we have the broad branch on GitHub also.
Now again going back to voice code.
All right.
So we are not going to use the stage pipeline Jenkins file.
We will be using the prod pipeline.
Jenkins file.
Now, this code, this pipeline code will be pretty simple.
We are not going to build and push our image.
We'll be just deploying it to production easiest cluster.
So we need to clean most of the things here and I will just replace it simply so you can clean that
extra stage.
So here this is the same slack function color map environment variable.
Actually we don't even need these one.
Not pushing an image from here.
If you're pulling in, you're pushing an image from here, then you can mention them.
Stage will be deployed to prod x.
And exactly same step.
So the cluster variable value you to make sure you give this cluster variable in value should be your
production cluster name.
Let me just verify that once again for you.
Yes.
Clusters.
The probe prod.
So, yeah, I need to change that.
Huh?
There.
And the service variable.
Let's check that also.
Let me just copy that.
I think it's the same.
Anyways, this boosted once again, okay, these two variables and then the same thing.
What we did for staging except here the cluster name is the production cluster name and the service
is the production service and then of course the slack notification.
That is it.
That's all.
Just save it.
All right.
And then let's push it.
Commit and push.
So there is no pipeline yet on Jenkins will create a pipeline also for this one.
Let's just push it first and see prod x pipeline.
Control less.
That Mark.
Thinking changes.
Okay.
That worked.
Now let's go to Jenkins and create a new pipeline.
For production, which will be similar to this one.
So it's a new item.
Wait.
Just copy the name from here first.
New item and I will see here Docker secede prod pipeline.
I would select here pipeline and I will say copy from.
Not one.
So simply replicate, right?
Clone the job and we'll change few things there.
So it's actually clone that is checked but.
And the branch was we need to change to prod.
John.
And that directory fraud pipeline directory we have in that.
Look just confirmed that you will name once again.
Proud pipeline.
P capital.
Yeah.
In that we have the Jenkins file.
Save.
I think it's just a matter of testing.
Now, before that, let's go to X.
So let's try it.
One.
Okay.
Deployment current state to field.
Now we know what is happening here.
We did not make the target group health check change and we did not make the security group change for
production.
We did for staging.
Right.
So if we see, let's go back to your.
Great task.
See the task.
So what really is happening is it's trying to access that container, do the health check on the container
since the target group health check is wrong.
The container declares as unhealthy, and then it deletes that container.
Then it launches a new container.
Then that also goes unhealthy.
And this goes on and on.
So let's go to back to Target Group.
Well easy to target group you should find here.
Broad target group.
Go to the health check.
Edit.
Okay.
Traffic.
All right.
We need to change the port number here to 80.
80.
Yeah.
Not one thing.
So you change.
And then the security group.
Broad.
So security group inbound rule edit.
Look right there, idiot.
From any IPV four and.
88 from any IPV six.
Steve this.
Seem what we did for staging, but in staging we did it.
As soon as we created the cluster in production, we just let it run.
Now this will work and sometime this will get stable in some time.
All these tasks are stopped.
But this task that is running now, it will be healthy and it will keep that task or the container.
Okay.
So wait for a few minutes, make sure it is stable, then test your pipeline.
So I'm going to pause my screen and resume after 5 minutes.
Okay.
Now it's time to test this production pipeline.
So I'm going to click on Build and now on this broad pipeline.
And we'll see what happens.
Okay.
My pipeline failed.
Let's look at the log.
And edit awkward cluster not found.
Well, the cluster name is right, but the region I have mentioned is wrong.
So I will change the region to us.
West one where my cluster is just one.
Save it.
Comment and push.
Updated correct region code controllers for check mark.
That should trigger the pipeline automatically.
All right.
We have Web hooks.
So let's go back.
Let's see this.
Yeah.
It triggered.
Let's look at the logs.
Oh, it's already done.
Okay.
Nice.
Let's let's check the X.
Prod.
Okay.
All right.
Tasks.
There's already two task.
The main task.
But two tasks are running.
So.
That one 4 minutes ago.
Now, this will go out of service in some time.
The newer one will be there if you see that the old task is taking time to go away.
It is probably you have opened the up load balancer.
You are there is a connection, so it's trying to drain the request.
If the request is completely drained, all the requests are coming to that container, then only it
will delete that container, that task.
So make sure you close all the tabs where you have opened the load balancer you are.
Okay, so this is it over here.
In the next lecture, we will see a proper process of how the pipeline runs, returns result, and then
how do we promote it to production?
The actual process I'm talking about.
Otherwise, your pipeline, both the pipelines are set.
They're working fine.
We'll just see how the real process is in the real time.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.