All right, so let's wrap this project now.
The only thing I need to show you the process from end to end.
So get check out secede hyphen Jenkins.
That's the branch so assume developers are making changes to the source code will not make change to
the actual java code will just open this read me file or we can do it from VTS code also.
So forced to switch to the cursed Jenkins branch.
Make sure you're switched and we'll just edit the MD file just to so you don't want to mess with the
Java code.
So just I'll just add here some hash control less.
All right, so, developer, we like that.
Make the code change.
And then they will publish their change to the GitHub.
Of course they'll be doing a test locally, but once they're done testing locally, they will push it
to the repository.
It's a test secede.
One some message, obviously, that they'll give more meaningful message and push it.
So once this changes are published on GitHub, our pipeline will get automatically triggered.
Right.
Staging pipeline that one night it will get automatically triggered.
It's it's it's running so it's going to build it do the code analysis do all the kinds of code testing,
upload the artifact, which is the Docker image to the repository if everything is good.
And then it will deploy to the staging environment after the staging environment deployment completes.
The people who are responsible, the quality assurance team.
Q Way or software testers.
Will test the application.
So there will be some kind of authority like that in the organization who will be in charge of.
Making sure all the changes are good.
They'll test it.
If this gives you the you the approval that everything is good, then you can promote it to the production
environment.
Now, how do we put up promote it to production environment?
We can just go and just click the pipeline, but it will be done like this.
The code, the production.
We come here?
Yeah.
So this is the staging code, right?
Get check out.
Prod.
So the staging code will be merged with the production code because all the code needs to be similar.
Right.
All the branches.
So get.
Merge CI cd hyphen Jenkins.
And this will be done after the approval or the authority will do it themselves, right?
They will do it once they verify all your code is good, they're going to merge it to the production
branch.
Once they merge into the production branch or you merge into production branch, our production pipeline
will also get triggered.
Oh, my bad.
I did not push it to get up, right?
Yeah, my bad.
So I just did it locally.
I also need to make sure I push it.
It's saying sync to changes or you can just run the git push command also or you can do it from voice
code.
Also.
Let me do it from.
The is from good Bashir so.
So changes are done.
So I get add sorry get push origin prod.
Okay there.
As soon as the changes goes to the production branch, our pipeline.
Production pipeline should get triggered there.
See that got triggered completes.
The deployment completes.
Maybe there are a few.
I'm sorry, there are a few more test smoke tests.
Sanity tests.
Sanity test will be conducted and then the user request can be diverted to production environment.
Now this process that I'm showing is a very general process.
There will be definitely some.
Differences when you merge will create a pull request on GitHub.
That pull request will be approved.
Then when it is approved, then the pipeline gets triggered.
All the software testers will be involved.
So these what I'm showing you is very general process.
There will be, of course, some changes, some differences, but overall it will be something like
this.
Different organization may follow different strategy.
They have different way of publishing.
They have different types of application.
Their business model is different.
So based on that, the strategy will change.
But more or less it will be like this deployed to staging environment.
Make a test, everything is good, then promote it to the production environment.
So you go ahead, do this process a few more times.
Make sure you grasp this concept.
Understanding the process is more important than writing the code because code is available everywhere
on Google, you can just find and just make the change and understand the process so you can talk about
it in front of the client in the interview.
All right.
So before you wrap, make sure you do some test, make some changes.
And once you are done, then make sure you shut down.
Boardof Jenkins owner Cuban Nexus do don't delete them.
We will need them in the next few other projects.
So just shut them down.
Stop it.
I'm going to stop them.
Stop.
You can delete the easiest cluster if you want.
You know how to create it whenever you want.
You can create it.
But to delete the cluster you need to force to delete the service.
Delete the servers, it will delete the task and then you can delete the cluster.
All right.
So that is all in this lecture.
I will see you in the next one.