We're going to talk about now how to take data backup of CD Stack Jenkins Nexus and Sonar Cube.
So if you have the backup of all the data that we have created, then we can safely delete our instances
and recover our data.
Whenever you want, whenever you want, we can recreate these instances and restore all the data that
we have taken the backup of.
Now, that is one reason of taking data backup of CD stack.
The other reason is we are going to use this backup in our cloud formation project, in cloud formation
project.
We will automatically set up the entire CD stack and restore all our data.
I will also show you how you can then restore your entire CD stack.
Okay, let's see the steps that we are going to take to do this entire backup.
So we need an S3 bucket, so we're going to create an S3 bucket.
You're to create.
I am role with SE three access and we're going to attach this role to all our instances.
Jenkins Nexus Ownership Server.
And if you are in continuous delivery projects and you have a Tomcat setter on an easy two instance,
then you have to attach this role to Tomcat Server also because you're also going to copy two configuration
files to S3 bucket.
Then we log into Jenkins instance.
We're going to shut down the Jenkins service.
We're going to clean up all unnecessary data.
Jenkins Home Directory will be huge in size and there'll be some unnecessary data like workspace, which
you really don't need to take backup, which can be generated any time you run the job.
So we'll clean such data.
Then we'll archive our Lib Jenkins directory.
We're going to use Star Command, so we'll create a tarball.
Will install a clean Jenkins.
And we'll copy the Jenkins archive to the S3 bucket that we created in the first step.
Similar way we log into the Nexus server.
We shut down the Nexus service, will archive OPPT Nexus Directory and this directory we have installed
Nexus in our project.
We're going to install a blue sky in Nexis.
Will copy Nexis archive to the same S3 bucket.
So the same S3 bucket will copy all the data.
Then we log into Sonar Cube Server.
And here we have actually two things to take back up.
So we'll first shut down this owner service will archive's OPPT Sonar Cube Directory where we have installed
on our cube server.
We are also going to archive our PostgreSQL directory.
We're going to install a blue sky and we'll copy sonar cube and Postgres Kill Archive to the same S3
bucket.
So then keep note of the S3 bucket that you have created and also the archive file names, because we
are going to use them into our cloud formation project.
And in any case, you want to recover, restore your stack, you can use this archive to restore your
data.
I'm in my management console and I have these many instances.
I have a Nexus server.
So in the server, Jenkins instance, if you're in continuous integration project, then you'll only
have these three instances.
If you're in continuous delivery project, you should be having database Windows Server and application
server Tomcat.
We're going to take backup of Nexus.
So Owner Server Jenkins and also a few configuration file from our Tomcat server.
We're not going to take any backup of DB and Windows Test Server.
So let's see the Jenkins first.
Also keep in mind the password that you have set, because when we restore, we'll be having the same
set up.
Exactly.
So you need to log in with your same username and password.
So currently I'm in this state.
I have few jobs and I have a lot of plug ins installed.
If I happen to delete this Jenkins instance, I have to recreate it, which is easy to do.
Setting up Jenkins service is no big deal, but then we have to set up all these jobs and install all
the plug ins to come to this level.
If you're thinking taking off AMA, you can do that, you know AMA of this instance and storing it.
But then we have multiple instances and you may end up paying some money for the EBS volume if you're
keeping it for a long time.
Okay.
First thing first, let's create an S3 bucket.
I don't try to create the bucket with the same name as three.
Bucket names are unique, so you have to find your own names.
I Mm.
V Profile.
Hyphen cic hyphen stack.
Hyphen backup.
I'm creating an Ohio region, so choose a region that you usually use.
So the data copy and data backup restore will be faster, but it really doesn't matter where they are.
We can still backup and restore from bucket in any region.
I hope that's my unique name and I have not used that name.
Let's try create bucket.
So I created a bucket with this name.
Now I'm going to create an I am role.
Go to rules.
Create role for easy to instance.
Next.
Policy so you can create policy.
To give access only to that S3 bucket.
Are much easier.
You can just say three full access policy, but then that will give access to all the S3 bucket.
If you are the only user of this account, then that is fine.
But if you are sharing with someone, then that could be a problem.
You have given some name to it.
Let's create role.
We profile CDs three full access.
Okay.
I will attach this role to all the instances.
Starting with sonar.
Sorry, Nexus.
Instance setting.
Modify em roll.
We profile CCD as three full access.
See.
Like that do for all the instances.
Give the stream roll to every instance.
Also, if you're in continuous delivery project, you'll have the application server give.
I am role access to this instance as well.
If you are in continuous integration project now, then this much is fine.
Okay.
So I log into Foss Jenkins instance.
Let's take backup of Jenkins first copy address.
So login to your Jenkins instance.
Switch to route user reset.
Stop.
Stop drinking service.
Yeah.
Let's go to var lib.
Okay.
You should see the Jenkins directory.
Let's see.
It's size.
Currently it's 428 and by year could be bigger because I have already cleaned some data.
But I'll show you how to clean the data.
Okay.
Let's do the cleanup of unnecessary files that we anyways get generated when you run the jobs first.
The repository.
Okay.
Dot m2 directory in lib jenkins dot m2.
You will see a directory called repository.
You can just delete that directory or you can just delete data from here.
Okay, because whenever we run the build job, it's going to increase, download the dependency and
keep it locally.
So we don't need this when we restore.
Okay.
Other data is workspace.
Workspace.
You will see the job in the directory name with the job names.
You can delete all this directory or you can get into this directory and delete the data.
Be careful what you're deleting.
RMF an RF star is a dangerous command, so be careful with that.
My recommendation you get into the directories and delete the data instead of deleting whole thing.
That's going to take a little while, but it's just one time backup.
Once you have the backup, then any time you can restore.
So we deleted dot MX to repository, we deleted the workspace.
Now one more thing is there if you are archiving your artifact.
Then you should have in jobs, you should have like for example, in build project job in the bills.
I should have this you should have this number one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight,
nine.
A number of times you ran the job whenever you said archive artifact.
You will create an archive over here like in this directory number name ten.
You have the archive.
So you see that there is an artifact over there, right?
What you can do is you can just delete these numbers.
The directory with the numbers, you can just delete them one, ten and nine and a half.
You may have different, different numbers.
So just delete those directories.
If you have if you're doing archive in other jobs, also, you should have these number directories
in other workspaces also in this jobs directory.
So what you can do?
You can run the hyphen search.
You can see the size of your current directory.
You can say Do hyphen search star.
And I will show you the size of all the directory.
It's in CVS and me b so doesn't matter if you have like larger mobs.
Get into that and biz or GBS, get into that directory, find the number of directories and just delete
them because they will get generated anyways.
Okay.
So we deleted three things.
Dart aim to repository workspaces and in the jobs directory.
We have again workspace directories and this we have deleted directories with build number.
Now your Ratliff Jenkins size should be smaller if you run.
Do you have an asset in Radley Jenkins?
You will see something around 500 and be if you're seeing more, find out unnecessary things and delete
them.
Do not delete plugins.
We need those plugins.
Okay.
Now it's time to archive this.
We're going to say cha hyphen C, Z, V, F, and I'm going to name this as Jenkins.
Underscore.
CI cd jobs dot dot dot gz.
You can keep the same name.
It will be helpful in the cloud formation project, but if you have given different name, it's jobs.
S But if you're given a different name, no problem in cloud formation project will change the name.
You can change the name of the archives.
That should be fine, but note down the names.
So let's archive this.
Okay.
Now you have some dots on our cashier directory.
We could have cleaned that also, but that is fine.
This much size is fine.
We should have now.
The ball.
Let's check its size to you.
High as such.
Okay.
That's reduced.
If even if it's big size.
Okay, don't worry.
We're going to put it on S3 bucket.
It will be copied very quickly over there.
If you want, you can download it and keeping your local machine also.
Okay, now let's run a SE three step or if we have to install it publicly.
I already have it installed but still I'll show you apt install a c.
Okay.
We have a IWC ally.
Now it's time to copy your data.
ewss3cp.
We're going to copy or jenkins if the tab does not work over here, i have to copy the file name.
Okay.
E w s.
s3cp.
And the bucket name is three colons slash slash.
So let me get the bucket name.
That's my bucket name.
They copy the name.
Don't create any subdirectories just in the bucket itself.
So they started copying.
You see, it's 348 and B and yeah, I didn't even complete my sentence and it has copied.
So as I told you, don't worry about the size even if you're not able to clean, clear or clean the
directories, that is also fine.
Okay, so one backup taken.
Let's see.
Good job.
Okay.
Let's do the same for the other other instances.
Now let's go to.
No nexus.
If you understood what you had to do, you can, you know, keep doing it.
Or if you still want to see, you can keep watching the video.
That is sent to a user.
It.
You should see an Excel directory in OPPT.
First, let's stop the Nexis service.
Okay.
Let's take it's archive cha hyphen c z vf.
Next is hyphen hyphen v pro hyphen pro dot GZ.
That's the name I have given.
Again, you can use the same name or you can use different name.
OC Archive taken a B+ 3cp.
I Strickland slash slash.
Same bucket name.
Done.
That was Foster.
Okay.
Let's log out from here.
If you want to continue and you know, with your stack, you can just start the Nexis and Jenkins service.
If you're done, you know, let it be.
Stop it.
Anyways, taking the backup, we can recover later.
So on the server.
Okay.
Here we have two things to back up.
One is Sona Ncube directory and then it's PostgreSQL.
Let's stop the sonar service first.
Oh, sorry.
Its name is Soner Kub.
You.
Let's go to OPPT.
Okay.
Let's take it back up.
So in the cube hyphen V pro hyphen pro hyphen data z as the name I have given.
Back up, Deacon.
Let's copy it.
SE three cp.
P tarball and oc done also.
If you wish, you can start the ownership service.
But if you're done, just log out.
All right.
If you're in continuous integration project, this is done.
If you're in continuous delivery project, then.
We only have one more server.
We're not going to take the data backup, but configuration file backup.
Which will be again using a cloud formation project.
If logging into the Tomcat server.
Get into your Tomcat home directory.
Yes.
Local Tomcat eight, I suppose.
Yeah.
In the contradictory, you should have tomcat hyphen users dot xml that file.
We are going to copy it to our S3 bucket.
Same name.
We don't need to change it.
Okay.
That's done.
Now in web apps, you should have a manager directory in that you have to have an INF.
Okay.
There you should see context xml e plus 3cp copy this file.
Copied to the S3 bucket.
All right.
Okay.
Let's check our S3 bucket.
aws3 ls.
All right, once you're done, you should have Jenkins CD Jumpstart GZ Nexus Hyphen CD Hyphen V Pro
Hyphen Pro dot z so in Q hyphen V Pro hyphen pro dot pro hyphen data mktg z, tomcat users dot xml and
context xml.
You should have this in your S3 bucket.
No down the name.
No down the name of the S3 bucket.
We'll be using this in cloud formation project.
Okay, one quick way, a sample to how to restore manually this data.
Let's take example of Jenkins.
Okay.
So I'm going to launch an issue to instance.
I'd say first, let me just shut down all this instant state.
Stop.
I don't need it now, so I'm going to shut them down.
Okay.
I'm going to set up a Jenkins server now, so.
One two server 20 should be fine.
Due to micro.
Okay.
I'm going to set up the Jenkins service from user data.
So I have to say sudo apt update.
To make sure to give the best part.
Sudo apt install open JDK hyphen eight hyphen JDK f and y solo.
APT install maven and whatever you need and just put it out there.
It should be fine.
And then Jenkins installation steps.
So the Jenkins installation documentation.
From there, I'm just copying this thing.
Commands.
Okay.
This will not work out.
We have to echo and put this into the file.
Okay.
So I'm saying sudo hyphen c ico.
And redirected to this file.
And finally sudo apt update and then sudo apt install jenkins.
Right now we know this is a fresh instances.
You'll be fresh jenkins up.
No jobs, no plugins, nothing.
Right.
This is fine now, but we'll see how we can restore from our data.
Restore.
Just give some name, restore, hyphen Jenkins.
Configure Security group.
I'm going to use some existing security group, genuine security group.
Launch, and I'll use a key that I already have.
Okay.
We wait for a few minutes.
We'll wait until this is entirely set up, and then we'll log in and we'll restore the data.
Now it's few minutes.
Now I will check whether the Jenkins service is up or not.
Okay.
Seems it's responding.
Jenkins is up and we have to do the post installation step.
It's a fresh set up and then you can have to set up all the jobs and install all the plug ins and stuff.
We already have the backups, so we're going to restore from that backup.
So we'll log into this Jenkins instance.
It's copy type.
Okay.
So be the root user.
First thing you're going to do is you're going to stop the Jenkins service here so it doesn't interfere
with our restore process.
Let's go to wire lib.
Okay.
Ellis hyphen ld.
You should have the Jenkins directory.
Okay.
Also note down the ownership of this.
This is Jenkins user.
Once we restore this, ownership may change.
So you have to make sure you give this ownership back to this directory.
Okay, now we have a backup on the S3 bucket and we want to download it to our instance.
So I'm going to attach a role so it can authenticate.
I'm going to use the same role v profile.
The time of restoration.
If you're not seeing this at all, create another rule.
Simple.
Okay.
So that's the S3 bucket.
Yeah.
That's copy its name.
Let's go back to our Jenkins.
So I'm going to say a s se three cb se three colon slash slash the bucket name.
Oops.
Bucket name slash.
And the final name.
That one.
Yeah.
I can copy it from there.
Copy.
Okay.
And I'm going to say dot, so download it in this VAT lib directory.
Now I have to install a silly app.
Install a silly.
Okay.
Localize.
Install.
Now I can run the command plus three.
Copy here.
Done.
Okay.
Now simply I'm going to say da x z v f extracted.
That's it.
It's going to override the files that you already have in Jenkins.
You did a Jenkins installation so that already Jenkins files.
It's gone.
All right.
A lot of files.
Check the permission.
If it's not good, just give Jenkins.
Jenkins.
But if you take a backup.
Well, you know, tarball you're doing right.
We are archiving so it's going to preserve the permissions and all.
But it's a good idea anyways.
Recursively.
So all the files are Jenkins permission.
Now, let's start.
Jenkins service system say it'll start.
JENKINS That's going to load.
JENKINS With the data in the Jenkins directory and this is the data from previous.
Jenkins setup.
Right.
Let's see that.
It's going to take a moment to come up.
Said Enter.
Okay.
Now login page.
Right.
So I remember the username and password that I have given.
Again.
And voila.
Back from where we started.
Right now, I know you can take a backup.
You can take my of the instance, but then you have to pay for the storage cost.
But in any case, do this backup process because we need this in cloud formation project.
Okay.
Now there will be in the jobs, there'll be all types of Nexus sonar, all tokens.
So you have to change all those things change the old IP right now, give the new IP in the jobs in
the next job and so on or cube job tokens.
Right.
All those things you have to change.
Right?
Then you can run the pipeline.
All right.
That's that's all in this video.
Thank you very much for watching.
Now you can continue with other videos.