Hello and welcome to the next project in our DevOps project CDs.
The name of this project is Continuous Delivery with Jenkins and Ansible.
So in this project we're going to combine the power of Jenkins continuous integration server with Ansible,
which is a configuration management tool or in general and automation tool.
Okay.
So this is the scenario.
Let's say there is an agile software development team and they're doing a continuous development of
the product.
So they're going to make continuous code changes.
This code this code needs to be packaged and needs to be deployed to servers for testing.
If the process is continuous, if the continuous code commit, we need to continuously deploy artifact
to servers for testing.
If all the test checks out, fine, then we can finally deploy to production.
So after the deployment, the software testing and other kinds of testings will be conducted.
And the test reports will be evaluated and approval will be given to promote it to production or not.
And this is going to be a process of deployment test, deploy test because you'll be having different
environments.
Dev.
Q Uid production staging.
So if you have like these multiple environments before you, when you deploy the production, then you
will understand there is continuous deployment.
If there is continuous code commit.
When there is continuous deployment, there's also continuous dependency on the operations team.
So different different teams will be there or different different product owners from different projects
will be dependent on ops team for the regular deployments and every project will have dev QA staging
production multiple environments.
So there'll be continuous deployment requests that will be sent to the operations team.
So this is the scenario.
Let's see the problem.
If the code deployment process is manual, it's going to take a lot of time to promote your changes
to production because there are multiple environments where the deployment needs to be done.
If it's manual, then it's going to take a lot of time.
It doesn't matter how fast you make the code change.
Still, the deployment will be slow.
And in this process of deployment, there will be ticketing systems, there'll be approvals assignments,
there will be different owners for different environments.
Developer owns the dev environment, queue owns the queue environments.
The software testers and productions are owned by different team monitoring team site reliability engineers.
So there'll be too many ticketing assignments and approvals going here and there, which actually is
a bit problematic in an agile process.
So too much dependencies on operations and build and release team for the deployment.
So the solution will be to first set continuous integration process and continuous delivery process.
So for every code comment, build, test, deploy, then test.
Now this happens for every commit and the deployment process should be automated.
So deployment on different, different environments and different environments have different owners.
So you can also notify them if something fails or passes successfully, like developer gets notification,
software testers gets notification.
So there'll be multiple teams.
And also.
There'll be multiple tools you need to integrate all the tools, all the automation tools together.
So continuous integration tool, integrated with repositories, integrated with automation tools, with
configuration management tools.
So when you do these integrations, it will remove human intervention.
Because just writing a script to automate a task is just not enough.
So let's say you done.
You deployed the artifact to the server.
Then you need to communicate this to software testing team.
They'll conduct their software test execution.
And there will be, again in this process also to get assignments and feedback and approvals.
So in order to get over from this problem, you need to integrate tools together.
And whenever there is a problem bug in the code or in the deployment process, you the process automatically
stops and you fix the problem.
And then the process repeats again.
And this entire automated process is called us continuous delivery process.
And in continuous delivery, try to integrate all the tools that that are used in the release management
process.
So in this project we are going to see varieties of tools integrated together.
So let's see the list of the tools now.
All right, let's see the tools that we will be using in this project.
Jenkins as our continuous integration server and access sonar type repository to download Maven dependency
and to upload our artifact to it.
So in our cube server for code analysis.
Maven to build our artifact git as a version control system where we'll also place our Ansible code.
Slack for notification.
It is easy to instance we will use on which we will be running Tomcat Server and Ansible, which is
going to deploy our artifact to Tomcat server.
So Ansible will download artifact from the access repository and deploy to Tomcat server.
While doing this project, keep our objective on our mind.
We have to do deployment automation.
So complete end to end automation of delivery.
So if anything happens, we can even repair things very quickly.
If something breaks, we can isolate, we can find the problem, right?
Team gets the notification in the meantime to repair is really really becomes short here.
When you have complete automated.
Release cycle.
Then any request that comes from the user, any code change, any bug fix, anything can be done very
quickly.
So developer makes a code change automatically the entire pipeline triggers and do the complete delivery
and testing right and no human intervention.
So nobody gets in or not many people get involved while the process is happening.
So it's going to be less disruptive.
All right, let's achieve this goal.
But before we do that, we are going to see the architecture of continuous delivery pipeline.
Okay.
So developers are going to make regular code changes as we're talking in an agile development process
and they make the code change the commit to the local git repository and then that will be sync with
a remote repository.
So we are going to use GitHub.
Our source code is in GitHub.
So whenever the new code is changed, whenever there's a comment on GitHub, Jenkins will detect that
automatically and fetch all the changes.
And then it's going to do code test, it's going to do unit test.
And whether it based on whether it's passed or fail, the notification will be sent.
If it passes, it goes to the next level.
The next level we'll have code analysis.
So we are going to use a check style and so on our cube scanner.
These tools are going to scan the code and a report will be generated and will be uploaded to Sonar
Cube's server.
So that Cube server will compare it with its quality gates.
If you pass the quality gate.
The job continues, the next job gets triggered.
If it's fail, then a note fail notification will be sent and the pipeline stops.
But if it's a success, it goes to the next level where Maven again is going to build the software.
This time, Maven is going to build the software in code testing.
Maven is going to do unit test here.
Maven is going to build the artifact and when it builds the artifact, it needs some dependency.
Those dependencies will be downloaded from Nexus repository.
So on Nexus, we're going to create Maven repository, maven central repository.
So all the dependency will be downloaded.
When the build process is happening.
If this fails, failure notification is sent pipeline's stop.
But if this passes, the packaging of the artifact will be done and the artifact will be uploaded to
Nexus repository.
So now you'll have a versioned artifact gone through unit test and code analysis.
If this is all good.
Then our Ansible will get kicked in.
The job of Ansible will be to deploy the artifact, download the artifact from Nexus and deploy to staging
server.
And while Ansible is doing that, it will also make sure the right packages are installed, the right
services are running, the configurations are correct.
So we can also make sure this all this happens along with the deployment process.
Also, one more thing while the deployment is happening and something fails, Ansible will put an intel.
It will put the kind of intelligence that it can roll back to the previous state.
So also we can do auto rollback and yes, so all that things we can do with Ansible.
That's why doing deployment with Ansible will be much more convenient.
So once Ansible is done by checking everything and deploying to the staging server, then our software
test suit can get executed and do the software testing on the staging environment.
They have a staging at all the environments and then if we get the approval, then we can use Ansible
to deploy the artifact to production server as well.
And this can be automatic without approval.
It's pre-approved or it can be with approval also.
In any case, you have a complete automated pipeline.
Flow of execution, the steps that we will take to complete this project.
So you must be already having a Jenkins server, which you must have stopped.
And when you power on, you get a new Jenkins IP.
We need to update that new IP in the GitHub webhook.
We might also need to resize Jenkins volume.
Now it is pretty simple to resize the Jenkins volume, and the reason we will be doing is Jenkins volume.
Easy two instance has just a GB and it is now almost full or it's already full.
So we need to increase its size so Jenkins can store more data.
Next, we will launch an easy two instance where we'll deploy our our artifact.
This is easy, to instance, will be running Tomcat service, which we will again set up with Ansible
automatically.
And this will be our app zero one staging.
Few Jenkins prerequisites.
We need to install Ansible in Jenkins.
We need to install Ansible plugin.
We will save AB zero one such login credentials in Jenkins.
Now Jenkins will run Ansible playbook.
Ansible will do a search to the app zero one staging and to do that says we need to save its search
credential in the Jenkins.
Time stamp a variable we will check and will make sure it is correct as per our need.
This is to version our artifact.
We will create a separate branch in our GitHub repository where we'll put our Ansible code.
And also we need to copy the Ansible code from the Vpro file project repository to our own repository.
So I prepared the Ansible code.
I have kept it in the profile project GitHub repository.
We just need to download it and copy it in our own repository.
We'll create a DNS record in Route 53 for App zero one staging.
So we will not use App zero one staging IP, private IP.
We will be using its name and that name will be stored in the DNS of Route 53.
And you will understand why we will do that.
We need to create inventory file in the ANSIBLE code.
This inventory file will contain the app zero one staging server name and the group name where we need
to do the deployment.
We need to update some security group rules.
We need to allow 22 in app security group from Jenkins.
So Jenkins will do ansible search.
So Ansible will do search two app zero one staging server.
So we need to allow Port 22 from Jenkins Security Group.
I know this is too much for now, but once we start doing it, things will get more clear.
These steps, it gives you a roadmap, right?
Whenever you are in the middle, you want to know where we are, what we are doing currently.
So you can check these steps anytime you want.
We need to also allow Port 88 even from Nexus Security in Nexus Security Group from App Security Group.
So Tomcat Application Server App zero one staging will download artifacts from Nexus.
So we need to allow Port 88 one in the next security group.
So observes app server can download artifact from that.
After all those things are ready, we will write a Jenkins file or we will update our Jenkins file to
run our Ansible playbook from Jenkins to basically prepare the Jenkins file code to run Ansible playbook,
and we'll create a pipeline in Jenkins.
Run this Jenkins file and test it.
This is for a staging environment.
Once we test the staging pipeline, we will do the same thing for production.
We'll update the Ansible Ansible code in production branch.
Then similar step is staging will launch your app zero one for instance will update the DNS record in
Route 53 will create an inventory file for it.
This is same as we did for staging.
Again, we'll create a pipeline.
Ford.
This will be for production.
Create a pipeline in Jenkins and test it.
And then we will see how we are going to promote changes to production by doing the merge.
I know there are too many steps.
Once again, this is a roadmap.
Which we are going to follow in this project.
Whenever you are wondering where you are.
You can always come back and check all these steps.
Okay, then let's get down to business.
So take a look once again and join me in the next lecture.