Okay.
Welcome.
In this lecture, we will be doing multiple things.
First, we will increase the Jenkins of volume size.
Second, we will update the Jenkins new public IP in the GitHub webhook and our GitHub repository.
Third, we will test our continuous integration pipeline before we continue with the continuous delivery.
How to use Ansible, we need to force to test our continuous integration pipeline.
If it is working, then we will continue from there.
So you can also think of this as the continuation of continuous integration project that we did earlier.
Okay.
So doing the first thing, increasing the volume size of Jenkins root volume.
So Jenkins server with a checkmark there make sure the instance are powered off.
Go to storage and that's the volume ID.
Let's click on that.
So we go to the volume section.
It will automatically take us to the volume section that is a Jenkins root volume, let's name it.
Jenkins route volume.
Now we will be increasing its size from eight GB to, let's say 12 or 15 GB.
The reason we are doing this is from a previous project.
Jenkins would have already collected a lot of or stored a lot of data in the hard disk in its route
volume, and it will get full or it is already full.
We don't know.
So we need to do this.
Select the volume action.
Modify volume.
And increase its size.
I will give it as, let's say, 15 gbps and I will say modify, modify.
Now we have used ubuntu 20 in the jenkins and with 1 to 20 just by modifying the volume size, it will
automatically modify the partition size.
Also in the operating system inside.
Otherwise this is just not enough.
We need to log into this and we need to check.
We need to resize the partition size, but this will be fine.
So that's 15 GB Now I did a refresh, it's so 15 GB.
Now let's go back to instances power on all the instances.
Start instance.
So if it's again, if it's 1 to 20, you don't need to do anything much.
That's it.
The route volume size is already increased.
If it's CentOS or Amazon Linux or Ubuntu older version, then you need to log in access to the Jenkins
server and resize the partition.
Okay.
It's already coming up and we already got the public IP of the Jenkins.
We will copy that and we'll update it in the GitHub webhook.
So let's go to GitHub.
Go to your repository.
The same repository that we used previously.
We profile a project that I created.
Settings.
The books.
And we'll say edit.
It will ask for the login.
Enter the password.
That's it.
Let's change the IP.
And let's see.
Update Webhook.
Okay.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Stake its IP.
Colon, 1880.
Okay.
Now I'm able to access it.
But if your IP has changed, go to the Jenkins Security Group.
Edit Inbound rule.
88, it's 88 from anywhere, so you should be able to access it.
If it's my IP, then make sure you update the IP.
If not, this is fine.
Let's log into Jenkins.
Okay.
So we did two things so far.
We increase the route, volume, size.
And we have updated the webhook.
Now it's time to test our continuous integration pipeline.
Now it's already there.
Previous continuous integration pipeline.
You can just run the same one or you can create a new pipeline.
Now I'm going to wait for some time.
I'm not going to hurry because I want the next session.
So now to be completely up and running stable and then we can test the pipeline.
Okay.
I read it enough.
So I'm going to say Bill now.
So the same previous continuous integration pipeline.
So it'll pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
Okay.
It's a it's a success.
My CI pipeline is completely validated.
One last thing.
We will really validate whether the root volume size has increased in the operating system or not in
the Jenkins.
We will do a search to the Jenkins.
So open get bash.
As I said, I.
And I.
My key is in.
The profile that one open to add the date and the IP.
Okay.
I won't be able to do a search.
I need to update the security group rule.
Of Jenkins.
Edit Inbound rule.
And I have to say 22 from my IP.
This is my older IP.
So now it is updated save rules.
Okay.
Let's try again.
Yes.
Login, please.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Switch to the root user pseudo hyphen I and under five an edge.
So you see that?
Okay.
I need to show this first f desc hyphen l.
So that one, that's the route volume, it has increased to 15 GB but then it has the partition achieved
a one.
And if you see its size has gone to 14.9 GB, which is the 15 GB, so it has extended the partition
size also automatically.
And if you check the DFI for each.
Right.
So the root partition size has also increased to 15 GB.
So partition is increased, its partition format has increased and we are good.
So we don't need to do anything in the operating system.
It's extended.
And if you look at this right, it is 7.4 GB available, it is 7.1 GB used.
If it is eight GB, then this will definitely go out of size in this project.
So we extended it to 15 GB and that is it now.
So join me in the next lecture.
Where we will do some predictive sites on the Jenkins so it can run ansible code.