All right, let's prepare application, server and its detail.
So three things we will be doing.
We'll be launching an easy two instance with open to 18 operating system.
That's it.
Just launch it.
That is our app server for staging.
Second will create a DNS record for it in Route 53 so it can be accessed with the name from Ansible.
So we will save it as a search login key in the Jenkins credentials first starting with launching the
app server.
So launch instance.
We will limit as zero one hyphen staging.
We will go with ubuntu 18.
You can also use CentOS seven as well.
Our Ansible playbook can do deployment on Ubuntu and centos both.
So 1 to 818 I selected instance type to micro is fine.
Let's create a key pair for it.
So you call it US App key?
And keep it.
Pen create.
Keep their.
Let's see what.
Make sure that key selected network setting will say edit.
And we'll create a security group for it.
We'll say app hyphen.
S.G..
And we'll give.
Same in the description.
You will see a Lao 22 from my IP if you want to do so just in case.
So it will be running Tomcat Service, which runs on port 88.
So I will say allow 88.
Also from my IP.
So after the deployment of our Vpro file artifact, we can see it from the browser.
We also need to allow Port 22 from Jenkins Security Group.
Oop.
Sorry, not in here.
Source Jenkins Security Group.
Okay, now the reason we are doing it, Ansible will be running from Jenkins, and Ansible will do a
search to this application server to run the Ansible playbook.
So Jenkins and Ansible are basically just one same instance.
We will so we will allow Port 22 from Jenkins Security Group so Ansible can do ssh to it.
I will write a description.
Also allow Ansible.
To two such.
And that is it.
Nothing else.
Just launch.
Tomcat Service will be automatically set up by Ansible playbook.
So we don't need to do anything.
Just launch the instance.
That is it.
Okay.
It's going to come up.
We got it's private IP.
Now we will go to Route 53 and add it, add in it the DNS record.
So let's search for a route.
53.
Let's open it.
And here in the DNS management will say create a hosted zone.
If you already have hosted zone from the previous project, you can use the same and create the record,
or else you can create a new hosted zone as well.
Like I'm doing it.
I will give this name as V Pro File Hyphen Project.
Sorry, not hyphen dot.
That's how the domain is given.
You can give dot com dot in whatever.
I'm just giving dot project.
Private hostages are not public private.
This will be internally used in that region.
So we need to select the region as well.
So we are doing everything in US East, one US hyphen east.
I mean, I am doing it in the US East one North Virginia.
So wherever.
Your easy two instances are selected the same region.
Mine is in the US East one.
Right.
See this?
This is an US East one, not California.
So I use that region and I have a default VPC there that I will select and create hostage zone.
Okay that got created now in this will create a record so let's say create record.
And this will be an A record.
So I will give the name app zero one hyphen or app zero one SDG.
And based the private IP over here, the private IP of app server app zero one private IP copy that.
Makes sure app zero one is selected here.
Copy the private IP and paste it here.
That is it.
They create record.
Okay.
So that is the name of our app server staging.
App zero one stg dot v profile dot project.
This we will use in ansible inventory.
You will see how we use it.
Okay.
Third thing we will add, it's its search login key in the Jenkins credentials.
Go to Jenkins manager Jenkins.
Manage credentials.
Jenkins.
Global credentials.
Ad credential.
So this will be the username and the private key for our app server, which Ansible will use.
So we will call it as.
App login.
See.
I'll put in the description.
Username.
So we have launched an ubuntu instance from open to am-I, so its username is open to.
And it's login key.
We say enter directly here and.
And let's look at the key, copy the key and paste it over here.
So I'm opening the git bash.
And I will simply do cat downloads.
AP.
Okay.
Copy that key.
Make sure no extra characters are copied.
Exactly how I copied it.
The same way you do.
And then paste it here.
And they create.
So Ansible will use this credential to login to app server.
So we did three simple things.
We launched an easy two instance app zero on staging.
We created its DNS record and we have saved its credential in the Jenkins.
Now we need to prepare Jenkins to run Ansible code that we will do in the next lecture.
So wrap this up and join me in the next one.