Okay.
This one is pretty simple.
We need to do just two things.
We need to install Ansible in Jenkins and then we need to install Ansible plugin in Jenkins.
So let's do switch to Jenkins first.
Let's get its IP version.
It's.
There.
Forget its IP.
Go to get Bash.
Just do an search.
To what?
The profile 61 to add the eight p.
Clear the screen, become the root user and let's get the steps of installing Ansible in Ubuntu.
No, I just googled ansible installation open to installing Ansible and a specific operating system
that link.
This is the documentation from Ansible itself.
And they're pretty simple steps.
Let's just copy them.
Oh, let's just execute them one by one.
First app update.
Okay.
Next.
App installs software properties common, I believe that will be already installed.
Yep.
Already installed.
Adding the ansible repository.
And then finally installing Ansible.
And hyphen y.
So what are the steps you see in the documentation use that it might change.
The steps might change.
Just go to the documentation, find the steps and install Ansible.
Okay.
Ansible installed.
Ansible hyphen hyphen version.
Okay.
We're good.
Now let's install ansible plugin in Jenkins.
So dashboard.
Manny Jenkins.
Manage plugins.
Available and search for Ansible.
There.
Put a checkmark on that hand.
Symbol 1.1 I'm seeing.
Install without restart.
Yep.
That's all.
In this lecture.
I'll see you in the next one.