All right.
So far, so good.
In this lecture, we will be preparing our source code.
So my repository.
It's here in my system.
This is the same repository we used in previous projects.
So go to your repository directory folder.
Make sure everything is good.
Get status.
If there is any changes, you need to pull the changes.
Make sure the repository is clean.
It's in sync.
Let's look at the branch, branch, if any.
Let's switch to see hyphen Jenkins branch first.
Get check out.
Sy hyphen Jenkins.
From this branch, we will create another branch and that branch will use in this project.
So we'll say get checked out.
Hyphen B.
And I will call this branch's CCD hyphen chain.
Quince.
Now you can call this branch water.
You want to make sure you remember the branch name.
This is the branch we'll be using in this project for staging environment.
We'll put all our ANSIBLE code in this branch.
Okay.
So it creates a new branch and switches to that branch.
And in this branch, we need to copy the Ansible code in this Ansible directory.
And that's what we'll do next.
We will go to.
Our GitHub repository, not our my GitHub repository.
We profile project repository.
Again, that's the link.
And you need to switch to the branch search for Ansible.
In this case.
Ansible.
Their Jenkins Ansible code.
That branch you need to switch to exactly this branch.
Not any other branch.
Jenkins hyphen.
Ansible hyphen code.
There are some other branches with names of Ansible, but they have slightly different code.
This is more twisted four or more updated for this project.
Here we have the Ansible directory.
All this.
We need to copy it into our repository.
So first we will download this.
We will say download zip which will download this branch.
In the downloads directory.
Let's go there.
Let's go to the downloads folder.
Showing folder.
And I'm going to extract this one.
Extract all.
Yeah.
Extract.
Okay.
Extracted.
Close this one.
Yeah.
That's the directory inside that we have.
Directory with the same name and that's the Ansible code.
So you need to copy this.
I'm going to do control.
See here, select the Ansible control key and go to our or your project repository.
Mine is in F drive.
In Project Get report.
We profiled C Project there and you just need to paste it here.
Yeah.
So once you see, hear Ansible, you will see a few playbooks, some templates.
It is copied if you go to get batch.
Right.
Okay.
We'll say it.
Ad dot.
So we copied all the ansible code here can get a dot.
And we will see it come at five hyphen M.
See Ansible code as a message and we'll say Git push origin.
Secede, hyphen, chink and symbol like that.
Make sure you use the correct branch name.
Okay.
New branch should get created now in your GitHub repository.
Yeah.
New Branch CD Hyphen Jenkins.
And Ansible.
Yeah.
And that code is there.
Make sure you do all these steps very carefully.
We need to have our Ansible code once again.
It's pretty simple.
We create a new branch in our repository.
We download Jenkins Ansible branch from the Profile Project Repository and we copy the Ansible folder
from that into our repository and then we push it to GitHub.
Right.
So the idea is to copy the Ansible code from high profile project repository to our repository in a
new branch.
That is all in this lecture.
In the next lecture we will look at the Ansible code that we will be executing from Jenkins.
So wrap this up and join me in the next lecture.