Okay.
So in previous lecture we have copied the Ansible code in our GitHub repository, in the Git repository,
we will look at that code now ansible code, the ansible playbooks that we will be executing from Jenkins
in order to set up Tomcat Server and deploy our artifacts.
In this lecture we will be talking about Tomcat Playbook specifically.
So open sublime text editor or Vsco or notepad plus plus anything you want and open your git repository
the folder where you have your get repository.
So I'm going to say file open folder.
So mine is in f drive project git repo.
That's the repository folder.
Select that and I will say just select folder.
Here we have the ansible folder and we have the first playbook site dot yaml.
This playbook will get executed and this will execute to playbook.
One is Tomcat setup playbook and the second one is Repro app setup playbook which is in the same.
Location.
You can also use vs code to view this playbook.
Just open gate bash.
Go to your repository.
Make sure you're in correct branch and say code dot, which should open the voice code.
And you have the ansible folder there.
Site, dot email.
Okay.
Now, let's look at this playbook in detail.
TomKat set up playbook first.
But before we go there, let me show you some templates that we are going to use.
So you're going to provision Tomcat servers.
So if if we are provisioning Tomcat service on a center machine.
Centers or any enterprise linux seven.
Then this template will be used for the system d service.
If this and any enterprise Linux six like or six or Article six, we can use that this template will
be deployed to set up the init script, the startup script, so we can manage the Tomcat with service
command or system Ctrl command if it's open to 16 or higher.
Then this system defined.
If it's 1 to 15 or lower than this in its startup script.
So based on the operating system that we have selected for Tomcat, our playbook is going to deploy
the right.
Startup script.
So now let's go to the Playbook first.
TomKat set up Playbook.
So this playbook is going to run on a group app server group become yes.
And we are forced to setting a variable tom underscore URL.
And this is the URL from where it's going to download the tomcat tarball.
And then we have this list of tasks.
First task is to install JDK if the operating system is sent to us.
So that will be the package name.
If the operating system is open to, then it will use apt module and install open JDK eight.
So based on the distribution, it will install the right package.
Next task is to download Tomcat tarball.
That's the variable that we have set over here.
It's going to download by using get you URL module, it's going to download Tomcat and place it at this
location.
Temp directory tomcat hyphen 8... GZ.
Then we're going to add a group called Tomcat with the group module, we're going to add a user.
Called Tomcat with user module and no logging shell and its home directory will be us our local tomcat
eight.
So when we create this user, this directory will also get created automatically and this will be our
home directory of Tomcat.
Next we are creating a directory slash temp tomcat eight state directory with file module.
And in this directive we are going to an archive tomcat tarball forced so an archive module.
So the tarball that we downloaded this location that's the source and destination will be temp Tomcat
eight which we created over here.
And remote source.
Yes, we're using an archive module and an archive module by default thing that.
The archive is in the control machine.
So we have to specifically mention remote sources because the source and destination exist both on the
app server.
List files.
Yes.
So this honor when we an archived tarball, it's going to list all the files and we are saying list
file.
Yes.
So it's going to return all that output and all that output.
We're going to register into this variable.
The reason why we are doing this is when we archive Tomcat tarball which you download it from this directory.
When it is an archive then the directory name could be anything.
8.5.37 hyphen something 1.2 something something.
It could be anything.
So we want to catch it in the runtime.
That's why we are storing the output into this variable.
And from that variable then we're going to extract the directory name where it get.
Created.
So all from all the list of files we are going to store into this variable then that there will be.
A key call file's value is going to be a list.
So first item in the list.
So we'll get a complete path and we're going to use a split function.
This works like cut command and so it's going to split at the forward slash.
And we're going to get first index, which will be actually the directory name.
So this is going to give us the directory name where the Tomcat is extracted.
And which synchronize module.
What we're going to do is we're going to sync that directory, which is an archived with the destination
user local Tomcat eight and this got created over here when we created the user.
So right files will get automatically copied into this destination and this will become the Na Tomcat
Home Directory.
Again, synchronize module will think that the source is locally on the control machine.
So to make sure it knows that the source is on the target machine, we use delegate to inventory underscore
hostname.
That's the magic variable.
So wherever this playbook is getting executed on whatever target, that will be the host name over here.
So source and destination both on the target machine.
Okay.
Next, we're going to change the ownership of user local Tomcat Directory to user Tomcat Group Tomcat
because when we archive or when we sync here the files from this directory to over here, it will not
have the Tomcat user ownership.
So we'll make sure that recursively this directory has every file in this directory has Tomcat Owner
and Tomcat group.
With Files module, of course.
So now our Tomcat binaries are ready in this directory.
Now it's time to set up the start up script.
So we're going to by using a template module, we're going to deploy our template.
So if the operating system when the.
So here's the condition when ANSIBLE distribution center.
So if the target is sent to us and.
Its major version is seven and both the conditions are true.
Then we are going to deploy this template at this particular location.
So that's the system d file.
So then we can manage Tomcat with system CTL command.
So in this case, it's going to deploy this template.
This template will be deployed.
Okay.
Next.
If it's a center is six four, center six, when it's centers and the distribution major version is
six, then deploy this template.
Six, that one.
So till Enterprise Linux six, it was in its script, right?
So basically that was a shell script.
But now things have changed from enterprise Linux seven onwards.
Everything is managed by systemd service system dx service.
So we need this file.
90 ways for every operating system we have the preparation if the operating system is open to and major
version distribution is less than 16.
So 1 to 14, 15 or even 12 older versions of Ubuntu you have, then you deploy this template at this
location.
If.
Ubuntu and major distribution version is greater than or equal to 16, so open to 16 or higher.
We deploy in this template at this location.
So based on the operating system, right template will get executed.
And once that happens based again based on the operating system, then if it's open to and less than
16, then we're going to execute this command which is going to reload our init configuration.
If it's centers.
And major version six.
Then we run this command check config add tomcat.
For a higher operating systems enterprise Linux seven and 1 to 16 greater and higher then we are going
to for for those operating system where major erosion is greater than six or 15.
Then we're going to just use this model systemd daemon reload.
Yes.
So if it centers seven or 1 to 16 or higher, then this model will execute.
Once that is done, then we use service module to start the Tomcat service and of course enable it.
So all this intelligence that we are doing in this playbook.
Creating user group and then deploying this template file is only so we can use the service module to
manage our Tomcat service.
So this playbook will set up Tomcat on most of the operating systems.
And so we support enterprise Linux 67012 12 1415 1618 I have not tested this playbook on 1 to 20, but
very soon we'll do that and we'll put templates for those also.