Okay.
Now, next, see, next, we'll see our main playbook, which is actually going to deploy Artifact to
Tomcat server.
And so this playbook web pro hyphen app set up HTML, this will get executed again on the same group
app server group and become yes variable timestamp.
We're setting a timestamp variable over here.
This is going to get values from the fact variable.
This variable you're going to use to create a backup file and archive.
So before we deploy our new artifact, we're going to take a backup of the existing artifact.
And when we take backup of a file, it's a good idea that we use Timestamp.
So we're going to use this variable now.
We get created every time you run the playbook.
So it will have the latest timestamp in this.
Okay.
First task itself is get URL and download artifact from Nexis.
Now will not have a static URL.
Right?
When we upload artifact to Nexis.
Every artifact will have its own URL and that you URL will be collection of the path of repository name
slash, group ID, slash, timestamp, slash, build, ID and slash version.
I'd like to check this.
Let's go to an axis.
Let's.
Let's go to the next server and check any artifact.
Okay.
Next this.
Let's take the public IP.
Colon, 1881.
Yeah.
Let's sign in.
Let's go to Bruce.
So we profile release.
This is our repository.
We are storing the artifact over there.
Q If we see.
See the artifact, right?
That's an artifact, let's say.
That is, let's say our latest artifact, right?
If you copy its URL.
You will see its collection, right?
So first IP 881 repository we profile release in the path is like this Q way that's the group ID we
profile and that's the timestamp, right?
The build timestamp we're using V 12, that's the build ID, we're using V profile and then the timestamp
hyphen version.
So this URL will be changing for every latest artifact.
It will have the latest timestamp and the latest build ID.
So it's going to be a dynamic URL.
So of course in our playbook.
We can put a static URL, then it will every time deploy the same artifact.
So we're using variables over here and these variables value we are going to pass from Jenkins.
So repository name, group ID, timestamp, build, ID, the entire version name all this you are going
to pass from Jenkins.
From Jenkins will execute this playbook.
So while executing, we're going to pass the value of this variable and this will be through a plugin.
So anyways, this URL will download at this location.
AMP, the pro app hyphen and the version profile version.
Now, as per our playbook, we will also give the version on artifact name v pro app, hyphen, v profile,
underscore version or we can just keep it as it is also.
Anyways, once we download the artifact to this location temp location, we're going to register the
output into this variable.
Var deploy.
And we have a tag also here, deploy tag.
So if you want, we can execute all the tasks by calling these deployed tags.
Right.
Let's go.
Next task stat module.
And I'm collecting statistics of the current artifact at this location that there will be this file
existing or could not be existing.
Also, if it does not exist, then I don't want to take the backup of something that does not exist.
But if it exists, then I'll take it's backup.
For that reason I'm using stat module and collecting statistics of this file and storing it into this
variable.
Then we stop the Tomcat service.
Once we stop the Tomcat Service with service module, then we're going to try backup and deploy.
I've used the word try because deployment fails for a number of reasons, so we should have some rollback
strategy.
We're actually here using multiple rollback strategies.
One will be automatic rollback.
So since we stopped the Tomcat Service, if the deployment fails, the playbook will stop and the Tomcat
Server Service will be stopped in a stop state.
So we have to take care of that.
Tomcat service is stopped.
So we take the backup and something goes wrong.
We start the Tomcat service.
That's one thing.
Also, while the deployment is happening, we have taken the backup, we rollback that.
Also we can do so.
We're using block and rescue.
From Ansible playbook.
So first main block is this.
It's going to try to deploy the artifact.
Till here.
This is our main block, which is which I have highlighted.
If anything fails in this, then the rescue will come into the motion.
Not Saudi, not this one.
Let me show you once again the main block.
Still here.
Anything fails in the main block.
Then the rescue will come and we'll start the Tomcat Service.
So anything fails over here.
Tomcat Service will get started.
Any case?
Cap now let's go again.
We also have a sub block and rescue.
Over here.
We'll understand that in the main block we have one more block and rescue nested.
Okay, let's see.
The task.
First task is archive.
Even try backup and deploy your first task as archive.
It's going to archive.
That's the path of an existing artifact.
We're in a copy at this location with the name route underscore timestamped tg z.
Write this variable we are constructing the very beginning.
So every time we'll have a version of our backup.
But do it only then.
Artifacts that don't start exist.
So this is a variable which we are collecting.
Out here.
We're checking the statistics of a file.
If this file exists.
If the destination exist.
Then artifact underscore stat stat exist.
Value will be true.
If it's true, then it will take the backup.
If it does not exist, it will not take the backup because if it does not exist, then this will fail
and playbook execution itself will fail.
And all the result will we registered again.
And we're taking this is our main backup, but we're also taking an instant backup in the same directory.
So we change the directory to this path where we have a root directory and we're going to copy the root
directory with name, all underscore route and the same directory.
I'll copy it with a different name.
So in case something happens, we'll quickly rollback.
If something happens, we'll use a copy command and just revert it.
All right, so we've taken the backup over here and we have taken backup in the same directory, and
then it's time to delete our current artifact.
So if you have an artifact with name, route or route dot where?
Of our file or the directory.
So we're running in a loop of file module.
So it's going to remove state absent.
So first this file will be removed and then this file will be removed.
Okay.
But we don't need to be worrying because we've already taken the backup not to twice.
Next task.
We'll now try to deploy the artifact.
Previously, we just trying to take the backup.
The backup complete successfully.
So it comes here.
So copy module.
At this location, we have an artifact that was downloaded in the first task there.
Right.
So we use copy module copy the artifact from this location to this location, use our local Tomcat ET
Web apps route dot var remote source.
Yes.
Again, for copy model, you have to use remote source.
If the source is on a remote machine, we registered the output.
If in any case this fails for there could be so many reasons it can fail.
If this task fails, the rescue will come into the picture and we'll just copy all underscore route
with the name route.
Instant rollback.
Right.
But it's going to go into that directory, of course, if the deployment fails.
In case any of this thing fails, the Tomcat Service will get started.
If everything completes successfully here.
Then the next task is start the Tomcat Service.
And if everything goes well, it will come till this task and start the Tomcat Service.
But if anything fails and we don't have any rescue, it will just the playbook execution itself will
fail and Tomcat Service will stay stopped.
It will not come till this task.
So that's why in the rescue we are putting here start Tomcat Service.
Okay.
If everything goes well, the Tomcat series get started.
And I would like to put a weight for.
This path to become available.
So when we start the Tomcat Service, the artifact takes time to get extracted sometimes, and I would
like to wait that much time.
Once the archiving and archiving completes, when we have root directory from root dot var.
Then we'll continue.
Until.
Unless.
Wait.
Okay.
And then finally.
There is a handler which we actually we are not using.
But if you are going to deploy application properties file from the playbook by using playbook, then
we can uncomment this and from our templates directory will have our own application properties file.
We deployed it this location and we notify to the handler, but application properties file, we are
building it in the build job itself.
So we'll have a build job.
We're going to build application properties, file with write backend server details and same artifact
will be pushed over here.
So it will anyways have the have the backend service details, the MySQL mem cache, all the details
will be already existing in this artifact.
If not, then you can uncomment these lines and deploy your own application properties file at this
location.
And for that very reason, we have this wait for model.
So it's going to wait until this path is available.
Once this is available, it's going to deploy our application properties file.
Now if you have set up the profile project.
Manually on local system and on a s then you know how important our application properties file is.
That's the file which is going to show us the backend services, not us, to our application, which
is running on Tomcat.
So it's very important to take care of that.
So these are the two playbooks that will get executed.
So we're going to just call this playbook site dot HTML first Tomcat setup playbook will run.
It will set up the Tomcat Service.
And then this playbook will get executed with Pro App set up, which is going to download the artifact
from Nexis and deploy it.
If anything fails, there's a rollback.
And then finally.
Application properties file and restart Tomcat service.