Now, again.
Now, we understood the playbook that will be executed by Jenkins.
Now we have to make sure those playbooks get executed from our pipeline.
So come to your repository and get bash wherever you are and open it in these codes.
A code.
Code.
Sorry.
Code space.
Dot, you'll open the code.
All right, so we have to prepare the Jenkins file to run this playbook.
So let's go to the Jenkins file.
This is the same Jenkins file we use in continuous integration project.
We are just going to append here.
One more stage after this.
One more stage which executes our Ansible.
Playbook by using Ansible plugin.
So let's check the documentation of Ansible plugin.
Okay.
So I just google ansible plugin jenkins file.
The first thing ansible plugin.
And here you can see the different parameters that we can pass in this plugin like the playbook user
color disabled host key checking the inventory file path.
Lets view this plugin on plugin site.
Okay.
Now, it should be some example here.
That's the way to execute it in Scripture.
That's the way to execute it in declarative.
We'll be using this way declarative.
And this one more example here in the Jenkins file.
It's pretty simple.
You say Ansible playbook open and close the parenthesis and mention all the parameters.
We will be doing that.
So let's go to VS Code now our playbook.
Don't get set setup playbook.
The host is app server group, the group name and in this playbook also the pro app setup playbook.
Here also host is app server group.
So we need an inventory file where the information about this app server group is present.
So we need to create an inventory file here.
So we will say on this ansible folder, right click.
New file and we'll say stage dot inventory.
So saying that this inventory file for staging environment and we'll create the group name here the
same what is in the playbook.
That one.
All right.
And then we need to mention the list of host that is in this group.
So we created the easy to instance.
AB zero one staging.
Right.
And we added its entry in Route 53.
So that's our host name.
It will be resolved to the IP address of this instance.
So let's copy that.
Let me copy it properly.
I'm zero and sticky.
And let's paste it here.
Now the log in detail, the search username and log in key is stored in Jenkins credentials.
We already saved that, so we'll be using the same in the playbook.
Sorry, not in the playbook.
In the Jenkins plugin.
Okay, let's go to Jenkins file and let's append a stage here.
Stage.
Parenthesis and let's give the name of the stage.
I would say Ansible.
Deploy to staging.
Open and close.
Curly brace.
You can just check the code from the resource.
In this lecture I have just uploaded the entire code over there.
Or if you intend to write it with me, you can write it as well.
Okay.
In this steps, obviously, the stage we have steps.
Now in this step we will mention the answer will plug in information and symbol playbook like that,
parentheses and all the parameters.
So I have some code already that I'm going to just paste it over there.
Okay.
There seem what we saw in the documentation and symbol playbook parentheses and I am mentioning all
the parameters in a list and vertically.
So I've given a square bracket.
They're opening and closing.
So first is the inventory failure to specify.
So inventory we just created in the ansible folder.
So Ansible slash stage dot inventory.
Make sure the name is correct of your inventory file.
Playbook ansible slash ci dot ml.
So that will execute the other two playbooks.
Installation ansible colorized true credentials id.
So this is the credential that we saved in the Jenkins.
All right, let's go to Jenkins.
Dashboard Manager Jenkins manage credentials.
There.
This is the login credential for the app server.
An app server detail is in the inventory file.
Yeah.
Let's go back.
So it's the same name as the credential app login disable host.
Keep checking to make sure this is there.
Otherwise Playbook execution will fail.
It will say host key checking is enabled so make sure this option is there extra variables now our playbook.
There has multiple variables.
User pus nexus IP rep on the report name group ID Artifact ID build hyphen time and v profile underscore
version.
We need to specify the value for all these ansible variables.
So let's do it.
Go back to Jenkins file.
Okay.
So I took a liberty to do this already and I'll add all the values.
So user variable, this is the user of the nexus username admin pass the password of nexus.
Now I could have done with the credentials also, which I will do next.
Instead of mentioning password like that.
I saved this as a credential in Jenkins and access it from here, which we'll do next.
But first I wanted to show you Nexus IP.
So yeah.
Before that, sorry.
So the Nexus login password, make sure you mentioned that Nexus login password.
Nexus IP.
So get the Nexus private IP.
I just pasted their repository name in the Nexis.
We have the repository named repro file hyphen release where we'll upload the artifact.
Let's go to Nexis.
Let's take its public IP.
Colon 88 one.
Look, I need to allow the security group rule to access nexus from my IP.
Next, a security group.
8081 from there.
Radio do you want from my IP?
See you.
What happened?
My IP.
And save.
Let's refresh this.
Okay.
Let's sign in admin.
And you already seen the passwords had been one, two, three.
Okay.
Browse.
We profile release in this repository.
We want to upload our artifact.
Sorry.
From this repository, you want to download our artifact?
Yeah.
Click on that.
So many artifacts there.
Right.
So we'll be downloading the latest one and deploying it.
So that will be the URL.
So in Ansible playbook, by using those variables, it's going to construct this URL and download the
latest artifact in the Tomcat.
Bring back Grupo de Cuba.
Not as we have given previously, the component group that's in the URL.
See that.
Let's copy that.
Sorry.
Right click.
Copy link.
Time in the dot build timestamp now build timestamp depends on what it was over here we are uploading
the artifact and we need to make sure in the Jenkins.
It is correct.
Let's go to Jenkins.
Manny Jenkins.
Configure.
So in continuous integration, we use this plugin to version our artifact and we use this variable build
timestamp variable and this is the pattern y y hyphen mx hyphen dx underscore h mm.
Right.
But that pattern.
What is that?
They're in the other.
So same we are mentioning over here that use this build timestamp value which will get us that particular
artifact.
So version of the artifact is EMV dot build underscore ID in the hyphen in v dot build underscore timestamp
coming there in our ansible plugin.
Okay.
Then build value.
Ian we don't build ID, we are using build ID again for versioning artifact ID Vpro app.
As we have used here while uploading the artifacts.
So whatever values you used while uploading artifact to next same, you have to mention over here because
that's what will be downloaded, right?
And then we profile version.
So if you look at it once again, Vpro app, it's like that, right?
Wipro app.
Hyphen build.
ID hyphen build.
Timestamp dot var.
Same we are mentioning over here.
Okay, so this is good.
We can execute.
But there's one problem.
The password here variable is in clear text, which is not good.
So we will store this in the Jenkins credentials and access it from here.
So let's go back to Jenkins one last thing before we execute the playbook.
Barry Jenkins.
Manage credentials.
So there is this previous Nexus login, but this is username and password.
We just need the password.
We need to just store the password.
So go to Jenkins Global Credentials.
And credential.
And just if you want to store the password, you can go with the kind of secret text.
Right and mention the password there.
And let's give Nexus, boss.
Okay.
And there also nexus pass the description create.
So that stored the Nexus password there.
And let's put that in our Jenkins file.
So we'll first put that into the variable.
We'll store it into a variable.
Right there.
Because I've taken a variable nexus pass all caps equal to credentials.
That's the function which will access this credential.
So this is are secret text that we stored.
Its value will be stored into this variable and then we are going to put this variable.
No.
Here.
All right.
So instead of this, we will say.
Dollar codebase.
Nexus pass.
Oops.
Yeah.
Okay.
Which will have the value of the password.
This is good.
Just review once again.
Download the pipeline code from the resource.
Compare it with your code.
Make sure all the commas, all the variables, all the opening and closing, everything is correct.
Do not make syntax error or typographical error.
That's our stage.
This is our.
Steps and this is the Ansible plugin and these are all the parameters.
These are extra variables.
So all looks good for now.
But who knows?
Let's save this and try this.
Save this.
I hope the stage inventory is also saved.
And it's time to now.
Commit and push.
Okay.
Let's see.
Jenkins file.
And to build plugin ID.
Let's see if this control this and put a checkmark.
Okay.
Publish.
Now let's go to the Jenkins.
Create a new pipeline, new item.
Well, it's a c, c, d hyphen Jenkins hyphen ansible hyphen stage.
Just giving the name.
Select pipeline.
C OC.
Okay.
GitHub Hook Trigger Forget ACM polling.
Put a checkmark on that Safe Pipeline script from ACM.
And here select target.
Repository URL.
Let's get our repository URL.
Code is is a all.
They stood there.
And select your already saved credentials minus GitHub login.
Branch c icd hyphen chink ans.
Right.
And the Jenkins file is just there.
And let's see if this.
And let's test it.
Build now.
Okay.
Before this completes, we need to do one very one thing very quickly.
So App server is going to download the artifact from next.
So we need to go to the Nexis server security.
Security group of the Nexus server.
Inbound rule.
So we need to allow 8081 from the App Security Group, 80, 81.
From the App Security Group so application server can download artifact from Nexus.
Several.
Okay.
Let's go back.
All right, the pipeline failed.
Let's see why it failed.
That is a mistake from not mistake when I intentionally failed this pipeline previously.
Let's make one one as the command, which is the wrong command.
So.
Yeah, there.
MV VN So in continuous integration project, I purposefully failed the pipeline to show you the notification.
That's why I made this one over there.
So I make the changes.
Now back to MV in control lists.
Save, commit and push.
I can see fixed maven command control less.
A check mark.
Now this should trigger our pipeline automatically because we have webhook already configured.
You go back.
Yeah.
The second job got triggered.
Let's wait.
It started to click on that.
Okay.
So I'm going to pause my screen and come back when this is completed.
This is going to take some time.
Okay.
My pipeline has failed once again.
So I thought of showing it to you.
So the hostname that we added, it's saying its name or service not known could not resolve the host
name.
That means it's not able to get the IP address of what is this hostname?
It doesn't know what it is.
Sure, we created a route 53 DNS entry.
And we created the homestead zone.
We created the entry.
Right.
And the IP also is correct of app server.
But the problem is what I did was.
We entered the hosted zone.
Go to edit.
I have given the wrong region here.
My instances are in US West one and I have given here US East one, so I need to see us hyphen west,
hyphen one.
Let's check once again.
US West one.
Okay.
Now let's save the change and try once again.
It is updated and not updated the same time.
Let's see once again.
Did it edit or not?
High profile project.
Okay.
Let me select it here and say edit.
No, it did not.
EDIT okay, of course.
US hyphen west hyphen one.
I select this and I need to change the VPC.
Also write the VPC in that region.
See if changes.
Okay.
Now let's try it once again.
So we did not make any code change.
So we need to say build now once again.
Okay.
And let's wait.
All right.
So that is a success.
Let's see what all happened here.
So we already know till uploading artifact to Nexus, right?
It was about executing the Ansible playbook.
So first Playbook got executed, gathering facts about this.
All right.
Installing JDK, right.
Downloading Tomcat tarball.
Setting up Tomcat.
Nice.
Okay.
So Tomcat Service should be there up and running and then deploying the artifact, the next playbook.
Right.
So it goes to the next case downloads the artifact extracted.
If there's nothing wrong, it restarts the Tomcat service, or if something's wrong, it can roll back.
Also, we talked about that.
So now we should be having app zero on staging this copy type.
So we should be having our application there.
Right, Colon 80, 80.
All right, let's see.
Yeah.
There.
If you don't see this page, check again the security group of application server, it should allow
it from your IP and there are no backend services we are set up.
So obviously you cannot log in.
But the point of this exercise, this project was to show you how you can do configuration management
and secede together.
So we're using Ansible to deploy the artifact, but we are running Ansible playbook in the pipeline
and this is for staging environment.
In the next lecture we will see how we are going to promote it to the production environment.
So complete this and join me in the next lecture.