All right.
We did complete the pipeline for staging environment.
And you know what is next?
Yes, for production environment.
So first, starting with setting up production application server, this is staging.
Now before we move, I want to point out here one more thing.
Here we have just one single application staging environment in production.
Also, we will be having single easy two instance, but a playbook has inventory file.
They're right.
And we mentioned just one single server there.
And as you can see, we can add multiple servers over here.
We don't need to make any change in our playbook or Jenkins file.
Nowhere, right.
It runs on the group and a group can have as many as host it wants.
So if you want, it can do deployment for multiple instances.
Also it will be same.
We just need to update the inventory file.
That's the power of configuration management.
Right.
So let's go back.
Let's set up a production instance.
So launch instance, same thing, what we did for staging, we're going to name it as app zero one hyphen
prod.
And we will go with open to 18.
Am I once again open to 18 free tier open to 18 free tier that one.
Scroll down rt to micro is fine now we already have a login key.
We can use the same, but as for production we use different login keys.
So let's create a new login key and center.
It's name will say app login sorry app key hyphen prod pen create key pair.
Save.
Okay.
Moving on now.
Yes, we can create a new security group and we'll have similar rules.
So we will just select the same security group.
App Security group.
But even if you have a different security group, it will have similar rules and similar steps to select
that security group.
And that is it.
Launch instance.
View all instances.
Okay.
It's coming up by the time we will add its DNS entry.
So let's copy its private IP.
Go to Route 53, same hosted zone.
Create record.
Okay.
Before that?
Yeah.
This is what we named AB zero one STG.
This one we're going to name as app 01prd for product and let's paste it's private IP, right?
Yeah.
And they create record.
Okay.
That's nice.
Now let's go to Jenkins.
Okay, so I did a shut down and power of the Jenkins, so I need to.
Get the new public IP of Jenkins AT&T.
Let's log in.
And let's save the production application server's credential in Jenkins.
So total three things launch instance add DNS record add its credential in Jenkins.
So Manager Jenkins.
Manage credentials.
That app login is for the staging one.
Just click on Jenkins here.
Global credentials.
Ad credential.
User name and private key.
Okay.
So it's the app.
App.
Login.
Hyphen.
Prod.
Copy that.
Same in the description I'm giving.
Username is ubuntu.
Enter key directly and, and we, we downloaded the login key right while launching the instance.
So let's get that file.
I open git bash.
I'm going to say cat downloads app key hyphen product PEM.
And let's copy that.
All that content.
Once again, be careful while copying.
Make sure no extra things are copied.
Copy going back to Jenkins and paste the content there and say Create.
Okay.
So we set up everything we need at the application server side.
We launch the instance for prod.
We updated the DNS record and we have saved the credential.
In next lecture, we will create a new branch and add our production code over there.
So complete this and join me in the next lecture.