Okay.
In this lecture, we will be writing the code for the production pipeline.
But before I start doing it, I need to update the GitHub webhook with new Jenkins IP because I did
shut down and power on Jenkins.
The public IP is changed, so I copy the public IP of Jenkins.
I go to the repository.
I'm in that right.
Yeah.
Correct.
Repository settings.
The books.
Edit.
Rendering the password.
And update the public IP.
So whenever you power off and power on your Jenkins, you should be doing this.
Okay.
Now I'm going to get Bash and we will work on the code that we will be using in the production pipeline.
So f my source code repositories here.
Correct.
Okay.
Now, from this branch, I'm going to create another branch that we will use for production deployment.
So git checkout hyphen b.
We'll use the same name.
We'll just add a prod at the end.
Okay.
And then let's open the VSE code.
Let me close the previous one.
Exit.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, code dot.
All right.
So let me close all these files first.
We'll open them once again.
Because of here in different branch, broad branch.
First updating the inventory file.
So change the hostname to correct hostname that we did add in with its PRD.
Yeah.
This is what I add in Route 53 DNS records and control.
As to that, go to Jenkins file.
And we do not need to build all this.
We will remove most of it.
So I'm going to remove build stage test check sonar quality gates.
Upload artifact.
And I'm going to call a delete on all that stage.
Okay.
Environment variable.
Also, we don't need these many because we are not using them, so let's remove them.
Only Nexus password, which will be used by the Ansible playbook to log into Nexus server tools.
Also, we do not need.
Let's remove that as well.
Now.
Yes.
You might be thinking that what we are done right?
That is it.
We just change the path.
We change the name, change the inventory file, and we're good.
But there's one problem here.
Very, very big problem.
So these variables that we are passing in the playbook, this will construct the URL in staging in the
same pipeline.
These variables are used to name the artifact so we can use the same variable to download the artifact.
But now if we access build timestamp in this pipeline, the timestamp value will be different and there
will not be such artifact with this version.
Build ID also will be different.
So what are our choices here?
What do we do?
Well, we need to have this job as parameterized.
That means we need to take the input from the user to enter the correct artifact name.
The user needs to enter the right build timestamp value and the right build ID, which is from the staging
environment, not from the production environment.
I'll show you how it is done.
So we'll say deploy to prod and.
Let's see things one by one inventory keep same credentials.
ID app login hyphen prod.
App login hyphen prod.
That's what we saved in Jenkins.
Username admin password of the nexus same nexus ip same repository name, same group are the same here.
We are going to mention a variable here which we will take as an input from the user build.
This is our own created variable.
Sorry not build here.
We'll set time and here we'll give it as build.
Now these variables does not exist yet.
We are going to take input from the user, which I will show you in a moment here in v dot build ID.
So that will be build and here it is the timestamp.
So instead of that we are going to use a variable time might seem two variables now these two variables
again they don't exist.
We need to take it from the user.
So we are going to add one more stage over here that will take input from the user.
So I have the code.
I will show it to you.
It's pretty simple.
Stage setup parameters, steps inside that script and properties inside that.
We have parameters and we are going to say string parameter.
That means the text.
So default value.
So to pair to argument in this default value, we are going to say null nothing, just single code and
the name is build.
That's the variable name here.
The variable name is time.
Now what happens is when you run this pipeline, it will ask for the parameter the user needs to enter
those parameter and this will be same as matching as we have the artifact version.
So I'm going to go to next just to show it to you, how the user can fetch the right value for it.
80, 81.
Sign in.
Okay.
So we go to browse.
That's our repository.
Right.
So let's say a user wants to deploy this particular artifact, so user will be passing in the place
of build 16 and in the place of time the user will be passing this 22 hyphen zero nine, hyphen zero
five, underscore zero three, underscore zero nine.
So you see user can deploy any version of the artifact that is on Nexus needs to just pass the right
build ID and right timestamp value so it will fetch the correct artifact.
Okay, going back to the code, let's just check the syntax once again.
Agent, any environment is this are the stages.
Stage starts here, completes there.
Staged Ansible deployed to prod all the details, you know, syntax only I'm checking because we cannot
be really sure whether it will work or not until we execute it.
I do control less to that.
And hey, one more thing.
I would like to rename this stage dot inventory file to product inventory.
So right click rename, there is a product inventory.
And in the Jenkins file will mention that product inventory.
Make sure you change the both place at both the places.
The name of the file in the Jenkins file.
Yeah.
Correct.
Okay.
Let's see if this.
It's time to commit and push.
So.
Come again and.
Save all and commit.
Let's give a message here.
Prod pipeline.
Save.
And let's put a checkmark there.
Nokia.
Publish the branch or publish that branch.
It seems like it published.
It's time for test.
So let's go to Jenkins.
What is my Jenkins there?
Okay.
I'm going to copy this name right here.
I'll create a pipeline with a similar name if I can copy it.
Command, select it.
Copy Control.
See new item.
And here, instead of that, I'll change it to product pipeline and I'm going to copy everything from
the staging environment staging branch, sorry, staging pipeline.
So I just say copy from this one.
So I get all the same thing except I change the branch.
Okay, let's come down and we are going to change the branch to hyphen proud here.
So that's the production branch that I created.
If you have if you created with a different name, make sure you mention the right branch name here
and really nothing much.
Let's just save it.
Let's refresh this.
Okay.
So it's really not showing here.
It's just showing Bill.
Now, it should show Bill with parameters.
I think we need to run it once and then it starts showing Bill with parameters.
So I'm going to say build now.
And then I want to cancel it, actually.
Let's see.
That works.
Okay.
That got canceled.
Let's refresh.
Still nothing.
Let's click on it once again.
Build now.
Okay.
Yeah.
Now it shows build with parameters.
I'm going to click on build with parameters there.
Right.
So build in place of build.
Now let's say I want to deploy this artifact, right?
That one.
So in place of build, which is the build ID, we're going to say 16.
And in place of time, we are going to mention that.
Right.
Okay.
I can get it from here.
And let's say Bill.
And let's look at the logs.
Okay.
Wait.
No inventory was passed.
It's not able to find the host ignoring app server group.
Oh, I see the mistake I've given here.
Prod one dot inventory.
Let me check my code.
Yeah, that one.
Okay.
That was a mistake the file name inventory filing have given wrong.
The file name is product inventory, not part one point inventory.
I don't know how I missed it.
Anyways, let's save it and then I'm going to commit and push once again.
Against some message control less.
And put a checkmark there.
Hopefully that should.
Come here.
Yeah.
Okay.
Trigger the pipeline.
I'm going to cancel it because we did not pass the parameters.
Cancel.
Cancel that.
Okay.
Now I'm going to say build with parameters, build ID and that are same what I entered previously 16
and time, which is the build timestamp of the artifact.
And let's say build.
Okay.
Let's look at the logs.
So I'm going to pause my screen and resume when this is completed.
I'll get one edit and I'll.
I wanted you to see this.
This is an apt error.
When we executed the playbook, it was already started the installation of JDC, so it was doing apt
install JDC like that and apt is already busy.
We canceled it the pipeline, but the command was already running over there and we tried to run it
once again.
So it is saying.
The big front end lock.
Once an apt command is running, you cannot run one more apt command.
So previous command got executed before we cancelled it.
So it is still running.
We need to wait for some time or it's still getting the error.
Better a reboot.
That server app zero one prod we can reboot, but I will wait for, let's say 5 minutes and then try
to execute the pipeline once again.
Okay.
I think I waited enough.
Let me run it once again.
So 16 was that and that timestamp again, take it from Nexis.
We should build.
Let's look at the logs now.
It seems that is working.
Let's wait for some time.
Okay.
That completed successfully.
I'm going to give it a few minutes and check.
The application server, the prod on Port 88, but I'm going to wait for a few minutes and then hit
enter.
Okay.
I did wait for a few minutes and just 2 minutes hit enter and you see it is showing the page.
That means the deployment completed successfully.
We are able to test it also.