All right.
So we created two pipelines successfully, one for staging and one for production.
Once these pipelines are ready, then every day they will be executing.
Let's see what happens on a regular basis.
And how do we move the chord changes to a staging environment and when it is approved from there we
move it to production environment.
So the process is similar to what we have seen in previous project.
We test a staging pipeline.
If everything is good, then we merge the code from staging branch to production branch.
But this time we don't want it to trigger this job automatically.
So production pipeline configure.
And we will remove this git hub hook trigger.
Forget ACM polling and check this save.
The reason we don't want it to run automatically is because we want to deploy the artifact that we mentioned.
This is parameter is job, so we need to pass parameters.
Once the software testers test the staging application and they give the go ahead, then we will run
this, pass the correct parameters and deploy the artifact to the production environment.
Okay, so let's go to VS Code now and we will switch from this branch to the staging branch we had created
previously that one sicced Ants and Stanford Ansible again.
Okay, we switch there, we close these files.
So now we again we are not going to make any code change really.
We will just put some hash or remove some hash in the file, which really doesn't affect our application.
So I'm going to just.
And here a few more hash and I'll say control se.
And this is the staging and staging branch.
So assuming developer made the code change and then they are going to test it locally, if everything
is good, they're going to commit and push like this.
Your test.
Staging pipeline.
Control less.
Checkmark.
So this will push the change to the staging branch, which will trigger the staging pipeline.
Let's go to staging pipeline.
And to stage there.
All right.
So it already triggered the pipeline.
And let's wait until this is completed.
So this pipeline completed successfully.
There's a new deployment, the software testers, the quality assurance.
Dean will test it.
If everything is good, they go ahead and give you a signal to deploy it on production.
So we are going to merge the code changes to production branch.
Okay.
I come to get back and get checked out.
Alright, I'll go back and I'll just say F project, intro e profile project.
Okay, so I'm in CCD, Genk Ansible Branch and I need to merge all these changes with the production
branch.
So I'm going to say git checkout.
See, I said hyphen chink and hyphen pro.
That is our production branch.
For this project that this is the production branch and we're going to say git merge.
With CIC hyphen Jen Gantz.
So that is our staging or testing branch, whatever you want to call it.
So all the changes is tested in that branch.
Now we're going to merge it with the production branch.
Yeah.
So we moved the changes to the production branch.
It says one file merged, one insertion that is just re-employed MD file we are testing right now.
This is not going to trigger our pipeline.
Right.
Because we have removed that option.
Let's go to.
Production branch.
Saudi production pipeline.
Now we say build with parameters, but we really need to now get the right parameters.
So I'm going to refresh this.
Okay.
This seems confusing from here.
Let's better get it from directly the pipeline, which will be absolutely correct.
So go to the staging pipeline and we go to the latest build logs, scroll down, scroll down or you
can at the end print those variables also, but we can get it from here.
I can get it from the URL that uploaded the artifact and best we can get it from here itself.
Right.
So the build id is four and the build timestamp is exact.
So we can just use it from here.
Let's copy the.
Timestamp.
Bill 34.
Let's go to the production.
Build with parameters.
Four as the bill died and time as this value.
Sure, there's no extra space.
Be careful in copy pasting this.
This will be the same artifact will be here for that one.
This is the artifact.
And we will say build.
That should trigger the pipeline.
Okay.
So that worked.
Of course it will work.
We already tested it, which is deploying a different artifact.
Now, you may think that this is a lot of work.
I am passing the parameters.
Now, in previous projects I have shown you how this can be done automatically, but this time we are
using configuration management and yes, there will be some manual intervention.
But here is the good part.
This job or this pipeline can deploy any artifact.
If you want to roll back to a previous artifact, you don't need to write a separate code.
You don't need to write a separate pipeline.
All you need to do is run this job and pass the parameter you want to rollback.
Pass the parameter of older artifact.
It's going to deploy the older artifact.
So it's multipurpose pipeline.
Now, it can deploy latest artifact, older whatever you want.
I call that efficient.
Not sure this can be refined much more for further, but this is all in this project.
We are going to now make sure we don't pay extra money.
We are going to terminate.
If you are done with this project, just terminate these two instances.
Only.
Only the application server.
You terminate.
Terminate.
And you know, it's no big deal.
You can just launch it anytime you want.
All you need to do is just update the Route 53 entries.
That's all with the new private IP launch.
Update The entry credentials are saved.
Pipeline everything is there.
I guess only these two things you terminate and the rest are there.
Three.
So Owner Nexus and Jenkins, you shut it down because we will need it in the next projects, so power
them off.
You can keep the Route 53 hosted records.
That's locked out anyways now.
So that's all you need to do as far as the cleanup is concerned in this project.
If you come this far.
A job well done.
Congratulation.
I will see you in the next project.