Welcome to the AWB Securities Project.
In this project, we are going to practice and implement AWB securities.
What does it really mean?
We'll understand that in a moments.
But as of now, I can tell you this, having securities concepts on your resume will really boost your
confidence.
And the power of your resume itself.
So let's understand a few things about this project.
So this project is for awareness, encouragement, and I want to equip you with the right knowledge.
Yeah, this is more about implementing security in all the other projects you have done previously,
which used A.W. as services.
So this is not like a wholesome project, but it's more like cherry on the cake for you and for your
resume, of course, which will, of course, benefit the organization which is hiring you.
So when I say awareness, that's because the biggest problem I see in the security is people are not
aware they make mistakes, which could be very expensive.
So this session is going to kind of enlighten you that, hey, there are these kinds of attacks and
you have so many tools with you that you can use and prevent those attacks.
Also, I want to encourage you to learn more in the security as more and more we shift towards cloud
computing, the more we are getting exposed.
So let's see different kinds of attacks.
Well, various kinds of attacks that you see nowadays here, there are just few of them distributed
denial of service where someone attacks you or your organization infrastructure to bring it down.
Or slow it down, so here the user will be affected, really.
And in turn, your business gets affected man in the middle attack, which is more like that between
the two phone lines, like we see we see in the movies that the phone gets tapped.
Similar to that, in sending data from point A to point B and there is a tap in the middle C, which
listens all the communication or has all the communication phishing, which you are aware about it.
We hear so many stories nowadays about phishing.
Drive by attack, which is mostly used to spread malware where a cyber criminal will inject some malicious
script into insecure websites like you have hosted a website that's really insecure.
So cyber criminals can use this website to plan attack on the user of the site.
So if you if your user uses, you know, accessing your website, the malware gets installed in the
computer or on their smartphone.
Basswood attack, as the name itself said, attack to get your password, and then there are various
methods in that really going in depth on this is really out of the scope of the session.
This for your awareness that there are attacks, lots of lots of attacks like that, and there are few
more.
As fuel injection attack or cross site scripting, eavesdropping attack or malware attack, SQL injection,
where a cyber criminal will use malicious Ezekial code.
So like through a website sending ESKIL injections, which gets inserted into the database, the database
runs those queries and which may reveal a lot of information about the database or even destroy the
database itself.
Cross site scripting, where the attacker aims to execute malicious scripts in a Web browser of the
victim itself.
These attacks occurs when victim visits the websites or the application that executes such kind of code
eavesdropping attack, which is really a theft of information.
It's also sniffing or snooping.
So here the attackers take the advantage of unsecure networks.
And malware attack, of course, where the cyber criminals, the attackers will inject some malware
like Trojan Horse and like that, there really many, many more attacks.
This is just an awareness that they that there is bad, bad, bad world out there which is waiting for
you to make a mistake.
So you'll ask me, what do we do really about it?
Well.
Stay alert.
You should keep security always in your mind, if you remember throughout the projects that he used
or where he used a cloud computing platform, we never exposed our security group or we kept our key
secret.
I did not wanted you to expose your access, your secret to so many places where we keep security.
We kept security in mind, but there are so many more things.
And really doing security on airplanes is very, very easy as compared to any other place.
So being a Davos, what do we really do about it being a diva?
So you have to work hand in hand with the security professionals.
I'm not saying that you go out there and you take all the responsibility in your hand, but everyone
plays their role in security, so as developes plays a role in the security.
Also.
And if you're interested more, you can gain more knowledge and security by learning penetration testing,
ethical hacking, cyber security.
So if you're wondering, are we really talking about def sec ops here, you can say in a sense, yes,
I know that's not such a confident statement and there is reason behind it.
Dempsey is a quantum.
We don't know where.
I really don't know where it got invented the stone, and there's so many people who don't agree with
this terminology and some people agree with this terminology.
I stand on the side of not agreeing with this terminology, because when you create these kinds of terms
in divorce, divorce is already a philosophy of unifying development and operations together.
But then we're creating more teams in that we are seeing dev ops, cloud ops, no ops.
Well, this really confuses the audience more, and the audience could be you and me, the customer
declined the idea organization.
So do I go with the devil?
Can you do.
Should I go with the deficit office candidate?
So just sample this, I'll show you some information from RedHat and EWR and you compare the difference
yourself.
So this is from RedHat, what is cops, I don't want to read all of it, but I wanted you to read a
few things.
Whether you call it a dev ops or dev ops, it has always been ideal to include security as an integral
part of entire app lifecycle.
So not such a confident statement right there, they are saying, is about implementing security in
the divorce pipeline and that's what you can understand for now.
A few more things.
Deficit jobs means thinking about application and infrastructure security from the start.
Now, if you're on cloud computing, you're talking about infrastructure.
You can see cloud security also then.
If you're talking about application security, then there is application security already in place.
To me, it's really about integrating security in Davos.
That is all that was about.
RedHat, let's see, about eight of us.
So on this site.
So Smith, Schmidt, I don't even know how to pronounce it, Julia, I'm so sorry about it.
He's a.
I can call him Stefán, that's his first name, so Stefán is a chief information security officer in
W.S. and he does not agree with this terminology.
Even I don't agree with this terminology.
This is what I really object is this notion that some people have.
That there is security development and operations and they are separate.
So it's not separate.
We really don't need to use a new terminology over there.
There used to be a word water rug to divorce.
If you just Google it rucked dev ops.
That's what we used to call it initially when it started integrating security with divorce.
But then desktops work.
So, no, not really.
I really don't want to confuse you more.
You can be on the side of agreeing with the terminology or not agreeing with any you have to keep in
mind.
So there was devlopment, right?
Then there was operations.
And we streamlined together, it became divorce.
Our developers, our operations team, working together hand in hand, gives you the philosophy of unifying
development and operations team.
We discuss that several times throughout our projects and have created a nice video in our portal,
in our YouTube channel, an animated video of what is developed.
If you still have confusion, you can go through that video.
You we get confused because people confuse us more, right?
So there is no security in Middleford so Dev set off.
That's how you get the terminology dev ops.
So.
Being a divorce, now, working hand in hand with security, you can take that as an objective.
And if you're if you're doing that, if you're implementing security in your divorce pipelines, in
your infrastructure, then you if someone asks you, are you doing sick hours, then you can say, yes,
I am.
But for now, to be very, very specific, what we are doing over here is doing security on eatables
cloud.
We are learning security concepts.
From EWR, the eatables sources we are using to implement the security so we can be safe from those
attacks that we are discussing.
So let's see what are the sources that we are going to use?
In EWR, starting with I am eatables organization, eatables trusted adviser, CM's in easy to keep
elastic load balancer with a secure connection.
So I am you already aware about it.
But we are going to talk about a few more good practices in that established organization, which is
grouping of multiple accounts and how we can implement security over their trusted advisor, which is
isn't completely replacement service, which will give you information security information or other
information.
Also about your account.
Eatables Account Kemmis is for encryption.
We you create keys and store it in CM's, which should be used to encrypt our data.
We are going to get into detail on all these services one by one and implement them.
In our eatables account and so as the same thing you will be doing in your projects also.
More services from eatables, again, eatables inspector, which is a service to scan vulnerability
in your network and in your operating systems.
VPC We already did that.
We did projects on VPC.
So you talk specifically about security group NaCl and VPC flew logs Clowe Trail, which is going to
store all the information, all the EPA calls, any changes happen or any EPA calls that goes through
your account will get recorded in Cottrill eatables config, which is really expensive service.
But what an amazing service, really.
You know, it can distort the configuration of your entire eatables account into one place and can also
show you how things are changing.
All right, other services, guard duty, eatables, wife, eatables, shield, eatables, can't think
guard duty is more like you can think of a security guard or a patrol police like an antivirus of your
account?
Not exactly, but for understanding.
As of now in a the office of the application firewall firewall for your application, not network firewall
lets the security group is a network firewall.
Nakulan PVCs network firewall is on your application.
We'll see how that works.
Eatables Shield, which is to prevent the DOS attack.
And if you go for the big vision, the Advanced Shield, it's very expensive, but it can prevent many,
many, many, many needless attacks for you and also.
If you happen to be a victim of Rudolph's attack and you have Eatables Shield advanced enabled, you
don't need to pay for that resources, it is going to refund that to you.
OK.
I need a misconfiguration.
We're going to talk once again.
Along with that, I'm going to take you through the a few of the data security services like Macie and
few the myriad of security services.
So all the best, good luck, I'm going to now go through all these security sources one by one and
implemented in our eatables account.
So join me on the Wisconsin.