So I have logged into my eatables management console.
And let's check your security, identity and compliance services.
So you see, there are quite many services, I am cognito, secrets, manager, guard, duty inspector,
Amazon Masih.
Van, she'll established firewall manager, detective.
These are some new so there are some new services also.
But you will not see few sources that we discussed in the introduction, like eatables organization
or config or clout through the intersection of management and governance, also VPC, if you talk about
it in network and content delivery.
So this a separate section for security services, because they are very specific for the security purpose,
but the other services like organization.
This is a service to group multiple eatables account, and there so many things you can do, plus you
can implement security policies also there.
I also config, which creates which has the entire configuration of variables account, you can keep
track of every configurations, plus you can set rules also which can find out like if Porton data,
for example, is open, it will alert you, oh, can you fix that automatically?
So services that are purely for security purposes, you will see that in the security section, but
services that are used for other purposes also you will see them in a different section.
So let's go through all the services of one by one that we discussed in introduction.
Understand?
Understand what they provide and how to use it to secure our account and our infrastructure.
Oedema, security, best practices, that's where our focus is going to be the best practices covering
all the security services out of the scope of this.
But nonetheless, we're going to cover so many homeless services for security and we'll see what are
the best practices, how we can leverage it to secure our infrastructure, our pipeline, what are we
using?
Developes.
There could be a misconception, you may be also having it, that if I put something on eatables cloud,
the security is really a tablas responsibility.
I don't need to do anything.
And that's very wrong.
This is a shared responsibility model, so definitely the blues has their own responsibility of securing
the data center, securing your infrastructure physically.
Which is at the region level, availability zone locations are easy to instant in the computer.
We talk about we launch easy to instance, it's in my account.
Can someone access that from their account?
No, it cannot be done.
That's eatables responsibility.
For an example.
I would even already has databases or the private subnets that you create in the VPC.
So it's eatables responsibility to preserve it.
But we also have a lot of responsibility in our head.
Eatables is going to give you all that security.
But for example, if you launch an easy to instance and if you see all traffic in security group is
allowed from anywhere, anybody can access any part of your receipt, for instance.
Now, that falls in your hand like that, there are so many things that falls in the customer's hand
and this is a same diagram which is in eatables documentation.
I have not made that.
This is Eatables shared responsibility model.
So if you see what are the responsibility in our customer data, the data that we put, let's see,
we put some data in every bucket encrypting that data or making sure it's not available for everyone
to be accessed.
That's our responsibility.
Platform, Application, Identity and Access Management IAM.
We have to create the Amusa.
We have to decide what permission it has.
The password offered these us that we are hosting.
Security securing it at no secured with security group or VBC National and even the operating system
Lewis firewall.
It's our responsibility.
So operating system, network and firewall.
Side data encryption and data integrity.
So when you are pushing the data and the data is going from, you know, let's say your data center
to a robust cloud data center, so the data which is going in transit should be encrypted.
You have to encrypt it and send it or Sarasate encryption.
Sajida in-transit should be encrypted data, which is stored on A.W. should be encrypted.
And we decide on those factors, which matters a lot.
So these are the areas will be working in security is really multiple layers.
It's not like one thing that you secure and you're safe and sound.
Security is created multiple layers.
Not think about a big house, right?
With the big house, with a main gate.
Then you have the door and then you have rooms in the doors.
In the rooms you have safe lockers, which is password protected or biometric inside that you have your
valuables.
There are so many levels that a thief has to break to get your valuable data, which is stored in a
safe, which is in a room protected by a door lock with that and then a main door and then the gate.
So you can protect at some level you could be having security guards, watchmen, CCTV cameras.
Biometric locks with which opens with your keys, similar with security, is multiple layers.
So if we take example, everything is secure, you have a secure VPC, you have everything control,
everything is you know, the security groups are in control.
You have the key to log in.
Everything is in your hand.
But if your identity access management, you create a user and it's access keys exposed.
So the cyber criminals can use that access quiggin the control in your account and they can make all
the changes.
They can get whatever they want if they get access to your entire console or you can think of the other
way, that is secure, but your network is not secure.
So you have to secure things at multiple layers.
So we can just start with identity access management.
We already did some part of it in political sites, video like multifactor authentication, securing
our route user.
And so we are going to go more than that.
We are going to get into policies detective controls.
Like using cloud watch for alerts, eatables trusted adviser sources with those infrastructure protection,
protecting your network through private subnets in the VBC National Security Group or Vav or SHIELD
or Guard duty data protection, you know, encrypting your data in transit and addressed incident response.
And you did everything.
But, you know, the incident happens.
So how do you get alerted about that and what actions you are going to take?
What are the sources that we can use to respond to an incident?
And also we're going to talk about application protection.
So all the sources that we are going to see will be falling in this four and five areas.
So along with whatever you're doing in this session, I'm going to also share some reinvent videos and
documentation with you on these services, which can really make you really master of these services,
for example, and different policies of how erm how to get really advanced in that, you know, expertise
in that or Adidas production by using she got due to different services and encryption using CMS.
So I will a lot of reinvent videos with you.
I really, really recommend you go through those videos and practice those things so you get very good
hands on these services.
Plus also throughout the session I'll be sharing documentation with you.
You can bookmark those and then you can use them whenever you want.
So let's get started with our Fausto's, which is an.