So can you talk about, erm, user group and rules?
And this is, I think, the primary thing that you should really take care of, if this is compromise,
you know, doesn't matter how much security you implemented, everything goes out of the window.
OK, so no shared user identity.
Every individual who is using your eatables account should have their own user, their own erm user.
And then you can control on that.
You can keep track of who is doing what and when.
OK, so individual user access only no sharing of credential and control them by using erm policies.
So if there is a developer, the developer should have only access to services that he or she needs,
like S3 or S.A.S. or MQ or whatever, and you can control all those things.
You're going to see that in policies on hands, on lab.
And you should group things together.
There could be many, many users having different different policies or similar policies or similar
policy different from user like developers, group or testers, group or developers groups or admins
group.
You can manage all all these things better by creating a group and giving permission at the group level,
which makes it easier to manage also.
In prerequisites video I have explained about username and password with multifactor authentication,
if it's a password based login to the console, there should be definitely multifactor authentication.
Be very careful with access keys.
You know, some organization have so much tight control that they will not allow users to create access
keys.
And we'll see how we can implement that law organization, you can have multifactor authentication on
APCLS as well, since access keys are so dangerous, it's always recommended to use embroils, which
will generate temporary credentials or the credentials that really rotates automatically.
So if you're purely on your WCA, using Kleinsorge uneatable servers also need a blast and you can use
IAM rules.
Do not use access keys.
This access keys are very dangerous rules uses the keys internally.
They get rotated automatically.
There is no chance of exposing it.
So that's the safest method if you're already on W.S..
So let's get into A.I.M. so we can see some action with policies.
So let's go to I am service.
So currently, I don't have any users in my account, no groups.
There are so many rules.
Customer managed policy, 65 customer managed policies now, by the way, is the same account that I
have used throughout the course in different different projects.
So as I mentioned the previous night's video, you have to enable multifactor authentication and water
security alerts.
You see over here, you have to fix it.
So it sees the root user for this account does not have a MFAT enabled.
So we should enable multifactor authentication for road user are much better when we see the next service
organization will disable the login itself, will not let anyone use the route user.
So no chance of making that mistake itself.
So I'm not doing that, I mean, those security things waterboarded in political video, if you're not
seeing it followed once again, do all the prerequisites for the I am for your loss account and then
you can continue from here.
And I will do one thing on this alias and give a new account name.
I will call it a secure.
The profile.
Alias or whatever, you feel like this has to be unique, OK?
So I'm jumping directly into policies now and policies we can attach it to user to group and to rules,
these policies gives the authorization for a user or a group or a role to do X, Y, Z things.
So you have two kinds of policies over here.
The one where you see that symbol.
These are eatables managed policies created by W.S. and managed by W.S..
You can directly selected and attach it, but they are more open or more closed, like a complete read-only
access or full access, something like that.
But when you want to be very specific, like if you remember, we did this in continuous integration
project on the of side where you used code commit, we specifically created our own policy.
We said this user can only access this repository.
These are called customer managed policies.
If you click on filter policies, you can see customer managed policies.
If you click on that.
These are the policies that I have created in my account, and they don't have that symbol of this scroll
down there, I see VPP proof code.
This is a policy.
Now, the policies are inducing format, but you really don't need to write it in, Jason, you can
create it will take some example.
We already did that, like we created this policy in the project in Continuous Integration Project on
EWR, which created this policy, which I use, which has.
The statement effect allow so this policy is about allowing this action is about allowing these are
the actions.
I could commit a service list repository now update approval.
These are the list of actions which are allowed.
On all the resources and then you have one more over here, which is allow cold comfort and you have
the irony of the repository, the repositories of being very specific.
Only actions are only for this repository, not all the repositories.
On this repository and then here it's similar, but there is a fourth star that meets on this repository
and also contained in the repository, and so policies will be like this effect, allow or deny action.
What actions can be taken and resource on what?
For what?
And this policy will be Atash can be attached to a user, can be attached to a group or can be attached
to a role, and we'll take an example of creating our own policy and we'll create a policy that can
start and stop one particular instance, that's all.
And we will assign it to a user and we'll see whether that user is able to do anything else apart from
that also will put some extra read-only access to that user.
So let's first launch Aniceto instance.
So I have an easy to answer here.
It's a jenkins' incidents and there's the instance ID.
It's in running state, so maybe there is a developer who is using this Jenkins' instance and this developer,
I want to give only this much access that he can start and stop this easy to insurgents and don't cannot
do anything.
So I don't want to you to us to be always up and running, but I don't want every damn developer asking
me that.
Can you start the instant?
How can you stop this?
Just I want to give this to a developer that you log to console and you can start and stop instantly,
but only this one.
OK, so let's do that.
So we need to first create a policy.
So let's click on Create Policy so you can be like really hardcore and create all the Jason yourself.
And this documentation, I'll run you through the documentation, but let's create it through the editor,
so choose a service, I will choose the service to.
If you do service action, what action do you want?
So by default, what an action you select, it's going to be for the allow action.
But if you want to have dinner, you can say switch to deny permission or you can go back to deny or
allow.
Remember one thing.
Deny, supersedes, allow.
So if you have given deny noisey to access and then you have given allowing you to access so deny will
supersede.
Keep that in mind.
If you have conflicting permission, Dinni will supersede.
So there's a list read the difference between a list on your list.
As you know, you can just list those things reads, you know, you can do some grid operations on that
tagging and write book, which is making changes, you know, you can delete also.
So you can click on that and you can see all the actions which are you prefer.
You can select that.
You can just search it from here itself.
So I would like to start.
And stopping since they started shooting so carelessly like that and so full stop.
Stop instance.
OK, so two actions are selected for you to start and stop.
Resources on what now here, it's time to be specific only for that particular issue, for instance.
So I'm going to see Ariadna.
Now, I can give the region name first.
All star means all the regions, so I'll be specific only for that particular region, so which is my
instances in the US West to region.
Account only and the instant.
So let's go to the instance that's, for instance, I'd put it out there.
And let's see, you know, you can just say any which would be for all these incidents that also I can
do, I just add.
Wait a second.
This is Denyer.
I made a mistake, so let's remove it once.
Cancel, whoops.
OK, let's created once again create policy, choose a service.
You see two.
Action, just start and stop.
Start.
Job.
Specifically, source, Aaron.
The region and the U.S. do instant add.
He's also request condition, you can put conditions also on that you can see probably if it's only
from this particular app, can you repeat your multifactor authentication is required or you can give
your own condition if something equals to something like the instance has or the user has this particular
tag, OK?
Like, for example, if you select your.
Like, for example, a resource tag, the tag resource tag means a tag on our resources, specifically
you to instance tag like you can give the tag.
And we can see if it's equal to a particular value, if this matches, then only it will allow that
action so you can give conditions like that again.
Think of many conditions based on your requirement.
We are not doing this because we are going to directly attach it to the user.
So we don't need this condition for now.
Let's review policy.
Let's give a name to this policy will start stop Jenkins'.
OK, create policy.
So this is a customer managed policy and start stop to think it's OK, that's a policy.
No, let's create a user and user, let's name it as.
Developer.
And we'll just give management console access and see custom password.
And give some password and remove request password reset.
Foster does not match.
Oh, yeah, so I have policies now.
It does not match my previous password.
OK, now here I am going to give permission.
Through my door policy to my policy that I created start and stop, OK, so this user will only have
this policy and create producer.
All right, and you are also I'm going to copy that you are an open a different browser.
I give the user name, which is a wrong spelling when I created it, says.
Signing.
Now we know this user, why is it asking to reset the password?
I thought to ensure that I can use let's reset the password, which is a good thing.
OK, we're in.
Let's go to the sea to service.
Oops, you see that we had appeared at EPA, at EPA.
And you will think, hey, I wanted to start stop instance, even that is not possible now, not because
we are in a different region, Ohio, Vihar instance in Oregon.
Right.
So let's do that.
Let's switch to that region.
Let's go to the instance.
OK, not a list of the instance we have given policy to start and out of the instance, but we have
not given permission to list to describe the instances.
You see that it is very, very specific.
Point is, if you can't see the instance, how can we start and stop?
So we have to change the policies or we can edit the existing policy or we can add more policy related
to existing policy.
So going back to our policies.
Let's find out our policy.
Start, stop, jenkins'.
And your policy.
Now we can use again the visual edited and edited, but this time let's do Jason.
John, what are you doing?
Again, you don't need to remember things.
So here I learned through the recommendation after this, and I'll show you some popular policies and
a lot of example policies also.
So this is one statement over here which will all start and stop the instance, I want to give one more.
I'm going to say comma there.
And I'm going to see clipless.
Effect.
Allow so I want to allow you to describe instances.
So action.
To action, honesty, to the action specific, to describe instance instances now I already know that,
so I can very easily write it, but how will you find out?
We'll find out from the documentation.
I get the karma resources.
Outside just the resource, and I'm going to see all so it should be able to describe all instances,
it can list this policy, can list all the instances, but can only start and stop this instance, the
specific Aaron.
So this policy has to permission both are allow one allow start and stop to a specific instance.
The other is allow describe instances for all the resources.
There's no specific order, everything.
Let's review this policy.
And let's see if the changes.
Now, let's go back to your Firefox logged in and I'm going to refresh.
The user only had this quality and you can see the instance, right, OK, in this user, stop the instance.
Yeah, there's so many issues going on there.
No problem, I can stop the instances, stop, stop.
Because you see that successfully stopped the instance at this year getting because not able to describe
so many things.
OK, and that's kind of really annoying, I know.
But then you can do to go online, OK, and stop this just can't start this with this end user launch
an instant.
All right, let's find that out and select already started issues coming up.
You can see the images.
You can do this.
You can do that.
All right, so if you started coming in Canada, do other things also going on Amway's or volumes,
OK, and keep getting letters.
All right, so being very specific, I'll do one more thing, I will find out one more policy.
Eatables managed policy and to the same instant, same user.
Sorry.
So let's go back.
And let's go to our user.
Now you see that one policy, which I have not been able to do that.
This user can change its own password, that's fine, had permission.
Adapt existing policy, and I would like to give his three.
Now, I want to give eatables Spanish policy is three read-only exis live, you don't have permission.
OK, a user having to policy, one created by us, which is customer managed policy and one eatables
managed policy, this one more, but that will be an their.
Now, let's go back to Firefox and let's go to S3.
So Read-Only access, of course, can do everything in list of all those things and click on that.
Advocate, for example, and we profiled artifact and files that can access and even download these
files.
Action.
Download.
All right, see you fine soldier level access can down, of course, download the files, but can this
user do some great operation?
So files downloaded already?
That's critical.
Can we create a folder and see just security with the wrong spelling?
But that's fine.
Let's create see, that doesn't have the permission and the really many, many, many things to different,
different ways.
It's all based on your requirement.
You can select any kind of permission and allotted to the user.
But be specific, OK?
To be safe here, you have to be specific.
It is a very nice reinvent eatables, reinvent video, which talks about more into these policies as
that's the one I am policy master in 60 Minutes.
So this is 2008, a video and this 2019 video of this Norwegian 2020.
And that's fine, this really not many changes.
You can check this 2019 video also.
So I really, really recommend you watch these video, understand practice, this will be, you know,
with the workshop kind of so you can do something, what they are doing over there or they're showing
like that for many, many services that we are going to see.
I show you the relevant videos.
I have used these videos to loan for my eatables certification exam, security exam.
And these videos helped me a lot in that I am policy is one thing you should really master, OK, when
it comes to mastering.
Well, we have to go through the documentation, right.
So let's go to the documentation.
So you can go to the AM documentation and it's really in the user guide, access management policies
and permissions example policies, OK, the best way I think, you know, instead of going through everything
is go with example's policy and you can learn a lot from them and you're going to use them, for example,
policies as so many data for the pipeline for Dinamo Debe, for Amazon, easy to, you know, like Amazon,
easy instanced to attach or detach volume to this policy.
OK, so it's going to be interesting format, of course, so.
Almost similar to what we did, right, but with the condition that I attach and detach the instances.
So here you see two star and star to all these instances, not only volumes and instant's condition,
the distance, Aaron, if this is these two incidents, then only that action like that.
So there are so many example policies, astar style policies is also there.
Policy for the erm itself, Lambretta for ideas for a three.
So you can see some example, politics are and again, simply Google, right, and you see so many examples
of documentation's night falling back to console management console.
So the user group things, we already covered this in political science.
And our focus should be more on policies, how to create policies, your own policy, being specific.
And then based on that, you attach to a role or to a user or to a group is always a good idea.
Our best practice to group users.
OK, so that's all in this video, in the next video, we will be seeing organizations and there is
also a few other policies, legacy policy.
Those will see for the other videos.
So let's go to the aid organizations now.