Aimless organization, this particular service is used to group multiple eatables accounts.
If you're wondering why multiple eatables accounts as well as Political Alert, it's a good practice
or a best practice to have different eatables account for your different environment, like developers,
different production, different testers and that kind of things to finance different.
So when you have multiple accounts, if you're following eatables best practices, then you lose the
control, they'll be different billings, they'll be different controls.
So the good areas have a master account.
And under that you add all your eatables accounts, which you use in your organization, and you can
then control it.
What you can control the billing is centralized.
So you just be the billing from, you know, you see the centralized billing in the master account and
all the accounts you can then group into.
Or you we call it organizational unit, like a finance organization, you can have multiple eatables
accounts and for production you can have a few other accounts.
Now you have enough then Abels accounts of all accounts are used for different, different purposes.
You can group them together, you can create subgroups also.
So it's easier to manage.
Plus, from a security point of view, you can apply policies on the account or on the group or on the
EU.
We call it organizational unit.
What are these policies?
Well, you have seen in policies now which controls the authorization, these policies will be mostly
deny policy, deny a specific thing.
Like, for example, I don't want anybody to create access key in a developer's account.
I can do that, I can implement that through these policies, I can apply to the developer, will you
and every account in that or you can not create access keys will do that exercise.
Also, we can disable route logins.
We can see do not no one can make a street bucket public as so many policies that we can apply.
So once it's applied from the master account with the EU, it cannot be overridden by from the EU to
the master account.
OK, it's actually pretty simple to do you could loose organization, agreeableness organizing shows
in your Mostert account.
You say, I want to create account or add account Yaraka and then you can have multiple accounts.
You can group them together into a new organization units, and then you can apply policies on that.
This is more for governing and management of your multiple accounts, but with security policies.
You can really tightly controlled things at a very higher level.
OK, so it will look something like this and you have a Mostert account, then you can create or you
can under or you can add accounts like a logging account, developers account.
Under that you can create more or use and more account.
So you can have hierarchy like that and you can create it.
Control policy.
Now let's say I want to deny everyone to create an extra bucket or make bucket public and I can apply
on an unemployed applied in or you it will be then implemented on all these sub or use and the account
inside that.
So it's going to be coming from top to bottom.
It cannot go from bottom to up like I cannot over ride like a devil.
Can't, cannot.
All right.
Those settings, it has to be on this coming from the top.
Like, we have courts and Supreme Court, High Court like that.
In India, that's how it is.
OK, let's see how this works, OK?
So I have to establish account for this exercise, you can create more revenues account and try more
things, but I would just have to give this account.
So this may account will be our master account and I'm going to go to organization, eatables organization.
I see you see there.
It's pretty simple, it's his account, organized account of life policies that's in place that you
can go to the user guide and you can read more about it.
Its features, its use cases is really amazing.
It is really amazing control on your multiple account.
I really love the service.
You know, like if I said noise free bucket public, then no, nobody can do it right.
It's kind of like that security very tightly controlled or implemented.
So secret organization.
Trade organization.
So I've created organization and my organization, I have just one account, which is it's just this
account itself.
OK, I want to add other accounts.
I see an account so I can either create a new account from here or I can invite in existing accounts.
I'll invite I already have an account.
So it is telling me to verify your own email account in which I go to my email address under.
So I got a meal like this, I a very fine email address.
So it seems my email address is very.
So let's refresh this.
OK, now I can send an invitation, I will either I can give the email address or I can give the account.
So I give the account idea, I'll keep the NMT, I'll just to invite.
And now I mean that other account, OK, and I'll go to the organization.
It what, our nation.
Yes.
I go to invitation and I can see an invitation.
There so I can see the intimidation.
Now.
Be careful with this, see who is inviting you.
All right, and I know this email address, I know this account name and I'm just going to see except.
Confirm.
OK, what do you see?
There is one problem here, you know, this account can leave.
The organization also logged into account, can leave organization, but you can control that also to
policies.
You can see no one should be able to leave organization.
OK, now let's go to our monster account.
OK, now you will see the other account, which the account name is Mutualistic, so I can keep adding
accounts like that and then I can really group them together.
So you should see it drearier and organize a county route is nothing.
Now I'll see great organizational unit, so I will see.
This is as my Cuvee account for my testers.
Great organizational unit.
And then I'm going to add.
I'm going to put a checkmark on this, we should move and I want to move it here.
And the U.S..
So you see that, and I can tell you and I can hardly and I can add multiple accounts in that, you
know, in this organization we have this particular account like that, again, criminal organization,
accounting and subglacial accounting that in that you can collect more you can add more account.
You can do that.
Now will do the obvious thing, will go to policy, will create policy and apply.
This is called service control policy will apply service control policy to or you.
So it is disabled, forced, I am going to see enable service control policy.
And here you can create policy that already one policy, U.S. fully develops access policy that allows
every operation.
I'm going to create a policy.
Can't you see as soon as they click on created, that shows me Denyer doesn't show me a because that's
why it's used mostly to deny some particular thing.
So let's take our first example that we discussed.
I am so I don't want any user in that account to create keys access here.
So I will search for I am as I am and I will find create Huskey.
OK, so deny I am critics is key, and that's just one thing I see at Resource, I will say this to
I am resource, all resource and resource.
And I don't want to put any condition, if you want, we can put conditions, this is going to be similar
to the I am policy that recruiting.
That's a great policy.
I have to give the name to the policy I see Denyer.
Exos case.
OK, let's create policy.
So I created a policy.
Now let's go to all you.
Go to my Oryu and then I will go to service control policy and then you can find your policy over here.
This is from the rebels.
SCHRUDER Rebels full access.
It's all it should be applied.
And I want to apply this one also.
OK, now let's go to this account and let's see if we can really create access, scheiße.
Come back to this account.
This is the account that is in our Kuai or you, and there is a policy applied to it, let's go to Al.
Go to Yuzu, let's try create a user given name, just keep it just keep it simple.
Service control policy.
I'm testing Coppelia and I'm going to see programatic axis OK, which will create me axis key and secret.
Let's see.
Can we do that.
OK.
As of now, I'm not giving you policy on anything.
Just go next.
And now when I click on Create User.
Users created but with errors successfully created the following user, but there are some problems,
you see I don't see any credentials over here.
So you can clearly use it all here, but that user cannot give cannot be given an excuse.
OK, maybe we denied it totally.
We just using rules, so no excuse.
So there are so many best practices running through documentation and shoyu popular things that should
be denied or allowed.
For example, service control policy, if you Google it, you can find this link.
So General Example's let's go to General Example's.
Denying access to the evidence based on requestor region, you can disable Regents' from the top Lolek
do not use this region and their example for OK.
Deny and not action, what action you cannot take is a condition strings not equal to this.
Can't you start then?
OK, prevent and use set Senate rules from making certain changes.
What changes a candidate so like that?
These are popular examples.
For cloud, watch my general examples, then you have conflict, this this is very important.
This is Austin.
The exam questions also eatables conflict, which, if you are eatables config, enable your recording
all the configuration.
You don't want anyone to disable the eatables configuration because if you disable, it will not record
the configuration and changes or even you don't want anyone to disable the guard duty service or don't
make any changes in the VPC, OK.
Or the tagging you can implement.
Hey, we should always have these kinds of tagging.
If you try to do something else, it will not allow you to tag those things.
OK, that will be very specific and tags.
And again, I recommend you learn more into this and the video.
It is 46 minutes of video, it's all worth and you have more videos falling to that so you can just
search on YouTube.
I also brought these links managing multiple dribblers account, using eatables organization.
Again, really, really recommending you to watch these videos, it will help you a lot to understand
things from a right perspective, from an EWR perspective.
Not from me, not from anybody else, directly from anybody else.
OK, so go through those videos.
So that should be all for your organization.
Join me in the next video for a trusted advisor.