A.W. is a trusted adviser, as the name says, it's an adviser here.
You really don't need to do much.
You just need to use the service.
It will give you advice on cost optimization.
You know, maybe you have some easy does just that is not used for a very, very long time or you have
some dubious volume that are unused.
So it will alert you, hey, you have resources, you're not using it now.
You can delete it and save some money performance.
Right.
You have too many users coming in and accessing a particular service.
But it's not optimum.
And the most requests are slowing down, failing.
So it will give recommendation or no tweet, tweet this or tuneless find you on this security.
That's where our attention is.
OK, I really like the service.
I don't need anybody else to tell me what to do or what not to do.
I the source will tell me, hey, you know, there is support.
This is crazily open and you should better take a look at that or your access keys are exposed to the
public.
It's in the GitHub public repository.
So it will tell you that.
Really.
Yeah, it will scan for the public repositories also and find if there is any access keys and, you
know, hello, alert you.
Hey, your access is exposed.
Amazing.
Right now.
So many recommendations that it gives for fault tolerance for service limits.
We are more interested in security.
Let's check this source.
So let's just search for trusted adviser, let's click on it.
And it is cost optimization, performance security.
And so if there is any Élodie to show you, I don't have any such problems.
So it's not alerting me security says Amazon.
eBay's public snapshot you don't have.
It's a green check.
So you know you're good.
Don't have a public snapshot that can be seen by everyone.
OK, I'm as an artist public.
Sure that's not.
There are other things is a question mark that Amazon has bucket permission.
It's not checking.
Let's see that question mark you can read when it will alert you on why it will work and why it's not
alerting you.
Amuse MFA en route account.
Right.
There's a question mark.
So we need to take care of these things.
Right.
Security group specific board is unrestricted.
You have some security port that is unrestricted.
OK, you better work it out.
But if you go down, these things are great out, OK, which are very, very important.
Checks exposed axis keys.
I really recommend you turn this feature on how well you to upgrade for a plan, you know, upgrade
and you have to start paying for it.
And there are different plans.
It's basically the support plan.
OK, so you have basic developer level, business level and enterprise level for big enterprise.
It's not a big problem is not big money for them are starting from fifteen thousand dollars per month.
This is for enterprise, but it gives a lot of recommendation for Enterprise.
It's fine.
You know, you can even enable business level, OK.
Hundred dollars per month.
Really no big deal for, you know, small organization developer and startups, you know, don't want
to invest.
But I really recommend in on business plan.
Because there's really so many things in this that we use, we consume the services, Vito says it's
not always possible to follow all the best practices.
So trusted adviser can keep alerting us.
And it's not only just about those recommendations, you know, that you get the customer service documentation,
white paper.
24 by seven, access to cloud support engineers via email, chat, phone, it will be definitely much
better in enterprise jindall guidance 24 hours.
And so it's also good for startups.
Maybe you're using an account that already has a business plan or enterprise plan, a check that, you
know, imagine that you already have these many recommendations, maybe you're not even using it.
OK, again, checking the preference section, you can give the email addresses so you get weekly mail
notification that trade preferences for this week, you know, you should do this, this, this, this,
this.
And, you know, you can follow the listings.
So really nothing much to do over here, just need to go for the business plan, what plan you prefer
enablers, give them a notification, you can keep watching it, you can give your notifications, check
trusted adviser documentation for more details, what all it can do, how you can what will be the best
support plan for you?
You can contact the support and discuss with them and get the right plan for you.
So that is all in this one I see in the next video.