OK, next time I'm going to talk directly about easy to keep here.
This is also very short video.
You can create cheapish whenever you want.
You can attach those key to when, when when you're launching Dunston's and you get the private key,
you use that to log in the keys with you, with the public keys, with a W.S. maybe for compliance reason
not.
Maybe it happens so many times because of compliance, you cannot allow anybody else, some third party
provider to create the key players.
You should create them public and private key.
And then you put your own public in your account so you will have only the public and private key will
be with you from the beginning.
Now, no, if you're thinking that it always keeps the private key for itself, that's wrong.
You can check the database compliancy no wants to keep is created to give you the private key.
And they don't hold any private key.
They don't have access to your to instance through Secich or RTP.
That's what they're in the company in their compliance.
But you also have to follow your own compliance.
And based on your compliance, you're not allowed to create keepers uneatable.
So you can create key public private both and you can upload your key and you can use it.
So private keys only with you.
Also sending private key to it all from an unencrypted channel.
And putting them in the pen drives and moving into the different system.
It's not really recommended.
You should keep it in a safe place and that safe place should be probably some tool or something password
protected.
That's the recommendation.
OK, so let's go to the console and see how we can create our own keys and upload it to establish.
Salguero, easy to.
Now, see, this is more of compliance than regular security.
OK, so let's go to keepers.
I clean my keys, OK, so we can create keeper.
I click on that and you know that's the problem, right?
Because of compliance, we should not create the key here.
All right.
So I'm going to cancel that.
I will keep it on my local machine, on my laptop and upload the public key.
Now, you can do that in the actions.
You can import Kebir.
So I'm going to use get back to my keeper, it has the tool as such, kigen.
OK, so I created a keeper.
It's in my don't necessarily directory of my user.
All right.
So I can just see Alice.
Anyways, I'm already in my home territory.
And so I should see here should be going to doctors as such, and so we see the public, we see the
private.
OK, so I look back to my public key and read this and I'm going to copy this public key.
Right now, if you see the matching private keys in my system, it's not with us.
I'm going to see action import Quebecer, give Keepit a name.
Maybe we profile logging key.
And you get this bastard.
Or you can just browsing and just upload your public.
OK, this is the public, not the private key.
All right, so that's where I have now the public debate, I'm launching the instance I can select Diski,
the private keys with me.
I can use that private key to login.
I can really say eye to search.
And I doubt I'm ordering such fake ID and you should clear it with a different name.
OK, just for recognizing which key matching otherwise, you know, it was just the idea.
And this quality here, you may be having the confusion, right.
So you the key and know again the user hatriot IP and you login right.
Like that.
So better again.
Maybe Creative Director Ecology's.
And I will move.
That idea underscored Odyssey to Keyes directly with name profile, hyphen Log-in, hyphen Ky Dot Pam.
Go to my case directly.
So it's easy to recognize that keys matched with that key named.
And then I can password-protected protect this directly or maybe use some tool that I put the keys and
password protect them.
Right.
So that was about compliance on the key, Piers.
And that's all in this video and next video, we'll be talking about encryption keys.
So wrap this up and join me in the next video.