Encrypting your data on cloud.
This is about protecting your data at rest, encryption at rest.
That really means the data which is residing in your cloud computing resources like S3 Dinamo, DB Ebb's
ideas.
This data is encrypted in the storage.
We'll be also talking about encrypting data in transit when the data is flowing, but this session is
about encryption at rest.
So how can we keep the data?
Well, there are so many services in the U.S. that by default provides the encryption like S3 that could
come.
It could there are options where you can just encrypt the data.
In some places they're even mandatory to encrypt the data.
But there the encryption keys are managed by eatables.
So if you already have done some encryption without Kamus, that means you have used eatables, managed
keys to encrypt the data.
In this session, we are going to talk about specifically CM's gimmies service, where you can create
encryption keys or just the keys, which it is used for, encrypt and decrypt both.
You can create symmetric or asymmetric keys in Kamus.
And if you want, you can also upload your own keys and store it in Camisoles Soki created by Cames
or we applaud the key, we are storing it in games.
But where is A.W. storing its keys in the keys that we are uploading or are we creating two games now?
There could be compliance that I don't want to keep my keys in the same hardware as the other customer.
That means I have any new account.
I have keys.
You also have a new account.
You'd also create the keys.
Are these keys stored in the same place?
That's virtually practically impossible for the other account to access your keys.
But even though there are compliance and further compliance, you can use Cloud HSM to the cloud based
hardware security module so you can create an upload your keys and stored in Cloud HSM, which is a
separate hardware.
And of course you'll be charged extra, much more extra than Kym's.
So Kamus is, you know, follows all the compliance of FIPS 140 to level three, validated as Yasim.
So all the popular standards that we have is going to use those and store your keys into a separate
hardware, which will be.
Protected and you can follow the compliance.
They're still not aware about what really deserted and you can just Google, you can find the images,
Claridges, some device.
Now, obviously, it's not the same if men may or may not be same device, what AWB is using.
But you can get an idea.
It's going to be a separate story.
It's going to be tamperproof and all those amazing securities will be there.
If someone is forcibly trying to access it from the AWB center, it will destroy the keys, stuff like
that.
So there are so many compliances.
Turns out to be very expensive to store it over here.
And we are not going to do that, obviously.
So if you ask me, these keys are more secure compared to we put it on normal CM's.
Well, not really any of the chemists will be starring in such kind of hardware, but it's just about
the compliance.
I don't want to store my keys at the same hardware where other keys are stored.
It's that, actually.
And so those are keys and are being installed on games directly or HSM.
What do we encrypt with that?
These are the things that we think we should encrypt as three data ebb's volumes.
You can encrypt with these keys, ideas, data, glacial data, Dinamo Debe EMR and there are a few
other.
But these are the most popular thing you should consider encrypting.
In fact, based on the statistics to most of the data, breach happens because of unencrypted data.
So let's do an exercise, will create keys on CDMs and then we'll use it to encrypt our data.
Let's see how that works.
So it was management council, let's just search for CM's.
Before we get into this, let me remind you, there is no free for CMS, so if you create a key, it
will be charged.
And if you're keeping it for a long, long time, the charges could be huge.
OK, it's not that cheap service, really.
OK, but I still recommend you create the muskies and delete it as I'm doing.
You do the same thing so you not be charged very minimum from a fraction of dollars maybe.
Really, before creating the skis, I will create some users and groups and I will really show you how
this works hand in hand with the erm users who will have the privilege to access the skis, who can
encrypt and decrypt.
Let's understand that as well.
That's the most important part.
So we go to a managed his.
You will see the keys that I have used in this region.
This is not keys that I have created.
This is the keys which AWB has provided us.
So we can include EBAs or for commercial forestry and corruption or ACM customer managed.
These are the key that we will recreate and these are the ones that are charged to this customer store
where you can store your own keys and let's go to erm service and let's create some user.
So I will really create three users.
So I named them as simple alpha.
Beta and Gamma Jass to make it simple.
Look, of course, there will be some real person name Houthi rebels, management control access or
200 Pastorale Keep and.
No password reset required, go next side, not give them any policy whatsoever, will do that to the
group.
OK, so I recommend you just, you know, just check this password's auto generated, so you should
go and I recommend you just put it into a knot somewhere.
I will use my sticky note.
All right, I see it on my sticky notes for now, I'm going to close just now and we will create Group
two groups.
One for the admin.
And I will give administrator access for this group, REDgroup, next user, next group I will create
and I will see you maybe the protesters.
And next step.
I will give this user three full access.
And I think you also give me only access so they can access all the services.
OK, here to scroll down a lot.
There is that.
It's call.
Scrimps, corkscrewing.
OK, OK, Wide-screen, back again and again, that's so weird.
If you don't access this route, only access will be uncharitably account.
So to policy for the second group, D'Astier Group is three full access and only access admin has full
access, let's add.
In the admin will add to the user alpha, so alpha user admin.
You know, like in a wolf pack, I'll fondly write like that in animals like that, our second group.
We will add Feodor to users.
We'll see Beta and Gamma.
OK, so two groups really are one group alpha testers, Group B down gamma admin, as the name says,
administrator full access testers group has three full access and read-only access.
I am currently logged in with my RWD account and now I will create keys with my hood account.
So let's go back to our CM's.
How does it create a key, the two options, symmetric asymmetric asymmetric is one single key which
is used for encryption decryption, but ultimately will have a public private key, just like, you
know, you have SSL key players like that.
So I'll keep symmetrically and advance auction.
So key material.
Do you want to create the key material or would you like to upload your own material external.
OK, but then you have to be very careful.
You have to keep those materials, see if you take some backup offered, because if it's gone, then
you're gone.
One big problem from a security point of view, it's not a problem here.
It is.
If you have deleted the key and you have already used that key to encrypt some data, you cannot recover
it ever.
So there's also not a new option to delete the keys over here directly, Kamus keys you cannot delete
directly, they will be forced.
You have to, you know, enable the delete scheduler delete, which minimum is seven days maximum.
So many more days.
Minimum is seven days or seven days.
You cannot delete a key even if you created it, even if you have full access.
So that's just a safety valve.
So in case by accidentally someone disable the key or schedule for deletion, then you can only have
seven days to no redo that and not delete it again.
Let me remind you, if you delete your keys, you will not be able to recover your data ever.
It will be encrypted and it does not hold the keys with them.
So there's no chance you will be able to ever recover the data.
So we will not use the external material, we'll just use the Kamus model, you.
You have the other option called HSM that is very expensive.
Just keep over here on the Kamus go next.
Let's give a name I will give them as a V profile hyphen ke.
In C or something like that, like encryption key.
All right, and I'll just see you next.
Now, permission who will be the administrator of the permission when I say it will be the person who
can control the key, the deletion, the disable, enable all those things.
So I would like to give that to Alpha.
I know Alpha is anyway's the admin.
I will give it to Beta, which is part of ESTOS group.
And Tester's group has three full access and only access, so I will make admin WITHA.
The second user, al-Malki administrator Julie Diski, how you keep that check mark on.
Now, you see, that was what I mean, but you can use this key for encryption and decryption, that's
where the magic happens.
I give it to be the only beta user can use this key to encrypt or decrypt.
No other user can use this to encrypt decrypt.
OK, and that's the safety.
All right, and you will see that Gameau user also belongs to the same group, but will not be able
to use that key.
So let's go next.
So this is really the policy that it creates.
And Jason Formato, what are the policies in action create describing right in the camps and who can
do it?
Principal by the user.
All right, so let's finish.
Not the very visible example that we can do with this is with history, but you can use this encryption
key to encrypt anything and we'll keep doing that.
But let's go to history first.
And I will create a bucket here with the name of science, some directly related to science.
And I'm going to be keeping it in the same region, I have the key also in the same region.
OK, now if you scroll down, you can see here is default encryption method, which is disable, we
can enable the encryption of the three Buchard.
When I say Nable, I can use Amazon as tricky.
Now, this is managed by A.W. or I can use the key Miski for the encryption not remember, we have the
full control on that key, OK?
We can decide that this deletion disable enable.
We can set up life-cycle on that.
You can use the sky who cannot use the sky, we can decide all that through policies.
So this comes for a three.
Also, there are choose from your master key.
This is the one that we created selected.
You can see or you can see the name we profile and corruption key in that.
And I want to see create Buchard.
Oh, of course, that will be a common name, people would have used to put some numbers over there,
seven, four, three is something random.
And I will create Buchard.
So I'll go to my bucket and.
To show you the really the visible change first world will make this bucket public, not the bucket,
probably actually a an object and let it make public.
So first, let's applaud an object, a file or text file.
Let's upload a text file.
So I'm a blue, I'm uploading a file into text file employee contacts, so let's assume that their contact
details of the employees in this file and I would like to upload it now.
OK, so use default encryption, Buchard setting or you know, you when you upload an object, you can
delete, decide more or other encryption method, but will keep Kamus, which we are using for the entire
weekend and also for this object.
And I will seek upload.
I acknowledge that I don't have visioning this is a new thing, I have to acknowledge that I don't have
any enabled and that's fine for now.
OK, that's done now who can access this data, think about it, but we created the IBM user, we have
a testers group, Gamma Beta, they have a street full access.
Right.
But the data is encrypted by the Kamus key, which is only accessible by the beta user.
So, yes, people in this use in this group can access the history, but they cannot decrypted if they
don't have the privilege to, the key to the game is key.
Only BITA user has the privilege to use that key for encryption and decryption and of course, the admin
user.
So now let's login with the beta user and let's see how that works.
Oh, before that, we have to make this.
Public, I know, try to make this public and just to show you how it really works, you know, you
in making it public, people will not be able to see this reason outside your permission, so.
I did.
Local public access, I'll remove that check mark, see if the changes as can form.
Yeah, and I will make my object public.
So the object action and make public.
Make public.
So.
OK, let's click on the object.
You should have the end point now if I click on Open, I'm opening it with my logged in user, which
is the route user, I click on it.
And I can open it, no problem with the of user.
I click with this end point.
Even though this is.
A public object, you see, if it's accessed over the Internet, it is invalid argument authorization
and you'll see some kimmons.
Yeah, there it to skim S.A.G. require signature.
So see, this data is public, but still people can't see it because it's encrypted.
That's the part of encryption.
Now, let's login with the user so I will see better user and the password that is in my sticky note
and I promise I'm going to delete that those users.
Signing.
OK, I can go to three and reduce it has a three full access beta user has the power to access the key
also.
OK, access Buckett.
He's an object.
Click on it.
And when this user clicks open, it's opening night.
A lot of.
It is opening with better user privilege, better use, and also has access for the game is key.
So it decrypted entering Mutata, but then.
This year, all it's an anonymous access from the Internet, you'll get the same error because this
is not the URL for the beta user to access it.
There's no authentication authorization here.
It's public.
But the key is not Boddicker.
So.
And that's not possible to see.
Now let's log out and log in with gamma yuzu, OK?
That's where you would see the fun.
OK, so gamma user does have.
The three full access, like the admin user and like the user.
But this user does not have the privilege to access the Kamus key.
OK, which is used to encrypt our data.
So let's go as keep in mind, I'm Gomaa user, I have full access on these three buckets.
Right.
Let's click on that object.
Right now, when I click on Open, I am opening with Gammer user privilege.
And you see that access denied, even though it's public, right?
But anyway, here, when I'm clicking it, that's click opening and with the Gama'a user.
So there's no concept of public I'm sorry here.
But access denied access and for what?
Access for the key galleries that cannot access it, even though has full access to the asri bucket
and of course, the end point, any this.
Cannot be accessed.
So you see, even the data is public and all we're not talking about any public data much, but even
the data is public.
It cannot be accessed.
If it's encrypted, that same will work.
You know, you have given privilege to this bucket for certain users.
So only those users, if those users have the Kimo's access, also Kamus key access, then only they
can use it.
OK, so what about this user goes to the games, right.
And can change things so they're not how about it can elevate its own privilege.
Can you do that.
All right, so that's the key, right, click on that.
Art collection.
So the administrator so let's see, Gama'a user want to make itself the administrator of this key select
and remember, Gammer user has access to a three full and read-only access.
OK.
All right.
Access.
You see, that cannot do that.
Key users want to use the key can can you do that?
OK, do you have to scroll down again, is the error that you're getting OK?
So that's the power of interaction with Kamus.
Now, if this bucket happens to be encrypted with a three keys.
So I'll go back as the admin user.
OK, there I am logged in with the root user, I see Buckett.
And now what I will do is I will change the encryption mechanism itself.
OK.
So let me go to properties.
And default encryption, we're using Kym's, so I'm going to change that.
And let me keep the encryption, but I use Amazon is tricky for encryption.
OK, you can see the difference now.
Not Kamus is three encryption keys.
OK, OK, I'm going to Firefox, where I'm logged in as the Gammer user, and let's see now what happens.
Now, this book is encrypted with three encryption key, not CDMs, and I click on that object.
And I see open.
I think it's still not reflected in that city flusters.
Well, I think it's something different.
Yeah, so the object is still encrypted with key hamis the bucket, which is the next object we applaud,
will be with that encryption is encryption with the this object, it's still with Kimmo.
So let's change that also.
So log in again with the root user.
And on the object, we have properties here and go through encryption, I will see, you know, use
the S3 encryption, see if it.
This got to do with the road user, not go back to the user and let's now try let's refresh this.
Let's see the encryption changed from games to a three.
Yes.
Setting aside encryption using extra key.
Let's click on Open now.
And you see that works, so this is the problem with S3 encryption key and Kim's encryption key came
as encryption key.
You can give privileged who can access the keys, who can use these keys.
But three keys, you know, it's encrypted good.
Like from the public.
You're you see the end point.
This is also happening, right?
So, yes, it includes the at rest, but when you make it public, it's for everyone.
The key can be used to encrypt, can campaign used, ridiculed by anybody is.
OK, now that that was about Ezri, OK, let's let's see S02, let's see what we can do with Ebb's volume.
Ebix volume is also data.
We can encrypt that.
So.
Why launching an instance again, like in a launch instance?
Just like any time I just take everything, default you to my crew, come on, go next single instance
and storage, OK, they're the root of all.
You can encrypt the root volume with your key.
There's an ebb key also managed by the blue.
But this is the key.
And you know, only the user who has access to the keys can encrypt and decrypt data.
So you can and the route volume also previously it was not possible.
Now we have option for that.
And obviously, any other Ebb's volume that you attach, you can encrypt that.
Now, whenever there is an encryption option as previous ideas I don't want to be, you will see the
key over there will all the keys of your Kamus and you can select that key for encrypt and you can then
decrypt your data.
It's that simple, but, you know, it's all about strategy.
So I again recommend you watch a eatables reinvent video.
On YouTube for Kamus, I share the link with you.
OK, that's 20, 19.
Just last year, using egoless games for data protection, access control and audit, so much in detail.
And there's also one more video I want you to see or really watch how encryption works.
This again from Eatables last year, Greenwalt.
So if you have no clarity or clarity or you want to know understand about encryption, decryption,
how it works, what are the keys?
Symmetric asymmetric.
You can watch this video nicely explained how encryption really works.
And I think it's in two parts.
There's also one more over here.
So go ahead.
Watch this.
Take your own notes.
Do the exercises.
And corruption is a very, very serious topic when it comes to data on abuse.
You have to delete as a evolves, as an admin, as a tester, as a developer.
So make sure you understand how encryption works and how you can do that on eatables.
And before I close this video.
Let's talk about deleting the key again, logged in as the root user, you can do anything as a user,
you can make yourself also as admin or you can give any user admin privilege or not privilege.
But deleting is really not possible directly if you see.
Those disable option, the schedule key deletion option, there is no delete option.
OK, so schedule deletion.
And you have a waiting period of 30 days.
You know, I recommend you make it seven days.
That's minimum.
You can go less than that.
If after the goal is, then that's going to alert.
You will not let you.
So once you're done with this exercise, delete the key.
Confirm that you want to delete the keys in seven days.
Yes, I confirm that serial deletion.
Novitzky deletion, that doesn't mean that you can't cancel that now, you can any time, you know.
They canceled mutilation and you have seven days of time, remember, you will not be able to decrypt
your data.
If this keeps going, you need a blue scan to do that for you.
OK, support will not be able to help you.
So I recommend you don't just right away go and delete your key force to watch these videos.
There are some exercises and now you can use that anyways for seven days.
It's not going to go anywhere.
OK, so you have seven days of time practice on campus and that is all in this video.
I'll see you in the next one.
We'll talk about encryption in-transit.