In this video, we'll be talking about encryption in-transit, the data that flows from point A to point
B.
As I said earlier, appeals mechanism can be used to encrypt the data in transit.
What we're really talking about over here is a user accessing your website through a load balancer,
you are giving access with a deep protocol which is unencrypted.
So if you use it as sending any data like user names, passwords, contact details, card details,
you will go on and cryptid.
Anybody can spoof, you know, in the middle and tap in the middle and get their data and clear text.
So it has the connection should be encrypted in this case.
So we can use DBS connection on your load balancer.
You can dominate the encryption at the load balancer.
We have done that already so many times in our projects.
We had a certificate provided by Amazon certificate manager.
We use that to encrypt our data in-transit just coming to our load balancer.
Then were there other kinds of loot as well, like S3 Buckett, the data that goes?
And if you want to force encryption like your data can be accessed from the supercut unencrypted also,
but you can force that with policy, with a three bucket policy that hate my data can be only access
with a secure connection to GPS and not with normal unencrypted data.
You can use for load balancing the certificate from ACM, which you already created in political science
video, and we have already done that.
So I'm just going to go through it.
Just do once again show you again explain the concept.
But a new thing that you're going to see is the bucket policy, which we're going to enforce for S3
encrypted connection.
The other connections to talk about is having a VPN access from your data center, from your environment
to eatables accounts, accessing your Dunston's through research or IDP or extra points or Dinham would
be whatever data you're accessing from your resources, it should be accessed through the secure connection.
So data would be Bengal's encrypted.
So services like, you know, as 3G access or the Internet are the data we can access.
If you make it public, you can encrypt that also in transit.
And again, this is about transit data not addressed in transit download Dinamo DB2 access to the end
points or Yamal data.
In these cases, you really don't need to do much.
You just need to enforce other kinds of data.
Of course, there are so many sources that goes with the study.
Connection could come a repository, for example, become overcommitting the code we can use to WRAL.
We can use such Yooralla.
In any case, both go send the data encrypted only connection.
The data again goes through encrypted Secich goes encrypted DB server traffic you can enforce and it
goes encrypted.
So you see most of the connection of protocol that we are using since the data encrypted using SSL Attila's.
But some places you have to really enforce like a load balancer, use only trippiest noise to traffic
or street use only is to be based on a secure connection.
Encrypted connection is nothing to do with the already been tested.
It's already encrypted connection.
So will take example of the load balancer and will take example of the EU budget.
So let's dive in.
OK, so I have an easy to it's running a service Jenkins service on board AT&T.
Which is unencrypted connection.
It's using the protocol, it should be so we can just access this oral.
Aditi.
OK, so that connection is not security, but clearly your browser will clearly tell you that it's not
a secure connection.
Now you say it's just jenkins', but think about it.
You're entering username and password here that's going on encrypted.
You're storing credentials in Jenkins, the copy paste work you're doing that's going over the connection.
There's so many things that we put in jenkins' like source code of so many, so many things, really.
Everything is going on encrypted.
So from point A to point B, let's assume Pierpoint E Jenkins is point B if there is some man in middle
reading your communication man in middle attack.
All right.
So if they're capturing your network traffic, they can see the data and clear text.
So there are two ways to do this.
One, in the server itself, you can store the certificate and you can enable the deepest connection,
but then that will put law on the system because then then the system will be doing encryption and decryption.
For Jenkins, it's at least it's fine.
But if it's on a website for the public, you know, to so many users coming in, the encryption decryption
is done by the website or the application server, it will impact on the law so we can take a load balancer,
put it in front of it, will encrypt the connection from us to the load balancer, from load balancer
to Jenkins or to any Web server.
The data can be unencrypted if as long as it's in a private network.
So if I put my jenckes in a private subnet load, balancing in a public subnet, which will see in the
VBC section after this and are dominated by a previous connection on load balancer, I'm totally safe.
So let's go to easy to let's create a load balancer.
One thing let me remind you, we're here, I have to switch to North Virginia region because I have.
My certificate in is included in North Virginia region, and I hope you would have also done the same
thing from the previous video.
So you're going to use a certificate.
That certificate of victory in the political sights, so the certificate is in North Virginia region,
so make sure your workload in this instance is in Norfolk, Virginia, and we have to carry the load
balancer also in that region.
So only in my North Virginia, I have the jenkins' server again, similar thing.
And I'm going to create a load balancer.
So I say create load balancer and go with classic for now.
And I am going to make this to be a secure connection and let me give a name and say Jenkins hyphen
Elby.
Insta sport, which will be jenkins', is running so soon.
So it's going to receive the request, dominate your previous connection at load balancer and from load
balancer, it will go to the instance on duty assigned security groups.
I'm going to create a new security group here.
I can see Jenkins hyphen Elby.
And this what if this is really for public, then you can give it anywhere, but if it's not, then
it might be.
Right to call dibs, go next.
All right, now here you will get an option to upload your certificate or you can choose a certificate
from Ekom, which you already have.
It's the same thing for the application load balancer, also configured health check.
Katie noindex A.M. Just four should be fine health check.
I would give just two for now so it can come off very quickly.
At instance, I will add my drinking, for instance.
Now, if this instance is in a private subnet, this is much more better.
Can do some tag, let's say create.
So load balancer is created, but it will not be able to perform the health check because my Ecija instance
security group will not allow to be accessed from anywhere other than my IP.
So I'm going to need the security group of my student students.
I will say I did rule.
And I will say AT&T is allowed from.
Portree, Haiti.
From the load balancer security group, so there's my Jenkins Elby security group, you want to be just
safe, just delete this rule.
And let's see, see, Ron.
So A.J. Jenkins instant security group allows connection from the Lord Balancer Security Group on board
so that we, the health check, will be able to perform and the traffic can be altered, altered or
allowed.
Let's go to the load balancer.
And it's going to take some time to make it healthy, declared healthy is currently out of service,
still in progress.
While it was out of service for a long time, the health check were failing.
Then I had to make a little change in the health check.
I said Slash Log-in and Cevdet.
And then it became healthy.
So if you're also using Jenkins's health check and then to be fined.
And to test that, I also had to enable the security group rule of the Jenkins' I said aloud from my
IP, but if I do that, I will be accessing it directly on duty from my IP.
That would be not secure connection.
So remove that rule.
Allow only access from the load balancer.
Save.
OK, now let's use the load balancer and point.
So each night, GDP is colon slash slash.
So that it alerts you that it is not a known certificate because a certificate is for gruffy dot in
domain, not for Amazon, Netflix, dot com, that's the problem.
But if you at the entry in the DNS.
Like, I'm using GoDaddy, so if I had the entry of this early, if I access it through that you all,
then I will not see this problem.
And let me do that, I'll go to GoDaddy account.
But you don't need to do that, you know, you can skip that part.
Nevertheless, it's going to go it's going to be an encrypted connection, but it's just that the browser
does not recognize cannot match your certificate with this end point.
So for that reason, you don't get that error message.
We can add a in record and we will see jenkins' or whatever hostname you want to prefer and give your
end point.
Of your load balancer Sievert.
And then we can access it like this jenkins', dot, gruffy dot in, and of course I would Jenkins'
and I have to say yes, colon slash, slash.
So that message you will get, because we just updated the entry and it's going to take time to publish
and come to our nearest DNS server or Internet service provider.
So after waiting for almost 15, 20 minutes, I am able to resolve that.
Minder's, those border DNS cache is audiences a little slower to fetch that right?
But maybe if you're in U.S. region, European region, and it will be resolved very quickly.
So, as I said, you can do this or you can skip this part, but I just wanted to show you the certificate
of connection is secure.
It's a as a certificate is valid.
You see that certificate valid and you can see the certificate it's issued for gruffy dot in.
By any star dot, gruffy dot in so any horse we can cure their cancer, gruffy dot and it works fine,
it is issued by Amazon right now.
It can actually see, can I give username and password?
I login, I store any information.
The data is going to go encrypted encryption in-transit.
I know we did this exercise previously also in our projects for the observers.
But now we focus, we're focusing more on encryption here, on security.
So you need to understand these points.
Let's see one more encryption in-transit, which is for S3.
Now, also, you can just delete the load balancer if your work is done, you can delete your instance,
I will go now to the free service.
I guess I'll pick up some random bucket, I have some data in the buckets, that one.
You can create a bucket, upload some data, so.
Let's see classis application, the Acropolis file.
This is a file on this.
Well, there's no next extension, so to be a problem, let's.
Find our science direct budget that we created previously.
And let me tell you this.
Object and we applaud this a bit.
If you have encryption enabled and if you want to disable it for this exercise, you can do that.
But if you're accessing with the admin user route user or the user who has the ownership of the key,
then this will work fine.
No problem.
So I applaud and contact text again.
So any bucket in utero is fine for now.
And just to follow the excise, just make sure it's a tax data.
The object.
And I click on Open.
All right, so you see beautiful, isn't it, strip's connection, but if we want and switch to a strategy
B.
That is also fine, you see, I'm seeing all this data unencrypted.
So no one is forcing me to sit in encrypted right now, this, if there is a man in middle can see this
data so we can only apply force on the EU budget through policies.
In your permission.
Budget policy added.
And I'm going to put a policy over here that will force for encryption, I assure you, that policy.
So your documentation is three Buckett SSL request only occasionally SSL.
So this is a policy.
I'm just going to copy that.
Here, there's a copy, but button copy that.
I go to my three bucket bastard and I just change the Iren, so Coppelia, it's right there off your
bucket, so I just replace it.
And this took place there.
Make sure that there is, you know, that and star there and also here.
OK, let's see what it is really releasing.
There's also an account number, Auriel, allow principal who OK, so I'm going to remove that and say
double courts staff.
So as three get for anyone, anyone is allowed to read it, but denies this basically makes the market
public OK, this ruling makes it public and here deny to everyone every action on this bucket if this
is a condition, OK, if it helps secure transport, false.
This is this is for us.
This is for everyone, OK?
It's a public access over here.
But anyways, it's going to be encrypted.
You should be having principle there like an accountant or your username user to make sure it's for
a specific person.
OK, but just for exercise, I will just show you changes.
And let's go to the object.
And let's click on that.
Open.
OK, if I change that from a strips to actually be it, enter.
If you're not allowed that, you see that now I can be really specific and give it to a user or any
tablas account, because this is public display.
Anybody can see it.
But the point here is the encryption in-transit.
Let's give the public until.
The trips, but not with a strip.
So here I am forcing.
In a different mechanism, I'm forcing here with policy that should be only encrypted, it's trippiest
connection for load balancer, how can be forceful?
Don't give direct access to to Dunstan's a business connection allowed only for a load balancer and
Noisebridge connection so you can force in that be.
OK, if you are done with the exercise, you can just terminate the load balancers and delete your instances.
So coming back to this policy, right, it should be a specific you know, you don't make it public
if you don't need to make it public.
And again, you can use eatables organization and force people to not make the buckets public, even
accidentally.
So that's all in this video, we have seen encryption in-transit for a lot of observers and forestry
bucket Secich RTP, we really need to make any changes, but there are so few things we need to really
take care of that we'll be seeing that in next videos.
That is all for now.