OK, in this video, I'm going to remind you of so many things that I already told you in projects in
previous security videos, also make sure you follow these things religiously.
It's just a reminder I told you these things.
You have to disable hood, Epic's keys and security again through a police organization.
You can force that route.
Logging is disable that also you can do, but primarily make sure Rutba access keys and secured keys
are disabled or deleted.
Again, I cannot keep this stressing more, but security groups should allow only limited IPD immediate
protocols and doesn't matter how many times I tell them there are people, not you specifically, but,
you know, in the project, the developers, the testers, the non ops guys mostly tend to enable rules,
allow everything.
So, again, you can force them by using IAM policies or organizations, ACP mostly through I am policy
that, you know, you don't have access to disable the access.
So they cannot, you know, edit the security rules.
That will be a vital thing.
Password, protect your login keys, keep us from where we create, put it into some password protected
folder or tool somewhere.
Whenever a person leaves an organization, it's an ideal practice to change your keys, you know, you
can go to the authorized keys, you can remove the existing public key, and you can generate new keepers
and store it annuities you to or you can launch a placement of EU instruments with new keys.
That's a standard practice of compliance, mostly only implemented in most of the organization.
Rotate your credentials, the access key secret if you're using if if you don't need a place using A.W.
services, then the rules are fine.
No, it's better to avoid keys.
But if you have keys used by from someone's laptop, some data center somewhere, so make sure you rotate
those credentials.
You should have some compliance in an organization like that to disable this Olcay then, you know,
create a new key DBE credentials, what credentials that you are maintaining.
You can also use a secret manager service, eatables, secret managers service to store your credential
and rotate the credentials.
It comes to be another thing.
But now take note on that.
It's expensive service.
Also, again, I know you.
It takes a lot of money for encrypting your variables, but it does so many amazing things.
Auditing credentials and ah, so you can use that eatables secret manager service, but do check the
charges before you use that service.
In Ayam, you have the access advisor service user to check.
The lease privileges, are you following that lease privileged to the users?
When the images are last changed.
If you go to I am user.
Axis adviser, you can see all this information.
And using Bastiaan Horse to enforce control, like only one point of entry into your VPC, we did this
in Terraformed Project Announceable Project and in the upcoming videos, I'm going to again talk about
Bastian Horse and how much more you can secure that and enforce control from that.
So this is really a secure design, you have an application VPC over there and you have public subnet,
private subnets, these and other WPK management VPC.
So we can put our Bastian host in a separate VPC together.
And we do work from management VPC to application VPC.
This is where you don't know your observer application server database server will be living off your
project.
To manage those.
We can create a separate VPC.
We can put our Bastiano there.
You can put even your developes tools over there.
But Bastiaan Horse is going to be in a public subnet because you need to exit from the public network
to jump into your vehicles, onto your private subnet in the BBC.
Right.
So accessing it from the accessing Bastian, Horst, from the Internet, you can see here one more thing.
You can have VPN connection.
So that goes privately encrypted connection.
And from there you can log in to your application VPC.
So this is really multiple layers.
To get into your infrastructure, if you are an authorized person, you should not have any problem,
but if you are unauthorized cyber criminals, someone then, you know, has to break so many levels
to get in.
So we are just becoming a tough target or tougher, tougher target.
And we are using all the amazing EWR security services to do that.
Now, when you're creating, as you do insurance, you you'll fetch an EMI from a marketplace, obviously.
So you have the option of open Oracle, S.O.S, Windows Server, so many options, but are they really
safe?
I mean, yeah, they applauded by Devinder and we can see want to officially Amies Centaurus, officially
Amemiya from RedHat and Amazon Linux itself.
But these images operating system, we have operating system that, of course, the operating system
has vulnerabilities and they keep growing and growing and growing.
So we need to find the vulnerabilities in the operating system and we are to fix it.
It's a lot of work, really.
Trust me, it's a lot of work.
If you ever done that scanning to find vulnerabilities.
You know, there's a huge list and it's also description how to fix those.
There's a lot of work.
So what can we do?
Well, you can use security hadan EMI from Eatables Marketplace.
You know, these are not free images for you provided from a center of Internet security or Eisel or
from Sance or from Nyst.
And there are a few other providers, but these are the famous ones.
So what these organizations will do, they will take an army of one, two or sentosa any operating system
like that, they will harden.
They'll find out all the vulnerabilities and they'll fix it.
And then you can keep updating them to make sure that you're using secure and hardened EMI.
So your operating system does not have a vulnerability or less vulnerabilities.
Big example of such.
We are saying it's encrypted connection.
Yes.
You're logging in with GIS.
Yes, these are serious, but the city itself has vulnerabilities which can be exploited by the cyber
criminals.
So these secure, hardened armies will remove those vulnerabilities to patch patriot or you can run
your own scanning and patch them.
And that is also fine.
So we'll see both ways.
We'll see the security in Miami.
We'll see scanning and patching, scanning mostly.
Well, here specifically, I'm talking about batching for vulnerabilities, but there are batching available
from the vendor itself.
Like from Ubuntu, from RedHat, from Windows, you know, really Ziggler Patches.
So make sure whenever you launch an instance, you do some bootstrapping and he can use the easy to
use areata.
And you can add on your app update, upgrade command, update windows, update all those commands.
So you for bootstrapping, you can use normal Basche or Bache or partial commands or you can use it.
Ansible pampered chef.
You need to regularly keep patching your operating system.
So if there is a unwanted abilities Apache's provided it gets applied.
All if you're using cloud formation, you can use cloud formations, see if it.
Now, a new patches may even break the system, so you better yesterday, of course, you'll be tested
in some test environment and then you do full production environment, but one that really should be
patched immediately.
So there is a database of vulnerabilities, if it is published that there is a vulnerability, it will
be known by everyone, you know, if you have not patched your exposed.
And one is like that, keep on coming and organizations.
And the vendors keep creating patches for that.
So this is going to be a regular thing, OK?
It's not like a one time walk.
It's going to be a maintenance kind of work.
And there's so many batching.
I'm specifically talking about security, patching, security patches, vulnerability assessment and
then patching it.
So.
AWB does provide a vulnerability assessment service, AWB inspector.
This can scan vulnerability in your network and in your operating system to scan it for your network.
There is no special settings you need to do.
Just go to inspect a service and scan your network.
That's fine.
But for scanning operating system, you need to install an agent based on your operating system.
It's a Linux.
You install Linux agent, Windows, Windows, Windows agent.
So you install an inspector agent and then you can use Eatables Inspector service to scan your network
and also the operating system.
It will generate a very detailed report of the vulnerability in your operating systems.
Or you can just use your top 10 vulnerability assessment tools like Comodo Open was necessary.
There are so many when there would be assessment tools, you can use them, generate report.
But keep in mind, you are generating the report badged so you can fix those vulnerabilities, not just
about scanning, it's also about patching after that.
So next, we'll be seeing a police inspector service.
So join me on Eatables console.
I'm opening the inspectors service.
OK, so it says, I have to install in Eatables agent on my instant's run assessment and then I can
review it.
If you're going to scan the operating system with Inspector, then you definitely need to install the
agent.
But if you just want to scan the network, you don't need to install any agent.
So we'll do both.
So I'm going to go to the easy to service.
I already have insurance agents over here.
Running.
And its name is Cops, and there's a log in Geekcorps Keisel, let me log in to the D.C. Dunstan's first.
It's an Ubuntu machine.
I guess I'll be the road user I have to install inspector agent.
From the documentation installing Amazon inspector agent.
So if it's Amazo Linux, it's really simple to install inspector agent, you can install Inspector Adrian
through systems manager.
Will install it directly logged into the U.S. Dunstone so I'm going to download this Shell script so
you can use Gathercole to download the script, install Scorpions Bastard.
And they should be in Shell script install, I'm just going to see Bash install.
OK, it's installed, let's see, it's status, it will create an Inuit script you see in it, don't
be eatables agent see status and it says it's active and running.
It's not registered to anything, so you can see these errors, but once we register it.
And we done the scanning, you should not see this error, so that's running as of now.
Also, we need to do one more thing before we scan.
We have to give a special tag, some tag.
So I just have the name tag for inspector to.
Scattergories, you tombstone's, we have to give the tag details which Dagg instance you want to scan.
So I want to see project.
If the profile.
If.
Now let's go to inspector service.
And we can see get started.
So network assessment and host assessment for network, you do need agent for host assessment.
You see, inspector agent is required.
And there are also charges mentioned over here, for example, an instance assessment weekly, sixty
one dollars per month, that's weekly.
So you can automate this process.
It runs weekly.
And generate reports for you, OK, this advance set up over here, you can just click on Ron Weekly
and it will automatically skirted around it weekly or you can run it once.
This will just scan everything in your current network, all these.
But let's be specific.
It was set up.
So assessment target we are going to create now for Target that we want to scan, so I will see the
profile in from something like that include all these other instances in this account and region.
No, I want to be specific so I can select the tag project, the profile so every in any instance that
has this tag.
And it has the agent installed and running, it will do the scanning install agent, do you want to
install agent will install, his agent is already installed, so we don't need to install it again and
check that if you wish to install it like this, then you have to make sure you create an IM role with
a system agent privilege so it will login to your insurance access, for instance, and install the
agent for you don't need to do it manually.
That also can be done.
So next.
Now we go to the target, we are going to see what we need to scan, so I'll just cancel all this forced.
I'll give some names can.
All.
Well, notably some, namely Canada like that.
So you have four options, security, best practices, it will scan, I want to do that.
Yes.
Common vulnerabilities and exposure.
Yes, I want that network reliability.
Yes, I want to scan that.
Six benchmarks.
Yes.
So these are very popular things.
OK, you can read about this, the lots and lots of checks that is done.
Against our operating system.
Duration one hour is recommended, it will take a very long time to generate all those reports, too
much of scanning happens.
You can set up a recurrence every seven days or aspell your preference.
I'm just going to do it for one side and check that.
Go next.
We will have everything is good and to create.
I guess it's his assessment started.
You can see I know I can see here collecting data, scan all one liberty, that's our template assessment
target.
Let's go to assessment.
So we profile intra.
Review target, so that's our target audience is unhealthy, it's not yet registered.
OK, what do you see in a moment at issuing Healthy Again Refresher, this releases that the agent is
running and it's able to talk to the inspector service.
If you keep seeing this unhealthy, then you better check your insurance agents health.
OK, ours is running and it's showing.
Healthy, these problems occur when you installing agent from system, so probably the rule you have
not given correct to these you Dunstan's.
And because of some reason, your system is not able to access your students to install the agent,
so it will keep showing you unhealthy, so you have to fix that forced.
OK, so that's healthy and that's our template.
She created we can change the rules whenever we want.
And assessment is going on and it's going to take very, very long time, but I do have a sample data.
Which is in Oregon region.
I did this yesterday, for Aniceto instance, and you can see your status.
Inspector received 857 deliberately message in total from one agent, so the scanning is executed by
the agent and then returns the data and you can see that in the findings section.
So you can filter it in a high priority, low priority, you know.
And you will go crazy if you've seen this first time vulnerability.
Now you'll go crazy looking at these many warnings, these many alerts.
It's crazy for a reason, I'm telling you, because you have to fix all this.
Imagine that, OK?
Of course, there will be details of how to fix their description, recommendation, what you have to
do.
Some are very simple.
Some takes time.
But imagine the amount of time that goes in fixing this with these many vulnerabilities.
OK, we have information on vulnerability.
Which is just one or it's going on a low.
So you target on high vulnerability first, right, and then medium and then low like that, it can
go.
If you want, you can download all this report and Taraborrelli, you can be selective and you can click
on this button over here, so you download export all columns or export visible columns.
I want to see all columns.
So since CSU format.
You can see those.
But they're not all, actually.
So this is for you know, you're looking for specific vulnerability, you find it and you want to export
it, but if you want to download this entire report, go to dashboard and you should see here all the
scanning results and you can click on that which you find and you can download the report.
So in PDF for the information which you wish to, you want to get a finding reports on your full report
and the full report and to generate a report.
The pop up is blog.
I will see Ladak.
Once again.
Generator power.
And that opens in a different browser.
Yes, of course, you can download it then.
Sievert.
You know, we downloaded let's open it.
On open file.
OK, be it was just opening it in the browser itself, I opened it from the add up reader, so you see
it's 212 pages of report.
OK.
Of course, it's everything, not just the finding, but, you know, take your time, take your time,
read these reports.
Not in the end, but, you know, go through them, at least the initial stages, you go through them,
see few of them randomly pick up anything and see if you can fix those things by the recommendation
that they're giving a description recommendation.
So I think I did this file and put this parameter in.
Once you do that, of course, you're to bounce the service.
So there are 100 businesses.
Yes.
So you have to first fix that.
I know if you think that's too much of a joke, man, so then you can invest a little more money and
you can go to D.C. to service.
And instead of.
Now fetching up an EU, Azarian, EMI, from the vendor directly, you can source from the tablas marketplace.
You can go for security product group or, you know, you can just search your favorite.
Provider like, for example, the center of Internet Security, a search for that, so Red Hat Enterprise
Linux, CISO want to now I'm not saying there would be no clarity on this, but there'll be very less,
which can be fixed very quickly.
And you get updates also and there are charges they are not free.
So zero point zero two dollars per hour, you can of course, try them.
It's not a big charge.
But if you want to go for nearly 130 dollars a year, really not a big thing for organization, even
if it's a startup.
So to begin with, you can again really try with.
The had am I run the assessment and you can find out the report and you can compare it with Ovando image
from Devinder.
And you can find a lot of differences, but nevertheless, this is going to be a continuous process.
You have to keep scanning things to keep fixing things so you can automate.
This process is also being a divorce, not fixing, but definitely running patches, running, scanning
regularly through Inspecteur.
Or if you using some third party tool, then you can automate that as well.
There could be a separate security team mostly, which can do and work on fixing.
All you did, Ozick environment, and you need to do that.
All right, so in this section, we talked about the police inspector service specifically, we talked
about what we need best practices also that you have to follow, keeping, patching and updating regularly,
securing your keys, your passwords and other things.
And the next video, we will be talking specifically on network security, VPC, security group Mackle,
those kind of things.
So that's all in the studio with you in the next one.