In this video, we will be talking about securing our network infrastructure, especially by using VPC.
Before we go ahead and create our entire stack, we're using various sources like AC2 ideas or elastic
gache water sources we're using, we need to first create a network layout for that.
And when we create this network layout, we have to be sure that we created safely and securely the
infrastructure layout should be like that.
The public data should be available in the public subnet and private data should be available in private
subnets.
We already did this in TerraForm Ansible, we created VPC public and private subnets with Bastiaan Horst
in the public subnet, but this time we'll be focusing completely on security.
So we also talking about a few other things, including the private subnets like Bastian Holst.
We can use hardened army instead of using Ubuntu or Oracle or a Windows machine.
We can use we can go with the same operating system, but we will go with an Hardan EMI.
From provider CIA Center of Internal Security.
Also, what other thing you can do is you can use a VPN over the Internet so your data goes privately
encrypted and if you can invest more, you can go with Eatables, Direct, connect.
Also, now we have with or without IP, without episodes better, it allows you to direct connect with
VPN.
The other thing is that we can do when we have the VPC.
We can take care of security group rules, which we've been talking from a long, long time in our projects,
but also there's also one more thing National Network Access Control List, which is a firewall on the
subnet, like we have security group, for instance.
Similarly, we have NaCl for this subnet.
And then we also have host based firewalls like in RedHat operating system.
We have five Waldy or IP DBAs in Ubuntu we have you have W in windows, you have Windows firewall and
then we can go for more third party firewall.
So we have multiple lines of defenses, as we discussed about an example where initially a main gate
after that door, after that we get in, there are rooms, doors on the rooms with lock matching keys
or biometric that inside that see if on multiple levels so we can have NaCl third party firewall security
group based firewalls on multiple layers of firewalls.
Sounds very interesting.
And doing it is also very easy in a W.S. third party firewall.
You can fetch from the images.
You can certainly replace marketplace.
There are so many.
EMI, we just thought we can use them as a firewall and we can proxy our connection from their infrastructure.
So VPC design that we have seen in the previous projects, multiple public subnet and multiple private
subnets and Bastion host in the public subnet, and you can connect to this Bastiaan host over IP.
To have a much more secure connection and bastion horseshit, we are going to use and harden EMI from
CIAs, which is not free, but will use it, for instance, and then will unsubscribe for it, not for
learning purposes.
And all our most of our infrastructure will be living in private subnet, like our MySQL databases or
any kind of database or caching nodes, skewing nodes, web server applications that everything in the
private nor Asadi in the private subnet.
In the public subnet, we have Bastion host and load balancer, which is to take traffic from public,
from the Internet.
And so once we have this, we can create more layers and this this is called protection layer.
So in your work in the public subnet, we have load balancer that sends the request not directly to
our application server, but through an easy to instance, which will act as a proxy.
And if you're using right tools, you can filter a lot of things over here itself.
Is Application B security also?
You can apply on that.
So that's your threat protection layer.
And then the traffic will be diverted to your application server, which will be in private subnet.
Then our databases will be in the private subnet.
So it's multiple layers of security for you as a search connection for your Bastiaan host or your instance,
you can have a VPN connection.
That's a once you build this rock solid track protection layer, then you can bring in your application
security or your penetration testers.
And test the security, if you don't have a security team, you can get a security consultant, which
they can scan, they can do the vulnerability assessment, they can do penetration testing.
Grey or white box testing, so this if you still have room for vulnerability, these things will be
again cleared by these kinds of people, security professional, and then you can fix those things as
well.
But one important note over here, you need to take permission from eatables before you run penetration
testing at a few places you don't need to take.
So check with Eatables support team before you run any kind of parental bomb penetration testing against
eatables infrastructure.
Now will go to ridiculous console and create a VPC, you can use your ansible playbook or terraformed
code, which we used in previous project to set up the VBC.
Plus, we'll do a few more changes with that.
So join me on the management console.
Well, before I go to the council, I would like to create my VBC to terraform, you can use the same
code from our.
So called GitHub repository.
Now, you should be in the terraformed branch again.
If you have gone through the terraformed project, you know what I am doing, but if you have not gone
through it, I recommend you go through the terraformed project first so you understand what we are
doing really here we are creating VPC, as we have seen in the architectural design, automatically
by using terraform.
We already have the code, but we are going to make some changes.
Like, for example, for Bastin, Horst will be using not Kubuntu instance, but we are going to use
CIAs of one two instance hardily Amoy so Amygdale, we have mentioned in the variables file.
So for our region, US is unwilling to use us to region.
Or I'm going to use you as a reason you can use anything else if you want.
And assuming you have omitted from your previous example, we need to change that, we are going to
use a hardened Oben to EMI from Sears, so let's see how we can find that.
So all you have to do is go to the U.S. to service.
Let's say launch instance.
You can go to a marketplace and we are going with a senior center of Internet security, so I just search
for that CIAs and we can find here.
The images, but we don't really see it's Heidi over here, that's because we have to subscribe for
it.
We get you know, we subscribe for this EMI and they are not free if you see where there's very little
charge for, you know, if you run it for a few hours.
And so we don't find the ideal here.
If we are doing it manually, then we can just select that and we can do next.
But we are doing through TerraForm, so we need EMI ID and for that purpose I'm going to search for
marketplace subscription.
If you see, I already have subscribed for center of Internet security, Ubuntu Linux, which I will
be using.
But I'll show you how you can find your own.
So you can come to market place, you can simply Google this or, you know, you can use that URL and
you can search for your EMI.
I thought you can just review all product and, you know, you can sort by the categories, also security
stuff, I would like to see this just as her enter.
And, you know, from CEOs, we have Red Hat Enterprise, Linux, open to Linux.
OK, so let's say you want to subscribe for an Ubuntu Linux.
So that's go click on that.
And you can say continue to subscribe.
Once you click on this, it will take some time, it will load a few things.
You will get an e-mail notification saying that, hey, you have subscribed for this e-mail.
You can confirm that once you do that, then you should get to continue to configuration button over
here.
Once you click on that, it will open something like this.
OK, so here you can select the region, which your region you want, and you should get the Amedee
casso that a remedy because I'm using not Virginia.
So select your right region now from here.
Also, you can directly launch, but we are doing it through terraformed.
So we just need Amedee also a few other things like the login user, how do we find out?
So now in the marketplace itself, we can see usage, how to use it, you usage instruction.
Once the instance is running, you know, use it saying Ubuntu as the username.
Mostly, it will be same for one, two, one, two, four, RedHat, it had for Amazon, Linux, you
do have one user, but do check it.
If they wish to change those users, you know, you should know them.
So once we get the Amedee, we are going to use it.
And let me remind you again, this is not a free Aimi, but once I am done with this.
We can get rid of the building also, so US East one and, you know, I can just update the other regional
so I can get the idea of all the regions.
But anyways, I'm just using one region, so I'll keep that much.
Now, about this hardened army has one problem with TerraForm.
So with the terraformed, we have the space station host.
Resources, which is going to launch, for instance, from the idea it is going to push this template
at dump location and with remote execution, going to execute a script in the temp location.
Now, one big problem with how they might could be a problem for us, but it's a security measure.
What a script you put in temperature.
It will not execute that.
You will get permission denied.
Plus, when you are doing remote exec and you're giving commands over here, it's going to create a
shell script.
In the Tampa directly and in that time directed, we put these commands and execute that, so basically
in our case we have to shell scripting them directly.
One will have this content and one we are pushing as the template.
So to shell script really both in terms direct, you will get permission denied.
It will not executed.
That's a security.
So what we'll do in our case, for now, we have to execute the script, which executes the initial
decision.
We have seen that in the TerraForm Project.
We have to remove this remote toxic option, there's no other way because it's a template.
OK, we need to push the template.
The variable will be extracted.
We can give a different part for this script, but it's not going to make sense.
I can give home Ubuntu and put it in home Ubuntu and then executed from home Ubuntu.
That is fine.
But the point is.
I couldn't give it over here, let me make you understand this point, otherwise you'll be keep struggling
with this.
So I can I can give that and I'll put this into home open today.
Not directly, but to execute these commands Terraformed will create a shell script in the temp directory
when put this content.
We can't do anything for that.
If you're using in line content, that is the issue you can do, you just have to remove that.
So after infrastructure is created, we login and we can execute that manually or instead of running
it in a Bastion host, I can launch another instance without her name.
I execute the script and terminate that instance that can be done.
OK, so let's keep this will execute it manually.
I'm going to remove this remote exec option completely from here.
And just to show you the problem, I'll keep it in the temp directorate's selfie last year to push the
directly and I will go there and try to execute it manually and you'll see the problem.
OK, anything else we need to do?
So no problem for this, it can push push the files anywhere where an execution is the problem.
So you can execute.
So is it terraform appli?
OK, have proven all my resources.
Let's go to Management Council.
This.
So we have high profile Bastiaan host, that's the IP address and let's look into it.
And we have the key here itself, right?
We profile key.
All right, 012, the address.
Yes.
OK, Verein, let's be the route user, I'll go to the ATM directly.
And you should see that Shell script over here.
And.
It does not have permission, but let's say we execute permission.
Back to all the U.S., right, and let's try and execute that, let's try absolute pot slash slash ridiculous
script.
You see that permission denied.
It's very simple things in that.
So we have given executable permission are the route user, but still it's going to throw permission
denied.
All right, all script is very simple, we install my sequel client, we clone our source code, and
we do the initialization.
Now we have the end point of the ideas over there.
So we have to create the template.
But if it's just a normal shell script, then you can do one another method over here.
So with remote access like we have in line, so we can't do anything, but we can do our part.
So it copies our script so we can we can copy it and do no home directly or anywhere else like that,
not in time, and then we can use part to execute our script, but that we can do for our template.
So for now, we'll just move this script to, let's say, wrote directly the users.
That's the route directly.
And if you see now, I can execute it.
See, that works.
He should have moved it to the home territory of open to use, let's move it.
Slash home slash of one to school to slash slash Ubuntu.
And there will execute those corpses, do it from the open to home directly.
That's just a minor glitch, we can fix that also.
So these are some problems that you can get while you're using hardily in my.
But here you are getting all the security with it.
OK, now let's go to AWB management console.
Let's go to VPC, Sebastian Horst is in the public subnet.
All the other resources are in the private subnet.
So radius is in private, Elastica is in private, Robert Mockus in private subnet.
And we have already seen that in the terraformed project.
Right, so we have a VPC.
We profiled VPC, which has six subnets.
Three public, three private private subnet are the subnets where we have almost all of our infrastructure
being is also in instances in private subnet, but are inaudible sort of been static, is in public
subnet.
So let's go to Bienstock.
The broad.
So the end point, and that's not a secure connection, right?
Very not Virginia region, we have a certificate over here so we can change the configuration of the
load balancer, which we should do.
Load balancer configuration, we will go for a previous connection, so we will see ad listener.
DPS.
Choose the certificate.
And the add of the port, no, of course, four for three that default and.
What we stand for for three.
Yeah, and.
OK, yeah, and I don't want to this, so we can just remove that.
There's no optional here.
We can disable it.
OK, if you're planning to upload your artifact, then you do the health check changes, also slash
login, but I'll keep it as it is because I'm not going with deploying the artifact for now.
We just checking it the security perspective for no other thing.
What you can do is you can also encrypt your Ebb's volume.
We have not given that Inotera phone code.
We can mention our game is key for encryption.
If you have not already encrypted, then we can.
So we're skipping this part over here because we've already done encryption and we will go back to PC
so we can see our security grows from here.
And one big problem I show you with the Bienstock Security Group.
See that inbound role of the security group, 22 allowed from anywhere, which is so bad, which we
can change it to wipe.
Seper.
So in all our previous projects where we have moved our application stack on eatables by doing real
architectural lift and shift, we have taken care of the security group are to keep similar thing in
mind about the security group.
But we have also Network ECL.
That is one more fired wall, but this is for your subnet.
For instance, are in private subnet and via public subnet also so we can create a network for public
and private subnet and we can attach our subnet inside that.
So it's always recommend that you create ECL for your public subnet.
Because that's where the main danger is coming in from the public network, so I will get an initial
network access control list.
Let's give a name and a SEAL, high profile hyphen, public selector VPC.
They create.
Let me first give rules and then I will attach it to the subnet, you can just go to subnet association
and attach the subnet, but let's give the rule.
So as security group, you have inbound and outbound rules both.
But there are a few differences like security group.
You have only allowed rule here.
You have allow and deny both.
So you can explicitly deny traffic over here that I don't want any traffic to be coming from this subnet.
You can do that.
Or this particular IP outbound rule will correct.
One will change one thing by default.
Everything will be denied.
So I'm going to say and rule and you have to do rule number.
The rule will be evaluated based on its order.
So all the numbers I'm going to see 100 and the best practices you give, 100, 200, 300, so you can
add a rule in the middle or do you want to add some rule in the middle of it in between hundred.
Two hundred against a 150.
Otherwise you have to change the entire all the rules, OK, for your many, many.
And also outboards like you want to see rule number 100.
All traffic.
Destination can go anywhere, so from my subnet, any traffic can go out, OK, I'm giving it allowed
will see this.
And if you want to control the traffic going out also, you can just be we can be very specific and
you can decide that only 80 or 443.
Or is the response going back, if you have any inbound as is allowed to introduce allowed in outbound
rule, everything is denied, then it does not work out.
So what is allowed in inbound has to be allowed in the outbound also, so that then only the traffic
will go in the subnet and come out of the subnet.
So outbound I'm giving all allow just to keep it simple for now.
Inbound rule.
So this is for public subnetwork.
So I'm going to say first rule here as.
The rule number 100.
I will see.
Airstrip's.
Four for three is allowed from anywhere because that would be that should be for my load balancer.
And then if you are giving HTP, which is not recommended, then you give the next rule.
But I don't recommend giving those rules.
Make sure you have any connection.
The other we are going to do Secich.
So I'm going to see.
As such, so this is for our Bastiaan host, and here you can give the specific IP if you want your
own public IP, but if it's dynamic, then you have to keep changing it so I can give my IP and I can
try to allow.
And the next rule I will see is.
All the other traffic is denied traffic coming from any other source, all the protocol Allport is denied,
so only to traffic can come in.
One is four for three for my website from anywhere.
And the other 22.
Only from Miyabe, so this is one more layer of security before your security group.
OK, so you had this so, you know, cyber criminal has to penetrate this and then security group.
And then I associated with the subnet, the public subnets.
OK, let's go to Bienstock, so Environment Health looks serious, and I think this is because it's
forwarding the request to instant's also on Potful for three.
And let's go to, for instance, now, load balancer, OK?
So we have disabled Port Eddie four for three.
Easily support that's added that.
Instance Port, also Gwynfor, given for three instance, transport, will see HTP.
Board 80.
Because our instance is running the souls on board, once you deploy your artifact, it should be added
and the health checks should be slashed long enough that you can change if your if you're planning to
upload the artifact.
But they should be fine for listner is for fortressed previous connection, for instance, bought it
is to review protocol cert.
See if this.
And planning to upload the artifact, remember, logging should be the health check.
Let's apply this.
So wait for few moments.
So the health check of Bienstock is severe, and this is because of the health check, let's check every
single instance.
So that's our instance, which is part of our Bienstock.
This is where our services install it to service and we have a load balancer on top of it.
And if you see the instance health is out of service, the status is out of service, the health check
is failing, there is a health check configured, but it is failing.
It is out of service, and that's why.
We see this as severe and you try to access the end point.
Any strip is blocked, so we're going to say DPS colon's.
You see you and that's not working because instance is out of service, the health check is failing,
it's because the health check is failing instances out of service.
And this all happened after we created the initial rule.
Our instance is in this NCCL, so there's an excuse for our private subnet, you name it, as private
hyphen in a civil high profile.
I am coming to the solution it, but we have to understand this new cycle is not like security group
in security group.
Inbound will allow and then automatic and outbound will be also created for it.
Now, here thing is.
Our load balancer, which is in a public subnet, we have this New Zealand, we have the inbounded here,
which is actually goes out Guzzardi coming in.
That is allowed from here.
The connection is made to the private NCCL and here all traffic is allowed.
No problem.
Outbound is all traffic is can go out, so halachic will respond back.
And this rule will allow the health check to go back on board.
Now, the request is going back on Port Etty to public NCCL it comes.
And here there is no port allowed from the instance subnet.
So we have to give one rule over here.
Now, rules are evaluated in numerical order, so we have we are going to give one rule over here,
rule number 99, and we'll see all traffic, all we can be specific.
You can see it also allowed from our VPC.
172 21 zero zero 16 and will receive.
So when the request comes back from the instance to the load balancer, this rule will say that traffic
is allowed, all traffic is allowed from the from this network, which is the VBC.
Yeah, that's our VPC network range, so from here, any traffic can come.
And pass the public subnet because all traffic is allowed from the BBC and the health checks should
pass after this.
Let's check now.
You see now it's instances now in service.
Let's refresh.
And it will be as if it's not secure because we don't have gruffy in sanitoria.
This is a sorry, goofy dot in domain.
He's not here.
We have elastic Bienstock domain, so that's why it's not secured.
But cert is for any of is gruffy dot in.
So goofy, that's why once we are in a cemetery in Gherardi and we access it with right subnet satellite
domain, then we should not have any problem.
So I have created a diagram for your understanding of what just happened, so we know our whole infrastructure
is in one VPC, we have public subnet and private subnet.
In public subnet, we have the classic load balancer.
And on the public subnet, we have inbound rules and outbound rules for any inbound rules.
Is four for three allowed from anywhere from the Internet.
It can accept the request.
And then we also have outbound rule.
What traffic can go out from the subnet?
So when the load balancer is performing a health check, the traffic goes out outbound.
We will check it all out from anywhere and we have that rule, so it will let it go out.
So health check is performed for the instance, which is in private subnet.
And we have NCCL on the private subnet also here in Boundaryless.
So we have not given any rule.
We have said allow everything and traffic, any traffic can go out.
So once the health check is performed, the instance will reply back with the status and it's going
to respond back on.
A random port is also called ephemeral port.
So when it sends the request back, replying to classic load balancer that, hey, this is my health
report, I'm good.
But there is an inbound rule on the public subnet, which is only four for three allowed from Internet
and not anything else, but also Wiggins's.
It's only association, four for three can get in is no other response.
It's going to accept the instances responding back on a random board which will be denied, and then
it shows the instances out of service because it's not getting the response back.
Classic load balancer does not get a response back and it thinks that instances out of service.
When we had the rule.
So public in Seattle, we have updated a rule, all traffic is allowed from the VP code, so instances
in this network, so it accepts the request and the health check is OK.
Otherwise, we had just 443 allowed from anywhere and 22 allowed from on IP and everything else is denied.
So that Helfrich response that was coming back on random board, that was denied.
And rules are evaluated in NCCL in numeric order, so ninety nine rule matches, it will not go and
check the other rules.
It will not go and deny it if it matches the first rule.
It is fine.
So that's the whole circus of initial, the inbound and outbound.
Both you have to take here.
We can put more tighter control on the private NCCL.
We can see in bounds rule allowed only from.
The VPC.
So anything that is in the private subnet will accept the NSA will only accept the connection if it
belongs to this IP address.
Anything else will be denied.
So any seal, any seal really gives very tight control, but you have to understand this, there's a
request that is going out is also going to come back in and on what boat?
No, it comes back.
It could be random boat.
So you have to take care of the inbound and outbound route port.
Now, next, you can go ahead and upload the artifact on the Bienstock do check to change the health
check to slash log-in, upload the artifact.
And, you know, everything is in the private subnet we have.
The memcache the elastic cash, which is in the private subnet, we have Amazon MQ that is also in private
subnet.
So I recommend you play more in this VPC, keep some time, play more, change the initial rules, see
how it affects inbound and outbound, both due to the distance which is in the Bienstock.
Just all those things play around with the initial and then once you're done, you can do the cleanup.
If you have used terraformed, then you can just say terraformed, destroy and everything will be deleted.
There are two amazing videos of eatables reinvent on VPC, VPC Fundamentals and connectivity option.
I recommend you watch.
This is also a repeat of 2009 and you can check that as well.
Another one, advanced VBC design and new capabilities for Amazon.
And again, there is a repeat of that and two thousand nineteen.
So you can watch this video also, it will give you a really deep understanding and VBC concepts and
how to design your work better and more secure.
And of course, it adds added advantage or extra lead on your resume.
You know, we believe in security in the VPC, so all the best for that.
That would be all in this area.
I will see you in the next one.