Ah, let's see a few more cool sources of us about monitoring our accounts for threats.
One is guard duty when we really talk about monitoring threats.
Think about our own operating system.
How do we monitor or prevent the threats on our own computer or on on our own laptop?
We use some antivirus or Internet security tools on guard duty is almost similar to that for your e-mail
account.
And you really don't need to do much over here to just enable the guard duty so that it will start monitoring
your account for potential threats, so you just see enable guard duty and we'll check coutry logs,
which we have enabled the peak flow log.
If you enable the VPC flow log and even DNS log, so it will analyze your network and see if there is
any potential threat.
If there is some Bitcoin mining happening in your account and you get alerted on that, you can even
have connected with Lambretta functions, which can take some action on that.
So let's see how the service looks.
So you really don't need to worry on building for at least one month, one month, you have fruitier
30 days, so you can just start.
Guard duty, you just have to click on this, you see you have 30 days free guard duty, so enable guard
duty and you have to wait.
We don't have really any finding yet.
It's going to take some time and it is based on machine learning automatically.
It will be scanning for long and will develop an intelligence in seven to 14 days.
And then it will and understand what kind of infrastructure traffic comes in and goes out.
It will have a study and if it finds something unusual than your usual traffic, it will alert you.
Let's go to settings.
His cool down a bit, you see, you have an export option, you can export the finding for every six
hours or one hour or 15 minutes, any common weaknesses it will find and export it.
And you can configure an extra bucket where you want to store that output.
So, as I told you, it's going to take a lot of time for it.
So many days, seven days, 14 days to really generate all the right findings.
But we have some sample data.
We can check the sample data.
Let's go to findings now.
And these are some sample data like unauthorized access to your three bucket penetration testing is
happening of interest.
Interesting tools.
Are there the Trojan unauthorized access to easy to back door entries?
We'll see cryptocurrency, if any, bitcoin mining is happening, so you can see such kind of unauthorized
and malicious activity in your account and then you can take action on that.
In the settings you have this list, you can also mention the IP address that you trust, you give the
list of IP address over here and then it will not generate any finding for those IP addresses.
Or you want to say that malicious IP IP addresses are there.
You can add the threat threat list.
So guard duty will keep finding those IP addresses.
Let's check some documentation on this, really, there is nothing much in terms of administration in
this.
Everything is done by God.
It uses machine learning.
But if you want to know what are the IP addresses that you are the trusted IPS or the threat IBBS and
what are the findings?
How to understand the findings.
And you can check the documentation you have the concepts and terminologies.
What are the findings, suppression rules, understanding the finding, finding details.
The finding somebody will have things like finding I.D. severity, which region account ID.
Access key details as three details.
Unusual protocol.
What does that mean?
What is anomalous behavior?
So really not much in documentation.
Also, if you go through the step by step and spend some time with guard duty, you should be able to
understand most of the threats and then you can understand how to deal with them.
You can keep the findings on, but if you are already close to 30 days, you want to disable it, then
you can disable the findings, you can suspend the guard duty.
Suspend means it will just stop the monitoring.
It will not generate a new findings.
But if you disable.
You will also lose any existing findings and any configuration Saltville Disabler.
So we can come back later and enable it and play more with guard duty.
Next, we are seeing Volf Web application firewall.
We already have seen some firewalls, we have seen security group, we have seen NCCL.
We also talked about some third party firewall.
You can purchase them from Marketplace and use it as a threat protection layer.
This firewall is very different.
This is about your applications.
You can put this firewall on in front of cloud front or application load balancer, or even if you're
using API Gateway, Amazon API Gateway, you can use that.
Also, there are some very common rules you can set up or you can set up your own rule that you don't
want any communication coming from in the world from some IP address or a secure injection.
You want to prevent or any such malicious code coming into you all.
You want to prevent that blocking filter it.
You can use that for that.
There are always top 10 security risk and they're already managed rule in for that, you can use it
and you can prevent those top 10 security risk like ESKIL injection cross site scripting, or you can
even create your own rules.
So let's go and check.
How does that work?
So you can search for wife and that's to solve this together, actually, Wolf, and she'll.
So if you use this together, you can have a firewall on your application and you can also be safe from
the DOS attacks, basic shield will be any reasonable.
But if you want to go with Advanced Shield, there are charges for it and we'll talk about that after
we are done with this stuff.
So let's go to Ralph.
So, again, involved there is no here, are there the rules are charged, so if you want to skip this
exercise, you can skip it also.
But I'm going to set a very simple rules.
So let's create web, atheel.
And let's give some name, I will see we profile.
That's.
You can select here which resource you want to use it for cloud front or you want to use it for load
balancer, EPA Gateway or replace absence, you can select the region where you want to create it.
And then you can add the resource here itself if you want, or you can add them later.
Also, as of now, I don't have any application load balancer or anything, but we can create that later.
Also, let's click on Next now about the rules over here.
So you have managed rules, you can create your own rules, but let's see this managed rules.
So mismanaged rules, you know, that A.W. release provides you to use like admin protection, you can
read about this anonymous IP list.
So there are some IPIS that you should prevent access from.
And Linux operating system ESKIL databases to provide to prevent ESKIL injections.
You can select those rules.
What you feel comfortable if you want more advanced rule.
The rules are also sold through a marketplace.
So cyber security cloud managed rules, so you can subscribe that in the marketplace, you can purchase
that a five.
And there's so many rules like that that you can purchase unsubscribe from the marketplace, and we'll
just keep these few rules.
So we selected these three rules, we just select all the three, we want these rules and I'm going
to say next.
You can decide the priority which you want to evaluate first or later, I'll keep that as it is.
Go next.
So cloud watch Metrick will be created for these things.
Let's go next.
Review all this and you can see create Web Essien.
We have of afros created over here, and if you want to, can attach to load balancer, so let's go
to Ecuador to launch an application load balancer.
You go to target group first al Qaeda target group.
Instances.
I just see my target group.
And just for the sake of creating it so I can show you how you can attach these rules.
I was create an empty target group, go to load balancer, load balancer, application load balancer.
To fill in the detail, go next.
That's a complete security group.
Go next.
Configure routing sender to this target group.
So we have an application load balancer created how we can go to work, and it is only for application
load balancer, not for classic.
So you can go to your rule.
Associated eatables resources.
And you can see adorableness resource, you can find your application load balancer and you can see
add now these rules will be applied to our application load balancer.
So, for example, like we have put a skin injection.
So it's going to prevent any activity through coming through the wall, which is trying to do a skill
injection.
To create these rules, you really need to be an expert in the application security.
If you want to include your own rules or you can buy some popular rules or subscribe for popular rules
from the marketplace.
OK, so once you're done with that deleteriously related application load balancer, the next service
will be seeing here in the same dashboard is Eatables Shield.
Eatables Shield protects you from do those attacks, so there is a basic shield or any ways enable in
your account, but you also have an option to subscribe for an advanced shield, which is three thousand
dollars per month.
So don't try to enable that for big enterprises, big companies, it's no big deal because this regular
those attacks on big enterprises.
So I think that's all worth doing it.
It also gives you a dashboard and the plus point of going for advice is not just about the protection
from the reader's attack in even if you already have an advanced shield in the details, attack happens
and you have too many resources that gets created.
The eatables will not charge you for all those resources if you have shield advanced enabled.
It will also show you the dashboard, also the global dashboard last two weeks, what happened, you
can see 157 and BP is largest packett attack for ninety nine GB, pIace largest Bitterroots.
So it will show you the common attacks that are happening and how you can prevent yourself very easily
by just enabling the advance shield.
So it's just about enabling, that's all.
Which is very simple to do, but don't do it if you have a free trade account, but if it's an enterprise,
I really recommend you turn this feature on so you can be protected from very, very common and regularly
happening Budos attacks.
So coming back to a sleights, well, we talked about Vav, and if you enable eatables wife rules,
then you would be protected from the top down oos vulnerability's injection broker authentication and
all the top 10 attacks.
You'll be safe from those attack if you're using Vav Web application firewall.
These are very common attacks that keep happening regularly.
And you can also go and subscribe for better rules from established marketplace.
Or you can write your own rules also for details protection.
You have established Shiel.
So the standard one is to enable the advanced, as I told you, it's three thousand dollars a month.
And if you're a big enterprise organization, then you can really go for it.
One more thing you can do for the lost production is go for Syrian OUTFRONT.
Which we discussed, which we have done the project Eatables Refactoring, that we use the content delivery
network CDN, if you use in the request, will be coming to your CDN or A.W. Education and Illuminists
will have all the kinds of security to prevent doors to its education.
So you can use that CDN and you can get benefited with A.W. security.
Also, if you put off, you can put the rules on CDN so everything gets filtered out at your content
delivery network, a student education, and you don't get any threat or you get very, very little
threat to your infrastructure directly to a load balancer, to your student students or in your VPC.
So imagine the threats would be filtered at so many level students.
There is a Vafamehr there that comes to your load balancer there.
You can have life and security groups and subnets and any NCCL then security group for the instances,
NCCL for the private instance or for the private subnets.
And then you have firewalls.
Still have an amazing track prediction layer, if you use all these sources that we discussed throughout
this eatables security session.
So we you do those attacks happening, Raffi's there, the have advanced will enable cloud front, it
will be neutralized and then the traffic comes to your load balancer and at the load balancer also you
can have the virus.
Things get filtered over there.
It's in the public subnet will have any and then the traffic is out to your private subnets where you
will have your databases, which will be again protected by any special security groups.
And also you make sure your data is encrypted.
So details protection plus all the kinds of security that you get if you use all these sources in a
sequence in the proper order.
All right, so that's all in this video.
Water resources you created, please clean those resources.
Thank you very much for watching these videos.
I'll see you in the next one.